<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601">
    <eadid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="identifier" identifier="80444/xv28350" mainagencycode="orngf" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv28350">gfc_gfu03.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the George Fox College Records
			 <date encodinganalog="date" normal="1949/1995">1949-1995&gt;</date></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">George Fox College Records</titleproper>
        <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding aid prepared by Zoie Clark</author>
        <sponsor>Sponsored by a grant from the National Historical Publications and Records Commission</sponsor>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">George Fox University/Northwest Yearly Meeting of Friends Church Archives<extptr show="embed" actuate="onload" href="http://www.georgefox.edu/offices/communications/creative_srv/logos/university-logos/centered-logos/GFU_logo_blue.jpg"/></publisher>
        <date encodinganalog="date" normal="2011">© 2011</date>
        <address>
          <addressline>416 North Meridian Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Newberg, OR 97132</addressline>
          <addressline>503-554-2415</addressline>
          <addressline>archives@georgefox.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>http://www.georgefox.edu/offices/murdock/Archives/index.html</addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by Zoie Clark
			<date normal="2011">2011</date></creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.</langusage>
      <descrules>Finding aid based on DACS (<title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content Standard</title>).</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="marc21">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">George Fox University, Northwest Yearly Meeting of Friends Church Archives</corpname>
        <address>
          <addressline>416 N. Meridian Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Newberg, OR 97132</addressline>
          <addressline>503-554-2415</addressline>
          <addressline>archives@georgefox.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>http://www.georgefox.edu/offices/murdock/Archives/index.html</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="us" repositorycode="orngf">GFU 03</unitid>
      <origination>
        <corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="110" role="creator">George Fox College, Newberg, Or.</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">George Fox College Records</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" normal="1949/1995">1949-1995</unitdate>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">Approximately 375 linear feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">George Fox College, Newberg, Oregon, was originally established in 1891 as Pacific College and is now known as George Fox University. This collection comprises a variety of documentation including correspondence, minutes, financial documents, planning materials, publications, photographs and other media.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>Collection materials are in <language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="5451_">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>George Fox College (GFC), Newberg, Oregon, was originally established in 1891 as Pacific College. Public and press confusion with other colleges prompted the name change in 1949. George Fox College was chosen to reflect historic and religious ties to the founder of the Friends (Quaker) Church since the college has strong ties to that body. In 1995, with the acquisition of Western Evangelical Seminary in Portland, the name of the college was changed to George Fox University.</p>
      <p> After World War II the Board of Trustees and administration took steps to implement strategic plans that enlarged facilities, salaries, and improved academic offerings.  As the curriculum developed, the education, fine arts, and engineering majors attracted a larger student body.</p>
      <p>During the 1970s and 1980s a Peace Learning Center, Tilikum retreat center, English Language Institute, all at the Newberg campus, and an extension center in Kotzebue, Alaska, were established. A degree-completion program for adults began in 1986 and remote campus locations were added in several Oregon cities and in Boise, Idaho. In 1989 the college acquired an established clinical psychology program from Western Conservative Baptist Seminary in Portland. Plans for master’s programs in education, business management, and Christian studies began at this time. While the main emphasis had been on academics, GFC also participated in collegiate sports throughout its history.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
      <p>This collection comprises a variety of documentation from George Fox College, including Board of Trustees and presidential files, minutes, accreditation, annual reports, and correspondence. Financial files feature budgets, audits, and related matter. Program planning, strategic planning, major campaigns, grant preparations, <title altrender="italic">GFU Life</title> (journal), and events brochures for development are reflected as well as alumni items. Curriculum development and faculty materials encompass academic affairs in minutes, newsletters, and planning documents. Facets of student life including government, organizations, and athletics, are represented through manuals, newsletters, <title altrender="italic">L’Ami</title> yearbooks, <title altrender="italic">The Crescent</title> student newspaper, course catalogs, event planning resources, the <title altrender="italic">Bruin Directory</title>, and photographs. A media collection of video and audio tapes represent various aspects of the college life.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <p>Collection is available for research; selected materials may be restricted.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <controlaccess>
      <p>This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online
		  catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or
		  places should search the catalog using these headings.</p>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">George Fox College, Newberg, Or.</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Quaker</subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Oregon</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Colleges and Universities</subject>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>

