<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://lcweb2.loc.gov/xmlcommon/dtds/ead2002/ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="DC">
    <eadid identifier="personal-papers-of-john-nellis" url="https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/personal-papers-of-john-nellis" encodinganalog="identifier">WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_115</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Personal Papers of John Nellis</titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">World Bank Group Archives</publisher>
        <date normal="2019-03-14" encodinganalog="date">2019-03-14</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>
      Generated by Access to Memory (AtoM) 2.6.4      <date normal="2024-04-05">2024-04-05 16:41 UTC</date>
    </creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
      <descrules encodinganalog="3.7.2">Internal World Bank Group Archives rules based on ISAD(G).</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="fonds" relatedencoding="ISAD(G)v2">
    <did>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Personal Papers of John Nellis</unittitle>
      <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_115</unitid>
      <unitdate id="atom_115355_event" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1990 - 1992, 1995</unitdate>
      <physdesc encodinganalog="3.1.5">
        0.20 linear feet of textual records    </physdesc>
      <repository>
        <corpname>World Bank Group Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <langmaterial encodinganalog="3.4.3">
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination encodinganalog="3.2.1">
        <name id="atom_115355_actor">Nellis, John</name>
      </origination>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="md5-14a68c0a2a61f0535127cce9396b2ec9" encodinganalog="3.2.2">
      <note>
        <p>An American national born in 1938, John Nellis received his B.A. (1960), M.A. (1964), and Ph.D. (1968) in Political Economy from the Maxwell School at Syracuse University. Prior to joining the World Bank, Nellis held teaching and research positions at a number of academic institutions, including the University of Nairobi (as a Fellow of the Institute for Development Studies), Carleton University (as professor of international affairs), and the Maxwell School at Syracuse University (as professor of Development Planning and Public Administration). He also served as the representative of the Ford Foundation in North Africa during which time he conducted research and administered aid programs. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Nellis was employed by the World Bank between 1984 and 2000 during which time he dealt with a variety of development topics and sectors, including privatization, public enterprise reform, market transitioning, and governance and public-sector management issues. Upon joining the Bank in 1984, he was named Management Specialist in the Public Management Unit (PPDPS) of the Projects Policy Department (PPD). The PPDPS, then just a year old, was responsible for advising and developing strategies for improving the management of governments and government-controlled enterprises. 
<lb/>
<lb/>As part of a 1987 Bank-wide reorganization, the PPD was terminated and the functions and staff of the PPDPS were transferred to the newly established Public Sector Management and Private Sector Development Division (CECPS) located in the Country Economics Department (CEC) of the Development Economics Vice Presidency (DEC). Nellis transitioned to CECPS, as well, and was soon after named Principal Management Specialist. CECPS specifically focused on private sector development activities such as assisting in the privatization of state-enterprises, performing private sector assessments, and improving the relations between the public and private sector through regulatory reform.
<lb/>
<lb/>A Bank-wide reorganization in 1993 resulted in the termination of CECPS. Much of its staff and functional responsibility was transferred to the Private Sector Department (PSD). Nellis was one of those transferred to PSD where he was made Manager and then, in 1994, Senior Manager. PSD did not contain internal divisions until 1997. At this point Nellis was named Senior Manager of the Department's Enterprise Group (PSDEN) which focused on country enterprise reform and privatization. His final position at the Bank was director of the PSD. Nellis officially left the Bank in 2000.
<lb/>
<lb/>Following his official departure from the Bank Nellis became a Principal in the research and consulting firm International Analytics. In this capacity he returned to the Bank regularly as a consultant in various regional and sectoral units. He also consulted for: the International Monetary Fund (IMF); the British Department for International Development; the Development Assistance Committee of the OECD; the Asian Development Bank; Transparency International; the Egyptian Centre for Economic Studies; the Government of Bolivia; the Government of Serbia; the Government of Tanzania; and the International Institute. He also served as a Non-Resident Senior Fellow at the Center for Global Development (CGD).</p>
      </note>
    </bioghist>
    <odd type="publicationStatus">
      <p>Published</p>
    </odd>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="3.3.1">
      <p>This fonds contains records related to John Nellis's work in the Public Sector Management and Private Sector Development Division (CECPS) located in the Country Economics Department (CEC) of the Development Economics Vice Presidency (DEC). The majority of the records relate to Nellis's participation in mission travel to the Soviet Union in 1990 and Russia in 1991 and 1992.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="3.2.4">
      <p>Donated to the World Bank Group Archives by John Nellis in 2016.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo>
      <p>
        <date>9 February 2017</date>
      </p>
    </processinfo>
    <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="3.5.3">
      <p>* See Records of the Public Sector Management and Governance Sector ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_101](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-public-sector-management-and-governance-sector)). 
<lb/>
<lb/>* See Records of the Office of the Chief Economist ([WB IBRD/IDA DEC](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-office-of-chief-economist)) for records relating to the Country Economics Department (CEC).
<lb/>
<lb/>* See Records of the Europe and Central Asia Regional Vice Presidency ([WB IBRD/IDA ECA](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-europe-and-central-asia-regional-vice-presidency)) for records related to country and economic work, technical assistance, and project lending to Russia and other Eastern European countries including former Soviet republics. 
<lb/>
<lb/>* See Records of Private Sector Development Sector ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_100](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-private-sector-development-sector)). 
<lb/>
<lb/>* See Records of the Public Sector Management and Governance Sector ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_101](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-public-sector-management-and-governance-sector)). 
<lb/>
<lb/>* See records of Vice Presidencies and networks that the Private Sector Department reported to during Nellis's time in the department (1993-2000): Records of the Finance and Private Sector Department Vice Presidency ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_102](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-finance-and-private-sector-development-vice-presidency)); Records of the Finance, Private Sector Development, and Infrastructure Network ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_103](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-finance-private-sector-development-and-infrastructure-network)); and Records of the Private Sector Development and Infrastructure Vice Presidency ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_107](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-private-sector-development-and-infrastructure-vice-presidency)). 
<lb/>
<lb/>* See oral history by [Geoffrey Lamb](http://oralhistory.worldbank.org/person/lamb-geoffrey-b)</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="3.4.1">
      <p>Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="3.4.2">
      <p>Records are subject to the Copyright Policy of the World Bank Group.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <c level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Country economic research and assessment</unittitle>
          <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_115-01</unitid>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="3.1.3">1990 - 1992, 1995</unitdate>
          <physdesc encodinganalog="3.1.5">
        0.20 linear feet of textual records    </physdesc>
        </did>
        <odd type="publicationStatus">
          <p>Published</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="3.3.1">
          <p>The records in this series primarily relate to the World Bank's involvement in the transition from planned to market economies in Russia immediately following the dissolution of the Soviet Union. Records specifically relate to missions made by Bank officials, including John Nellis, to the then Soviet Union in September and October 1990 and to Russia in November 1991 and August and September 1992. Series primarily consists of handwritten notes written by Nellis during these missions. 
<lb/>
<lb/>The 1990 mission to the Soviet Union was the World Bank's first and was undertaken with staff from the International Monetary Fund (IMF), the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), and the European Bank for Reconstruction and Development. The mission resulted in the publication of the joint authored ['The Economy of the USSR: Summary and Recommendations'](http://documents.worldbank.org/curated/en/187491468769887526/pdf/multi-page.pdf). During the trip, John Nellis's role was to examine the prospects for enterprise reform and privatization primarily through interviews with Soviet ministries (including Ministry of Justice and various sector and union ministries), other government officials, companies, financial authorities, and academics. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Notes taken by Nellis during these interviews are included in this series. The handwritten notes are heavily annotated in Nellis's hand. A transcription of the notes is also included as is a brief summary of the trip authored by Nellis and submitted to a select number of Bank staff. Further, notes authored by Nellis for a presentation to Bank President Barber Conable are included. The presentation, dated November 10, 1990, is titled, "Soviet Economic Study: Enterprise Reform and Privatization Component" and summarizes what the mission to the Soviet Union learned about potential enterprise reform and suggests avenues for the Bank's involvement in the reform process. In addition, a World Bank Discussion Paper authored by Nellis entitled "Improving the Performance of Soviet Enterprises" is included. The paper is based on interviews undertaken by Nellis during the 1990 mission and was published in 1991. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Records relating to a second trip to Moscow by Bank officials in November 1991 are also included. The purpose of the trip was to gain knowledge about the state and its economy and advance the process of enterprise reform and privatization. Notes are, again, handwritten and heavily annotated by Nellis. The World Bank team also stopped in Hungary and notes from Nellis's meetings in Budapest are also included. A mission summary authored by Nellis entitled "Privatization in the Republic of Russia" is also included. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Records relating to a third trip to Moscow in August and September of 1992 are also included in this series. Nellis was charged with researching corporate governance and property funds. Again, records include handwritten notes made by Nellis during interviews with Russian government officials and other interested parties, both Russian and international. Topics include: economic and political developments in Russia; privatization efforts; voucher program; corporate governance; finance sector; energy sector; foreign investment; and inflation.
<lb/>
<lb/>The series also contains a small amount of notes made by Nellis during a series of talks and meetings between May 18, 1992 and May 27, 1992. The notes appear to have come from the same notebook as the Soviet Union/Russia notes. These events include a number of Bank staff and external parties speaking on privatization in Russia and EasternEurope. A separate set of notes on a talk by World Bank staff member Qimiao Fan in April 1995 on restructuring of Russian enterprise is also included.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement encodinganalog="3.3.4">
          <p>Original order of records has been maintained.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <processinfo>
          <p>
            <date>9 February 2017</date>
          </p>
        </processinfo>
        <accessrestrict encodinganalog="3.4.1">
          <p>Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on the Disclosure of Information.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict encodinganalog="3.4.2">
          <p>Records are subject to the Copyright Policy of the World Bank Group.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Soviet Union - Report: Improving the Performance of Soviet Enterprises</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">30317472</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1991-03-01/1991-03-04" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1991-03-01 - 1991-03-04</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Russia - Enterprise restructuring and economic policy - Notes from presentation</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">30317471</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1995-04-11/1995-04-11" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1995-04-11</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Russia - November 1991 mission summary</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">30317470</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1991-12-04/1991-12-04" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1991-12-04</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Russia and Hungary - Mission and meeting notes</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">30317469</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1991-11-24/1992-09-29" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1991-11-24 - 1992-09-29</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Soviet Union - Presentation to President Conable - Soviet Economic Study: Enterprise Privatization Component</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">30317468</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1990-11-10/1990-11-10" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1990-11-10</unitdate>
            <dao linktype="simple" href="https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/uploads/r/world-bank-group-archives/7/3/7/737378241223903b87b4e8143aa13edbf78dca8c25d5503958249cc24e5be27b/WorldBankGroupArchivesFolder30317468_141.jpg" role="reference" actuate="onrequest" show="embed"/>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Soviet Union - September/October 1990 mission summary</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">30317467</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1990-10-10/1990-10-10" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1990-10-10</unitdate>
            <dao linktype="simple" href="https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/uploads/r/world-bank-group-archives/1/0/5/105b5e448744baa79abc65de7b15f8a522e7cabaffee8c342edfafaa3d4ecd08/WorldBankGroupArchivesFolder30317467_141.jpg" role="reference" actuate="onrequest" show="embed"/>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Soviet Union - September/October 1990 mission notes transcribed</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">30317466</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1990-10-10/1990-10-10" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1990-10-10</unitdate>
            <dao linktype="simple" href="https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/uploads/r/world-bank-group-archives/5/b/4/5b4864cdc9c1a9744f7474c009b079c7096a4e4f994ead949c57b367a04f16a1/WorldBankGroupArchivesFolder30317466_141.jpg" role="reference" actuate="onrequest" show="embed"/>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Soviet Union - Mission notes</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">30317465</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1990-09-17/1990-10-04" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1990-09-17 - 1990-10-04</unitdate>
            <dao linktype="simple" href="https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/uploads/r/world-bank-group-archives/7/7/a/77a0800239f8c8262268091b61da549c455fcc598b3f299e18b1e89adba3debf/WorldBankGroupArchivesFolder30317465_141.jpg" role="reference" actuate="onrequest" show="embed"/>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
