<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://lcweb2.loc.gov/xmlcommon/dtds/ead2002/ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="DC">
    <eadid identifier="records-of-environmentally-and-socially-sustainable-development-network" url="https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-environmentally-and-socially-sustainable-development-network" encodinganalog="identifier">WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_92</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Records of the Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network</titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">World Bank Group Archives</publisher>
        <date normal="2015-03-05" encodinganalog="date">2015-03-05</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>
      Generated by Access to Memory (AtoM) 2.6.4      <date normal="2024-04-05">2024-04-05 16:38 UTC</date>
    </creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
      <descrules encodinganalog="3.7.2">Internal World Bank Group Archives rules based on ISAD(G).</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="fonds" relatedencoding="ISAD(G)v2">
    <did>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Records of the Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network</unittitle>
      <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_92</unitid>
      <unitdate id="atom_629_event" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1994 - 2003 (predominant 1998 - 2003)</unitdate>
      <physdesc encodinganalog="3.1.5">
        26.56 linear feet of textual records    </physdesc>
      <repository>
        <corpname>World Bank Group Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <origination encodinganalog="3.2.1">
        <name id="atom_629_actor">Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network</name>
      </origination>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="md5-da8efc1c518854db39b7f20647509a1f" encodinganalog="3.2.2">
      <note>
        <p>The Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network (ESSD) was created in 1997 as part of President Wolfensohn's reorganization of the World Bank. The reorganization's objective was to strike a better balance between country focus and sectoral excellence. It was also motivated by recognition that the Bank's development programs were excessively driven by a culture of lending. The need to increase attention towards on client needs and the quality of results was addressed.
<lb/>
<lb/>To facilitate sharingof expertise and knowledge, the Bank established networks that linked Bank-wide communities of staff working in the same field across organizational boundaries and with external partners. The networks were intended to link staff working in the same sectors throughout the Bank, whether the staff member was located in the regional Vice Presidencies, sectoral departments, Independent Evaluation Group (IEG, formerly the Operations Evaluation Group [OED]), World Bank Institute (WBI), or Development Economics (DEC). The objectives and responsibilities of the networks were many: reduce fragmentation; increase information flow; set priorities; manage quality; run the information system; consolidate external partnerships; vet staff promotions; and disseminate best practices. The work programs of network staff focused on:
<lb/>
<lb/>* Global knowledge - putting the best development knowledge in the hands of Bank task teams; ensuring that the knowledge base was accessible to external clients; and contributing to the growth of the knowledge base.
<lb/>
<lb/>* Enhanced skills - developing and providing content to training courses; establishing professional and technical standards for professional development.
<lb/>
<lb/>* Shared strategies - assisting regional and central units to develop a common sector agenda, and ensuring that skills are effectively deployed across the entire network. Network leadership assumed responsibility for global programs, sector strategy development and evaluation, strategic partnerships, and learning and dissemination.
<lb/>
<lb/>* Best teams and best practices - improving the Bank's flexibility and mobility by building stronger task teams and delivering higher quality products.
<lb/>
<lb/>* Institutional initiatives - providing substantial support for new Bank-wide initiatives, such as social development, rural development, financial sector, anti-corruption, human resources, and knowledge partnerships.
<lb/>
<lb/>ESSD was one of the first of three networks to be created in 1997; the others were the Poverty Reduction and Economic Management Network (PREM) and the Human Development Network (HDN). Soon after, in 1997-98, the Private Sector and Infrastructure Network (PSI) was created. In 2000-01, the Operation Policy and Strategy Department became the Operations Policy and Country Services Network (OPCS). In 2003-04, the PSI became the Financial and Private Sector Development Network (FPSD). In 2007 ESSD was combined with Infrastructure to form the Sustainable Development Network (SDN).
<lb/>
<lb/>ESSD is organized in the same way as the other Bank networks. Each network is headed by a vice president and head of network. Under the vice president is a network council which that oversees the entire network. The council is composed of the top network managers from each Region and is responsible for setting the overall agenda for the network and for promoting effective deployment of skills across network units. It deliberates on issues relevant to the functions and objectives of the network - e.g., strategy; people; knowledge; quality/business process; and external partnerships.
<lb/>
<lb/>Each thematic network covers several related sectors of development. When the ESSD was created in 1997, it contained three sector departments: Environment Department (ENV); Rural Development Department (RDV); and Social Development Department (SDV). It also contained the Secretariat of the Consultative Group for International Agricultural Research (CGIAR). In 2002, RDV was renamed the Agriculture and Rural Development Department (ARD). Each sector department has its own board, with representatives drawn from the Regions as well as from the network itself. The sector boards are accountable to the network council and are supported by a secretariat.</p>
      </note>
    </bioghist>
    <odd type="publicationStatus">
      <p>Published</p>
    </odd>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="3.3.1">
      <p>The fonds consists of records that reflect the various activities of the Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Vice Presidencyof (ESSDVP) and its oversight of, and involvement with, sector departments within the network. Note that a small amount of records in this fonds were created prior to the creation of ESSDVP by Bank staff within the Environmentally Sustainable Development Vice Presidency (ESD); the records were brought into ESSDVP's recordkeeping system as a result of staff transfer into ESSDVP. The majority of the records in this fonds are clearly associated with the activities of Ian Johnson, ESSD Vice President from 1998 to 2006.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="3.2.4">
      <p>Records were transferred directly from sector units to the Archives using approved records retention and disposition schedules.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <accruals encodinganalog="3.3.3">
      <p>Accruals are expected.</p>
    </accruals>
    <processinfo>
      <p>
        <date>15 November 2012</date>
      </p>
    </processinfo>
    <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="3.5.3">
      <p>* See Records of the Environment Sector ([WB IBRD/IDA ENV](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-environment-sector)).
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>* See Records of the Agriculture and Rural Development Sector ([WB IBRD/IDA AGR](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-agriculture-and-rural-development-sector)).
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>* See Records of the Social Development Sector ([WB IBRD/IDA 87 WB_IBRD/IDA_87](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-social-development-sector)).
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>* See Records of the Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research ([WB IBRD/IDA CGIAR](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-consultative-group-on-international-agricultural-research-cgiar)).
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>* See Records of the Environmentally Sustainable Development Vice Presidency ([WB IBRD/IDA 90 WB_IBRD/IDA_90](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-environmentally-sustainable-development-vice-presidency)).
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>* For records of ESSD Vice President Ian Johnson (1998-2006), see Records of Individual staff members -- Ian Johnson files ([WB IBRD/IDA STAFF-13](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/ian-johnson-files)).</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="3.4.1">
      <p>Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="3.4.2">
      <p>Records are subject to the Copyright Policy of the World Bank Group.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <c level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Budget and resource allocation</unittitle>
          <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_92-01</unitid>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="3.1.3">1994 - 2000</unitdate>
          <physdesc encodinganalog="3.1.5">
        0.60 linear feet of textual records    </physdesc>
          <langmaterial encodinganalog="3.4.3">
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
          </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd type="publicationStatus">
          <p>Published</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="3.3.1">
          <p>Series consists of records related to, or the product of, budgetary planning and resource allocation. Included are a number of budget reports, including some that were created for the Environmentally Sustainable Development Vice Presidency (ESD). These include: ESD Work Program Indicators (FY96 and FY97); ESD Retrospective Reviews (FY 94, FY 95, and FY 96); ESD Original FY95 Work Program; ESD FY96-98 Business Plan; ESSD FY98-00 Business Plan; ESSD Final Budget Outcome. Also included are records that relateto: the Leadership Asset Management Program (LAMP); the allocation of funds to the Development Grant Facility (DGF); and budget planning for FY00 and FY01.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement encodinganalog="3.3.4">
          <p>The original order of the records has been maintained. Records are arranged in chronological order.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accruals encodinganalog="3.3.3">
          <p>Accruals are expected.</p>
        </accruals>
        <processinfo>
          <p>
            <date>30 October 2012</date>
          </p>
        </processinfo>
        <accessrestrict encodinganalog="3.4.1">
          <p>Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict encodinganalog="3.4.2">
          <p>Records are subject to the Copyright Policy of the World Bank Group.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Budget, Work Program, and Accounting Records - Environmentally Sustainable Development [ESD] Original Fiscal Year [FY] 1995 Work Program - Report - September 1994</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833713</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1994-09-01/1994-09-01" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1994-09-01</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Budget, Work Program, and Accounting Records - Environmentally Sustainable Development [ESD] Work Program Indicators - Fiscal Year [FY] 1996 - 1997</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833711</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1995-09-01/1996-09-01" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1995-09-01 - 1996-09-01</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Budget, Work Program, and Accounting Records - Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network [ESSD] Business Plans - Reports</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833722</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1995-03-01/1997-04-01" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1995-03-01 - 1997-04-01</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Budget, Work Program, and Accounting Records - Environmentally Sustainable Development [ESD] Retrospective Reviews - Reports</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833712</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1994-08-01/1996-07-01" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1994-08-01 - 1996-07-01</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Budget, Work Program, and Accounting Records - FY99 Final Budget Outcome - Budget File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832714</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-01/1999-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Budget, Work Program, and Accounting Records - Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network [ESSD] Leadership Asset Management Program - General Correspondence - 2000</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833714</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-31/2000-10-12" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-31 - 2000-10-12</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Budget, Work Program, and Accounting Records - Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network [ESSD] and the Development Grant Facility - General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833731</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-11-06/2000-11-07" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-11-06 - 2000-11-07</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - FY 02 - MC / VP Quarterly Business Review Meetings - Report</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832819</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-01-01/2002-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-01-01 - 2002-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - ESSD FY 2001 Quarterly Business Review - Report</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832812</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-01-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-01-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Budget, Work Program, and Accounting Records - ESSD Front Office Budget - Budget File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832711</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-01/2000-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-01 - 2000-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">CGIAR meeting and planning records</unittitle>
          <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_92-02</unitid>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999 - 2002</unitdate>
          <physdesc encodinganalog="3.1.5">
        0.83 linear feet of textual records    </physdesc>
          <langmaterial encodinganalog="3.4.3">
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
          </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd type="publicationStatus">
          <p>Published</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="3.3.1">
          <p>Series consists of records related to Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research (CGIAR) and ESSD Vice President Ian Johnson's role as CGIAR Chairman. Johnson served as Chairman from 2000-2006. Records relate to CGIAR planning and policy development and to CGIAR meetings, conferences, and workshops.
<lb/>
<lb/>Series contains agendas, supporting materials, and notes related to a variety of meetings, conferences, and workshops participated in and/or attended by Ian Johnson, including: European Donors Meeting, Paris (17 April 2001); CGIAR System Office Workshop (13-14 March 2002); CGIAR North American Donors Meeting (5 April 2001); and CGIAR's Synthesis Meeting, Reading, UK (4-7 October 2000). Materials supporting the European Donors Meeting are also included.
<lb/>
<lb/>Supporting materials include numerous reports. A number of these reports relate to CGIAR planning, organizational changes and strategies and were authored by the CGIAR's Change Design and Management Team (CDMT). Reports on these activities preparedby the CGIAR Technical Advisory Committee (TAC) are also included.
<lb/>
<lb/>A small amount of records which relate to the Operation Evaluation Department's (OED) meta-evaluation of CGIAR of 2002 are also included. The majority of these records are correspondence and discuss CGIAR staff feedback and comments.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement encodinganalog="3.3.4">
          <p>The original order of the records has been maintained. Records are arranged in chronological order.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accruals encodinganalog="3.3.3">
          <p>Accruals are expected.</p>
        </accruals>
        <processinfo>
          <p>
            <date>30 October 2012</date>
          </p>
        </processinfo>
        <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="3.5.3">
          <p>* See Records of the Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research (CGIAR) ([WB IBRD/IDA CGIAR](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-consultative-group-on-international-agricultural-research-cgiar)).</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <accessrestrict encodinganalog="3.4.1">
          <p>Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict encodinganalog="3.4.2">
          <p>Records are subject to the Copyright Policy of the World Bank Group.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund:  Consultative Group for International Agricultural Research (CGIAR) - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831237</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-01-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-01-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Consultative Group On International Agricultural Research [CGIAR] System Office Workshop - March 13 - 14, 2002 - Workshop File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833739</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-01-01/2002-03-14" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-01-01 - 2002-03-14</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Operations Evaluation Department [OED] Meta Evaluation of the Consultative Group On International Agricultural Research [CGIR] - Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network [ESSD] and CGIAR Secretariat Response - August 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833738</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-07-30/2002-08-08" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-07-30 - 2002-08-08</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Consultative Group On International Agricultural Research [CGIAR] New Vision and Strategy - Reading, United Kingdom - October 4 - 7, 2000 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833737</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-05-07/2000-10-30" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-05-07 - 2000-10-30</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Consultative Group On International Agricultural Research [CGIAR] European Donors Meeting - Paris - April 17, 2001 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833745</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-04-11/2001-04-16" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-04-11 - 2001-04-16</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Consultative Group On International Agricultural Research [CGIAR] North American Donors Meeting - New York - April 5, 2001 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833744</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-03-13/2001-04-05" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-03-13 - 2001-04-05</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Ian Johnson and Robert Thompson Visit Centro Internacional de Mejoramiento de Maiz y Trigo [CIMMYT] - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833746</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-07-07/2000-07-17" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-07-07 - 2000-07-17</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund:  Consultative Group for International Agricultural Research (CGIAR) - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831236</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-01/2000-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Trust Fund management and oversight</unittitle>
          <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">WB IBRD/IDA 92 WB_IBRD/IDA_92-06</unitid>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="3.1.3">1996 - 2003</unitdate>
          <physdesc encodinganalog="3.1.5">
        2.01 linear feet of textual records    </physdesc>
          <langmaterial encodinganalog="3.4.3">
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
          </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd type="publicationStatus">
          <p>Published</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="3.3.1">
          <p>Series consists of records related to ESSD's role in providing management, oversight, and resource allocation for those trust funds that involve ESSD sectors. Records relating to trust funds provided by Denmark (TF024153), Norway (TF0231295), and Italy (TF023333) are the most numerous. Records related to Denmark are dated from 1996-1997 and 2000 and include: proposals; trust fund agreements; budget requests; initiating briefs; and correspondence between ESD and Danish government ministers. Records from 2000 relate to a proposal for a possible second phase of the Danish ESSD Trust Fund. These records include a proposal by SDV to the Government of Denmark as well as debriefing and consultation notes and a copy of Denmark's Development Policy (2000). Records related to Italy include correspondence between Bank officials (including the Bank President and ESSD Vice President) and Italian officials including their American Ambassador. Also included is background material on the Trust Fund for Culture and Sustainable Development for which Italy provided funding. Records related to Norway include funding proposals by SDV as well as other Bank units external to ESSD. Also included are records relating to the Norwegian Trust Fund for Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development (NTF-ESSD). These records include: status reports; reports; meetings notes; and background information on the Bank-Netherlands Partnership Program related to Water Resources Management. A small amount of correspondence from 1999 related to a proposed Social Development Trust Fund funded by Japan is also included.
<lb/>
<lb/>Records relating to funds managed or overseen by ESSDVP are also included. Records related to the launch and subsequent Donor Councils of the Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund are included; correspondence related to this Fund is also included. In addition, the series also contains correspondence files for the Prototype Carbon Fund.
<lb/>
<lb/>A variety of records related to the general management of ESSD-related trust funds is also included. These include: records related to fund allocation and transfer; a list of task managers and division chiefs for specific, ESSD-related trust fund projects; and notes, slides and announcement emails for a Trust Fund Awareness Training program organized by the ESSDVP.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement encodinganalog="3.3.4">
          <p>The original order of the records has been maintained. Records are arranged in chronological order.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accruals encodinganalog="3.3.3">
          <p>Accruals are expected.</p>
        </accruals>
        <processinfo>
          <p>
            <date>12 November 2012</date>
          </p>
        </processinfo>
        <accessrestrict encodinganalog="3.4.1">
          <p>Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict encodinganalog="3.4.2">
          <p>Records are subject to the Copyright Policy of the World Bank Group.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Records Related to Trust Fund Programs - Consultation on Netherlands Trust Fund - April 28, 2000</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833710</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-04-18/2000-04-21" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-04-18 - 2000-04-21</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Records Related to Trust Fund Programs - Trust Fund Awareness Training - Presentation by Ian Johnson</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833636</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-12-12/2001-12-12" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-12-12</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Records Related to Trust Fund Programs - Request for Exception to the Application of the Disbursement and Trust Fund Policies to Get Supported Conservation Funds - March 15, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833637</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-03-15/2002-04-15" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-03-15 - 2002-04-15</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Records of the Trust Fund Cycle - Danish Trust Fund TF 024153 - Trust Fund File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833621</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1996-04-18/1996-07-11" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1996-04-18 - 1996-07-11</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Records Related to Trust Fund Programs - Consultations on Danish Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network [ESSD] Trust Fund - November 2000 and June 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833638</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-09-12/2001-06-14" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-09-12 - 2001-06-14</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Records of the Trust Fund Cycle - Danish Trust Fund Extras - Trust Fund File - 1996 - 1997</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833625</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1996-04-08/1997-06-13" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1996-04-08 - 1997-06-13</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund - Second Meeting of the Donor Council - Washington, D.C. - December 11, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831198</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-12-11/2001-12-11" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-12-11</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Critical Ecosystems Partnership Fund - Launch Design and DGF Application Form - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831155</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-01/2000-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Critical Ecosystems Partnership Fund - Report</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831154</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-01/2000-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund - First Meeting of the Donor Council - Meeting File - December 14, 2000</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831197</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-12-14/2000-12-14" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-12-14</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Prototype Carbon Fund - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831153</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-01-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-01-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Prototype Carbon Fund - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831152</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-01/2000-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Prototype Carbon Fund - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831150</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-01-01/1998-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-01-01 - 1998-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Fourth Meeting of the Donor Council - February 12, 2003 - Briefing Material for J. D. Wolfensohn</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831200</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2003-02-12/2003-02-12" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2003-02-12</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831199</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Biocarbon Fund Memorandum of Understanding Meeting - February 24 - 26, 2003 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831239</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2003-02-24/2003-02-26" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2003-02-24 - 2003-02-26</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Records of the Trust Fund Cycle - Danish Trust Fund TF 024153 - Trust Fund File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833622</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1996-08-06/1997-08-29" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1996-08-06 - 1997-08-29</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Prototype Carbon Fund - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831151</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-01/1999-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Records of the Trust Fund Cycle - Italian Trust Fund for Culture and Sustainable Development - Correspondence File - June - December 1999</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833627</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-03-29/1999-12-10" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-03-29 - 1999-12-10</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Records of the Trust Fund Cycle - Trust Fund Representation Letters - Correspondence File - June - July 1997</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833628</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1997-06-27/1997-07-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1997-06-27 - 1997-07-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Records of the Trust Fund Cycle - Norwegian Trust Fund for Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development - Correspondence File - November 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833635</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-10-31/2001-11-13" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-10-31 - 2001-11-13</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Records Related to Trust Fund Programs - Norwegian Trust Fund for Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network [ESSD] - 2000 - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">30181562</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-12-07/2000-09-18" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-12-07 - 2000-09-18</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Records of the Trust Fund Cycle - Japan Integrated Social Development Trust Fund Proposal - Correspondence File - October 1999</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833630</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-10-28/2000-02-09" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-10-28 - 2000-02-09</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Management and oversight</unittitle>
          <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">WB IBRD/IDA 92 WB_IBRD/IDA_92-07</unitid>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998 - 2003</unitdate>
          <physdesc encodinganalog="3.1.5">
        5.22 linear feet of textual records    </physdesc>
          <langmaterial encodinganalog="3.4.3">
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
          </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd type="publicationStatus">
          <p>Published</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="3.3.1">
          <p>Series consists of records related to management and oversight activities of ESSDVP. Records primarily relate to high-level meetings attended by ESSD Vice President Ian Johnson within ESSD as well as other units and committees of the World Bank. This includes meetings with Bank President Wolfensohn and Managing Director Shengman Zhang as well as meetings of the Bank's Operational Vice Presidents. Records from Bank-wide Corporate Days (1998-2002) and Strategic Forums (2000-2001) are also included. These records include: background notes (prepared for ESSDVP Ian Johnson by ESSD staff); presentation notes and slides; correspondence; progress reports; agendas; and follow-up materials.
<lb/>
<lb/>Records related to management and organizational meetings of the ESSD include: ESSD Council meetings (2001-2003); ESSD Anchor meetings (2000-2001, 2003); ESSD FY02-04 Business Planning MD/VP Meeting; ESSD FY04-06 Strategic Planning; ESSD Knowledge Management strategy (1998-2000); and ESSD Management Retreats (including EnvironmentSector Board retreat [2002]) and Team Meetings.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement encodinganalog="3.3.4">
          <p>The original order of the records has been maintained. Records are arranged in chronological order.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accruals encodinganalog="3.3.3">
          <p>Accruals are expected.</p>
        </accruals>
        <processinfo>
          <p>
            <date>12 November 2012</date>
          </p>
        </processinfo>
        <accessrestrict encodinganalog="3.4.1">
          <p>Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict encodinganalog="3.4.2">
          <p>Records are subject to the Copyright Policy of the World Bank Group.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Committee Records - DGF Applications to be Discussed at the Environmnetally and Socially Sustainable Develoment [ESSD] Council Meeting - February 26, 2002 - Reports</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832596</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-02-26/2002-02-26" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-02-26</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Committee Records - ESSD Anchor Meetings - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832681</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-02-08/2001-05-17" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-02-08 - 2001-05-17</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESSD Anchor Meeting - Background Documentation - February 26, 2003</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832682</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2003-02-25/2003-02-26" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2003-02-25 - 2003-02-26</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Environment Sector Board Retreat - November 19, 2002 - Background Documentation</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832696</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-11-14/2002-11-19" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-11-14 - 2002-11-19</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - ESSD FY 02-04 Business Planning Meeting - Background Documentation</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832730</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-03-20/2001-03-20" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-03-20</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - ESSD Strategic Planning Management Meeting - Background Documentation - FY 2004-2006</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832733</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-11-26/2002-11-26" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-11-26</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Knowledge Management in ESSD - Background Documentation</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832805</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-01/2000-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-01 - 2000-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Knowledge Management in ESSD - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832807</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-01-01/1998-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-01-01 - 1998-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - FY2003 ESSD - Wide Learning Program - Plan for Strategic Learning Centers - Background Documentation</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832809</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-07-16/2002-07-16" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-07-16</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - ESSD Staffing and Human Resources - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832811</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-01-01/1998-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-01-01 - 1998-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Office of Business Ethics and Integrity Investigation of Alleged Conflict of Interest - International Task Force on Commodity Risk Management - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832815</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-10-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-10-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - ESSD Staff Survey - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832821</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-07-01/1999-07-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-07-01 - 1999-07-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Briefing Books for Senior Officials - Commodity Risk Management - Briefing for Shengman Zhang - Briefing Papers - July 10, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833130</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-06-01/2002-07-10" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-06-01 - 2002-07-10</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Briefing Books for Senior Officials - Quarterly Reports to Shengman Zhang on Rural Development and on Safeguard Activities - January 2003 - Briefing Notes</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833141</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2003-01-17/2003-01-28" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2003-01-17 - 2003-01-28</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Briefing Books for Senior Officials - Human Development Report 2002 - Presentation and Meeting with Sakiko Fakuda Parr, United Nations Development Programme [UNDP] - Briefing Notes</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833150</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-01-01/2003-01-14" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-01-01 - 2003-01-14</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Briefing Books for Senior Officials - Community Driven Development - Briefing with Shengman Zhang - Briefing Notes - March 1, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833389</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-02-25/2002-03-01" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-02-25 - 2002-03-01</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Briefing Books for Senior Officials - Commodity Risk Management - Technical Briefing - Board Meeting - Briefing Notes - December 14, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833390</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-12-03/2001-12-10" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-12-03 - 2001-12-10</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Briefing Books for Senior Officials - Ian Johnson Meeting with J. D. Wolfensohn - Briefing Notes - June 6, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833396</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-05-21/2001-06-06" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-05-21 - 2001-06-06</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Ian Johnson Meetings with World Bank Managing Director Shengman Zhang - General Correspondence - 1999</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833397</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-09-02/1999-10-12" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-09-02 - 1999-10-12</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Mining CEO Initiative - J.D. Wolfensohn Meeting with Rio Tinto, Noranda and Phelps Dodge - October 28, 1999 - Background Documentation</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833419</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-10-27/1999-10-28" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-10-27 - 1999-10-28</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Aga Khan - Development Network - Visit to the World Bank - October 13 - 15, 1999 - Background Documentation</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833420</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-10-13/1999-10-15" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-10-13 - 1999-10-15</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Eastern African Biodiversity Trust - Ian Johnson with Hal Wackman and Richard Leakey - April 24, 2002 - Background Documentation</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833422</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-07-11/2002-04-19" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-07-11 - 2002-04-19</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Eastern African Biodiversity Fund - Draft Concept for Discussion - April 24, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833428</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-04-24/2002-04-24" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-04-24</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Partnership to cut Hunger and Poverty in Africa - Meeting with United States under Secretary of State, Alan Larson - March 6, 2002 - Background Documentation</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833434</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-11-01/2002-03-04" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-11-01 - 2002-03-04</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Ian Johnson Meeting with French Development Agency Executive Director, Pierre Jacquet - September 25, 2002 - Background Documentation</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833438</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-09-06/2002-09-25" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-09-06 - 2002-09-25</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Ian Johnson Meeting with Peter Woicke - Carbon Financing in World Bank Group - August 21, 2002 - Background Documentation</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833450</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-08-20/2002-10-18" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-08-20 - 2002-10-18</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Consultation with Masafumi Kuroki, Japanese Ministry of Foreign Affairs - April 22, 2002 - Background Documentation</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833524</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-04-17/2002-04-22" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-04-17 - 2002-04-22</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Ian Johnson Meetings with World Bank Managing Director, Shengman Zhang - General Correspondence - 2000</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833525</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-31/2000-12-21" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-31 - 2000-12-21</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Ian Johnson Meeting with Consultative Group On International Agricultural Research [CGIAR] TAC Chair, Emil Javier and CBC Chair, Kurt Peters - General Correspondence - July 21, 2000</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833527</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-05-23/2000-07-21" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-05-23 - 2000-07-21</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Ian Johnson Meetings with World Bank Managing Director, Shengman Zhang - General Correspondence - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833528</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-02-22/2001-04-25" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-02-22 - 2001-04-25</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - ESSD Management Retreat - Correspondence - March 26, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833536</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-03-26/2002-03-26" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-03-26</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Management Committee Meeting - Correspondence File - October 22, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833537</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-10-22/2001-10-22" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-10-22</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - ESSD Management Retreat - Background Documentation - December 17, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833538</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-12-17/2001-12-17" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-12-17</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - ESSD Management Team Meetings - Correspondence File - 2000</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833539</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-12-15/2000-10-17" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-12-15 - 2000-10-17</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - ESSD Management Team Meetings - Correspondence File - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833540</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-01-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-01-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - ESSD Management Team Meetings - Correspondence File - January 27, 2003</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833542</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2003-01-27/2003-01-27" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2003-01-27</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - ESSD Council - Background Documentation - 2000 - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833543</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - ESSD Council Retreat - Background Documentation - September 18, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833544</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-09-18/2002-09-18" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-09-18</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - ESSD Council Meeting - Background Documentation - April 23, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833545</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-04-23/2002-04-23" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-04-23</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - ESSD Council Meeting on Strategic Staffing - Correspondence File - January 15, 2003</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833546</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2003-01-15/2003-01-15" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2003-01-15</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Corporate Days - Correspondence File - 1998</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833758</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-01-01/1998-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-01-01 - 1998-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Strategic Forum - Background Documentation - January 13 - 14, 2000</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833759</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-13/2000-01-14" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-13 - 2000-01-14</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Strategic Forum - Background Documentation - January 24 - 26, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833760</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-01-24/2001-01-26" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-01-24 - 2001-01-26</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Corporate Days - Correspondence File - 1999</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833761</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-01/1999-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Corporate Days - Correspondence File - 2000</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833762</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-01/2000-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Corporate Days - Correspondence File - September 13, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833764</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-09-13/2002-09-13" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-09-13</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Operational Vice President [OVP] Meetings 1999 - Correspondence Records</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833771</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-08-18/1999-12-02" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-08-18 - 1999-12-02</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Operational Vice President [OVP] Meetings 1999 and 2000 - Correspondence Records</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833772</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-10-19/2000-12-18" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-10-19 - 2000-12-18</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - ESSD Knowledge Management Meeting - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">30181564</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-08-22/2002-08-22" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-08-22</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Corporate Days - Correspondence File - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833763</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-01-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-01-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Strategic Compact and Strategic Forum - Background Documentation - December 2000 - January 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833765</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-12-01/2001-01-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-12-01 - 2001-01-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Operational Vice President [OVP] Meetings 2001 - Correspondence Records</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833773</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-01-03/2001-05-22" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-01-03 - 2001-05-22</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Operational Vice President [OVP] Meetings 2002 - Correspondence Records</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833774</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-01-07/2002-07-15" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-01-07 - 2002-07-15</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESSD Vice President's conference attendance and participation</unittitle>
          <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">WB IBRD/IDA 92 WB_IBRD/IDA_92-03</unitid>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998 - 2003</unitdate>
          <physdesc encodinganalog="3.1.5">
        3.32 linear feet of textual records    </physdesc>
          <langmaterial encodinganalog="3.4.3">
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
          </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd type="publicationStatus">
          <p>Published</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="3.3.1">
          <p>Series consists of records related to ESSD Vice President Ian Johnson's attendance and participation at various conferences, seminars, and workshops organized by governments, agencies, and institutions external to the Bank. Records include: correspondence; briefing notes; agendas; list of participants; presentation notes; background papers and speeches written by Johnson or by other attendees; pamphlets; travel itineraries; and speakers' biographies.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement encodinganalog="3.3.4">
          <p>The original order of the records has been maintained. Records are arranged in chronological order.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accruals encodinganalog="3.3.3">
          <p>Accruals are expected.</p>
        </accruals>
        <processinfo>
          <p>
            <date>31 October 2012</date>
          </p>
        </processinfo>
        <accessrestrict encodinganalog="3.4.1">
          <p>Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict encodinganalog="3.4.2">
          <p>Records are subject to the Copyright Policy of the World Bank Group.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - University of Toronto World Bank Development Workshop - October 26 - 28, 1998 - General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832588</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-09-18/1998-10-21" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-09-18 - 1998-10-21</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - World Commission on Dams - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832435</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-10-11/2001-03-20" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-10-11 - 2001-03-20</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - World Food Prize International Symposium - Des Moines - October 18, 2001 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832517</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-10-18/2001-10-18" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-10-18</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - World Summit on Sustainable Development - Johannesburg - August 26 - September 4, 2002 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832438</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-08-26/2002-09-04" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-08-26 - 2002-09-04</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - World Summit on Sustainable Development - Outcomes and Follow Up - August 26 - December 4, 2002 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832443</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-08-26/2002-12-04" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-08-26 - 2002-12-04</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - World Summit on Sustainable Development - Preparations for World Bank Participation - August 2002 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832445</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-08-01/2002-08-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-08-01 - 2002-08-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - World Water Forum III - Kyoto - November 25, 2002 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832419</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-11-12/2003-01-30" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-11-12 - 2003-01-30</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - WSSD Prepcom II - New York - January 31, 2002 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832446</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-01-31/2002-01-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-01-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - WSSD Prepcom II Meeting - Ian Johnson's Briefing to the Board on World Bank Participation - February 6, 2002 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832436</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-02-06/2002-02-06" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-02-06</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - WSSD Prepcomm and GEF Energy Roundtable - New York - January 28 - February 1, 2002 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832439</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-01-28/2002-02-01" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-01-28 - 2002-02-01</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Correspondence File - Forestry Briefing - Reference Code Meeting Treatment of Revised Forest Sector Strategy Paper - April 23, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832579</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-07-13/2002-04-22" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-07-13 - 2002-04-22</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Africa Day - United Nations - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832592</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-04-03/2002-04-03" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-04-03</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - African Workshop on the World Summit on Sustainable Development - Preparation Meeting - April 23, 2002 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832512</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-04-23/2002-04-23" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-04-23</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Agricultural Science and Technology Roundtable Discussions with the Private Sector - December 5, 2000 - General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832575</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-11-28/2000-11-28" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-11-28</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Annual Environment Forum - Annapolis - March 20 - 22, 2000 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832420</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-20/2000-03-17" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-20 - 2000-03-17</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Asia - Pacific Roundtable - Georgetown University - November 28 - 29, 2000 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832424</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-11-29/2000-11-29" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-11-29</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Bellagio Forum for Sustainable Development Annual Meeting - December 12 - 14, 2001 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832412</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-12-05/2001-12-14" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-12-05 - 2001-12-14</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Cotton and Global Trade Negotiations Conference - The World Bank - July 8 - 9, 2002 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832586</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-06-12/2002-07-08" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-06-12 - 2002-07-08</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Agricultural Science and Technology Roundtable Discussion - April 16, 2001 - General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832573</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-04-04/2001-04-16" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-04-04 - 2001-04-16</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network [ESSD] Day at the United Nations - New York - September 30, 1998 - General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832591</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-05-15/1998-09-25" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-05-15 - 1998-09-25</unitdate>
            <dao linktype="simple" href="https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/uploads/r/world-bank-group-archives/7/e/7/7e7209741aff9e5eceebe425cb56532f088ce0ff957f9964ee61d091cb39bfdc/WorldBankGroupArchivesFolder1832591_141.jpg" role="reference" actuate="onrequest" show="embed"/>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Empowerment Retreat - May 7 - 8, 2002 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832584</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-05-07/2002-05-08" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-05-07 - 2002-05-08</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network [ESSD] Week and Sustainable Development Month - April 2002 - General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832577</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-04-01/2002-04-21" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-04-01 - 2002-04-21</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network [ESSD] Week - March 10 - 14, 2003 - General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832572</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2003-02-21/2003-03-11" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2003-02-21 - 2003-03-11</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - ESSD European Forum - Paris - May 29 - 30, 2001 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832410</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-05-08/2001-05-30" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-05-08 - 2001-05-30</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Finance, Mining and Sustainability Conference - April 8-9, 2001 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832408</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-11-01/2001-04-09" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-11-01 - 2001-04-09</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - First Meeting of a Global Consultative Process on an International Assessment of the Role of Agricultural Science and Technology in Reducing Hunger, Improving Rural Livelihoods, and Stimulating Economic Growth - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832503</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-11-06/2002-11-08" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-11-06 - 2002-11-08</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - ESSD Vice Presidential Day at the UN - April 18, 2001 - Briefing Book</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832409</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-04-12/2001-04-18" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-04-12 - 2001-04-18</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Freshwater Conference - Bonn - December 3 - 7, 2001 - Conference Papers</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832414</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-11-14/2001-12-07" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-11-14 - 2001-12-07</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - GEF Ministerial Roundtable on Financing Environment and Sustainable Development - Monterrey, Mexico - March 17 - 18, 2002 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832567</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-03-17/2002-03-18" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-03-17 - 2002-03-18</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Global Accords for Sustainable Development: Innovative Mechanisms and Enabling Technologies - Cambridge, MA - September 16 - 17, 1998 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832505</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-09-16/1998-09-17" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-09-16 - 1998-09-17</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Globe 2002 Seventh Biennial Trade Fair and Conference on Business and the Environment - Vancouver - March 13 - 15, 2002 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832566</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-03-13/2002-03-15" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-03-13 - 2002-03-15</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Food Security: A Pillar of Sustainable Development - Delhi Sustainable Development - February 8 - 11, 2001 - Conference File - Speech by Ian Johnson</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832501</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-02-08/2001-02-11" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-02-08 - 2001-02-11</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Hydropower in the Implementation Plan of WSSD - Exchange Between Brazil and the International Rivers Network - November 16 - 18, 2002 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832514</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-11-16/2002-11-18" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-11-16 - 2002-11-18</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Interagency Standing Committee - 23rd. Meeting - UNICEF House - December 6, 1999</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832416</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-12-06/1999-12-06" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-12-06</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - International Landcare Conference - Melbourne - March 2 - 5, 2000 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832422</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-02-28/2000-03-13" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-02-28 - 2000-03-13</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - International Funders for Indigenous Peoples - July 10, 2002 - General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832585</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-05-17/2002-07-10" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-05-17 - 2002-07-10</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - IUCN Council Task Force on Governance - August - October, 2002 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832519</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-08-01/2002-10-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-08-01 - 2002-10-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Organisation for Economic Co-operation and Development [OECD] Roundtable on Sustainable Development - Paris - December 6, 2001 - General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832583</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-10-12/2001-12-06" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-10-12 - 2001-12-06</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Preparatory Meeting of the WSSD: Passing of the Torch From Rio de Janeiro to Johnnesberg - Rio de Janeiro - June 23 - 25, 2002 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832444</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-06-23/2002-06-25" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-06-23 - 2002-06-25</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Preparatory Meetings for WSSD Johannesburg, Briefing on Development at UN Forum on Forests (UNFF) - Presentation at New School University - New York - November 20, 2001 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832449</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-11-20/2001-11-20" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-11-20</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Public Health and Sustainable Development - School of Advanced International Studies - Johns Hopkins University - November 13, 2002 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832509</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-11-13/2002-11-13" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-11-13</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Rural Strategy Update Retreat - July 17, 2000 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832587</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-07-17/2000-07-17" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-07-17</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Keidanren Nature Conservation Fund - Symposium on Nature Conservation in Asia  - September 2, 1998 - General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832589</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-08-07/1998-09-02" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-08-07 - 1998-09-02</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Soliciting Chinese Participation in Post WSSD Intenational Assessment of Agricultural Science and Technology - Memorandum and Briefing Material from Ian Johnsonto to Executive Director Guangyao Zhu - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832516</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2003-01-31/2003-01-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2003-01-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Rural Week 2001 - General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832569</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-04-18/2001-04-23" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-04-18 - 2001-04-23</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - The Berlin Forum - Committed to Sustainability - Berlin - May 20 - 23, 2002 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832593</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-05-03/2002-05-09" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-05-03 - 2002-05-09</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - The Global Environment - Presentation by Ian Johnson - New York - November 20, 2001 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832518</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-11-20/2001-11-20" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-11-20</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Third Training Course on Environmental Economics and Policy - Shenzhen, China - October 12 - 22, 1999 - Training File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832421</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-07-29/1999-10-19" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-07-29 - 1999-10-19</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - United Nations [UN] Framework Convention on Climate Change (UNFCCC) - Buenos Aires - November 1 - 12, 1998 - General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832590</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-10-21/1998-11-04" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-10-21 - 1998-11-04</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - Voices and Choices at a Macro Level - Participation in Country - Owned Poverty Reduction Strategies - Washington, D.C. - April 3 - 5, 2001 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832502</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-04-03/2001-04-05" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-04-03 - 2001-04-05</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - World Summit on Sustainable Development - Prepcom III - April 3 - 4, 2002 - Conference File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832441</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-04-03/2002-04-04" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-04-03 - 2002-04-04</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Conferences and Seminars - World Water Forum - December 2, 2002 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832417</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-11-15/2002-12-03" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-11-15 - 2002-12-03</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy and guidelines development and supporting materials</unittitle>
          <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">WB IBRD/IDA 92 WB_IBRD/IDA_92-08</unitid>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="3.1.3">1994 - 2003 (predominant 1998 - 2003)</unitdate>
          <physdesc encodinganalog="3.1.5">
        6.05 linear feet of textual records    </physdesc>
          <langmaterial encodinganalog="3.4.3">
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
            <language langcode="fre">French</language>
          </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd type="publicationStatus">
          <p>Published</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="3.3.1">
          <p>Series consists of records related to ESSD and Bank-wide policy and guidelines development. In some cases, ESSDVP and Vice President Ian Johnson played active roles in the development of policy and guidelines while in others reports and correspondence were forwarded to ESSDVP for comment or for informational purposes. The series contains some records that evidence the formation of institutional rules and policies, namely Operational Policy and Business Practice (OP/BP). However, the majority of records in this series are the product of ESSDVP research and information exchange on various topics for the purpose of writing reports, planning projects, or developing relationships with external agencies, institutions, and governments.
<lb/>
<lb/>The series contains a significant amount of records related to the development and evaluation of OP/BP. Records related to Bank forestry policy are numerous and include: a copy of Forest Policy Implementation Review and Strategy (OP/BP 4.36); a copy of Revised Forestry Strategy for the World Bank Group; minutes of an ad hoc group on the topic; ESSD Council meeting minutes on the topic; related correspondence; and an inventory of projects having to do with the topic. Series also contains records related to OP 4.12 Involuntary Resettlement and OP/BP 13.05 Guidelines for Projects Supervision. These include: correspondence; drafts of policy; and comments made by ESSDVP staff.
<lb/>
<lb/>Records of the Operational Policy Committee Meeting from 1999 to 2002 are also included; records discuss OP/BP and guideline development. Records include: minutes; agendas; reports; comments; correspondence; and supporting materials.
<lb/>
<lb/>Records in this series that do not relate to the development of specific policy may relate to ESSDVP and Ian Johnson's involvement in the research and writing of guidelines, reports, and evaluations but may also be limited to providing comments or receiving reports and correspondence for informational purposes. Topics include but are not limited to: human rights; indigenous peoples; safeguard policies; social development strategic directions; civil society; disaster management; water management and infrastructure; food assessment; climate change; desertification and drylands management; fisheries; commodity price risk management; global public policy; investment in energy infrastructure; promoting sustainability in development ; and Green procurement. Records on these topics include but are not limited to: final and draft versions of reports; comments from ESSDVP and, most often, Vice President Johnson; correspondence; meeting agendas and minutes; and briefing notes. Records from meetings and workshops attended and, in some cases, participated in by Johnson are included. These records include event and background materials and Johnson's notes.
<lb/>
<lb/>A small amount of files contain records forwarded to Johnson from the Social Development Department (SDV) of ESSD. Topics of these records include: NGO/Bank relations; community driven development; cultural development; civil society; and post conflict development. Records generally include reports and correspondence.
<lb/>
<lb/>Records related to Johnson's activities involving the Global Environment Facility (GEF) are also included, although small in number. These include correspondence and informational reports forwarded to Johnson and materials from replenishment meetings attended by Johnson.
<lb/>
<lb/>The series also contains final reports and other records that the Operations Evaluation Department (OED, now the Independent Evaluation Group [IEG]) created that relate either directly to ESSD or to topics relevant to ESSD's sectors. OED reports found in this series include: OED Review of the Bank's Performance on the Environment (2001, draft, accompanied by presentation slides); Phase I Interim Report: 'Promoting Environmental Sustainability in Development: An Evaluation of the World Bank's Performance' (2000); Safeguard Policy Framework: OED Comments on Systemic Issues (2000); OED Forest Strategy Review (2000); OED Review of the World Bank Forest Strategy and Its Implementation (2000); The World Bank and Global Public Policies and Programs: An Evaluation Strategy (2001); How Far into the Mainstream? A Review of Environmental Issues in IDA Activities (2001); IDA's Partnership for Poverty Reduction (FY94-FY00) (2001); and OED IDA Review: Environmental Sustainability Issues in IDA 10-12 (2000). A number of reports on Forest Development and World Bank Assistance related to specific countries (China, India, and Brazil) are also included and are accompanied by briefing materials. Records that accompany reports include comments from ESSDVP and sector department staff as well as correspondence. A small amount of correspondence and reports forwarded to ESSDVP for informational purposes that relate to the Committee on Development Effectiveness (CODE) are also included in this series.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement encodinganalog="3.3.4">
          <p>The original order of the records has been maintained. Records are arranged in chronological order.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accruals encodinganalog="3.3.3">
          <p>Accruals are expected.</p>
        </accruals>
        <processinfo>
          <p>
            <date>15 November 2012</date>
          </p>
        </processinfo>
        <accessrestrict encodinganalog="3.4.1">
          <p>Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict encodinganalog="3.4.2">
          <p>Records are subject to the Copyright Policy of the World Bank Group.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Forests, Forestry and World Bank Forest Strategy - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831147</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-01/1999-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Forests, Forestry and World Bank Forest Strategy - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831148</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-01/2000-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Forests, Forestry and World Bank Forest Strategy - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831149</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-01-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-01-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Forests, Forestry and World Bank Forest Strategy - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831146</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-01-01/1998-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-01-01 - 1998-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Human Rights - Correspondence - February 27, 2003</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831240</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2003-02-26/2003-02-26" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2003-02-26</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Revised Forest Strategy for the World Bank Group - Board Meeting and Management Response - October 29 - 31, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831238</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-10-29/2002-10-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-10-29 - 2002-10-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Human Rights and the World Bank - Correspondence - September - November 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831241</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-06-17/2002-11-10" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-06-17 - 2002-11-10</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Indigenous Peoples Meeting - Correspondence - October 17, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831278</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-10-03/2002-10-16" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-10-03 - 2002-10-16</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Indigenous Peoples Meeting - Correspondence - October 2, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831279</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-08-07/2002-10-02" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-08-07 - 2002-10-02</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Proposed Memorandum of Understanding with International Organization for Migration - Correspondence - November 8, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831281</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-10-09/2001-11-08" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-10-09 - 2001-11-08</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Safeguard Policies - Framework for Improving Development Effectiveness - Correspondence - August 13, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831280</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-08-13/2002-08-13" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-08-13</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Strategic Directions for the World Bank in Social Development - Correspondence - October 15 - 16, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831283</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-10-10/2002-10-14" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-10-10 - 2002-10-14</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Empowerment, Culture and Civic Engagement - Proposed R and D Program - Follow-Up on External Advisory Committee Meeting - November 5, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831282</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-11-02/2001-11-05" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-11-02 - 2001-11-05</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - World Bank Engagement with Civil Society - Report - October 3, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831376</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-09-24/2001-10-03" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-09-24 - 2001-10-03</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Water Resources Management - Correspondence - 1998 - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831627</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-12-01/2001-07-22" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-12-01 - 2001-07-22</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Disaster Management - Prevention Consortium and World Institute for Natural Disasters - March 1999 and February 2000 - Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831626</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-07-06/2000-01-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-07-06 - 2000-01-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Use of World Bank Funds for Land Acquisition - Correspondence - December 2000 - October 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831628</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-12-22/2001-10-16" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-12-22 - 2001-10-16</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - SDV - NGO Unit and Bank - NGO Relations - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831706</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-11-01/2001-05-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-11-01 - 2001-05-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - World Bank - Global Environment Facility [GEF] Quarterly Management Meeting - Correspondence - April 2, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831629</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-02-08/2002-04-02" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-02-08 - 2002-04-02</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - SDV - Foundations and Community Driven Development - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831708</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-01/2000-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-01 - 2000-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Involuntary Resettlement - Committee on Development Effectiveness - Correspondence File - 1999</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831713</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-01/1999-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records -  SDV - Cultural Development 2000 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831709</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-01/2000-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - NGOs and Steering Committee on NGOs - Correspondence File - 1999 - 2000</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831714</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-01/2000-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-01 - 2000-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Environment - Climate Change - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832149</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-07-08/2001-06-14" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-07-08 - 2001-06-14</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Environment - Global Environment Facility (GEF) - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832152</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-05-20/1999-12-21" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-05-20 - 1999-12-21</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - ESSD - SDV General - Correspondence File - 2000 - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831716</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - ESSD / RDV - General - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832162</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-12-01/2000-11-16" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-12-01 - 2000-11-16</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - RDV - Forestry - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832169</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-09-24/2001-03-29" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-09-24 - 2001-03-29</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Desertification and Drylands Management - Correspondence - 1998 - 2000</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832170</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-08-06/2000-12-06" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-08-06 - 2000-12-06</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Fisheries - Correspondence - 1999 - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832171</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-03-19/2001-07-11" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-03-19 - 2001-07-11</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - ESSD - Environment General - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832157</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-05-03/2000-09-25" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-05-03 - 2000-09-25</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Commodities Price Risk Management - Correspondence - 2000 - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832175</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-12-14/2001-06-01" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-12-14 - 2001-06-01</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Water Resources Management and Land Management - Correspondence - 1999 - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832174</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-08-25/2001-03-20" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-08-25 - 2001-03-20</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - ESSD - Science and Technology - Correspondence - 1999 - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832177</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-03-22/2001-07-25" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-03-22 - 2001-07-25</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">World Bank Strategy for Science and Technology in Development - Draft Executive Summary - January 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832189</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-01-31/2002-01-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-01-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Social Development - Proposing an Articulated Social Strategy, Mission Statement, and Sustainable Livelihoods Framework - Correspondence - June 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832192</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-06-05/2001-06-12" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-06-05 - 2001-06-12</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Promoting Environmental Sustainability in Development - OED Draft Evaluation and ESSD Comments - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832216</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-05-01/2000-05-30" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-05-01 - 2000-05-30</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Energy Sector Management Assistance Programme [ESMAP] - Correspondence - 1999</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832186</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-11-04/1999-11-09" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-11-04 - 1999-11-09</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Sustainable Land Resources Management [SLRM] Thematic Group - Formation - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832221</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-09-01/1999-09-30" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-09-01 - 1999-09-30</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Fuel for Thought - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832225</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-04-01/2000-09-30" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-04-01 - 2000-09-30</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - The Future of the Global Reporting Initiative - New York - December 8 - 9, 1999 - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832217</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-12-08/1999-12-09" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-12-08 - 1999-12-09</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Global Public Policy - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832235</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-01/1999-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Safeguard Policies - Improving Development Effectiveness - Discussion at ESSD Council Lunch - Correspondence File - March 20, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833541</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-03-20/2002-03-20" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-03-20</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Budget, Work Program, and Accounting Records - Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development Network [ESSD] Comments on OP / BP 13.05 on Supervision - General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833723</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-12-28/2000-01-27" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-12-28 - 2000-01-27</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Operations Evaluation Department [OED] Review of the Bank's Performance on the Environment - Reports - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833747</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-06-05/2001-03-06" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-06-05 - 2001-03-06</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Operations Evaluation Department [OED] Review of Environmental Issues in IDA 10-12 - Correspondence File - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833749</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-12-21/2001-02-01" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-12-21 - 2001-02-01</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Global Public Policy - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832234</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-01-01/1998-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-01-01 - 1998-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Environmental Sustainability Issues in IDA 10-12 - Correspondence File - April 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833750</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-04-06/2001-04-18" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-04-06 - 2001-04-18</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - OED Review of the World Bank Forest Strategy and its Implementation - Briefing by Uma Lele and Gregory Ingram - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833752</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-11-23/2000-01-28" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-11-23 - 2000-01-28</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - OED Work Program Activities in ESSD - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833751</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-10/2000-02-14" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-10 - 2000-02-14</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - CODE Subcommittee on Social Development Strategy - Background Documentation - March 19, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833753</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-01-01/2002-03-27" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-01-01 - 2002-03-27</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - ESSD and Operations Evaluation Department [OED] - Background Documentation - 1998 - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833754</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-12-13/2001-06-18" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-12-13 - 2001-06-18</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - CODE Subcommittee Meeting on Rural Strategy - Correspondence File - May 14, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833757</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-06-09/2001-05-14" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-06-09 - 2001-05-14</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Operations Policy Committee Meetings - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833766</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-01/1999-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Code and Board Meetings on Cultural Resources - Correspondence File - Janaury - June 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833755</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-11-06/2001-03-01" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-11-06 - 2001-03-01</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Operations Policy Committee Meetings - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833767</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-01/2000-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Operations Policy Committee Meetings - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833768</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-01-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-01-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Operations Policy Committee Meetings - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833769</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-01-01/2002-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-01-01 - 2002-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Code and the Environment Strategy - Making Sustainable Commitments - May 23, 2003</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">30182412</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-05-22/2001-08-06" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-05-22 - 2001-08-06</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Committee Records - Greening Committee - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832602</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-10-15/2001-03-09" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-10-15 - 2001-03-09</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Committee Records - GEF Trust Fund - Meeting on the Third Replenishment and Note on Structures, Processes and Procedures of the GEF - Reports</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832606</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-08-22/2001-10-12" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-08-22 - 2001-10-12</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">NGO - World Bank Committee - Meeting of December 6 - 9, 1999 - Background Notes for Ian Johnson</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832684</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-12-05/1999-12-06" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-12-05 - 1999-12-06</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Papers, Board Papers and Research Studies - Rural Sector Board Contribution to Operational Quality - QAG Pilot Assessment - Background Documentation</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832859</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-08-28/2002-08-28" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-08-28</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Papers,Board Papers and Research Studies - World Bank Strategy for Supporting Environmentally and Socially Sustainable Development - Sector Strategy Papers as Building Blocks - Robert Watson and Rita Hilton</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832806</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-05-29/2002-05-29" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-05-29</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">World Bank / World Wildlife Fund Alliance - Briefing Paper for the Global Vision Research Project Steering Committee - January 15, 2000</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833144</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-18/2000-01-18" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-18</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Community Driven Development [CDD], Rural Development and Water, Education for All, and HIV/AIDS Case Studies - Briefing Notes - Ian Johnson with Mamphele Ramphele - July 12, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833147</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-07-11/2002-07-12" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-07-11 - 2002-07-12</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Briefing Books for Senior Officials - Briefing on First Quarterly Global Environment Facility [GEF] Secretariat - Bank Management Review - Briefing Notes - February 14, 2000</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833394</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-02-11/2000-02-14" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-02-11 - 2000-02-14</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Briefing Books for Senior Officials - Bank - Global Environment Facility [GEF] Briefing - Briefing Notes - November 29, 1999</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833145</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-11-24/1999-11-29" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-11-24 - 1999-11-29</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - Resettlement Committee Meeting - Inner Mongolia Highway Project - Background Documentation - March 22, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833535</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-03-22/2002-03-22" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-03-22</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Organization and Management Records - SDV Joint Facilitation Committee Meeting - World Bank Civil Society Global Dialogue - Background Documentation - December 13 - 14, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833534</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-12-13/2001-12-14" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-12-13 - 2001-12-14</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - International Food Assessment - Correspondence - April 30, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831630</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-03-07/2002-04-30" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-03-07 - 2002-04-30</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - World Panel on Financing Water Infrastructure / World Bank Water Week - Report - March 2003</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831703</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2003-03-07/2003-03-07" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2003-03-07</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - SDV - Post Conflict Unit and Inter - Agency Standing Committee - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831710</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Social Dimensions of Adjustment - Correspondence File - 2000 - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831711</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Safeguard Policy Framework - Correspondence File - 2000</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831712</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-01/2000-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - Operational Policy 4.12 Involuntary Resettlement - ESSD Correspondence File - October 1998</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01831715</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-10-01/1998-10-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-10-01 - 1998-10-31</unitdate>
            <dao linktype="simple" href="https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/uploads/r/world-bank-group-archives/4/c/a/4ca61858f1f5dec6d972f6efa567d05574195920deac1ddeca894e67cecd1e9a/WorldBankGroupArchivesFolder1831715_141.jpg" role="reference" actuate="onrequest" show="embed"/>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Policy Development Records - Environment Strategy - Making Sustainable Commitments - Correspondence - 1999 - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832187</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-10-08/2001-07-17" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-10-08 - 2001-07-17</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Shared Unit Files - Policy Development Records - World Bank Draft Energy Strategy - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832215</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-04-01/2000-04-30" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-04-01 - 2000-04-30</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Briefing reports for World Bank President and related materials</unittitle>
          <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">WB IBRD/IDA 92 WB_IBRD/IDA_92-04</unitid>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999 - 2003</unitdate>
          <physdesc encodinganalog="3.1.5">
        0.66 linear feet of textual records    </physdesc>
          <langmaterial encodinganalog="3.4.3">
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
          </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd type="publicationStatus">
          <p>Published</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="3.3.1">
          <p>Series consists of briefing reports prepared by the ESSDVP and its sector departments for World Bank President James Wolfensohn. Records also include research materials used in the creation of the briefs (including reports, biographical information, and correspondence) as well as correspondence discussing brief requirements and meeting details. Briefs were created in preparation for the President's meetings with representatives from non-governmental organizations (NGOs), government agencies, and other external agencies and institutions. Topics include: climate change; environmental law; resettlement policy; environmental and social safeguard policy; agriculture science and technology; food security; climate change; biodiversity; energy; dams and water resources; forest policy; and empowerment, culture, and civic engagement.
<lb/>
<lb/>A small number of letters drafted by the ESSDVP for the President's signature are also included in this series.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement encodinganalog="3.3.4">
          <p>The original order of the records has been maintained. Records are arranged in chronological order.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accruals encodinganalog="3.3.3">
          <p>Accruals are expected.</p>
        </accruals>
        <processinfo>
          <p>
            <date>2 November 2012</date>
          </p>
        </processinfo>
        <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="3.5.3">
          <p>* See Records of the Environmentally and Socially Sustainable -- ESSDVP correspondence files ([WB IBRD/IDA 92 WB_IBRD/IDA_92-05](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/essdvp-correspondence-files)), of this fonds for a small amountof records that also relate to ESSDVP's interaction with the World Bank President. Records include briefing memoranda, correspondence, and letters written for his signature.</p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <accessrestrict encodinganalog="3.4.1">
          <p>Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict encodinganalog="3.4.2">
          <p>Records are subject to the Copyright Policy of the World Bank Group.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Briefing Books for Senior Officials - J. D. Wolfensohn Meeting with World Food Programme Executive Director James Morris - Briefing Notes - December 4, 2002 - ESSD Briefing</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833221</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-12-04/2002-12-04" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-12-04</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Critical Ecosystems Partnership Fund and Forest Policy - Briefing Material for J.D. Wolfensohn for January 28, 2003 Meeting with Conservation International Chairman, Peter Seligmann</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833149</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2003-01-22/2003-01-27" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2003-01-22 - 2003-01-27</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Briefing Books for Senior Officials - Jan Pronk - Netherlands Minister for Environment - Meetings - Briefing Notes - 2001 - 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833148</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-04-17/2002-01-17" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-04-17 - 2002-01-17</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">United Nations Foundation - Background and Briefing Material for President Wolfensohn with Tim Wirth - December 3, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833139</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-10-17/2001-11-30" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-10-17 - 2001-11-30</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Briefing Books for Senior Officials - United Nations [UN] Framework Convention on Climate Change - CO6 - Robert Watson - November 2000 - Briefing for J.D. Wolfensohn - January 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833138</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-10-07/2001-01-21" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-10-07 - 2001-01-21</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Role of Science and Technology in Food Security - Briefing for J. D. Wolfensohn - November 26, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833137</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-11-20/2001-11-26" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-11-20 - 2001-11-26</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Spring Meetings 2001 - Briefings Prepared for J. D. Wolfensohn - April 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833132</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-12-11/2001-04-23" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-12-11 - 2001-04-23</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">External Advisory Committee Meeting on Empowerment, Culture and Civic Engagement - Briefing Materias for J. D. Wolfensohn - July 24 - 25, 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833395</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-07-23/2001-07-24" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-07-23 - 2001-07-24</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Critical Ecosystem Partnership Fund - Briefing Notes for President Wolfensohn Prepared by Ian Johnson - November 10, 1999</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833143</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-11-09/1999-11-16" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-11-09 - 1999-11-16</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Briefing Books for Senior Officials - J. D. Wolfensohn Correspondence with Aracruz Celulose President Erling Lorentzen - March - November 2001 - Briefing Books - World Bank Forestry Policy</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833140</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-06-13/2001-11-29" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-06-13 - 2001-11-29</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Draft Water Resources Sector Strategy - Letter to Water Commissioners of the World Commission on Dams by Ian Johnson on behalf of J.D. Wolfensohn - August 22, 2002</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01833146</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2002-08-22/2002-08-22" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2002-08-22</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
      </c>
      <c level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESSDVP correspondence files</unittitle>
          <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">WB IBRD/IDA 92 WB_IBRD/IDA_92-05</unitid>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998 - 2001</unitdate>
          <physdesc encodinganalog="3.1.5">
        7.04 linear feet of textual records    </physdesc>
          <langmaterial encodinganalog="3.4.3">
            <language langcode="eng">English</language>
          </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <odd type="publicationStatus">
          <p>Published</p>
        </odd>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="3.3.1">
          <p>Series consists of correspondence files created by the ESSDVP. All of the correspondence in this series was authored by, addressed to, or forwarded to ESSD Vice Presidents Ismail Serageldin and Ian Johnson. There are, however, different forms of correspondence. Numbered correspondence in the form of a Lotus Notes log book is the most voluminous; these records span March 1998 to July 1999 and include correspondence to and from both Serageldin and Johnson. Correspondence of similar type, but that was not managed under the log book system, is included from 1999 to 2001 and is exclusively authored by or addressed to Johnson. Included in these records are a small number of short briefing notes authored by Johnson and/or the ESSDVP for the World Bank President. Memoranda files created in 2000 to 2001 are also included in this series as are a small number of records filed separately that only contain correspondence between the ESSDVP and the World Bank President between 1999 and 2001. The latter contains correspondence related to event and meeting attendance and planning, information exchange, briefing reports, and letters written by the ESSDVP for the President's signature.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <arrangement encodinganalog="3.3.4">
          <p>The original order of the records has been maintained. Records are arranged in chronological order.</p>
        </arrangement>
        <accruals encodinganalog="3.3.3">
          <p>Accruals are expected.</p>
        </accruals>
        <processinfo>
          <p>
            <date>2 November 2012</date>
          </p>
        </processinfo>
        <accessrestrict encodinganalog="3.4.1">
          <p>Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.</p>
        </accessrestrict>
        <userestrict encodinganalog="3.4.2">
          <p>Records are subject to the Copyright Policy of the World Bank Group.</p>
        </userestrict>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4900 to 98-4950</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832386</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-07-29/1998-08-10" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-07-29 - 1998-08-10</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-5000 to 98-5047</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832388</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-08-24/1998-09-07" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-08-24 - 1998-09-07</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book - I-98-00629 to I-98-00600</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832394</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-11-13/1999-02-09" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-11-13 - 1999-02-09</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book - I-99-00100 to I-99-0150</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832395</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-19/1999-07-02" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-19 - 1999-07-02</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book - I-99-00151 to I-99-00199 - Lotus Notes Log</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832396</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-15/1999-03-16" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-15 - 1999-03-16</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-5050 to 98-5078</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832389</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-09-07/1998-09-11" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-09-07 - 1998-09-11</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book I-98-00400 to I-98-00450</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832391</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-10-20/1998-10-30" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-10-20 - 1998-10-30</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book - I-99-00200 to I-99-00250</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832397</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-02-13/1999-02-22" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-02-13 - 1999-02-22</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Ian Johnson - Lotus Notes - Log Book - I-99-00300 to I-99-00350</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832399</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-10-07/1999-03-23" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-10-07 - 1999-03-23</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Ian Johnson - Lotus Notes - Log Book - I99-00451 to I-98-00499</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832400</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-11-19/1999-04-29" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-11-19 - 1999-04-29</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book I-98-00351 to I-98-00450</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832390</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-03-11/1999-04-05" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-03-11 - 1999-04-05</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book I-98-00500 to I-98-00550</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832392</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-11-30/1998-12-08" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-11-30 - 1998-12-08</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book - I-98-00500 to I-98-00599</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832393</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-05-06/1999-04-20" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-05-06 - 1999-04-20</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Chronological Correspondence Files - ESDVP Chronological - Correspondence Signed by JDW, Vice Presidents, and Directors - Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832398</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-02-23/2001-03-23" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-02-23 - 2001-03-23</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Ian Johnson</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832401</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-07/2000-08-29" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-07 - 2000-08-29</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Ian Johnson - Correspondence with J.D. Wolfensohn</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832407</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-01/2000-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-01 - 2000-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice President's Files - Chronological Correspondence File - 1999</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832267</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-10-20/2000-06-14" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-10-20 - 2000-06-14</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Ian Johnson - Vice President's Files - Correspondence File - April - June 1999</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832268</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-05-30/1999-12-13" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-05-30 - 1999-12-13</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP Chronological Records - Correspondence File - Ian Johnson</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832265</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-01-01/1999-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-01-01 - 1999-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice President's Files - Chronological Correspondence File - Memos - 2000 - 2001</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832269</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2000-01-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2000-01-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP Chronological Correspondence Records - Vice President's Files - Ian Johnson - Correspondence File</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832272</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="2001-01-01/2001-12-31" encodinganalog="3.1.3">2001-01-01 - 2001-12-31</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Correspondence - Chronological Records - Ismail Serageldin - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4300 to 98-4350</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832280</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-03-23/1998-04-06" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-03-23 - 1998-04-06</unitdate>
            <dao linktype="simple" href="https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/uploads/r/world-bank-group-archives/f/d/9/fd99a7f3a1e3660350599e0867234427fc5de50e280d6b69786eb9a11375f9a8/WorldBankGroupArchivesFolder1832280_141.jpg" role="reference" actuate="onrequest" show="embed"/>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice President's Files - Chronological Correspondence with JD Wolfensohn - 1999</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832270</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1999-08-24/1999-11-15" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1999-08-24 - 1999-11-15</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP Vice Presidents Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4650 to 98-4699</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832282</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-05-15/1998-05-28" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-05-15 - 1998-05-28</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Correspondence - Chronological Records - Ismail Serageldin - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4500 to 98-4550</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832281</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-04-24/1998-05-04" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-04-24 - 1998-05-04</unitdate>
            <dao linktype="simple" href="https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/uploads/r/world-bank-group-archives/f/3/c/f3c792c2b0cb1760bcb4215fa0f547d0a496c8865382937863baf35bd33ed492/WorldBankGroupArchivesFolder1832281_141.jpg" role="reference" actuate="onrequest" show="embed"/>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP Vice Presidents Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4700 to 98-4749</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832283</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-06-01/1998-06-12" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-06-01 - 1998-06-12</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4800 to 98-4850</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832384</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-06-30/1998-07-14" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-06-30 - 1998-07-14</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4851 to 98-4899</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832385</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-07-15/1998-07-29" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-07-15 - 1998-07-29</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP - Vice Presidents Chronological Records - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4951 to 98-4999</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832387</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-08-10/1998-08-20" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-08-10 - 1998-08-20</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
        <c otherlevel="folder" level="otherlevel">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">ESDVP Vice Presidents Correspondence - Lotus Notes - Log Book 98-4750 to 98-4799</unittitle>
            <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">01832284</unitid>
            <unitdate normal="1998-06-12/1998-07-02" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1998-06-12 - 1998-07-02</unitdate>
          </did>
          <odd type="publicationStatus">
            <p>Published</p>
          </odd>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
