<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "http://lcweb2.loc.gov/xmlcommon/dtds/ead2002/ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="DC">
    <eadid identifier="resource-mobilization" url="https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/resource-mobilization" encodinganalog="identifier">WB IBRD/IDA CFOP</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Resource Mobilization</titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">World Bank Group Archives</publisher>
        <date normal="2016-03-16" encodinganalog="date">2016-03-16</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>
      Generated by Access to Memory (AtoM) 2.6.4      <date normal="2024-04-05">2024-04-05 16:45 UTC</date>
    </creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langusage>
      <descrules encodinganalog="3.7.2">Internal World Bank Group Archives rules based on ISAD(G).</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="fonds" relatedencoding="ISAD(G)v2">
    <did>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="3.1.2">Resource Mobilization</unittitle>
      <unitid encodinganalog="3.1.1">WB IBRD/IDA CFOP</unitid>
      <unitdate id="atom_46878_event" encodinganalog="3.1.3">1966 - 2010</unitdate>
      <physdesc encodinganalog="3.1.5">
        1,300 linear feet of textual records; 423 audio-cassette tapes (all figures approximate)    </physdesc>
      <repository>
        <corpname>World Bank Group Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <langmaterial encodinganalog="3.4.3">
        <language langcode="eng">English</language>
        <language langcode="spa">Spanish</language>
        <language langcode="fre">French</language>
      </langmaterial>
      <origination encodinganalog="3.2.1">
        <name id="atom_46878_actor">Resource Mobilization</name>
      </origination>
    </did>
    <bioghist id="md5-8953350d51928377f7c9900f5cae0064" encodinganalog="3.2.2">
      <note>
        <p>This fonds contains the records of the World Bank Group units responsible for donor-based resource mobilization functions related to cofinancing, trust funds, and International Development Agency (IDA) replenishments. The fonds does not include records related to the Bank's traditional resource mobilization efforts of acquiring IBRD financing through the world's financial markets because the function does not share a provenance with the units described. This administrative history describes the provenance of the administrative units for cofinancing, trust funds, and IDA replenishments separately. After 1996, the functions merged under one vice presidency. As a consequence, the post-1996 section focuses on all functions together. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Cofinancing 
<lb/>
<lb/>Cofinancing is defined as additional funding sought by borrowing member countries from external sources outside of the World Bank. Cofinancing is meant to supplement funding resources provided by the World Bank (e.g. IBRD/IDA loans, credits, and grants), which may fall short of the funding needs for projects and programs associated with a borrowing member country. Cofinancing funding is sought by the Bank and its member countries from the following external official and private sources: agencies or government departments administrating bilateral development programs; multilateral agencies such as regional development banks; export credit agencies; and commercial banks. Cofinance funding is administered through two types of financing methods: 1) parallel cofinancing, in which the Bank and cofinanciers finance different goods and services or parts of the project; and 2) joint cofinancing, in which the Bank and cofinanciers finance expenditures from a common list of goods and services in agreed proportions, which adhere to the Bank's procurement guidelines. Cofinancing activities were developed in the Bank to help mobilize additional funding for sector-oriented programs and projects, fill funding gaps, and also foster greater international coordination to respond more rapidly to global macro-economic crises.
<lb/>
<lb/>The first use of cofinancing in Bank operations was a joint cofinancing agreement drafted for the Mexico Power Sector Program in 1966. Initial Bank loans fell short of financing needs for projects under this program, so external funding sources were sought and renegotiated by members of the Bank's Loan Committee, cofinanciers, and the Government of Mexico. Similar agreements were negotiated thereafter for other programs and projects, including a parallel cofinancing agreement negotiated between the Bank, cofinanciers, and the Brazilian Government related to steel industry projects in 1971. 
<lb/>
<lb/>The use of cofinancing to mobilize resources significantly increased in World Bank operations during the oil and energy crisis that began in 1973. In this period, Arab/OPEC multilateral institutions emerged as a primary contributor for providing cofinancing sources. Newly founded regional multilateral institutions such as the Inter-American Development Bank, the Asian Development Bank, and the African Development Bank also emerged as valuable multilateral cofinancing partners. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1975, the Bank's cofinancing functions were formalized with the establishment of the Senior Adviser for cofinancing in the Front Office for the Senior Vice President of Operations (SVPOP). Regional Cofinancing Coordinators (RCC) were also established in the six Regional Vice Presidencies (RVP). The Senior Adviser for Cofinancing took lead responsibility in Bank-wide overall planning, policy making, communication, coordination, and monitoring of cofinancing operations. The RCCs were given line responsibilities of identifying operations to be cofinanced and arranging cofinancing with official sources in the Regional Programs Departments (RPD). The RCCs were also responsible for arranging cofinancing with export credit and commercial banking sources for the Regional Projects Departments. Roger Hornstein served as the Senior Adviser for Cofinancing. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1981, Frank Vibert succeeded Roger Hornstein as Senior Adviserfor Cofinancing in the SVPOP Front Office. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Demand for cofinancing sources grew in the late 1970s and the early 1980s with the ongoing oil crisis and emerging debt crisis. This demand strained the limited cofinancing operations in the Bank. As a result, the Vice President of Cofinancing (VPCOF) was established in May 1983. Teruyuki Ohuchi served as Vice President for VPCOF. The new VPCOF reported to the Senior Vice President, Operations (SVPOP). The VPCOF was created to strengthen and expand the Bank's cofinancing operations as a means to maintain and increase international capital flows to developing countries in times of constrained financial resources. The RPD retained line responsibilities for identifying and arranging cofinancing and also for arranging cofinancing for commercial and export credit sources. A new Regional Cofinancing Advisor was also established who would have functional control for cofinancing activities in the Region. The VPCOF was given responsibilities for:
<lb/>
<lb/>*	maintaining top-level contacts and promotion with cofinanciers; 
<lb/>
<lb/>*	developing new cofinancing tools; and
<lb/>
<lb/>*	planning, coordinating, and monitoring the Bank's overall cofinancing program.
<lb/>
<lb/>The VPCOF included the subordinate Cofinancing Advisory Unit (VPCAU), which was staffed by cofinancing advisers with expertise in commercial banking, export credits, and official financial sources. 
<lb/>
<lb/>During the establishment of VPCOF, the Japanese government emerged as the largest cofinancing contributor to the Bank by launching a number of cofinancing programs through the Overseas Economic Cooperation Fund (OECF), Japan's development aid agency, as well as the Export-Import Bank of Japan (UEXIM). This marked the beginning of strong Japanese leadership in the Bank's cofinancing operations, which extended from the 1980s into the early 2000s. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1983, the Bank's "B-Loan" program was launched to expand private cofinancing efforts and channel commercial bank resources to Bank operations. Shortly after, multilateral, bilateral, and export credit agency cofinancing programs were launched as part of the Japanese Grant Facility (JGF, later renamed the Japanese Policy and Human Resources Development [PHRD] Fund). In 1985, the multi-country official cofinancing (bilateral and multilateral) programs, the Special Facility for Sub-Saharan Africa (SFA) and the Consultant Trust Fund (CTF) Program, were launched. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In June 1986, Teruyuki Ohuchi was succeeded by Kunihiko Inakage as Vice President for VPCOF. In the May 1987 Reorganization, the Cofinancing Vice Presidency remained structurally unchanged but new acronyms were assigned to the Office of the Vice President (COFVP) and to the Cofinancing Advisory Unit (COFAU). 
<lb/>
<lb/>In June 1989, the COFVP was terminated and its functions were combined with the former Vice President of Financial Intermediation (VPFIS). This merger broadened cofinancing functions to include technical assistance in debt management and resource mobilization. The new combined VP was renamed the Vice President of Financial Intermediation and Cofinancing (CFSVP). The CFSVP reported to the Senior Vice President, Operations (OPNSV). CFSVP responsibilities included:      
<lb/>
<lb/>*	assisting member countries in restructuring debt;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	assisting member countries with deregulation, public sector restructuring and privatization;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	advising member countries on management of their foreign financial assets and liabilities;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	procuring cofinancing arrangements from commercial and public sources; 
<lb/>
<lb/>*	developing a Bank-wide strategy and capability for dealing with privatization requests; and
<lb/>
<lb/>*	developing new lending products to mobilize financial resources in commercial markets.
<lb/>
<lb/>At the time of its establishment, the CFS had one subordinate unit, the Cofinancing and Financial Advisory Services Department (CFS), which incorporated the financial engineering functions of the former Debt Management and Financial Advisory Department (DFS) formerly located in the Vice President of Financial Intermediation (VPFIS), as well as most of the staff of the former CofinancingVice Presidency (COFVP). CFS consisted of the following units: the Cofinancing Group (CFSCO); the Financial Advisory Services Group (CFSFA); and the Private Sector Development Group (CFSPS). The CFSVP was also supported by a Front Office consisting of advisers in the following areas: commercial finance; official sources; export credits; and banking institutions. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Koji Kashiwaya assumed the role of Vice President for the new CFSVP. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In late 1989, the CFSPS was transferred from the Cofinancing and AdvisoryServices Department (CFS) to the Front Office of the CFSVP. In December 1990, the CFS Department was restructured, splitting the CFSCO into the new Official Cofinancing Group (CFSOC), and the new Private Cofinancing Group (CFSPC). In this same year, the Expanded Cofinancing Operation (ECO) program replaced the "B-Loan" program. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1990, the CFSVP was renamed the Vice President of Cofinancing and Advisory Services (CFSVP). 
<lb/>
<lb/>In February 1992, the CFSVP underwent a comprehensive reorganization to strengthen private sector development work and streamline the process of financial resource mobilization. This entailed building up the cofinancing and financial advisory capabilities in the regional Country Departments, which were given primary responsibility for implementing private sector development programs, and a consolidation of CFSVP's subordinate units. Specific responsibilities included:
<lb/>
<lb/>*	mobilizing official and private equity financing to cofinance Bank supported projects;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	managing and reducing the external debt of heavily indebted countries;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	developing programs for public enterprise divestiture;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	restructuring and privatizing of specific major public enterprises; and
<lb/>
<lb/>*	developing new approaches to attract private sector investment into major infrastructure projects. 
<lb/>
<lb/>The CFSVP restructuring included the merging of CFSPC and CFSPS, as well as some of the functions of the CFSFA, to create the new Private Sector Finance and Advisory Services Group (CFSPS). The responsibilities of the former CFSOC were also redefined and the unit was renamed the Official Cofinancing and Trust Fund Management Group (CFSOC). The remaining functions of CFSFA created the new Project Finance Group (CFSPF). 
<lb/>
<lb/>In April 1992, the CFSPS was further restructured, and became the Private Sector Development and Privatization Group (CFSPS).
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1994, Hiroo Fukui succeeded Koji Kashiwaya as Vice President for CFSVP. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In March 1996, CFSVP was terminated and the subordinate CFSOC and the CFSPF staff and functions were absorbed by the new Resource Mobilization and Cofinancing Vice Presidency (RMCVP). The CFSPS staff and functions were removed from cofinancing operations and absorbed by the Private Sector Development (PSD) Department located in the Finance and Private Sector Development Vice Presidency (FPDVP).
<lb/>
<lb/>Trust Funds
<lb/>
<lb/>A trust fund is a financing arrangement set up with contributions from one or more donors and, in some cases, from the World Bank Group. The Bank establishes and administers trust funds as a complement to IDA and IBRD financing to promote development and aid effectiveness by leveraging its capacity and development knowledge. The Bank encourages trust funds that: draw on its operational role; include contributions from more than one donor; reinforce country capacity and ownership; and promote harmonization and alignment of donor aid modalities. Selectively, the Bank also provides specific administrative and financial services to the international community for trust funds that support work on issues of global importance and where the Bank may not perform an operational role. Trust funds differ to cofinancing arrangements in that trust funds are not limited to being tied to an existing Bank loan or grant for a program or project. Trust funds are also not generally initiated by the recipient member country like cofinancing. Many funds acquired through cofinancing arrangements are distributed into a Bank administered trust fund, but cofinancing arrangements serve as one example of a more restricted type of trust fund. Trust funds have a diversity of arrangements, which provides donors flexibility to target a variety of sectoral, regional, and global initiatives. 
<lb/>
<lb/>The earliest use of trust funds in World Bank Group operations can be traced to 1960 when the Bank administered the multi-donor Indus Basin Development Fund to help finance the Indus Basin Project in Pakistan. In the 1970s, the Bank also served as a financing partner in multiple global programs in partnership, with the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP), the Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations (FAO), and the World Health Organization (WHO). The most notable examples were, the Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research (CGIAR), established in 1972, and the River Blindness (Onchocerciasis) Control Program established in 1974. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Significant growth of trust fund mobilization, however, occurred in the early-1980s. At this time, the Bank lacked a formal trust fund administrator or central authority charged with implementing, coordinating, and monitoring trust fund administration, and developing trust fund related policies, guidelines, and procedures. Instead, trust fund administration responsibilities were fragmented among multiple Bank units. In this period, trust funds fell into two broad categories: 1) cofinanced trust funds; and 2) trust funds that are not tied directly to Bank loans (non-cofinanced), but augmented or diversified the sources of funding for a wide range of activities, including studies, institutional development training, and technical assistance. 
<lb/>
<lb/>The first category, cofinanced trust funds, were tied to existing Bank loans or credits, and were arranged either through a joint or parallel cofinancing agreement. Joint cofinancing required an agreement between the Bank and the cofinancier on the expenditure of a common list of goods or services for a project, and abided by the procurement and disbursement procedures of the Bank. Agreed upon joint cofinanced funds were deposited into a Bank administered trust fund. With parallel cofinancing, the Bank and the cofinancier agreed to finance different services, goods, or parts of a project, but the cofinancier was not required to use the procurement and disbursement procedures of the Bank. This allowed for the cofinancier to disburse funds to colenders according to their own procedures, and not have to be part of a Bank administered trust fund. Parallel cofinancing funds were part of Bank administered trust funds, however, if the parallel cofinancing agreement was "untied" and the cofinancier chose to have the Bank administer funds on the cofinancier's behalf. 
<lb/>
<lb/>The second category of trust funds were not tied directly to a Bank loan (non-cofinanced). Instead, the Bank served the role of trust fund administrator either as a fiscal agent or as the Executing Agency for trust funds financed by external donors. Such trust funds included contributions from governments, private foundations, or intergovernmental organizations. Many of these trust funds were either one-time contributions, or were subject to periodic replenishments, and were also free-standing programs with their own independent administration, executive secretariat, committee structure, and funding apparatus (e.g. CGIAR and the Global Environmental Facility [GEF]). Administering trust funds as a fiscal agent simply implied the Bank was responsible for the financial management functions of accounting and disbursement for a trust fund. The role of Executing Agency was more complex in that it included accounting and disbursement functions, but also responsibilities for hiring consultants and consulting of firms, procuring goods, organizing training activities, administering project budgets, and reviewing studies and reports prepared by consultants. The Executing Agency functions not related to financial management were generally handled by program coordinators, project officers, and advisers located in the Bank's sector departments, or country program departments and country project departments located in the Regional Vice Presidencies. An executive secretariat or independent administrative unit was also usually established to administer this type of trust fund. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1983, the newly established Vice President of Cofinancing (VPCOF) served as a focal point for the arrangement and management of cofinanced trust funds. VPCOF evolved into the central unit responsible for the management of some of the Bank's largest pooled and multi-donor technical assistance and consultant trust funds. In the early 1980s, the Japanese Government emerged as the largest cofinancier for the Bank and took a strong leadership role in leading cofinancing operations in the Bank. This included the launch of numerous grant-based trust fund programs through their donor agencies, the Overseas Economic Cooperation Fund (OECF) and the Export-Import Bank of Japan (JEXIM). The Japanese led programs were collectively referred to as the Japanese Grant Facility (JGF). 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1984, the Chief United Nations Development Programme (UNDP)/Trust Funds Section (LOATF) of the Loan Department (LOA) located in Vice President of the Treasurer (TREVP) was established to administer financial management (accounting and disbursement) of the Bank's trust funds, including the United Nations Development Programme (UNDP) financed trust funds in where the Bank served as the Executing Agent. Kah Hie Lau served as Chief for the UNDP/Trust Fund Section. The VPCOF continued to be the unit responsible for the arrangement of cofinanced trust funds, but the LOATF handled the financial management of cofinanced trust funds. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1985, the multi-donor Special Facility for Sub-Saharan Africa (SFA) and the multi-donor Consultant Trust Fund (CTF) Program consisting of donors from multiple Bank member countries were launched. They were also managed by VPCOF and its subordinate Cofinancing Advisory Unit (VPCAU).
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1986, LOA and its subordinate LOATF were transferred to the Vice President of the Controller (CTRVP). LOATF was renamed and upgraded to the Trust Funds Division (LOATF) due to the expanding use of trust funds. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1987, the VPCOF remained structurally unchanged but new acronyms were assigned to the Office of the Vice President (COFVP) and to the Cofinancing Advisory Unit (COFAU).
<lb/>
<lb/>In the same year, the Resource Mobilization Department (FRM) was established in the Vice President of Financial Policy and Risk Management (FPRVP). The FRM focused on resource mobilization of official IDA concessional resources and IBRD capital resources, but also played a role in managing donor negotiations and relations related to trust funds that helped supplement the concessional lending of IDA operations. This was done in close collaboration with the COFVP, or other trust funds operations focused on providing concessional resources. For instance, the Special Facility for Sub-Saharan Africa (SFA) consisted of trust funds designed specifically to supplement IDA projects and programs. The COFVP and FRM worked closely to mobilize resources for SFA, and to help foster agreements between the Bank, borrower, and donor. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1989, the COFVP and the subordinate COFAU were terminated, and replaced by the Vice President of Financial Intermediation and Cofinancing (CFSVP). Within CFSVP, the new Official Cofinancing Group (CFSOC) served as the focal point for managing the Bank's cofinanced trust funds. CFSOC served as the key unit responsible for managing the technical assistance portions of the Consultant Trust Funds (CTF) Program, and the Japanese Policy and Human Resources Development (PHRD) Fund, which consolidated numerousgrant-based programs of the former Japanese Grant Facility (JGF). Specific responsibilities of CFSOC included: 
<lb/>
<lb/>*	developing and maintaining institutional relations with the main donor agencies;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	establishing and monitoring formal arrangements for cofinancing so that clear operational procedures and policies are in place for cofinancing with colenders;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	assisting both potential cofinanciers and task managers in bringing together financing interests and funding needs; and
<lb/>
<lb/>*	mobilizing grant funds for consultants to be used for the Bank's operational work, and other special purposes.
<lb/>
<lb/>John Taylor served as the Manager for CFSOC.  
<lb/>
<lb/>In same year, the Bank issued Operation Manual Statement (OMS) 4.40, Trust Funds. This statement designated the role of Trust Funds Administrator (LAOTF), and assigned this role to the reorganized Loan and Trust Fund Department (LOA). This was done to expand the responsibilities of the former LOATF Chief, strengthen trust fund policies and guidelines, consolidate the fragmented trust fund administration functions, and strengthen trust funds administration Bank wide. Specific responsibilities included:
<lb/>
<lb/>*	implementing the policies and guidelines for administering funds;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	ensuring the consistency of information given to donors on the terms and conditions on which funds are administered by the Bank;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	coordinating within the Bank to ensure compliance with Bank policies and with the specific provisions of each agreement;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	participating in negotiating agreements and clearing them before signature;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	ensuring that disbursements are for eligible countries only;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	preparing financial reports on each fund in accordance with the agreement;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	coordinating the preparation by Task Managers of implementation reports and other reporting requirements; and 
<lb/>
<lb/>*	requesting the donor to replenish trust fund accounts as needed. 
<lb/>
<lb/>The new Trust Funds Administrator of the Loan and Trust Fund Department (LOA) remained in the CTRVP. Kah Hie Lau was promoted to the Trust Funds Administrator. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In1991, the Global Environment Facility (GEF) was launched. The COFVP and the FRM served as the key units in the Bank responsible for the resource mobilization and replenishment of the GEF trust funds. In the same year, the Trust Funds Administrator was transferred to the Resource Mobilization Department (FRM) located in the Vice President of Financial Policy and Risk Management (FPRVP), and its acronym changed to FRMTF. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In February 1992, the CFSVP underwent a comprehensive reorganization and the CFSOC wasrenamed the Official Cofinancing and Trust Fund Management Group (CFSOC). The newly reorganized CFSOC responsibilities included:
<lb/>
<lb/>*	administering the Japanese Policy and Human Resources Development (PHRD) Fund;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	administering the Consultant Trust Fund (CTF) Program;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	managing institutional relationships with bilateral and multilateral cofinanciers to include proactive initiatives to increase cofinancing; and
<lb/>
<lb/>*	maintaining the Bank's Cofinancing Database and CTF Management Information system. 
<lb/>
<lb/>CharlesMeissner served as the new Manager for the reorganized CFSOC.
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1993, the Trust Funds Administrator was removed from FRM, and transferred to the Trust Funds Administration Department (CTRTA) in the Controller Vice Presidency (CTRVP). 
<lb/>
<lb/>In March 1996, CFSVP was terminated and CFSOC staff and functions as well as the Resource Mobilization Department (FRM) were absorbed by the new Resource Mobilization and Cofinancing Vice Presidency (RMCVP). CFSOC was placed in the new Cofinancing and Project Finance Department (CAP), and renamed the Official Cofinancing and Trust Funds Group (CAPOC). 
<lb/>
<lb/>The Trust Funds Administrator was transferred to the new Trust Funds Division (ACTTF) in the Accounting Department (ACT) of the Controller Vice Presidency (CTRVP), and supported the new RMCVP in financial management of trust funds, and implementing policies and guidelines related to trust fund administration. 
<lb/>
<lb/> IDA replenishment 
<lb/>
<lb/>This section focuses on the units responsible for the following functions: leading and supporting IDA replenishments negotiations with the Bank's IDA Deputies; managing the finances of IDA's concessional lending funds; managing the allocation of IDA resources; and monitoring the implementation of IDA mandated policies within Bank operations. 
<lb/>
<lb/>The International Development Agency (IDA) was established in 1960 to complement the role of the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (IBRD) in promoting economic development by offering concessional financing to the poorer developing countries within its membership. The IDA replenished its resources through negotiations held every three years, wherein the Bank sought donations from its wealthiest Part I member countries. 
<lb/>
<lb/>The first replenishment of IDA resources was held in 1962. The Bank's Board of Governors requested that the Board of Executive Director's assess financial requirements for IDA operations. Subsequently, the Financial Policy Committee of the Board was given the task of leading replenishment negotiations, and did so in a number of informal meetings with Part I member country leaders.
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1965, the second replenishment was held and, much like the first replenishment, it was initiated by the Board of Governors with a request to the Board of Executive Directors. The second IDA replenishment negotiations established Part I member country representatives as the new IDA Deputies, and the formal IDA replenishment negotiations became known as the IDA Deputy Meetings. IDA replenishment negotiations included senior officials of the Bank andthe IDA Deputies.
<lb/>
<lb/>The third replenishment was held in 1968, and the process of initiating formal negotiations by a Board of Governors request to the Executive Directors was discontinued. Formal donor meetings with the IDA Deputies where arranged by Bank management after this point. The Office of the Vice President of Sir Denis Rickett (OVPDR) established on April 1, 1968 was the unit responsible for such IDA replenishment arrangements. The OVPDR was created in conjunction with the appointment of PresidentRobert McNamara, and reported directly to him. This OVPDR was established as a liaison office of the Bank with Part I countries. Specific responsibilities included leading negotiations for IDA replenishments, and providing information on the Bank's lending programs and policies. The OVPDR was not assigned any direct responsibility for department supervision.
<lb/>
<lb/>On October 4, 1974, with the resignation of Vice President Rickett, the OVPDR was terminated. The functions of OVPDR were absorbed by the Vice President of Finance (VPF) led by I.P.M. Cargill. The VPF was also responsible for managing the Bank's financial operations and advising the President on Bank financial policies, and consisted of the following subordinate units: the Treasurer's Department (TRE) and the Programming and Budgeting Department (PAB). The IDA replenishment function was supported by two Special Assistants in the VPF Front Office. The PAB Department's Financial Analysis Division (PABFA) was responsible for providing staff support to IDAreplenishment efforts of the Front Office assistants. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1977, the Financial Analysis Division (PABFA) of the PAB Department absorbed greater responsibility for supporting IDA replenishment from the former IDA Special Assistants of the VPF Front Office due to increased workload of the function, and planned retirement of one its assistants. The VPF continued to lead IDA replenishment negotiations, but was primarily supported by PABFA. Within PABFA, the IDA replenishment related functions were merged with financial policy, financial projections, and IBRD capital increase support responsibilities. Specific responsibilities of PABFA included: 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>*	maintaining analysis of Bank Group financial policies and activities as they affect the soundness and financial needs of the institution;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	alerting management to potential financial problem conditions and proposed changes to the Bank Group's financial policies;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	providing staff support related to IBRD capital increases, including periodic reviews of the appropriate capital structure of the Bank and analysis of the size, timing, and distribution by country of increases in subscribed capital;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	providing staff support for the periodic IDA replenishment negotiations, including analysis of the size of replenishment burden-sharing arrangements, voting rights issues, method of payment, maintenance of value, and other topics; 
<lb/>
<lb/>*	preparing periodic reviews of the Bank's lending rate, liquidity policy, and allocation of net income;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	preparing the sections on Bank/IDA financial position and prospects for inclusion in the annual review of the five-year program as well as for the mid-year review of operations;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	preparing standard long-term financial projections for the Bank and IDA;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	reviewing the changes in the quality of the Bank's overall loan portfolio; and
<lb/>
<lb/>*	maintaining awareness of changes in the external financial environment. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The PABFA was led by Division Chief David Bock at the time it absorbed IDA replenishment related functions. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>In July 1978, VPFI.P.M. Cargill was promoted to Senior Vice President of Finance (SVPFI) to further assist the Bank President more broadly on priority areas, and serve as Acting President and Board Chairman in the absence of the President. The position of Vice President of Finance (VPF) remained, and Cargill relinquished most of his responsibilities of overseeing the operations of the Finance Complex to the new VPF Moeen Qureshi. With this change, PABFA reported to the VPF, but still supported the SVPFI, who continued to lead IDA replenishment negotiations. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1980, SVPFI I.P.M. Cargill retired from the Bank. Moeen Qureshi was promoted soon after as the new SVPFI, and retained the responsibility of leading IDA replenishment negotiations. The position of VPF was terminated. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>At the same time, the PABFA and the Financial Studies Division (PABFS) of Programming and Budgeting Department (PAB) were transferred to the new Financial Policy and Analysis Department (FPA), which reported directly to the SVPFI. The FPA Department was assigned the following responsibilities: 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>*	performing analytical work on Bank financial policies, and supporting the Senior Vice President, Finance in such key activities as IDA replenishment negotiations, IBRD capital increases and analyzing the financial impacts of new initiatives; 
<lb/>
<lb/>*	producing long-term financial projections and plans beyond a one-year horizon; 
<lb/>
<lb/>*	assessing and managing financial risks; and 
<lb/>
<lb/>*	providing support to Operations in areas involving financial analysis.
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The former Financial Studies Division and Programming and Budgeting Department maintained their titles in the new FPA, but their acronyms were changed to FPAFA and FPAFS, respectively. The function supporting IDA replenishment negotiations was moved to the FPAFS Division. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1983, the FPA reported to the new Vice President of Financial Policy, Planning, and Budgeting (FPBVP). 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>During the 1987 Bank-wide reorganization, the FPA was terminated. As a result, the FPAPP and FPAMA divisions were absorbed by the new Risk Management and Financial Policy Department (FRS), and the FPAFS, which maintained responsibility for IDA replenishment negotiations, was absorbed by the new Resource Mobilization Department (FRM). Both departments reported to the new Vice President of Financial Policy and Risk Management (FPRVP), which reported to the new Senior Vice President of Finance (FINSV) Ernest Stern. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>FRM was given the responsibility of securing official funding necessary to fund the Bank's planned programs. Official funding sources sought by FRM included capital subscriptions by Bank shareholders for IBRD lending operations and IDA concessional resources for its lending to countries which were not creditworthy for IBRD borrowing. Specific responsibilities included:
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>*	maintaining a positive environment for Bank funding approaches;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	developing a system for monitoring funding approaches;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	monitoring the adequacy of the Bank's capital and taking steps to replenish it;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	managing the subscription payments and the release of local currency contributions;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	replenishing IDA;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	managing donor contributions to IDA's contributions; 
<lb/>
<lb/>*	exploring new facilities that use official funding; and
<lb/>
<lb/>*	analyzing the role of Bank/IDA flows in relation to aggregate aid and commercial flows. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>At its inception, the FRM had the following subordinate units: the Replenishment Policy Division (FRMRP) and the Replenishment Operations Division (FRMRO). Basil Kavalasky served as Director for FRM.
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1991, the Trust Funds Administrator Kah Hie Lau was transferred from the Loan and Trusts Funds Department (LOA) of the Vice President of Controller (CTRVP) to FRM. In 1993, the Trust Funds Administrator was removed from FRM, and transferred to the Trust Funds Administration Department (CTRTA) in the Controller Vice Presidency (CTRVP).
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1996, the Vice President of Financial Policy and Risk Management (FPRVP) was terminated. As a result, the Risk Management and Financial Policy Department (FRS), was absorbed by the new Office of the Vice President Financial Policy and Institutional Strategy (FPIVP). The Resource Mobilization Department (FRM) was transferred to the new Resource Mobilization and Cofinancing Vice Presidency (RMCVP).
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>Cofinancing, trust funds, and IDA replenishment (1996-present)
<lb/>
<lb/>In April 1996, the cofinancing, trust funds, and IDA replenishment functions were merged under the new Resource Mobilization and Cofinancing Vice Presidency (RMCVP). More specifically, the functions of the former Official Cofinancing and Trust Fund Management Group (CFSOC) and the Project Finance Group (CFSPF) of the former Vice President of Financial Intermediation and Cofinancing (CFSVP), and the functions of the Resource Mobilization Department (FRM) of the former Financial Policy and Resource Mobilization Vice Presidency (FPRVP) were absorbed by the new RMCVP. The new RMCVP was created to enable the Bank to forge a more effective partnerships with the donor community and the private sector. RMCVP focused on mobilizing funds from official and private sources to IBRD and IDA operations and services and the Global Environmental Facility (GEF). Specific responsibilities included:
<lb/>
<lb/>*	expanding resource mobilization efforts to achieve greater financial sustainability through donor support, official cofinancing, export credit, and trust funds;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	accelerating the implementation of the guarantee Program, expand the use of guarantees, and increase the pipelines of guarantee operations; and 
<lb/>
<lb/>*	supporting the Bank's efforts to mainstream the trust fund activities into the Bank's processes. 
<lb/>
<lb/>At its establishment, the RMCVP consisted of the following subordinate units: the Cofinancing and Project Finance Department (CAP) and the Resource Mobilization Department (FRM). CAP consisted of the Official Cofinancing and Trust Funds Group (CAPOC) and the Project Finance and Guarantees Group (CAPPF). The FRM Department consisted of the Replenishment Operations Unit (FRMRO) and the Replenishment Policy Unit (FRMRP). CAPOC served as the main unit for cofinancing related responsibilities, which consisted of promoting and monitoring official cofinancing of Bank Group operations. CAPOC was also responsible for trust fund functions including monitoring, mobilization, and administration. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Hiroo Fukui served as Vice President for RMCVP. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Soon after the establishment of the RMCVP, the Highly Indebted Poor Countries (HIPC) Debt Initiative, a debt restructuring trust fund, was launched. RMCVP served as trustee for this fund. In 1997, the global trust fund program, Development Grant Facility (DGF), was launched. The RMCVP also served as trustee for this fund. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1998, the RMCVP was restructured. FRM remained unchanged, but CAP functions were divided into two new departments: the Trust Fund and Cofinancing Department (TFC) and the Project Finance and Guarantees Department (PFG). 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1999, PFG was removed from the RMCVP, and its functions were transferred to the Private Sector Development and Infrastructure Vice Presidency (PSIVP). 
<lb/>
<lb/>The early 2000s marked a significant increase in the Bank's trust fund portfolio, primarily due to the 2002 launch of the United Nations Millennium Development Goals (MDGs). This prompted the creation of numerous global programs and partnership trust funds to respond to the international initiatives of the MDG, including the Global Fund to Fight AIDS, Tuberculosis, and Malaria (the Global Fund) and the Climate Investment Funds (CIFs), both established in 2002. The use of global programs and partnership existed prior to this period, most notably GEF and DGF, but their use rapidly expanded in the 2000s. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Furthermore, due to the growth and increasing complexity of trust funds, this period also experienced a shift in the type of trust funds arrangements used for various funds. This included the growing use of the following types of trust fund arrangements: Financial Intermediary Funds (FIFs); Bank Executed Trust Funds (BETF); and Recipient Executed Trust Funds (RETF). FIFs, in particular, saw significant expansion foster the arrangement of complex global programs and partnership trust funds. With the changing trust fund landscape, more traditional cofinancing arrangements experienced gradual decline as a source for external funding. Cofinancing, however, still remained a component of these trust fund arrangements, and the cofinancing function was integrated into broader trust funds operations. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 2001, RMCVP was again restructured. The functions of TFC were split into two new departments: the Trust Fund Operations Department (TFO) and the Trust Fund Strategy and Donor Relations Department (TFS). FRM remained unchanged.
<lb/>
<lb/>In June 2003, the RMCVP was terminated and its functions absorbed by the new Concessional Finance and Global Partnerships Vice Presidency (CFPVP). The responsibilities of the new CFPVP included: 
<lb/>
<lb/>*	mobilizing and managing concessional and grant finance in the Bank;
<lb/>
<lb/>*	agreeing to the policy framework with which these resources are provided by donors; and
<lb/>
<lb/>*	facilitating and overseeing the robust and accountable framework of partnerships to take forward the Bank's strategic priorities. 
<lb/>
<lb/>At its establishment, the CFPVP consisted of the following subordinate departments and units: the Resource Mobilization Department (FRM); the Global Programs and Partnerships (GPP); the Trust Fund Operations (TFO); the Trust Fund Strategy and Donor Relations Department (TFS); and the Multilateral Trustee Operations (MTO). 
<lb/>
<lb/>Geoffrey Lamb served as Vice President of the CFPVP. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 2004, the Finance and Risk Unit (CFPFR) and the Multilateral Trustee Innovative FinanceUnit (CFPMI) were added to CFPVP. In 2006, Phillippe Le Houerou succeeded Geoffrey Lamb as Vice President for CFPVP. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 2008, the GPP and the TFO were merged to create the new Global Partnerships and Trust Fund Operations Department (CFPTO). CFPTO was assigned two subordinate units: the Global Partnership and Trust Fund Policy Unit (PTP) and the Program Administration and Management Unit (PAM).
<lb/>
<lb/>In 2009, Axel van Trotsenburg succeeded Phillippe Le Houerou as Vice President for CFPVP. Around this time, the CFPVP was reorganized into the following subordinate units: IDA Resource Mobilization (CFPIR); the Global Partnerships and Trust Fund Operations (CFPTO); and the Multilateral Trusteeship and Innovative Financing (CFPMI). 
<lb/>
<lb/>In 2012, Joachim von Amsberg succeeded Axel van Trotsenburg as Vice President for CFPVP. 
<lb/>
<lb/>In July 2014, the CFPVP was terminated and replaced by the new Development Finance Vice Presidency (DFIVP). 
<lb/>
<lb/>The Development Finance Vice Presidency (DFIVP) absorbed the IDA replenishment, trust fund, and cofinancing related functions of the former CFPVP. It additionally absorbed functions related to IBRD capital monitoring, planning, and management from the former Vice President of Corporate Finance and Risk Management (CFRVP). The DFIVP includes the following subordinate units: the Development Finance Resource Mobilization Department (DFiRM); the Development Partner Relations Department (DFDPR); the Trust Funds and Partnerships Department (DFPTF); and the IBRD Corporate Finance Department (DFICF). Joachim von Amsberg serves as Vice President for DFIVP.</p>
      </note>
    </bioghist>
    <odd type="publicationStatus">
      <p>Published</p>
    </odd>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="3.3.1">
      <p>Records of the VP Front Office 
<lb/>
<lb/>The fonds includes Front Office records for the following vice presidents: Teruyuki Ohuchi, Vice President of Cofinancing (VPCOF) from 1982 to 1986; Kunihiko Inakage, VPCOF/COFVP from 1986 to 1989; Koji Kashiwaya, Vice President of Cofinancing and Financial Advisory Services (CFSVP) from 1989 to 1994; and Hiroo Fukui, CFSVP and Vice President of Resource Mobilization and Cofinancing (RMCVP) from 1994 to 1999. The records include incoming and outgoing chronological correspondence files for each vice president. The records also consist of subject files, including correspondence, internal memoranda, and reports related to the functions, activities, and administration of the VPCOF, CFSVP, and the RMCVP. The records also include external liaison records consisting of: travel arrangement records; briefing books; back-to-office reports; Terms of Reference; and meeting minute and agenda records for liaison with donors or other external organizations. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Budget and planning 
<lb/>
<lb/>The fonds includes budget, work program, and business plan records for the Vice President of Cofinancing (VPCOF), the Vice President of Cofinancing and Financial Advisory Services (CFSVP), and the Vice President of Resource Mobilization and Cofinancing (RMCVP) from 1987 to 1999. These records contain: correspondence; monthly budget reports; mid-year review reports; task budget reports; equipment budget reports; budget guidelines; prospective budget summaries; accrual and charges budget reports; reports regarding staffing and recruitment; work programs by unit; VP strategic compact summaries; and VP business plans. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Records of Cofinancing directors, advisers, and staff
<lb/>
<lb/>The fonds consists of records of cofinancing directors, managers, advisers, and senior level staff who served in the front office or in higher level roles in the Senior Vice President of Operations (SVPOP), the Vice President of Cofinancing (VPCOF/COFVP), the Vice President of Cofinancing and Financial Advisory Services (CFSVP), and the Vice President of Resource Mobilization and Cofinancing (RMCVP) from 1981 to 1996. The records include incoming and outgoing correspondence, memoranda, and reports that cover an extensive range of cofinancing related topics, programs, functions, and activities. Records are included for the following directors, managers, and advisers: Frank Vibert, Senior Adviser of Cofinancing for SVPOP and VPCOF from 1981 to 1987; Waman S. Tambe, Cofinancing Adviser Export Credit Agencies of VPCOF/COFVP and CFSVP from 1984 to 1991; John Shilling, Economic Adviser of VPCOF and Manager of the Financial Advisory Services Group (CFSFA) from 1985 to 1991; Sanjivi Rajasingham, Adviser of North American Resources for the Private Cofinancing Group (CFSPC) from 1988 to 1990; John Taylor, Manager of the Cofinancing Group (CFSCO) from 1989 to 1991; Ibrahim Elwa, Manager of the Private Sector Development Group (CFSPS) from 1990 to 1991; Kenichi Ohashi, Adviser to CFSVP from 1989 to 1991; John Niehuss, Director of CFSVP from 1990 to 1991; Inder Sud, Director of CFSVP from 1992 to 1995; Rom Chopra, Director CFSVP and later Cofinancing and Project Finance Department (CAP) from 1995 to 1996; Anthony Toft, Financial Adviser of CFSFA from 1990 to 1991; Salem Gafsi, Manager of the Official Cofinancing and Trust Funds Group (CFSOC) from 1990 to 1992; Kyung Soon Sung, Adviser to CFSVP from 1991 to 1995; and Ulrich Kiermayr, Cofinancing Adviser for Official Aid Agencies of VPCOF/COFVP and CFSVP from 1982 to 1992. Similar records are also included for other senior level cofinancing advisers and financial officers, including: Jamil Saghir, 1990 to 1994; Gian Spota, 1990-1992; Ulrich Zachau, 1989 to 1993; John Bowlin, 1986 to 1992; M. Fedder, 1990 to 1991; Hortensia Hill, 1985 to 1990; Christina Kappaz, 1992 to 1994; and Fredrick Schwartz, 1990 to 1992. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Operational cofinancing support
<lb/>
<lb/>The fonds includes records related to the CFSVP's various subordinate units responsible for operational support of cofinancing related to projects in the Bank's regional departmentsfrom 1989 to 1995. This includes operational support in the areas of: official and private sector cofinancing; technical support and advisory services to regions in country debt management and restructuring; privatization; and private sector development. The records are related to the development of projects initiated by the CFSVP and Bank regional departments. The records focus on the following phases of project development: identification, pre-appraisal, appraisal, project preparation, and negotiation.The records include: project-related documents; correspondence; appraisal reports; back-to-office reports of CFSVP units and regional departments; copies of loan or credit agreements; internal memoranda; correspondence with member governments, consultants, and other external sources; and briefing notes. 
<lb/>
<lb/>Cofinancing conferences, seminars, and training workshops 
<lb/>
<lb/>This fonds includes records related to cofinancing related conferences, seminars, and training workshops organized or attended by staff from theVice President of Cofinancing (VPCOF) and its successor the Vice President of Cofinancing and Financial Advisory Services (CFSVP) from 1987 to 1996. The records include: staff papers, speeches, and publications; teaching materials used at seminars and conferences; information concerning externally sponsored events; research projects and studies undertaken by cofinancing staff, including drafts and final versions along with staff comments; cofinancing publications; informational brochures; and leaflets.
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>Cofinancing arrangement and administration 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The fonds includes records related to the various types of cofinancing arrangements, programs, and projects of the Vice President of Cofinancing (VPCOF), the Cofinancing and Financial Advisory Services Vice Presidency (CFSVP), and the Resource Mobilization and Cofinancing Vice Presidency (RMCVP). 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>This includes records related to the establishment and maintenance of cofinancing arrangements between the Bank and official cofinanciers (e.g. bilateral government agencies, multilateral development agencies, and multilateral development banks). The records were maintained by the following responsible units: the VPCOF from 1984 to 1989; the Official Cofinancing Group (CFSOC) of CFSVP from 1989 to 1992; the Official Cofinancing and Trust Fund Management Group (CFSOC) of CFSVP from 1992 to 1996; the Official Cofinancing and Trust Funds Group (CAPOC) of the RMCVP from 1996 to 1998; and the Trust Fund and Cofinancing Department (TFC) of RMCVP from 1998 to 1999. The records include files arranged by region, country, or official cofinancing agency related to projects cofinanced by the Bank and an official cofinancier. Each file may contain: correspondence between official cofinanciers and Bank staff; internal memoranda; briefing notes for meetings with official cofinanciers; background records related to cofinanced projects; Cofinancing Framework Agreements or Loan Agreements for cofinanced projects; records related to consultation meetings with official cofinanciers; back-to-office reports; Terms of Reference; lists of potential official cofinancing projects; and records related to meetings with a country's Executive Director or Finance Minister related to proposed cofinanced projects. The official cofinancing records also include official cofinancing seminar records, training materials, and publications related to official cofinancing. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The records also consist of materials related to the establishment and maintenance of export credit agency (ECAs) cofinancing arrangements of the VPCOF and successor units of the Financial Advisory Services Group (CFSFA) and the Project Financing Group (CFSPF) of CFSVP from 1984 to 1993. The records consist of correspondence, meeting minutes and agenda, and reports related to liaison and relationships with export credit agencies in various member countries. More specifically, the records include: correspondence and reports of the major export credit agencies of various member countries; correspondence and reports of umbrella organizations such as the Berne Union, the Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD), and the European Commission (EC); correspondence and reports detailing IBRD policies in regard to ECAs; funding requests, creditor reports, project reports, and reports on debt; offers by ECAs to provide financing for projects; information on various financial instruments, most notably the Export Credit Enhanced Leverage (EXCEL) program. The records also include agenda, minutes, and reports from the bi-annual meetingof the ECAs. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The records also include project finance transaction records of the VPCOF as well as successor units CFSFA and CFSPF located in CFSVP from 1984 to 1995. The records are related to private cofinancing arrangements (e.g. commercial banks), and management of privately cofinanced projects, primarily infrastructure and private sector development projects. The records include: internal memoranda; internal and external reports related to a project; project documents; consultant reports and documents; Procurement Technical Notes (PTN); copies of project cofinancing agreements and other legal documents; operations policy statements related to cofinancing procurement; procurement guidelines; back-to-office reports; Terms of Reference; records related to meetings with private cofinanciers and member countries; correspondence between Bank staff and private cofinanciers; and consultation meeting records with private cofinanciers and member countries. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>Lastly, records relate to CFSFA's and CFSPF's involvement in negotiating and administering debt reduction programs for member countries from 1988 to 1996. The records consists of: correspondence between the member country government asking for assistance, and the formal response from IBRD; an initiating memoranda from the Region to the Regional VP, with background information; a presentation to the Board of Executive Directors requesting a technical assistance grant; procurement records for legal and financial advisors; grant agreement from the Board; mission reports; back-to-office reports; report from the government, based on the technical assistance mission, on restructuring debt; CFSFA and CFSPF meetings and correspondence with donors to negotiate funding; report to the Executive Directors Board to obtain IBRD funding; member country offering to its creditors and the creditors' responses; all required legal records between the government, creditors and IBRD; and a final audit report of the debt restructuring. 
<lb/>
<lb/>      
<lb/>
<lb/>Cofinancing policy development and research
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The fonds includes records of the Financial Advisory Services Group (CFSFA) and its successor the Project Financing Group (CFSPF) of the CFSVP related to their involvement in the development and research of Bank Group policies and procedures on various cofinancing topics. The records include: internal correspondence and memoranda; draft operational policies and bank procedures; background research materials; back-to-office reports; Terms of Reference; working papers; studies; and papers and memoranda prepared for the Board of Executive Directors. The records cover a wide range of topics, including: capital markets; Expanded Cofinancing Operations (ECO); Guarantee Policies and Procedures; the Export Credit Enhanced Leverage (EXCEL) Program; the IDA Debt Reduction Facility; the Portfolio Management Task Force (Wapenhans Committee); Private Sector Development; and Trust Funds Management Working Group.
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>Records of the Office of the Director of the Resource Mobilization Department (FRMDR)
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The fonds includes the records of the Office of the Director for the Resource Mobilization Department (FRMDR) from 1987 to 2006. This includes records maintained by the following FRM Directors: Bavil Kavalasky 1987 to 1992; Paula Donovan 1993 to 1998; Geoffrey Lamb 1999 to 2002; and Philippe Le Houerou from 2003 to 2006. The records of the FRMDR include incoming and outgoing chronological correspondence for each director. The records also contain subject files consisting of correspondence, internal memoranda, papers, and reports related to the FRM functions and activities, Bank institutional policies and activities, and other departmental matters. Subject files cover a wide variety of topics, including some the following: multilateral development banks (MDBs); export credit agencies (ECAs); external grants; technical assistance; the Gulf Crisis; the Brandt Commission; the Future Role of the Bank Task Force; proposals on the World Bank's Bank; the Bank's 50th Anniversary; the Fifth Dimension Program; IBRD capital adequacy; General Capital Increase (GCI); Special Capital Increase (SCI); IBRD accounting; commitment fees; disbursements; communications with Executive Directors and the Office of the President (EXC); papers prepared for the Board of Executive Directors; factors affecting IDA; the Global Environment Facility (GEF); Maintenance of Value (MOV); the Paris Club; IDA replenishments; IDA Reflows; the Wapenhans Report; African debt; Annual Meetings; IDA foreign exchange; and exposure management.
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>IDA replenishment administration 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The fonds includes records created in the administration and support of IDA Replenishment negotiations. The IDA replenishment records were maintained by the following units: the Financial Analysis Division (PABFA) of the Programming and Budgeting Department (PAB); the Financial Studies Division (FPAFS) of the Financial Policy and Analysis Department (FPA); the Replenishment Operations Unit (FRMRO) of the Resource Mobilization Department (FRM); and the IDA Resource Mobilization Department (CFPIR). The records cover IDA2 to IDA15 Replenishment negotiations from 1966 to 2009. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The records include materials prepared to help facilitate IDA replenishment negotiations, including: memoranda prepared for the Executive Directors, IDA Deputies, the Bank President, and senior staff related to IDA replenishment negotiations; policy and discussion papers prepared for meetings with the Bank's Board of Executive Directors, the Board of Governors, and IDA Deputies, which cover numerous topics such as burden sharing, sectoral programs, country allocations, additions to IDA, IDA reflows, IDA Arrears, etc; draft reports and resolutions for IDA replenishment; implementation arrangement reports related to procedures for IDA replenishment; and briefing books prepared for Deputies Meetings for IDA Replenishments. The records also include: background papers on past IDA negotiations; notice of IDA meeting announcements; list of IDA Deputies; memoranda, correspondence, and technical notes that summarize IDA Deputies meeting discussions; chairman reports from the IDA Deputies meetings; minutes and agenda of IDA Deputies meetings; transcripts and audio-cassette recordings of IDA Deputies meetings; and records related to informal meetings with IDA Deputies. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The IDA replenishment records also includes voting rights, capital subscription, donor contributions, encashment, commitment, legal, accounting, and IDA reflow records produced as a result of IDA replenishment negotiations, and subsequent implementation of IDA replenishment resources. Specifically, the records include: IDA voting rights and power records, which include reports, memoranda, and Board papers on the review and adjustment of IDA members voting rights and power after each replenishment, changes to voting rights and power, legal background, current voting rights system, proposals, discussion notes, and voting rights and power of smaller countries; monthly commitment authority reports, which include introductory memoranda and tables showing the status of IDA contributions and resources available for commitment; IDA donor subscription correspondence; IDA subscription and accounting records, including letters from the Bank requesting note deposits for installment payments, vouchers, note substitution requests, copies of promissory notes, letters and telexes acknowledging receipt of non-negotiable promissory notes, cash receipts regarding note encashment, notification of transfer of funds, and accounting ledgers; IDA call letters, notifications, and encashment records, which include correspondence, call letters requesting release of funds for IDA note encashment, projections and schedule tables of encashment contributions, and letters to IDA countries notifying them of overdue payments and quarterly calls; IDA reflows reports; IDA disbursement projections reports; mid-year reports on IDA replenishments; and subscription history of IDA members.
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The records also includes materials related to the establishment and replenishment negotiations of the global programs of the Special Facility for Africa (SFA) and the Global Environment Facility (GEF). The SFA records include materials maintained by FPAFS of FPA, and FRMRO of FRM from 1985 to 1989. SFA records include: drafts and copies of the resolution of the Executive Directors of the IDA on the Establishment of the SFA from 1985; technical notes prepared for senior staff related to SFA issues; donor meeting minutes, agenda, opening remarks, and summaries of donor meetings; Chairman reports for SFA donor meetings; records related to donor contributions to SFA; SFA press communiques; records related to guidelines and procedures for SFA; IDA8 replenishment negotiations records related to SFA; background papers on SFA grant recipient countries; copies of cofinancing agreements with donor countries for SFA; proposals to extend SFA; SFA quarterly financial statements; SFA progress reports; SFA publications; calls and notifications regarding encashment of funds for SFA; requests for payments; SFA disbursement reports; SFA projection tables; Board papers submitted to the Board of Executive Directors requesting termination of SFA; correspondence and memoranda related to termination of the SFA in 1989; and Board of Executive Directors meeting minutes and agenda regarding SFA. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>Records related to the establishment and replenishment negotiations of the Global Environment Facility (GEF) maintained by the FRMRO of FRM are also included for the years 1989 to 1999. The GEF records include: copies of Board papers; discussionpapers; reports and memoranda related to funding for GEF; talking points for meetings on the environment; reports on discussions at Board meetings related to the environment; transcripts of GEF meetings; and agenda and meeting minutes. Specific topics of the records cover natural gas, forestry, the Montreal Protocol, technical assistance for the environment, and funding for GEF. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>IDA country strategy development and advisement 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The fonds consists of records dating from 1987 to 1997 that relate to the Resource Mobilization Department's (FRM) involvement in the development of country strategies. This involved advising the Bank's Operations Committee and senior staff on country strategies. The records contain: policy framework papers; Board papers, including IDA Board papers on technical assistance; country strategy papers; briefings for meetings of the President's Council; reports on sector adjustment operations; progress reports on sector adjustment credits; IMF reports; and credit and project progressreports.
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>Third Window feasibility, projections, and analysis
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>In 1975, the Bank launched the Intermediate Financing Facility ("Third Window"), an interest subsidy fund created to mobilize and leverage limited concessional funds from donors. This fund was created due to constrained availability of lending and donor resources prompted by the 1970s oil crisis. The fonds includes records related to the original "Third Window", and feasibility studies, projections, and analysis for a second "Third Window" fund. The records were maintained by the Replenishment Policy Division (FRMRP) of the Resource Mobilization Department (FRM) from 1987 to 1996 (background records are also included from the 1960s to the 1980s). The records are related to the projections and analysis of the feasibility of a third window lending. The records include: background records related to the first Intermediate Financing Facility ("Third Window") launched in the 1970s; draft reports with comments; final reports; copies of Executive Director Board papers; computer printouts; projection tables; internal memoranda; and other internal communications regarding projections and analysis of the feasibility of a third window lending to provide funds on terms and conditions between the near market terms for IBRD funds and the concessional terms for IDA funds.
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>Trust fund program management and support 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The fonds includes records related to the life cycle (establishment, implementation, evaluation, and financial management) of trust fund programs. The trust funds were managed by the followings units: the Vice President of Cofinancing (VPCOF) from 1984 to 1989; the Official Cofinancing Group (CFSOC) of CFSVP from 1989 to 1992; the Official Cofinancing and Trust Fund Management Group (CFSOC) of CFSVP from 1992 to 1996; the Official Cofinancing and Trust Funds Group (CAPOC) from 1996 to 1998 of the RMCVP; the Trust Fund and Cofinancing Department (TFC) of RMCVP from 1998 to 2001; the Trust Funds Operations Department (TFO), the Trust Fund Strategy and Donor Relations Department (TFS), and the Global Partnership Programs (GPP) of RMCVP and the CFPVP from 2001 to 2008; and the Global Partnerships and Trust Fund Operations (CFPTO) of the CFPVP from 2008 to 2010. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The records include management and support records maintained by the program managers and administrators of various trust fund programs. Included are trust fund program management records of grants for the Consultant Trust Fund (CTF) Program, the Policy and Human Resource Development (PHRD) Fund, Global Partnership Programs (e.g. Development GrantFacility [DGF]), and other special trust fund programs. The majority of the trust fund records focus on the technical assistance trust fund programs of PHRD and CTF, and the global program and partnership trust fund of DGF. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The records of the Policy and Human Resources Development (PHRD) Fund (formerly the Japanese Grant Facility) include correspondence, reports, legal, and financial management records related to PHRD grants. The PHRD records were maintained by VPCOF, CFSOC, CAPOC, TFC, and TFO from 1984 to 2006. The records generally include specific PHRD project implementation files consisting of the following types of records: correspondence between the Bank and the Government of Japan; PHRD technical assistance funding proposals; PHRD implementation reports; contract for consultant services; Terms of Reference; Japanese grant agreements with grant recipient country; correspondence with the Regional departments regarding implementation and disbursement; policies and guidelines related to PHRD grants; records related to monitoring of compliance with the grant terms; and records of quarterly PHRD Fund Tranche budgets. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The records also consist of material related to the management and support of trust fund grants of the Consultant Trust Fund (CTF) Program maintained by VPCOF, CFSOC, CAPOC, TFC, and TFO from 1974 to 2006 (predominantly 1985 to 2006). The records include correspondence, reports, legal, and financial records between the World Bank, participating donor countries, and the grant recipient. The CTF records generally include country files with the following types of records: Initiating Briefs for Trust Funds (IBTF); Cofinancing Framework Agreements; CTF Agreements; Memoranda of Understanding between the Bank and donor country; the CTF funding request from Regional Division Chiefs; Terms of Reference; back to office reports; terms and conditions of the grant; briefing notes prepared for donor countries; letters of appointment; reports to the donors describing the disbursement of funds; list of CTF allocations; internal reports on each trust fund; daily reports on each trust fund; semi-annual and annual donor consultation reports; mid-year reports; evaluation reports; agenda and meeting minutes for semi-annual and annual donor consultation meetings; financial reconciliation reports; CTF pledges and cash receipts; CTF grant entries for the Grant Reporting and Monitoring System (GRMS); requests for consultants; lists of consultants; guidelinesand policies for CTF grants; and CTF summary reports for earmarked uses of trust funds. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The records also include material related to the Development Grant Facility (DGF) maintained by TFC and its successor TFO from 1985 to 2006 (predominantly 1997 to 2006; some reference records predate establishment of DGF in 1997). The DGF records include: records related to the strategy and procedures of the DGF; DGF publications; DGF Council meeting records, which include minutes, agenda, and discussion notes; records prepared for or part of meeting with the Bank's Board of Executive Directors, including Board papers, discussion notes, minutes, agenda, technical briefings, and Memoranda to Executive Directors for Annual Review of DGF; records related to meetings with the Bank's Network vice presidencies focused on proposed grants for sector partnerships and projects; records related to DGF eligibility criteria; legal agreements for DGF grant programs and projects; DGF procurement guidelines; records related to meetings of the Special Grant Committee for the Special Grants Facility Program; DGF unallocated funds, savings, carryovers, overruns, and underrun budget reports; DGF statistical tables; DGF budget and expense reports; records related to donor coordination; and records related to DGF major issues. The records also include review and evaluation records of the DGF, including: records related to internal evaluations from the Bank's Operations Evaluation Department (OED) and the Internal Audit Department (IAD); annual review reports of DGF; review, evaluation, and monitoring reports of grant programs and projects of DGF; mid-term and retrospective reviews of DGF; and individual progress, completion and audit reports on individual grants. The records also include copies of parent level entries for proposed Bank-Foundation Partnership grants of the DGF entered as part of the Partnership Approval Tracking System (PATS) database. The entries consist of basic data on each proposed grant, and are arranged by sector, region, or alphabetically by donor foundation. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The records also include IBTF clearance and revision records maintained by the CAPOC, TFC, and TFO for regional, Global Partnership Programs (GPPs), multi-donor, and other ad hoc trust fund programs from 1997 to 2005. The records include: drafts and final copies of IBTF documents; copies of trust fund agreements; and IBTF clearance memoranda with comments and revision input from CAPOC, TFC, TFO Clearance Officers, and staff in the Bank's legal, accounting, and Regional departments.
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>The records also consist of trust fund review, monitoring, and reporting records maintained by the Trust Fund Management Oversight Unit (TFMOU) and the Trust Fund Monitoring and Reporting Unit (TFMRU) of CAPOC, TFC, and TFO from 1996 to 2004. TFMOU records primarily include: portfolio status and IBTF review case files for regional trust fund projects; IBTF monthly summary reports; IBTF clearance reports; strategy papers; presentations prepared for donor conferences on trust fund monitoring and reporting; briefing books, minutes, and agenda records for donor meetings; and case and review reports for trust fund grant projects and programs. The TFMRU records include those related to the procedures and guidelines for trust fund review documents of the Implementation Completion Memorandum (ICM) and Implementation Completion Reports (ICR) and records of received ICMs and ICRs for reviewed trust fund grant projects.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="3.3.4">
      <p>The following arrangement is provisional. Records are arranged into twelve series:
<lb/>
<lb/>*	Records of the VP Front Office
<lb/>
<lb/>*	Budget and planning 
<lb/>
<lb/>*	Records of cofinancing directors, advisers, and staff
<lb/>
<lb/>*	Operational cofinancing support
<lb/>
<lb/>*	Cofinancing conferences, seminars, and training workshops
<lb/>
<lb/>*	Cofinancing arrangement and administration
<lb/>
<lb/>*	Cofinancing policy development and research
<lb/>
<lb/>*	Records of the Office of the Director of the Resource Mobilization Department (FRMDR)
<lb/>
<lb/>*	IDA replenishment administration
<lb/>
<lb/>*	IDA country strategy development and advisement
<lb/>
<lb/>*	Third Window feasibility, projections, and analysis
<lb/>
<lb/>*	Trust fund program management and support</p>
    </arrangement>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="3.2.4">
      <p>Records were transferred to the Archives using approved records retention and disposition schedules assigned to the units of: the Financial Analysis Division (PABFA); the Vice President of Cofinancing (VPCOF/COFVP); the Vice President of Resource Mobilization and Cofinancing (RMCVP); the Vice President of Cofinancing and Financial Advisory Services (CFSVP); and the Concessional Finance and Global Partnerships Vice Presidency (CFPVP).</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <accruals encodinganalog="3.3.3">
      <p>Accruals are expected.</p>
    </accruals>
    <processinfo>
      <p>
        <date>1 December 2015</date>
      </p>
    </processinfo>
    <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="3.5.3">
      <p>*	For records related to the Operations Complex, which cofinancing related units were part of from 1975 to 1992, see Records of the Senior Vice President of Operations ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_106](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-senior-vice-president-of-operations)).
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>*	For records related to the Senior Vice President of Finance (SVPFI/FINSV) and Chief Financial Officer (CFO), which many of the resource mobilization related units reported to, see Records of the Chief Financial Officer ([WB IBRD/IDA CFO](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-chief-financial-officer)).
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>*	See also Records of the Office of Operations Policy ([WB IBRD/IDA OP](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-office-of-operations-policy)) for additional records related to the Operations Complex.
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>* See Financial Policy, Planning, and Budgeting ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_110](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/financial-policy-planning-and-budgeting)) fonds for records relating to World Bank resource allocation and managing the Bank's strategic capital adequacy with respect to IBRD capital subscription. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>* See Records of the Population, Health, and Nutrition Sector - Grant and trust fund management ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_89-05](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/grant-and-trust-fund-management-2)) for records related to managing and monitoring grants to partnership programs and activities in the HNP sector. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>* See Records of the Education Sector - Grant and trust fund management ([WBIBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_88-06](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/grant-and-trust-fund-management)) for records related to managing and monitoring grants to partnership programs and activities in the education sector. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>* See Records of the Energy Sector - UNDP/World Bank Energy Sector Programs management and donor coordination ([WB IBRD/IDA ENGY-01](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/undp-world-bank-energy-sector-programs-management-and-donor-coordination)) for related trust fund records concerningESMAP. Also see Records of the Energy Sector - Liaison, partnerships and program collaboration ([WB IBRD/IDA ENGY-06](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/liaison-partnerships-and-program-collaboration)) for trust fund management records of other activities in the energy (power, oil, gas) sector. 
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>*	For records of Geoffrey Lamb in positions prior to his roles in cofinancing and trust funds operations, see Records of individual staff members -- Geoffrey Lamb files ([WB IBRD/IDA STAFF-25](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/geoffrey-lamb-files)).
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>*	See the Oral History Program website for interviews with former staff that discuss topics of resource mobilization. Specifically, see the interviews of [Geoffrey B. Lamb](http://oralhistory.worldbank.org/person/lamb-geoffrey-b), [Alexander Shakow](http://oralhistory.worldbank.org/person/shakow-alexander), [Luis Machado](http://oralhistory.worldbank.org/person/machado-luis), and [Sir Denis H.F. Rickett](http://oralhistory.worldbank.org/person/rickett-sir-denis-h-f).
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>*	See Records of Private Sector Development Sector ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_100](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-private-sector-development-sector)) for records and administrative history related to the Private Sector Development and Privatization Group (CFSPS), which was transferred to the Private Sector Development (PSD) Department in 1996.
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>*	See Records of the Finance and Private Sector Development Vice Presidency ([WB IBRD/IDA WB_IBRD/IDA_102](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-finance-and-private-sector-development-vice-presidency)) for additional records and administrative history for CFSPS.
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>*	See Records of the Global Environment Facility ([WB IBRD/IDA GEF](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/records-of-global-environment-facility)) for records related to this trust fund program.
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>
<lb/>* See Records of the Water Sector -- Partnerships and program collaboration ([WB IBRD/IDA WAT-02](https://archivesholdings.worldbank.org/partnerships-and-program-collaboration-3)) for records related to trust fund program management on water initiatives.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="3.4.1">
      <p>Records are subject to the World Bank Policy on Access to Information.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="3.4.2">
      <p>Records are subject to the Copyright Policy of the World Bank Group.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <dsc type="combined">

        
        
  </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
