<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-txsmtsu" url="urn:taro:tsusm.00007">urn:taro:tsusm.00007</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Billy Lee Brammer Papers</titleproper><author>Gwynedd Cannan</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>The Wittliff Collections</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://alkek.library.txstate.edu/images/WC.png" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><date era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1993</date><address><addressline>601 University Drive</addressline><addressline>San Marcos, Texas 78666</addressline><addressline>Wittliff_Ref@txstate.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-07-28 16:57:59 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>2004</date><item>Inventory revised.</item></change><change><date>2021</date><item>Revised for ArchivesSpace by Susannah Broyles.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <head>Collection Summary</head>
    <repository encodinganalog="852$a">
      <extref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:type="simple" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu/">
      <corpname>The Wittliff Collections</corpname></extref>
    </repository>
    <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Billy Lee Brammer Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname encodinganalog="100" authfilenumber="n79133738" source="lcnaf">Brammer, Billy Lee</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="US" repositorycode="US-txsmtsu">SWWC.007</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole" encodinganalog="300$a">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 Linear Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="whole" encodinganalog="300$a">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3  boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1946/1993" type="inclusive">1946-1993</unitdate>
    <physloc id="aspace_a920d3c4224509be1620aa77b88f82af">Materials may be stored off-site. Advance notice is required for use: <extref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:type="simple" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href = 'https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu/research/makearesearchappointment.html'>https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu/research/makearesearchappointment.html.</extref></physloc>
    <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" id="aspace_247e9c62c2a2173b9cfe4f7ed63c0564">The Billy Lee Brammer Papers document his writing career (including <emph render="italic">The Gay Place</emph> and its' unfinished sequel <emph render="italic">Faustian Days</emph>) along with various articles.</abstract>
    <langmaterial encodinganalog="546$a">
      <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506" id="aspace_9e9290434a67b00e27abdf933ae6924c">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
    <p>Collection is open for research.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="aspace_3c252e75f09cb9148ec9c8be43e77148">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
    <p>Donations by William Broyles, Nadine Eckhardt, Sidney Brammer, Bill Wittliff, Bud Shrake, and Paul Cullum.  Some items were purchased.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo encodinganalog="583">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
    <p>Processing information not available.</p>
  </processinfo>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="545" id="aspace_0e9c4b9fef8088c118ca3a4aed8c5e99">
    <head>Biographical Notes</head>
<p>Billy Lee Brammer was born April 21, 1929, in Dallas, Texas.   He graduated from North Texas State College in 1952 with a degree in journalism.  Brammer was a reporter for the <emph render='italic'>Corpus Christi Caller Times</emph> and the <emph render='italic'>Austin Statesman</emph>, where he won a press award for excellence in writing in 1952.  In 1954, he won the Texas Associated Press Managing Editors Contest for a feature sports story written for the same paper (newly titled the <emph render='italic'>Austin American-Statesman</emph>).  As the <emph render='italic'>Statesman</emph> reported in its January 10, 1954 issue, the prize-winning story was written in Brammer's "usual unusual style."</p>
 
<p>In 1955, Brammer became an associate editor of the <emph render='italic'>Texas Observer</emph>, a magazine of liberal dissent at a time when in Texas "the impulse for dissent scarcely existed" (<emph render='italic'>Texas Observer</emph>, August 25, 1961).  There he attracted the attention of Texas Senator Lyndon Baines Johnson, who invited him to join his staff.  While employed by Johnson in Washington, D.C., Brammer began working on his first and only published novel, <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph>.  The book was published by Houghton Mifflin in 1961 to wide critical acclaim.</p>
 
<p><emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph> (reissued by Texas Monthly Press in 1978 and by Vintage Press in 1984) is where Brammer's literary reputation rests.  The book consists of three novellas, all revolving around politics, all dominated by the larger than life, omniscient, manipulative Governor Arthur Fenstemaker.  Brammer told friends Fenstemaker was a composite, but the character is largely reminiscent of Lyndon Baines Johnson.  Willie Morris calls <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph> a "symphony of politics and sex and ambition and the immense Texas landscape [that] remains the great authentic modern novel we have yet of the state"  (<emph render='italic'>Texas Observer</emph>, Mar 3, 1978).</p>
 
<p>In 1959, after the still-unfinished <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph> had been bought by Houghton Mifflin, Brammer left Johnson's staff to work for the economist Eliot Janeway.  <emph render='italic'>Time</emph> hired him in 1960 to cover civil rights issues from the magazine's Atlanta office.  Brammer quit the <emph render='italic'>Time</emph> job in 1961 and thereafter never held sustained employment.  He began a sequel to <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph> titled <emph render='italic'>Fustian Days</emph>, but it was never completed.  Though he did write several articles, Brammer never followed up the promise of his first book.  Several reasons have been put forth for his writing block: disappointment at being barred from access to Johnson, who was displeased with <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph>; the overwhelming success of his first novel; and drug abuse.  Brammer at one point gave his own explanation in a letter dated August 23, 1968 to Larry L. King - the problem was "getting hanged-up with attempts at over-perfection, compounded by uptight-making realization that [one] is really on [one's] own and has to be-god-effing mother produce as fulltime free-lance typewriter fella." (King Papers, The Wittliff Collections)</p>
 
<p>Various friends tried to help Brammer produce again.  Fellow Texan and writer Larry L. King lobbied magazine editors into giving Brammer assignments.  Texas columnist Jay Milner hired him as a journalism professor at Southern Methodist University in 1969 and then got him a position as a writer-in-residence at Bowling Green.  William Broyles signed him on as a contributing editor for <emph render='italic'>Texas Monthly</emph>.  In 1976, Brammer's former wife, Nadine Eckhardt, asked him to help her write a memoir.  Brammer took these offers in earnest, but after an initial spurt of activity he always drifted off.  He held numerous other jobs for short periods of time, among them rock and roll promoter, dishwasher, and cook. </p>
 
<p>Those who knew Brammer remember him fondly and with admiration.  Filmmaker Robert Benton testified, "Bill was one of the most charming, charismatic people I've ever met in my life.  And he could talk about anything … "(<emph render='italic'>Austin Chronicle</emph>, March 26, 1993).  Jay Milner, in his syndicated newspaper column, portrayed Brammer as having been a "soft-spoken, gently lecherous, incredibly widely read, avid rock aficionado, ultimately rather seedy bon vivant, neurotic little man  ("Remembering Billy Lee Brammer, a man of the Sixties" 1993).  Willie Morris reminisced that he was "kind, unselfish, and giving of the things he knew - a sweet, gentle man, a teller of stories who never knew how to attitudinize" (<emph render='italic'>Texas Observer</emph>, Mar 3, 1978).  Brammer, tongue-in-cheek, did his own summing up in 1976:  "Bestowed from birth with a lucy-in-the sky twinkle and irreverence for everything, Brammer bounced around the sub-culture after leaving LBJ, writing unfinished masterpieces by the score, ingesting hogsheads of drugs and acquiring a local image as the best approximation of guru and human wonder around" (Brammer Papers, The Wittliff Collections).</p>
 
<p>Brammer married Nadine Ellen Cannon (Nadine Eckhardt) on April 22, 1950 while both were students at North Texas State College.  They had three children, Sidney Gail, Shelby Ellen, and William Raoul.  The two were divorced in 1961.  In 1963, Brammer married Dorothy Brown; they were divorced in 1969.  Brammer died of a drug overdose on February 11, 1978.</p>
  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent encodinganalog="520$b" id="aspace_0ddb0a9a917f33241e912bc3c45d9bee">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The archive contains book manuscripts, newspaper clippings, tear sheets, correspondence, photographs, and Brammer's high school baseball uniform pants.  Included in the collection are the typed manuscripts of <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph>, and the unfinished sequel to that work, <emph render='italic'>Fustian Days</emph>; newspaper and magazine articles written by Brammer; reviews for <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph>; and letters which describe Brammer's tenure as a Johnson staff member, his marriage to Nadine Eckhardt, and his writing.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <prefercite encodinganalog="524" id="aspace_c38d0ae218985abd1b15698438b8d7e0">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Billy Lee Brammer Papers, The Wittliff Collections, Texas State University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="aspace_8c7a2cfc4656ab0a940034b79296216b">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Materials from the Wittliff Collections are made available for use in research, teaching, and private study.  The user assumes responsibility for determining copyright status, obtaining permission to publish, and abiding by U.S. copyright laws. <extref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:type="simple" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href ='https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu/research/visit/policies/publication.html'>https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu/research/visit/policies/publication.html</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1" id="aspace_df81fb2fd1433d28accb11110be34adf">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>See the Nadine Eckhardt Papers (Collection 105).</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess><controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Political fiction, American</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh88002586" source="lcsh">Authors' spouses</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Authors, American -- Texas -- 20th century</subject>
    <persname authfilenumber="n79133738" source="lcnaf">Brammer, Billy Lee</persname>
    <persname authfilenumber="n2008039633" source="lcnaf">Eckhardt, Nadine, 1931-</persname>
  </controlaccess></controlaccess>
  <dsc type="in-depth"><c01 id="aspace_8086" level="series"><did><unittitle>Writings</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1959/1963" type="inclusive">1959-1963</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c682b2c399e9d3763861fda3645cc34b"><head>Series Description</head><p>This series contains Brammer's typed manuscripts of <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph> and the unfinished novel, <emph render='italic'>Fustian Days</emph>. Both manuscripts are a gift from William Broyles, the first editor of <emph render='italic'>Texas Monthly</emph>, who admired Brammer, hired him to write for the magazine, and encouraged him to write consistently again. <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph> manuscript is followed by the play adaptation, <emph render='italic'>Come and Join the Dance</emph>, by Brammer's daughters, Sidney and Shelby.  Included are Brammer's two <emph render='italic'>Texas Observer</emph> articles:  a tear sheet about the <emph render='italic'>Observer</emph> editor, Ronnie Dugger, from the August 25, 1961, issue; and the January 10, 1963 edition, which contains Brammer's <emph render='italic'>Glooey</emph>, a satire of the Kennedy White House based on J. D. Salinger's <emph render='italic'>Frannie and Zooey</emph>.  There is also a file of Brammer's jottings - a 1965 interview with a writer called Norman Maelstrom set in El End Zone; a memo of advice on running El End Zone; notes on the media, possibly written for the SMU journalism class; and a page titled "The Angst Book." (Ronnie Dugger in a reminiscence on Brammer states, "he made a bundle of journal type notes he called 'the Angst Books" [<emph render='italic'>Washington Post</emph>, June 18, 1978].)  These pieces were purchased from Larry McMurtry's bookstore, Booked Up, in 1988.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_8089" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Gay Place</unittitle><container id="aspace_378ec2abd8195b32d96cfb472e9c99d2" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_33a8f22406e634b5cfa53a46400555fa" parent="aspace_378ec2abd8195b32d96cfb472e9c99d2" type="folder">1-6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8095" level="file"><did><unittitle>Come and Join the Dance</unittitle><container id="aspace_3040063249c2b2d1ef5863f642057787" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_ca9d6fe98857f8e88f7887c0fac334c7" parent="aspace_3040063249c2b2d1ef5863f642057787" type="folder">7</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8096" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fustian Days</unittitle><container id="aspace_5a26ba51172f5c19e2296bfe5390a147" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_fbcc8063f192adc307921c8761ed49fd" parent="aspace_5a26ba51172f5c19e2296bfe5390a147" type="folder">8-12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8101" level="file"><did><unittitle>Texas Observer articles</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" type="inclusive">1961, 1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe352b38dc47d4665c81fd4caf42b13e" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_768b546e7a7ef992b37d4c89237f6ec6" parent="aspace_fe352b38dc47d4665c81fd4caf42b13e" type="folder">13</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8102" level="file"><did><unittitle>Drafts and notes</unittitle><container id="aspace_a9b1beeda22a9a2836f59316cd3de474" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_2c54f561afacd7bbd3e340ea224fc982" parent="aspace_a9b1beeda22a9a2836f59316cd3de474" type="folder">14</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_8087" level="series"><did><unittitle>Critical/Biographical Papers</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1950/1993" type="inclusive">1950-1993</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6236921d4550d26e6f9c50f46433944d"><head>Series Description</head><p>This series contains clippings and articles about Brammer, reviews of his work, and the eulogy presented at his funeral.  Also included are correspondence - many from his publisher Houghton-Mifflin about <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph>, some from his agent, a few personal letters, and a dust jacket of <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph>.  There are photos of Brammer with his family and friends, which were enlarged and duplicated by Bill Wittliff. The material is filed in chronological order.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_8103" level="file"><did><unittitle>Clippings about Brammer and his work </unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" type="inclusive">1952-1978, 1993</unitdate><container id="aspace_5a6d61522bfac9c4acd7538d99f8df06" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_7404cf6b8cbc60d65cfbfec07ff09881" parent="aspace_5a6d61522bfac9c4acd7538d99f8df06" type="folder">1-2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8105" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1959/1973" type="inclusive">1959 - 1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_003469b11b41c4a8f626bb58e06e365d" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_f46af8cf6ae0d94f441c44a1f1f1aa2f" parent="aspace_003469b11b41c4a8f626bb58e06e365d" type="folder">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8106" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photos and realia</unittitle><container id="aspace_78126b6bbe5181fcb97a458bca2af4e0" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_f2d4e4c94382f510039b454af9fa1784" parent="aspace_78126b6bbe5181fcb97a458bca2af4e0" type="folder">4</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_8088" level="series"><did><unittitle>Nadine Eckhardt Papers</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1951/1985" type="inclusive">1951-1985 </unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_92ca2f0cbafde5e11d3085be1bf40e44"><head>Series Description</head><p>Nadine Eckhardt (nee Nadine Ellen Cannon) was the first wife of Billy Lee Brammer and the mother of his three children.  The two met as students at North Texas State College and married on April 22, 1950.  Nadine Brammer worked for a time on the Lyndon Baines Johnson staff along with her husband, but later returned with her children to live in Austin while Brammer remained in Washington.  In 1961, the Brammers were divorced and in 1962, Nadine married Texas Congressman Bob Eckhardt.  Her papers contain Brammer's school records, his Air Force application, correspondence, and a file on <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph>.  The bulk of the correspondence comes from those times during the Brammers' marriage when they lived separately - while Nadine lived in her parents' home in McAllen during her first pregnancy, and while she lived with the children in Austin when Brammer worked as a Johnson staff member in Washington.  Their letters discuss their marriage, their children, work, and Brammer's writing.  Brammer writes about his Washington staff job, Johnson, and other staff aides.  There are also letters to and from Brammer's McAllen in-laws, the Cannons.  Photographs and clippings are interspersed throughout the correspondence.  The final folders contain <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph> file, which contains a wide range of information related to the book and the author.  In the divorce settlement, Nadine received one-half interest in <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph>; and the collection of these materials is related to that interest.  It consists of reviews, sales records, examples of Brammer's newspaper writing, clippings about Brammer, Brammer memos to Johnson, etc.  In 1976, Nadine Eckhardt considered writing an autobiography and she asked Brammer to collaborate with her, hoping to spark Brammer back into writing.  This project produced a chronology and a few notes from Brammer.  There is also a chronology of Johnson's activities from 1955 to 1956, which Nadine Eckhardt was given by government oral historian Michael L. Gillette to help her remember events for an interview.  The material is in chronological order except for <emph render='italic'>The Gay Place</emph> file, which is in the original filing order.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_8107" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence </unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1951/1961" type="inclusive">1951-1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_779ddfc6f057e52871c1939d7b659ab4" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_4beef81451949752dbf8956d3203e455" parent="aspace_779ddfc6f057e52871c1939d7b659ab4" type="folder">5-13</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8116" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brammer College Records, Air Force application</unittitle><container id="aspace_03de73fc653685a81044a4df9b037b4c" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_7094d432d283ffd882c854e80a2b8953" parent="aspace_03de73fc653685a81044a4df9b037b4c" type="folder">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8117" level="file"><did><unittitle>The Gay Place file</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1957/1985" type="inclusive">1957-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_d186fa217dec6b0a848cfb273bda58a8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_4261264eed16fef9e16938a4a72f51dc" parent="aspace_d186fa217dec6b0a848cfb273bda58a8" type="folder">2-5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8121" level="file"><did><unittitle>Brammer chronology </unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1976/1976">1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_807a36ef28dcb2e123be24fd4bce9612" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_5106b3fe5ac9046790a4c95776b16f30" parent="aspace_807a36ef28dcb2e123be24fd4bce9612" type="folder">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8122" level="file"><did><unittitle>LBJ chronology</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1955/1957" type="inclusive">1955-1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_8720c36b64a24c61144d2775c0829090" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">3</container><container id="aspace_51dcbcfdb3f941b079ac4e01f88bbf18" parent="aspace_8720c36b64a24c61144d2775c0829090" type="folder">7</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
