<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-txsmtsu" url="urn:taro:tsusm.00088">urn:taro:tsusm.00088</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the John Wesley Hardin Papers</titleproper><author>Archival Staff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>The Wittliff Collections</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://alkek.library.txstate.edu/images/WC.png" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><address><addressline>601 University Drive</addressline><addressline>San Marcos, Texas 78666</addressline><addressline>Wittliff_Ref@txstate.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu/" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address><date calendar="gregorian" era="ce">2021</date></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-07-28 10:57:03 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <head>Collection Summary</head>
    <repository encodinganalog="852$a">
      <extref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:type="simple" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu/">
      <corpname>The Wittliff Collections</corpname></extref>
    </repository>
    <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">John Wesley Hardin Papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname encodinganalog="100" authfilenumber="n79068394" source="lcnaf">Hardin, John Wesley, 1853-1895</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="US" repositorycode="US-txsmtsu">SWWC.088</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole" encodinganalog="300$a">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 Linear Feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="whole" encodinganalog="300$a">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3  boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1874/1895" type="inclusive">1874-1895</unitdate>
    <physloc id="aspace_56543ed913dca12a2a6bf8b6c11aa012">Materials may be stored off-site. Advance notice is required for use: <extref xlink:href= 'https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu/research/makearesearchappointment.html'>https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu/research/makearesearchappointment.html.</extref></physloc>
    <abstract encodinganalog="520$a" id="aspace_826abbdd027da3b37f7aabe79052fbd5">The letters in this collection date from 1874 to 1931 and the bulk of them concern John Wesley Hardin's arrest and imprisonement.</abstract>
    <langmaterial encodinganalog="546$a">
      <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506" id="aspace_20a786447e3569399977cee344ad8fa0">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Collection is open for research. Photocopies of Hardin collection material will be provided for general reference. Original material from this collection may be accessed with special permission only.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="aspace_ad827d39152df5b331fe14b2047a772a">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift of Ernest Spellman, 1982. (Spellman's mother was the daughter of Hardin's eldest daughter Mollie. Spellman and his father, Elmer, both attended Texas State University.)</p>  </acqinfo>
  <processinfo encodinganalog="583">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
    <p>Refer to finding aid data.</p>
  </processinfo>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="545" id="aspace_2d40d9bbb11dcd45fd423c257bcb1009">
    <head>Biographical Notes</head>
<p>John Wesley Hardin was born on May 26, 1853 in Bonham, Fannin County, Texas, the second of James Gibson and Elizabeth Cartwright Dixon Hardin's eight children.  Hardin's father was a circuit-riding Methodist preacher and named his son after the founder of the Methodist sect. </p><p>J. G. Hardin moved the family frequently during Hardin's childhood.  They settled in Moscow, Polk County, in 1855, then moved in 1859 to Sumpter, Trinity County, where J. G. Hardin taught school.  In 1861, J. G. Hardin passed the bar and moved the family to Livingston, Polk County, Texas where he taught school and practiced law.</p><p>After the war, in 1865, the family returned to Sumpter.  In 1868, the 15 year old John Wesley Hardin killed his first victim, a former slave.  Texas was ruled by the military according to congressional reconstruction policies and Hardin believed that he would not receive a fair trial.  He fled and later claimed to have killed three soldiers who were sent to arrest him and that his relatives and neighbors helped him bury and hide the evidence.  In 1869, his father sent him away from the area to teach school in Pisga, Navarro County, where other relatives lived.  He left the school after one term to take up more lucrative pursuits.  He developed his skills in gambling and became enamored of horse racing.  By the end of 1869, Hardin by his own admission had killed a freedman and four soldiers.  In December of that year he killed Jim Bradly in a fight after a card game.  His life subsequently became a pattern of gambling, saloons, fights, and killing.</p><p>In 1871, Hardin visited his relatives, the Clements, in Gonzales County.  J. G. Hardin's sister Martha Balch had married Emmanuel Clements and Hardin was close to his first cousins, Mannen (or Manning), Joe, and Gip.  They convinced him to go with them on a cattle drive to Abilene, Kansas.  Hardin used his gun often on the drive.  Among his victims were an Indian who shot at him with an arrow and five Mexicans with whom he had argued for crowding his herd.  In rough and ready Abilene, Hardin fraternized and sparred with Wild Bill Hickock and Ben Thompson.  When his cousin Mannen Clements was jailed for the killing of two of Clements' cowboys, Hardin made arrangements with Hickock for Mannen to escape.  Later Hardin killed a man at his hotel and fled Abilene fearing arrest by Hickock. </p><p>Hardin returned to Gonzales County, Texas, where he and the Clements piled up indictments (Marohn 44).  Hardin married Jane Bowen on February 29, 1872.  Jane was fully aware of Hardin's way of life and remained totally loyal to her husband through all the vicissitudes of their married life.  Hardin was frequently apart from Jane, often to avoid the law.  In August 1872, Hardin was wounded after being shot by Phil A. Sublett who had lost money to Hardin in a Trinity City Saloon.  Hardin tried to hide out while he recovered but finally gave himself up when his whereabouts were discovered.  Along with an indictment for assaulting Sublett, Hardin had several other indictments outstanding when he was arrested.  He was sent to Gonzales County at the request of Sheriff W. E. Jones who held warrants against him (Marohn 56).  He broke out of the Gonzales County jail with the help of Mannen Clements.</p><p>On February 6, 1873, Hardin's first child Mary Elizabeth (Mollie) was born.  In April, he killed J. B. Morgan in a Cuero barroom, one of the two killings for which he would ultimately be convicted.  The same year, he became embroiled in the Taylor-Sutton feud as a leader of the Taylor faction.  Hardin was related by marriage to the Taylors and both Taylors and Suttons relied on the loyalty of kin.  Hardin and Jim Taylor killed the powerful and ruthless Sutton supporter, Jack Helm.  In March of 1874, Hardin and his older brother Joseph aided Billy and Jim Taylor in their assassination of the leader of the Sutton faction, Bill Sutton, as he boarded a boat in Indianola on his way to New Orleans.  After Bill Sutton's murder, Hardin put together another cattle drive and journeyed to Comanche to say goodbye to his family.  On May 26, he was celebrating his winnings from a horse race, drinking at the Comanche saloons, when he met up with deputy sheriff Charles Webb from neighboring Brown County.  Webb was killed and the crowd turned against Hardin and his companions.  Hardin escaped but his father, brother Joseph, and other kinsmen were arrested.  Joseph Hardin and two cousins were taken from jail at night and lynched.  Hardin, vowing to avenge his brother's death, fled Texas followed by his wife and daughter.  Under the name of J. H. Swain he relocated in Florida among his wife's relatives.  He later moved his family to other Bowen relatives in Pollard, Alabama across the Florida border.  John Wesley Hardin, Jr. was born August 3, 1875.  A daughter, Callie, (later renamed Jane Martina and called Jennie) was born July 15, 1877. </p><p>In 1873, Reconstruction had ended in Texas with the election of Richard Coke over radical Republican E. J. Davis.  As soon as the former confederates were returned to power, the populace was eager to see an end to the violence and lawlessness which had been rampant since the end of the war.  Coke re-established the Texas Rangers in 1874, in part to reinforce local law enforcement in their ineffectual fight against cattle thieves, gangs and feudists.  He created a Special Force whose first duty was to end the Sutton-Taylor feud.  In 1877, John B. Armstrong, a second Lieutenant in the Special Force, requested that he be commissioned to find and arrest the fugitive Hardin.  A Dallas detective Jack Duncan was hired to live undercover among Jane Hardin's relatives in Gonzales County in order to learn where Hardin was.  Jane's brother, Brown Bowen, also a fugitive hiding in Alabama, betrayed their whereabouts when he wrote his father and told him that his sister Jane sends her love.  Armstrong and Duncan went to Pensacola Junction in Florida and made arrangements with the sheriff to arrest Hardin on the train as he was returning home to Alabama on August 23, 1877.  They overpowered Hardin and transported him back to Texas where they lodged him in the Austin jail.  Under heavy guard by the Texas Rangers, Hardin was taken to Comanche County and tried for the murder of Charles Webb in September of 1877.  He was convicted to 25 years in the state prison but appealed the sentence on technical grounds.  He was returned to Austin October 6, 1877 to await his hearing.  Hardin's brother-in-law, Brown Bowen, was also in the Austin jail sentenced to die by hanging for the murder of Thomas Haldeman.  The Bowens asked Hardin to take the blame for the Haldeman murder.  Hardin refused maintaining his innocence.  Jane Hardin stood by her husband, thereby estranging herself from her father.  Brown Bowen was hung proclaiming Hardin was the guilty one to the very last.</p><p>In June 1878, Hardin's conviction was upheld.  He entered prison in Huntsville on October 5, 1878.  He made several unsuccessful attempts to escape and was harshly punished each time.  Eventually he settled into prison life, joined the debating society, attended Sunday school and studied law.  In January 1892, Hardin was sent to Cuero, Texas where he plea bargained a 2 year concurrent sentence for the 1873 murder of J. B. Morgan.  He was released from prison February 17, 1894 after 15 years and 5 months with time off for good behavior.  He rejoined his children in Gonzales County.  His wife Jane had died November 6, 1892.</p><p>Hardin's attorney wrote Governor Hogg for a full pardon based on the fact that Hardin had completed his sentence and was "behaving in an orderly manner." (Marohn 180)  The pardon was granted on March 16, 1894.  Hardin then passed a law examination and set up practice in Gonzales.  He became embroiled in a controversy with W. E. Jones in Jones' campaign for Gonzales County sheriff.  Hardin supported Jones' opponent and charged that Jones had helped him escape from prison in 1872.  When Jones won a close election, an embittered Hardin left Gonzales and moved to Junction where his brother Jeff was living.  By December, he opened a law office there.  In January he married the 15 year old Callie Lewis but she left him soon after.</p><p>A relative, Jim Miller, asked Hardin to come to Pecos in far West Texas to give legal assistance in his feud with the Pecos County Sheriff, Bud Frazer.  Miller was suspected of several murders himself, and when Hardin consented to help him, he was walking straight back into his old way of life.  The Miller case ended with a hung jury and Hardin drifted to El Paso.  He set up a law office there but soon let his practice slide.  He again frequented saloons, gambled, drank to excess and got into fights.  On August 19, 1895, John Selman, with whom Hardin had been arguing, shot Hardin in the back of the head as he threw dice at the bar of the Acme Saloon.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_3ee42983e9dca4df1b5719e1dee73d50" encodinganalog="520$b">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The letters in this collection date from 1874 to 1931.  The bulk of the letters cover Hardin's arrest and imprisonment.  Several of the letters describe in detail Hardin's version of the Webb killing and lynching of Hardin's relatives as well as his own arrest, trial and incarceration.  There is good documentation of the 1894 Gonzales County election controversy in which Hardin was deeply involved.  The correspondence also offers insights on 19th century Texas life, i.e. politics, reconstruction, the Texas Rangers, the State Police, the Taylor-Sutton feud, prison life, farming practices, and country social life and mores.  The collection also contains handwritten legal exams and papers as well as family photographs.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1874 Letters: </emph>There is only one letter from this year.  On September 18, Hardin, on the run after the Webb killing in May, writes to his father to make a payment to his cousin, Mannen Clements.  In a postscript, Hardin tells his father to destroy the letter after it is read.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1875 Letters: </emph>There is one item from the year 1875, a bill dated September 25 from Joseph DeMartini of Jacksonville Florida to J. H Swain.  In his autobiography, Hardin says he was in Jacksonville using the alias of Swain from July 1875 to July 1876. (Hardin, 110-112)</p><p><emph render='bold'>1876 Letters: </emph>There are scraps of bills and invoices from Jacksonville, Florida dating from May until January. Present also is the first letter from Hardin to his wife. It is dated September 8 and he writes he will send for her when he has set up a business.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1877 Letters: </emph>The Hardins contacted their families in April to let them know for the first time since they left Texas how they had fared. They are answered by Jane's uncle Joshua Bowen (May 6) and Hardin's uncle Robert  E. Hardin (alias R. E. Barnette, May 9. See Marohn 104). Both responses relate the state of affairs in Texas, update the Hardins on their respective relatives and mention the status of the Sutton-Taylor feud factions.  After Hardin was captured by John Armstrong and Jack Duncan on August 23, 1877, he writes Jane from Decatur Alabama on August 25 explaining what happened and hinting that he might be able to escape. He accuses her brother Brown of being the cause of his capture. The majority of letters in September and October are letters of support from the family. Hardin is tried in September and convicted of Second Degree murder. He is returned to the Austin jail October 6 to await his appellate hearing. Letters from the family lament his sentence, and encourage him in his appeal.  Beginning in November, the Hardin family urges Jane to return to Texas.  Other letters of interest are a letter from Doc J An which mentions his knowledge of the detective who arrested Hardin, October 13; from Hardin's mother, Elizabeth, recounting the family version of the Webb killing, October 26; from Hardin giving his wife a detailed account of what happened on the day of the Webb killing and mentioning Brown Bowen who is also in the Austin jail, December 5, 1877; and again from Elizabeth Hardin discussing her family's tragedies and asking Jane what exactly had been Hardin's occupation, December 14, 1877.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1878 Letters: </emph>Jane Hardin and her children arrived at Hardin's mother's home in Bennett Station in North Texas in February. Brown Bowen is sentenced to hang for the murder of Tom Haldeman and on March 11, Hardin complains that Brown is blaming him for the murder. He tells Jane that her father has been the cause of the indictment against him for the murder of J. B. Morgan in 1873. On March 26, Hardin writes Jane that Brown got Mannen Clements indicted for the Paten Patterson killing of July 25, 1872. Brown Bowen was hung on May 17 and Hardin, in a May 18 letter to Jane, describes how her sister and father begged him to take the blame for the Haldeman murder, tells why he refused to do so and describes Brown's hanging. On May 19, Mattie Bowen writes her sister Jane how she found Brown's corpse waiting for her and her father when they returned home to Gonzales County from Austin. Hardin learns his conviction has been affirmed in June. Jane Hardin quarrels with her mother-in-law and Hardin writes her in August to mend her relations with his mother. (The reasons for the quarrel are not given.) An August 3 letter from Mannen Clements to Jane also urges her to end the quarrel and advises her not to worry Hardin with her problems. Jane and the children go to Austin in the same month and are able to visit with Hardin in the Austin jail. On September 16, 1878 Hardin is taken under Ranger guard to Comanche for sentencing and he writes Jane describing his travels. On October 5 he enters the Huntsville penitentiary to serve a 25-year sentence as #7109. Jane returns to his mother in Red River County. Hardin's letter writing in prison is restricted and letters are read by prison authorities. By December he has found a guard, J. C. Outlaw, who will slip out letters for him. Hardin writes in his autobiography (127) that he immediately began planning his escape. His letters are circumspect but in a slipped out letter of December 28 he describes an escape attempt.  He does not admit blame but says he was punished.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1879 Letters: </emph>In his letters to Jane, Hardin often expresses his love for her and the children. On January 9, 1879, he reminisces on their courtship in uncharacteristic detail. Later he apologizes that he exposed their courtship conversation which intimates how very aware he is that his letters are being read by others. In a letter of February 23 which he is slipping out through a guard, he warns Jane to be careful about what she writes, to pretend that she only wants him to be released legally. Letters to Jane of January 26 and February 9 also go into more detail about conditions at prison mentioning escape attempts and punishment. On February 9, Hardin tells Jane about Mannen Clements' legal troubles and that her sister Mattie married Oliver Odom. While Jane is still in Bennett he repeatedly urges her to be considerate of his mother and family. Jane leaves Hardin's mother around April 4 and goes to Austin. By May, she is living with Mannen Clements' family in San Saba County. In a May 11 letter to Mannen Clements, Hardin asks him to give information to Texas Rangers, Lee Hall and J. B. Armstrong, which will help them convict members of the mob who lynched Scrap Taylor. (Hardin relates in his autobiography that Scrap Taylor was lynched by Suttonites after the Webb murder). Mannen Clements is in Austin to take care of an aggravated assault charge mentioned in an earlier letter. In June, Hardin is put in boot shop and writes he has become a good fitter and cutter. On June 19, 1879, Sally Jane Clements, wife of Joseph Hardin Clements, writes Jane about an Indian raid against nearby settlers in West Texas. In August and September, Hardin's mother and family are moving around looking for another place to farm. November 2, Hardin tells Jane to enjoy her stay in Gonzales where her family lives and advises her to "let bygones alone." He is most likely referring to the animosities between Hardin and the Bowens over the Bowen's part in Hardin's arrest and Brown Bowen's hanging.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1880 Letters: </emph>There are only five letters and one four-side page of school exercises belonging to Edward Bowen from this year. None of the letters are to or from John Hardin. In May, Elizabeth Hardin writes to Jane in Gonzales that Hardin has had his letter writing privileges taken away after he has been caught planning an escape in clandestine correspondence with Mannen Clements.  In August 1880, Hardin attempted escape again and these attempts undoubtedly are the reason he is unable or unwilling to write.(Marohn, 150)</p><p><emph render='bold'>1881 Letters: </emph>On June 3, 1881, Hardin writes Jane again after a long hiatus.  He explains, in a rather circumspect manner, why he had not written. He is basically saying that since he could not be frank with her (he is possibly referring to his escape attempts and punishment), there was no point in writing at all. He also offers her the opportunity to leave him since they are forced to live apart. He indicates a prison superintendent convinced him to write his mother after she repeatedly wrote asking what had happened to him. He claims that he has decided to make no more attempts to escape and hopes now to gain early release by earning good time or being pardoned.  On July 3, 1881, Hardin writes that he worships on the Sabbath, belongs to the Moral and Christian Society and is secretary of the Debating Society. Once again he offers Jane her freedom if she thinks it is in her best interest. In a letter of August 14, he acknowledges that Jane has responded that she wants to remain his wife. He again gives reasons why he did not write her for so long including "to Keep you out of a disgraceful correspondence Something I cannot mention Now." On September 25, Hardin once more offers Jane her release if she wants it. He asks her to write and offers to give her advice on how to educate the children if she wants it.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1882 Letters: </emph>In a letter of February 26, Hardin writes that he is glad Jane has chosen to wait for him. In his next letter of April 2, he tells her that he wants to see her but not in stripes. Hardin's mother is writing from Gainesville in May and Hardin's sister, Matt Smith, moves to Lampasas Springs after her husband Bright's house burns down.  The children are growing and Hardin's letters increasingly discuss their upbringing beginning with Sep 3. There is one letter from Jane's father Neill Bowen, the only letter of his in the collection. It is written from Pollard, Alabama to Wad who is probably a resident of Gonzales County. Some have thought Wad was Wes but the contents of the letter indicate rather that Neill is writing to someone who has family in Florida and is living in the free world.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1883 Letters: </emph>There is only one letter from this year written to Jane Hardin by her sister. Hardin writes in his autobiography that he tried to escape in 1883 without success. In the fall, he became very ill from an abscess to an old gun wound received in 1872. When he is well enough, he is put to work in the tailor shop.  (Hardin 131-133)</p><p><emph render='bold'>1884 Letters: </emph>Hardin's letters begin to appear on prison forms.  He writes Jane two letters in this year indicating he spent most of the year sick from his wound.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1885 Letters: </emph>In May, Hardin's mother Elizabeth died at the age of 58 in Ennis, Texas.In August, Hardin asks prison superintendent Ben McCulloch for proper medical treatment saying he has been suffering for two years. In September, Hardin writes Jane that he is feeling better after 2 years of sickness and that sickness prevented him from writing more. His two oldest children begin to write him.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1886 Letters: </emph>Hardin begins to write his children directly, giving them advice on the importance of education and the proper way to behave.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1887 Letters: </emph>Hardin continues to lecture wife and children using more biblical quotes and religious references. He explains to his children that he was unjustly imprisoned.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1888 Letters: </emph>Hardin writes flowery letters instructing Jane and the children on how they should behave. In a February 5th letter, he tells Jane his release date has been moved up because of his good conduct. He promises that if released, he will try to purge himself of his "wicked intemperate ways." On June 24, he defends his past as the actions of a brave man fighting all foes. He has never surrendered and he stood up against the mob. On October 7, Hardin tells Jane to tell the children all about him and that they should imitate his virtues and avoid his faults.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1889 Letters: </emph>All the letters from this year are addressed to the children but the body of the letter often contains individual messages to each member of his family.  Hardin continues to claim he is imprisoned unjustly. In the July 14 letter to his daughter Jane, he relates his version of the Webb killing, his brother's lynching, his arrest and trial. He also expresses sorrow that Jane's father, Neill Bowen has died. In October he asks Jane why she is not writing.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1890 Letters: </emph>In an April letter, Hardin attacks successive Governor's administrations from Davis to Ross. He writes that he has endured 13 years of slavery in prison and the 10 years before he was in "tragic battle" with Yankee soldiers and their supporters. In a November letter, Hardin tells Jane to keep her good looks since he expects to be free in three years. He adds that he will continue to battle for his rights, and for the children to cease writing for the present. In every letter, Hardin gives advice on the behavior of the children.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1891 Letters: </emph>Many of these letters are addressed to Jane Hardin written by John and various other family members. Following a Southern familial custom, John continues advising Jane on the behavior of the children. In an April letter, John pleads with Jane to teach the children "that it is cowardly to lie to Steal to rob […] to murder or to violate any law civil."  Hardin also receives a letter from L.A. Whatley, Superintendent of Penitentiaries, detailing additional prison time Hardin has accrued on account of his "misconduct" and relates to Hardin's that his term will thus expire on January 22, 1894, if Hardin "will be acquiescent &amp; obedient to the rules."   </p><p>    
<emph render='bold'>1892 Letters: </emph>Letters from the Fly &amp; McNeal law firm are of interest here, such as one letter dated May 18, in which W.S. McNeal writes to Hardin reassuring him that his case "is a good one and will be of great benefit with the governor in obtaining a pardon for you."  Also of interest here are the heartfelt letters that Hardin sent to his children.In an August letter to his son and two daughters, Hardin writes that "Your papa" desires to greet his family with "Kisses of love and tender caresses emblematic of his deep and Sinceere [<emph render='italic'>sic</emph>] affection for each of you."</p><p><emph render='bold'>1893 Letters: </emph>Considering that Hardin was released from prison the following year, many of documents contained here are not surprisingly related to Hardin's case (with various references to the murder of J.B. Morgan); including formal interaction with state legislators and Governor J.S. Hogg.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1894 Letters: </emph>Recently released from prison, Hardin is involved in prolific correspondence with various persons including sheriffs, attorneys, and local merchants. Of peculiar interest are several bills Hardin received from J.P. Randle, P. Levyson, and (responding to a request for a law book catalogue) Gilbert Book Company.</p><p><emph render='bold'>1895 Letters:</emph> One singular article of interest here is Hardin's business card—as an attorney at law in El Paso. The card is fixed to a note, which reads, "This card and about 80 others were found in Hardin's room after he was killed in 1895." One humorous letter dated July 11, from J.H. Flynth, asks Hardin to "please tell me when you was convicted the first time and what was your sentence […] for the purpose of settling a dispute here in regard to the matter." This was answered in a script that (to this writer) appears to be J.W. Hardin's, but was written "in regard to Mr. Hardin," and is unsigned.</p>
    <p>Correspondents and Index</p>
<p>Not all names have been indexed.  First names without surnames which cannot be otherwise identified or are merely mentioned in passing are not indexed.  A question mark in brackets means the identity or spelling is uncertain.  The relationship after the name refers to the subject's relationship to John Wesley Hardin unless otherwise identified.</p><p>An, Doc J-cousin[?] may be an Anderson (see Parsons, Capture 34).
Letters From:  1877 Oct 13[?]</p><p>Anderson, James (Jim)-cousin, was at the Waldrup ranch when Mrs. Waldrup told of Charles Webb's visit to arrest her son.  Helped J.W. Hardin circulate pardon papers.(See Hardin vs. State 359, and Life 89)
Letters From:  1892 Jul 17
Mentioned:  1877 Sep 9, Oct 26; 1879 Mar 2; </p><p>Anglemiller, Joe-acquaintance in Austin.
Mentioned:  1879 Apr 13</p><p>Anglin, Mrs. Mollie - The Andrew Anglin family made clothes on order and sold them through the Bowen store in the 1870s.  (Parsons, Brown 26).  They are listed in the 1880 census as living next door to Jane.
Mentioned:  1881 Jul 3, Dec 14 1882 Jan 18</p><p>Ann-sister-in-law [?] Jane had an older sister named Ann (Parsons, Bowen 15)
Mentioned:  1877 May 6, Sep 5</p><p>Armstrong, Lieut. John B.- one-time Texas Ranger who participated in capture of Hardin.
Mentioned:  1879 May 11</p><p>Ashe, J.D. - District Clerk - Harris Co.
    Letters From : 1894 Mar 6, Aug 16, 23, Sept 20
    
Auguero, Louis – Client of J.W. Hardin
    Letters From : 1894 Oct 7
    
Auguero, Roman – Client of J.W. Hardin
    Letters From : 1894 Oct 7</p><p>Baker, D.(avid) P. - probably an inmate with Hardin in the Travis County jail.  J. H. Clements writes him a letter on the back of a letter to Hardin.  Mentions other names that are difficult to decipher or identify.
Letter To:  1878, Feb 15</p><p>Barbisch, Joe – Austin Printing Co.
    Letters To : 1894 Nov 20
    
Barnett, Mary - cousin to John and Jennie Hardin.</p><p>Letter From: 1894 Oct 4.
    
Barnette, R. E.-see Robert E. Hardin.</p><p>Bishop, F. D. - supporter of Hardin's pardon.
Letters From : 1894 Apr 14</p><p>Bell, Tom - Sheriff - Hill Co.</p><p>Letters From : 1894 Mar 27, 30, Apr 14,  
    
Benny- perhaps Edward Bowen's brother and Joshua Bowen's son.  Joshua mentions him in a letter to Edward Bowen, .
Mentioned:  1879 Jul 2; 1880 Jul 15</p><p>Blackburn, M. – Client of J.W. Hardin
    Letters From : 1894 Oct 6
    
Blackshear, K.R. - Tax collector.
    Letters From : 1893 Jul 14(2); 1894 Feb 7
    Letters To : 1894 Jan 9
    
Bond, F.[?] M.- addresses herself as Jane Hardin's sister.
Letter From:  1888 May 22</p><p>Bowen, Beasley- Jane's half-brother, son of Neill and Purity Bowen.
Mentioned:  1881 May 1</p><p>Bowen, Brown (Joshua) -brother-in-law, Jane's brother.  Brown Bowen was hung for the murder of Thomas Haldeman in 1872.  His father Neill Bowen asked Hardin to take responsibility for the murder but Hardin refused.  Brown claimed Hardin was the guilty party even to the gallows.  Mentioned:  1877, May 6, Aug 25, Oct 26, Dec 5, 20; 1878 Jan 31, Feb 15, Mar 14, 23, 26, Apr 19, May 18, 30, Jun 1  </p><p>Bowen, Edna-Jane's half-sister, daughter to Neill and Purity Bowen.
Mentioned:  1881 May 1</p><p>Bowen, Edward- Jane's cousin, son of Joshua Bowen.
Letter From:  1880 Jul 13 [Copybook]
Mentioned:  1877 May 6, 1879 Jul 2</p><p>Bowen, Elizabeth (Lizzie, Liza?)-sister-in-law, Janes older sister.
Mentioned:  1877 Oct 26; 1878 Aug 19; 1879 Jul 22[?], 1881 Mar 5, May 1; 1882 Oct 4</p><p>Bowen, Joshua-Jane's uncle.  Lives in Sadlers Mill, Gonzales County and is possibly the Josh in Santa Rosa, Florida.
Letters From:  1880 Jul 15
Letters To:  1877 May 6 1878 Mar 23 [?], 1879 Jul 2
Mentioned:  1881 May 1; 1882 Feb 26</p><p>Bowen, Mattie (Mat, Martha, M. E, see also Mattie Odom)-Sister-in-law.  Jane's sister.  Becomes Mattie Odom December 1878)
Letters From:  1877 Sep 5, Oct 26, Dec 20; 1878 Apr(May) 19, Jun 29, Aug 19
Mentioned:  1877 May 6, May 9; 1878 May 18, 30</p><p>Bowen, Neill (Neal)-Father-in-law, Jane's father.  
Letter From:  1882 Nov 26
Mentioned:  1877, May 6, Aug 25, Sep 12, Oct 26, Dec 5, 14, 20; 1878 Feb 15, Mar 14, 26, Apr 19, May 18, 2?, Jun 11, Aug 2, 19 1879 Jul 2, 22; 1881 Mar 5, May 1, Aug 14; 1889 Jul 14.</p><p>Bowen, Purity Ann Sunday-Neill Bowen's second wife, Jane's stepmother.
Letter From: 1881 May 1
Mentioned:  1878 Aug 2</p><p>Bowen, William-brother-in-law, Jane's brother.  
Letters From: 1877 Oct 26
Mentioned:  1877 Dec 20; 1878  Apr 19</p><p>Bratton, B – Friend of J.W. Hardin
    Letters From : 1894 Oct 22
    
Brazell (Brassell) murders-Dr. Phillip Brassell and his son George were called from their beds on the night of September 19, 1876 and murdered by a group of men identified as members of the Sutton faction in the Sutton-Taylor feud.  These murders aroused public outrage.  The rangers were called in and eight men were arrested and charged.  This is considered the last murder resulting from the long-running Sutton-Taylor feud.
Mentioned:  1877 May 6, May 13</p><p>Brockius (Brosius), Doc-was in charge of the cattle that Hardin had gathered for a drive at the time of the Webb killing.  Brockius was arrested and about to be lynched with Scrap Taylor and others when a member of the lynch mob helped him escape.
Mentioned:  1877 Oct 26; 1880 Aug 30; 1882 May 25
Buchanan, John - County Clerk - Halletsville.
    Letters To : 1894 Aug 22
    
Burnet, Sally-acquaintance.
Mentioned:  1889  Dec 8</p><p>Bush, Dr. - Prison doctor.
Mentioned:  1885 Aug 26</p><p>Camel, Mary - see Campbell
Campbell [?], Caroline- Jane's cousin.  Mentioned in letter from Mattie Odom.
Mentioned:  1879 Jun 15</p><p>Campbell, Charles-acquaintance of the Bowens, probably related.
Mentioned:  1877, May 6</p><p>Campbell, Mary-Bowen relation.  Writes from Santa Rosa, Florida
Letters From:  1878 Mar 23, 
Mentioned:  1879 Jun 15</p><p>Campbell, Neal-with Hardin when he was captured on the train in Pensacola.
Mentioned:  1877, Aug 25</p><p>Campbell, Sallie-Hardin knew her family in Sumpter and is reacquainted with her when he is in jail in Austin.
Mentioned:  1878 Mar 14</p><p>Carnes (Karnes), Sheriff John-Sheriff of Comanche County when Webb killing occurred.
Mentioned:  1877, Sep 9</p><p>Choate, Mr. of Karnes County-Mattie Hardin writes that Choate is a friend of Hardin's who wishes to help him in his legal troubles.
Mentioned:  1877 Nov 26</p><p>Clements, Gip - cousin, Mannen's brother
Mentioned:  1877, May 6, May 9; 1878 Feb 15, Oct 21; 1879 Mar 23, Jun 19</p><p>Clements, Jim- cousin, Mannen's brother.  Married Annie Caroline, daughter of George and Amanda Jane Billings Tennille.
Letters To: 1894 Oct 4
Mentioned:  1877 May 6, May 9; 1878 Feb 15[?], Oct 2, 1879 Jun 19; 1892 Jan 25</p><p>Clements, Joe [Joseph Hardin, Jo]-cousin, Mannen's brother.  Married Sarah Jane, daughter of George and Amanda Jane Billings Tennille.  February 1878 is in the Gonzales County jail awaiting trial.
Letters From:  1878 Jan 31, Feb 15
Mentioned:  1877, May 6, May 9, Sep 9, 12, Oct 14; 1878 Oct 21; 1879 Mar 23, Jun 19, Aug 17</p><p>Clements, Manning [Emanuel, Mannen].  Cousin.  Mother, Martha Balch Hardin, was sister to Hardin's father.  The two were very close and helped each other out of various scrapes.  Mannen Clements helped Hardin escape from the Gonzales County jail in 1872 when W. E. Jones was sheriff.  Clements unsuccessfully tried to help Hardin escape from Huntsville.  He was shot and killed in a saloon fight in 1887.
Letters From:  1878 May 2?, Jun 1, Aug 3, 27, Oct 21; 1879 Mar 23
Letters To:  1879 May 11, 25, Jul 6, 27 (note), Aug 10 (note)
Mentioned-1874, Sep 18; 1877, May 6, 9; 1878 Jan 19, Jan 31, Mar 14, Mar 17, 26, Jun 15, Jul 4, 14, Aug 2, Sep 11, 28, Oct 4, 22/27, Dec 3, 8, 23, 28; 1879 Jan 10, 26, Feb 9, 23, Mar 2, Apr 13, 20, May 4, Jun 1, Jun 15, 19, Jul 6, 22, 30; Aug 10, Sep 21; 1880 May 27; 1881 Jun 1; 1884 Dec 7</p><p>Clements, Jr., Mannen (Mann)-Mannen Clement's son.
Mentioned:  1878, May 2?, Jun 1, 27; 1879 Mar 23, May 25, Jun 1</p><p>Clements, Mollie, Mary A.-Mannen Clement's wife.
Letters From:  1879 Mar 23
Mentioned:  1878, Jan 29, May 2?, Jun 1, 1879, Apr 13, 20, Jun 15[?], 19, Jul 6, 27, 30, Aug 10, Sep 21</p><p>Clements, Sallie-Mannen Clement's daughter.  Married to Jim Miller.
Mentioned:  1878 May 2?, Jun 1; 1879 Mar 23, May 4, 25, Jun 1, Sep 21</p><p>Clements, S. J. [Sarah Jane Tennille, Sallie]  Daughter of George Tennille and Amanda Jane Billings, married Mannen's brother Joseph Hardin Clements.
Letters From:  1879 Jun 19
Mentioned:   1879 Aug 17</p><p>Cloud, Mr.-Offers hospitality to Jane when she goes to Austin in 1878 to see Hardin in jail
Mentioned:  1878 no date (mid August)</p><p>Cobb, Ben - Married to Jane's aunt Margaret, Neill Bowen's sister.
Mentioned: 1877 May 6, Dec 20; 1879 Jun 15, Jul 2; 1882 Feb 26, Nov 26</p><p>Cobb, Bent-married to Lizzie Hardin Cobb?
Mentioned: 1879 Sep 21</p><p>Cobb, J.B. "Buck"-Jane's cousin.
Letters To : 1892 Sept 11, Nov 6; 1893 May 18
Mentioned:  1882 Sep 3; </p><p>Cobb [?] Daisy,-possibly Jane's cousin, Margaret Cobb's daughter
Mentioned:  1879 Jul 2; 1890 Apr 6, </p><p>Cobb, Lizzie (Sissie, Elizabeth)-sister.
Letters From:  1877 undated; 1878 Feb 17, Mar 11
Mentioned:  1877 Sep 9, 15, Oct 26, Nov 21, 26, Dec 5; 1878 Jun 15, Aug 30, Nov 17; 1879 Jan 10, 26, Apr 27, Jul 30, Sep 21; 1880 Apr 24; 1882 May 25, Aug 13; 1885 Nov 22; 1886 Aug 3</p><p>Cobb, Mary - mentioned in Purity's letter from Florida as a neighbor.
Mentioned:  1881 May 1</p><p>Cobb, Margaret-Jane's aunt, Neill Bowen's sister, married to Ben.
Letter From:  1879 Jul 2
Mentioned:  1879 Jun 15, 19; 1881 Apr 26; 1889 Dec 8</p><p>Cobb [?], Mollie-Probably Margaret Cobb's daughter Mary.  
Mentioned:  1879 Jul 2; 1882 Sep 3; 1889 Dec 8</p><p>Cobb, Mr.-brother-in-law, married to sister Lizzie. see Bent Cobb.
Mentioned:  1879 Apr 27, May 4; 1882 May 25?</p><p>Cobb, Nannie-married Tony Tenille.
Mentioned:  1877 May 6, Sep 5; 1889 Dec 8</p><p>Cobb, Sally (Sarah)-Jane Hardin's cousin.  Daughter of Margaret and Ben.
Mentioned:  1889 Dec 8</p><p>Colbey [sp?], F. A. - Hosts a ball in 1882
Mentioned: 1882 Mar 20 (invitation)</p><p>Coleman, R.R. – Ran for Sheriff of Gonzales Co. 1894
    Letters To : 1894 Oct 14
    Letters From : 1894 Oct 20, 21, Nov 2
    
Cooley, George-broken out of Lampasas County Jail with John Ringo.
Mentioned:  1879 Apr 13</p><p>Corwin, Dennis-Sheriff of Travis County when Hardin is jailed there.
Mentioned:  1878 Jan 31, Sep 16, 17, 24, Oct 4; 1879 Apr 13</p><p>Cresap, S.H. – Neighbor of J.W. Hardin
    Letters From : 1894 Nov 1
    
Cunningham, William-testified in Hardin's Comanche County trial that Hardin and his associates had conspired against Charles Webb.
Mentioned:  1877, Oct 26</p><p>Denson, James M.-Mannen Clement's brother in law.  Married his sister Mary Jane Rebecca Clements.
Letters From : 1894 Oct 27
Mentioned:  1879 Mar 23</p><p>Denson, Mary Jane Rebecca Clements-cousin, Mannen Clement's sister.
Mentioned:  1879 Mar 23</p><p>Diedrich, F. 
    Letters From : 1894 Oct 29
    
Dikes, A. C.-cousin living in Eastland, Texas.
Letters From:  1877 Dec 3</p><p>Dinkins, B. R.-sold cattle to Hardin (alias Swain) in Jacksonville, Florida.
Letters From:  1876 May 2 </p><p>Dixon, Jack-mentioned in Doc J An's letter
Mentioned:  1877 Oct 10</p><p>Dixson, Ellack (Elec)-uncle, mother's brother living in Navarro County.
Mentioned:  1879 Mar 2, Sep 21</p><p>Dixson, Mollie-Aunt, married to Elec Dixson?
Mentioned:  1879 Sep 21</p><p>Dixson, Tom -  Hardin's mother writes Dixson conspired with Cunningham to help kill Hardin on day Webb was killed.
Mentioned:  1877 Oct 26</p><p>Dorst, Jim-friend from Gonzales.
Mentioned:  1878 Jun 27</p><p>Doublin, Dell-acquaintance.
Mentioned: 1879 Aug 17</p><p>Downing, L. M.-Meat vendor in Jacksonville, Florida who bought from Hardin as J. H. Swain.
    Letter To:   1876 Mar 23
    
Duncan, Jack-Dallas detective who assisted in the discovery of Hardin's whereabouts and his capture in Pensacola.
Mentioned:  1877, Aug 25, Oct 10; 1878 May 2?, </p><p>Ed - Purity Bowen writes in a letter from Florida that Ed is in Sunday School.
Mentioned:  1881 May 1</p><p>Ed-Hardin's mother Elizabeth writes that she is living with daughter Nannie and Ed (Nannie's Husband?)
Mentioned: 1882 Aug 13</p><p>Ellis, Wadkin-see Wad.</p><p>Finley, R.W. - Comptroller of Public Accounts, State of Texas.
   Letters From : 1894 Apr ?
   
Fleming, J. R.-Judge who presided over Hardin's Comanche County trial.
Mentioned:  1877 Oct 26, Dec 5; 1878 Dec 3</p><p>Fleming, Mart-Comanche County citizen.
Mentioned:  1878  Oct 20, Jul 6, 27</p><p>Fly &amp; McNeal, atty.- Initiated petition to pardon J.W. Hardin from Cuero case.
   Letters From:  1892 Jan 8, 25, May 18,
   Letters To :  1893 Nov 5
   
Frank - Jane Hardin's sister?.
Mentioned:  1877, May 6, Sep 5, 1878 Aug 19; 1879 Mar 16, May 13 1881 Mar 1, Apr 26, May 1, Dec 14; 1882 Jan 18, Feb 26, May 28, Oct 4, Nov 26; 1886 May 2, Aug 3; 1888 May 22</p><p>Freeman, Pone-acquaintance of Bowens.  Was subpoenaed as a witness in Brown Bowen's trial for the murder of Thomas Haldeman.
Mentioned:  1879 May 13</p><p>Godfrey, John C.-cousin, offers support and money for Hardin's legal fees.  Letter From:  1878 Apr 7
Letter To:  1878 Mar 15(26), Apr 7
Mentioned:  1878 Mar 14, Mar 17, Apr 29, May 2?</p><p>Gary, W.J. - wrote a poem for Hardins</p><p>Letters To : 1892 Oct 2
    
Gibbs, Barnett – Lawyer
    Letters From : 1894 Feb ?
    
Gilbert Book Co. - Provided J.W. Hardin with law books.Sept 15, 28</p><p>  Letters From :  1894  
      
Glover, R.M. - Sheriff and friend of J.W.Hardin
     Letters From: 1894 Feb 28, Mar 28, 30, Apr 13, 16, Dec 1	
     Letters To :  1894  Mar 27, 30, Apr 14  
     
Goree, Major Thomas J.-became superintendent of the Texas prison system in 1877.
Mentioned:  1879 May 4 (note); 1880 Apr 24; 1885 Aug 26 </p><p>Gray, Mr.-First husband of one of Elizabeth Hardin's Red River County neighbors.
Mentioned:  1879 Apr 27</p><p>Grear, Mary Smith-mentioned in letter from Bright Smith's mother
Mentioned:  1882 May 1</p><p>Grear, Will-Mentioned in letter from Bright Smith's mother.
Mentioned:  1882 May 1</p><p>H, S. E.-Gives Jane $10 to help her get to Austin to visit Hardin in jail.
Letters From:  1878  Aug ?</p><p>Haldeman, Tom (Halderman) -Murdered in 1872.  Brown Bowen was hanged for his death on May 1878.
Mentioned:  1878 Mar 14</p><p>Hall, Capt. Lee-Texas Ranger.
Mentioned:  1879 May 11</p><p>Hardin, Aaron-cousin, son of Robert E. Hardin.
Mentioned:  1877 Oct 14, Nov 26; 1878 Mar 15, Jul 6</p><p>Hardin, Alie B [Bell, Arabella]-sister-in-law.  Married to brother, Jo Hardin who was lynched after the murder of Charles Webb in 1874.  By 1880, Bell was married to her second husband, Mr. Pierce.
Letters From:  1877 Sep 9
Mentioned:  1877 Sep 9, 15, undated; 1878 Feb 17, Mar 11; 1879 Jul 30, Sep 21; 1880 Aug 30; 1882 May 25, Aug 13</p><p>Hardin,  Barnett (W. B., Sr.) -Uncle, Polk County.  
Mentioned:  1877,undated[?]; 1878 Feb 17, Mar 30, Apr 7; 1879 Mar 2</p><p>Hardin, Dora-niece, daughter of Jo and Bell Hardin.
Mentioned: 1882 May 25, Aug 13</p><p>Hardin [?], Elizabeth-Cousin [?], possibly daughter of Robert Hardin.
Mentioned:  1877 May 9</p><p>Hardin, Elizabeth Dixon-Mother.
Letters From:  1877 Sep 9, Oct 26, undated, Dec 14; 1878 Jan 15, Feb 15, 26, Mar 30, May 30, Aug 16, 30, Oct 10; 1879 Apr 27, Jul 30, Sep 21; 1880 May 27, Aug 30; 1882 May 25, Aug 13; 
Letters To:  1878 Dec 8;  1879 Jan 10
Mentioned:  1877, May 9, Sep 9, 12, 15, undated, Oct 14, Nov 21, 25, 26, Dec 3, Dec 5, 29; 1878 Feb 17, Mar 11, Jun 1, 2, 15, Jun 8, 23, Aug 2, 3, Oct 4, 20, 21, 27, Nov 17; 1879 Jan 10, Feb 23, Mar 3, Mar 23, Apr 13, May 4, 25; 1880 Apr 24; 1881 Jun 1; 1882 Feb 26, Apr 2; 1883 Jan 6; 1884 Dec 7; 1885 May 29 (funeral)</p><p>Hardin, Gippie [Barnett Gipson]- youngest brother.
Mentioned:  1877, May 9, Sep 9, Oct 26, Nov 21, undated, Dec 14; 1878 Jan 15, Feb 15, May 30, Jun 15, Jul 4, Jul 9, Aug 16, 30, Oct 10, Nov 17; 1879 Jan 10, 26, Feb 23, Jul 30, Sep 21; 1880 Apr 24, May 27; 1882 May 25. Aug 13; 1885 Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, Aug 3, Sep 5; 1888 Feb 5, </p><p>Hardin, J.[ames] G.[ibson]. - Father, son of Benjamin Hardin and Martha Ann Barnett.  He married Elizabeth Cartwright Dixon in 1847.  They had eight children, five of whom reached maturity.  Hardin was a Methodist circuit rider, a lawyer and a teacher.  He died August, 1876.
Letter To: -1874, Sep 18, 1874
Mentioned:  1877, May 9, Sep 9, Oct 26, undated, Dec 3, 14; 1878 Jan 15, Feb 15, Mar 30, Jun 2, Aug 30; 1882 Apr 2</p><p>Hardin, Jane Bowen (alias Jane Swain, Jennie) -Wife, married February 1872.  Jane died November 6, 1892 while Hardin was still in prison.
Letters To:   1876, (Thomasville, Ga), Sep. 8; 1877 May 6, 9, Jun 6, Aug 25, Sep 12, 16, Oct 14, 26, Dec 5, 14, 29; Nov 25; 1878  Jan 29, Mar 14, 17, 23, 26, Apr 29, May 18, 19, Jun 1, 2, 11, 15, 23, 27, 29, Jul 4, 14, Aug 2, 3, ?, 19, 27, 28, 31, Sep 11, 16, 17, 28, Oct 4, 10, 20, 21, 27, Nov 17, Dec 3, 8, ?, 28 1879 Jan 9, 10, 26, Feb 9, 23, Mar 2, 16, 23, Apr 13, 20, 27, May 4, 11 (note),13, 25, Jun 1, 15, 19, Jul 2, 6, 22, 27, 30, Aug 10, 17, Sep 21 (3), Nov 2; 1880 May 27, Aug 30; 1881 Mar 5, Apr 26, May 1, Jun 1, Jul 3, Aug 14, Sep 25, Dec 14; 1882 Jan 18, Feb 26, Apr 2, May 25, 28, Aug 13, Sep 3, Oct 4; 1883 Feb 16; 1884 Jan 6, Dec 7; 1885 Sep 27, Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, Aug 3, Sep 5, Nov 7; 1887 Mar 27, Sep 4, Nov 6; 1888 Jan 22, Feb 5, Mar 25, May 22, Jun 24, Oct 7; 1890 Apr 6, Nov 2; 1891 Apr 5, Oct 25;1892 Jan 4
Mentioned:  1877, Sep 9, 15, Oct 29, Nov 21, undated; 1878 Jan 15, Feb 15, Feb 26, Mar 11, Mar 30, May 30, Jun 8, Jul 9, Aug 16, 30; 1880 Apr 24, Jul 15; 1882 Aug 28Nov 26; 1886 Mar 7, May 2, Oct 3; 1887 Apr 3; 1889 May 5, Jul 14, Oct 20, Dec 8; </p><p>Hardin, Jeff (Jefferson Davis)-brother.
Mentioned:  1877, May 9, Sep 9, undated, Oct 26-27, Nov 21, 25, undated, Dec 14, 29; 1878 Jan 15, Feb 15, 26, May 30, Jun 8, Jul 4, Aug 16, 30, Oct 10, 20, Dec 28; 1879 Jan 10, Mar 2, 23, Apr 27, Jul 30, Sep 21; 1880 Apr 24, May 27; 1882 May 25, Aug 13; 1885 Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, Aug 3</p><p>Hardin, Jennie (Callie, Jennie Martina, Jane)-daughter born in 1877.  Letter of Jun 15, 1878 refers to the change of her name from Callie to Jane Martina.
Letters To:  1886 May 2; 1887 May 1, Aug 28; 1889 Jul 14, Dec 8; 1892 Aug 28; 1893 Jun 30 
Mentioned:  1878 Mar 17, May 30, Jun 8, 15, 27, Jul 9, Jul 14, Aug 30, Oct 20, Nov 17, Dec 3, 8; 1879 Jan 10, 26, Feb 23, Apr 20, 27, May 4, Jun 1, Jul 6, 30, Sep 21; 1881 Aug 14, Sep 25; 1882 Feb 26, May 25, Aug 13, Sep 3, Oct 1; 1884 Dec 7; 1885 Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, Mar 7, Aug 3, Sep 5, Oct 3, Nov 7; 1889 May 5, Oct 20; 1890 Apr 6, Nov 2; 1891 Apr 5, </p><p>Hardin, Jodie-nephew, son of brother Joseph Hardin.
Mentioned:  1877  Sep 9, 15; 1880 Aug 30, Aug 13</p><p>Hardin [?], John- Cousin[?], possibly son of Robert E. Hardin.
Mentioned:  1877 May 9</p><p>Hardin, John Wesley-b. May 26, 1853
Letters From:  1874, Sep 18; 1876, May 12, Sep 8; 1877 Jun 6, Aug 25; 1878 Jan 29, Mar 14, 17, 26, Apr 29, May 18, Jun 2, 11, 15, 23, 27, Jul 4, 14, Aug 2, 28, 31, Sep 11, 16, 17, 28, Oct 4, 20, 27, Nov 17, Dec 3, 8, ?, 28; 1879 Jan 9, 10, 26, Feb 9, 23, Mar 2, 16, Apr 13, 20, May 4, 11, 25, Jun 1, Jul 6, 27, Aug 10, 17, Sep 21, Nov 2; 1881 Jun 1, Jul 3, Aug 14, Sep 25; 1882 Feb 26, Apr 2, Sep 3; 1884 Jan 6, Dec 7; 1885 Aug 26, Sep 27, Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, Mar 7, May 2, Sep 5, Oct 3, Nov 7; 1887 Mar 27, Apr 3, May 1, Aug 28, Sep 4, Nov 6; 1888 Jan 22, Feb 5, Mar 25, Jun 24, Oct 7; 1889 Feb 1, May 5, Jul 14, Oct 20, Dec 8; 1890 Apr 6, Nov 2; 1891 Apr 5, Oct 25, Sept 11; 1892 Jan 4, Aug 21, 28, 30, Sept 11, Nov 6; 1893 Oct 29, Nov 5; 1894 Jan 1, Aug 22, Oct 4, 14. 
Letters To:   1875, Sep 26; 1876, Jan 24, 26, Mar 23, Apr 27, May 1, May 2, 12, 1877 May 9, Sep 9, 15, Undated, Oct 13, 26, 29, undated, Nov 21, undated, Nov 26, Dec 3, 5; 1878  Jan 15, 31, Feb 15 (2), 17, 26, Mar 11, 30, Apr 6, 7, 16,  May 2?, 30, Jun 7, 8; 1891 Aug 4; 1892 Jan 8, Jan 25, May 18, Jul 5,Jul 17; 1894 Jan 28, Feb 28, Mar 6, 8, 28, 30, Apr 13, 14,16 28, May 9, 20, 23, Jun 22, Aug 4, 16, 23, Sept 1, 20, 28, Oct 4, 6, 7, 15, 21, 22, 28, 31, Nov 2. Dec 1, 30</p><p>Hardin, John Wesley, Jr.-son, B. August 3, 1875.
Letters To:  1886 Mar 7; 1887 Apr 3; 1889 Oct 20; 1892 Aug 28.
Mentioned:  1878 Mar 17, Jun 8, 15, 27, Jul 4, 14, Aug 30, Oct 20, Nov 17, Dec 3; 1879
Jan 10, 26, Feb 23, Apr 27, Jul 6, 30, Aug 17, Sep 21; 1881 Aug 14, Sep 25; 1882 Feb 26, May 25, Aug 13, Oct 1; 1884 Dec 7; 1885 Sep 17, Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, May 2, Aug 3, Sep 5, Oct 3, Nov 7; 1888 Oct 7; 1889 May 5, Jul 14, Dec 8; 1890 Apr 6, Nov 2</p><p>Hardin, Joseph (Jo, Jodie)-brother, b. January 5, 1850.  Lynched in retaliation for the killing of Charles Webb by John Wesley Hardin.
Letters From:  1894 Jan 28
Mentioned:  1877 Oct 26, undated, Dec 14; 1878 Jan 15; 1879 Sep 21; 1880 Aug 30; 1882 Apr 2; 1888 Jun 24; 1889 Jul 14, </p><p>Hardin, Mattie-sister.  See Smith, Mattie Hardin</p><p>Hardin, Mattie [Martha] -cousin, daughter of Robert E. Hardin.
Letter from:  1877 May 9, Sep 9, 12, Oct 14, 29, Nov 26;
Mentioned:  1877, Sep 9, 15, Oct 26</p><p>Hardin, Mollie (Mary Elizabeth) -daughter, b. February 6, 1873.
Letters To:  1880 Apr 24; 1882 Oct 4; 1886 Oct 3; 1889 May 5; 1891 Sept 11; 1892 Aug 21; 1893 Jun 30.
Mentioned:  1877, May 9, Oct 14, 26, Dec 14; 1878 Mar 17, Jun 8, 15, 27, Jul 9, 14, Aug 30, Oct 4, 20, Nov 17, Dec 3; 1879 Jan 10, 26, Feb 23, Mar 16, Apr 27, May 4, 11, 25, Jun 1, 19, Jul 2, 6, 30, Aug 17, Sep 21; 1880 Aug 30; 1881 Mar 5, Apr 26, Aug 14, Sep 25, Dec 14; 1882 Jan 18, Feb 26, May 25, May 28, Aug 13, Sep 3, Oct 1; 1883 Feb 16; 1884 Dec 7; 1885 Sep 27, Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, Mar 7, May 7, Aug 3, Sep 5, Nov 7; 1887 Apr 3; 1888 Feb 5, Oct 7; 1889 Jul 14, Oct 20, Dec 8; 1890 Nov 2;  </p><p>Hardin, Molly E.-cousin.
Letters From:  1878 Jun 7</p><p>Hardin, Nannie-sister.
Letters From:  1878 Jun 8, Jul 9, 1879 Sep 21; 1880 Apr 24; 1894 Oct 28
Letters To:  1879 Feb 23
Mentioned:  1877, May 9, Sep 9, Oct 26-27, Nov 21, 25, undated, Dec 14; 1878 Feb 15, 26, May 30, Jun 15, Aug 16, 30, Oct 10, 20, Nov 17; 1879 Jan 10, Apr 27, Jul 30, Sep 21; 1880 Aug 30; 1882 Feb 26, May 25, Aug 13; 1884 Dec 7; 1885 Nov 22; 1886 Jan 3, Aug 3; 1888 Feb 5; 1891 Apr 5, </p><p>Hardin, Robert E. (Bob) [also R. E. Barnette, Marohn 104]-Uncle, brother to Hardin's father.  Married Nancy Brinson Dixon.  Living on a ranch in Brenham, Washington County, Texas.  Helped harbor Hardin when he was on the run and with legal fees after he was captured.
Letter From:  1877 May 9, 
Mentioned:  Sep 9, 12, undated, Oct 26-27, 29, undated, Nov 26, Dec 5; 1878, Jan 15, Feb 15, Mar 17, Apr 6; 1879 Jul 6</p><p>Hardin, W. B. (Barnett)-cousin in Woodbury, Hill County.  
Letters From:  1878 Mar 15(26), Apr 6
Mentioned:  1877, Sep 9; 1878 Mar 14, Mar 15(26), 17, Apr 7, 19, May 2?; 1879 Jan 9, Jan 10, Jul 30, Sep 21; 1884 Dec 7</p><p>Hardin [?], Will-cousin.  Robert Hardin's son?
Mentioned:  1877 May 9</p><p>Hardy, Shep-friend.  Hardin's logging partner.  Was with Hardin when he was captured.
Mentioned:  1877, Jun 6; </p><p>Harison [Harrison?], James-acquaintance. 
Mentioned:  1878 May 2?</p><p>Hays, Captain Jack - Texas Ranger.
Mentioned:  1879 Sep 21</p><p>Helm, Jack-leader of the Sutton faction.  Member of the State Police and Sheriff of DeWitt County.  Killed by Hardin and Jim Taylor in Cuero 
Mentioned:  1878 Jun 15</p><p>Hendricks, Ben (Captain)-Hotel keeper in Austin.
Mentioned:  1878 no date (mid August), Sep 11; 1879 Apr 13</p><p>Hickock,  Wild Bill (Heycoc)-Marshal of Abilene, Kansas.
Mentioned:  1888 Jun 24</p><p>Hodge [?], Nelson-His case for attempted murder is mentioned by J. H. Clements in a letter to Hardin along with another name that cannot be deciphered.
Mentioned:  1878 Feb 15</p><p>Homesley, Jim-Comanche County resident.
Mentioned:  1878 Oct 20</p><p>Hogg, James A.- Governor of Texas (1891-1895)
    Letters To: 1892 Jan ?; 1893 Oct 29; 1894 Jan 1
    
Howell, E. - Friend of the Hardins</p><p>Letters From : 1893 Jun 30
    
Howell, Frank – Friend of R.R. Coleman
    Letters From : 1894 Oct 21
    
Hudson, R.B. – Sheriff of Dewitt Co. 
    Letters From :  1894 Nov 1</p><p>Jernigan, Lomax - Purity Bowen writes from Florida that Lomax killed relation Steve Jones in a drunken fight in Pollard.  Several Jernigans married into the Bowen family (Parsons, Brown 138)
Mentioned:  1881 May 1</p><p>Jones, B. H.-Probably cousin Barnett Jones who was with Hardin in the John Gates saloon when Hardin was shot by Phil Sublett in 1872.
Mentioned:  1879, Jul 6</p><p>Jones, Caroline-Rents cottage to Hardin as Swain in Jacksonville.
Letters From:  1876 Apr 27 </p><p>Jones, Lizzie - Purity Bowen mentions death in letter from Florida.
Mentioned:  1881 May 1</p><p>Jones, Steve (Steave) - Purity Bowen in letter from Florida mentions Jone's killing in a drunken fight in Pollard, Alabama.
Mentioned:  1881 May 1</p><p>Jones, Willis-Purity Bown calls him uncle and mentions death in letter from Florida.
Mentioned:  1881 May 1</p><p>Jones, W.E. – Sheriff of Gonzales Co.
   Letters From – 1894 Nov 3</p><p>Karnes, Sheriff John-see Carnes</p><p>Kelso, Frank – Friend of R.R. Coleman
    Letters From : 1894 Oct 20
    
Kendrick, M. E.-Jacksonville Florida buyer of beef from Hardin as J. H. Swain.
Letters From:  1876, Jan 26[?], </p><p>Kimbro, Manen-Mannen Clements writes Jane that Kimbro brought him news of her family.
Mentioned:  1879 Mar 23</p><p>King, Fannie - friend of Jane Hardin</p><p>Krueger, O.P. – Friend of J.W. Hardin
    Letters From : 1894 Nov 20
    
Kotzel, - Druggist
    Letters To : 1894 Oct 29</p><p>Landrum, J. C.-teacher of Hardin and brother Joseph.
Mentioned:  1878  Jun 27</p><p>La Opinion Del Pueblo – Gonzales paper – </p><p>Letters From : 1894 Oct 13 – Vol 1 No 2
    
Lay, John - Friend to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Letter From: 1894 May 20, Jun 22.
    
Levyson, P. - General store owner - Gonzales.
    Letters From : 1894 May 23 (bill)
    
Lewis, Callie – see Jennie Hardin
    Letters From : 1894 Dec 30
    
Lewis, Judge-Judge who heard Mannen Clements trial for the killing of Peyton Patterson in Gonzales County during February of 1878.
Mentioned:  1878 Jan 31</p><p>Lipscomb, J A.-Attorney hired by Robert Hardin to defend Hardin 
Letters From:  1877 undated
Mentioned:  1877 Oct 29</p><p>Loide-Mentioned in letter by mother of Bright Smith, Hardin's brother-in-law.  
Mentioned:  1882 May 1</p><p>Long, J.D.- friend of J.W. Hardin.
    Letters From : 1894 Mar 8</p><p>Mann, Jim-friend.  Was with Hardin when he was overpowered on the train in Pensacola.  Mann was shot and killed as he tried to run off the train.
Mentioned:  1877, Aug 25</p><p>Mat-mentioned in 1882 letter from Mattie Odom, living with her in 1883.
Mentioned:  1882 Oct 4; 1883 Feb 16</p><p>Mendoza, M. – Wife of Roman Augurero
    Letters To : 1894 Oct 7
    
McCall, J.D. – Comptroller
    Letters From : 1894 Jan 9
    
McCulloch, Capt. Ben-Superintendent at the Texas Prison System.
Letters To:  1885 Aug 26
Mentioned:  1888 Jan 22</p><p>McGee, Duncan-friend or relative of the Bowens.
Mentioned:  1877, Dec 20</p><p>McKenzie, J. W. T.-friend of Hardin family.
Mentioned:  1877 Oct 26.</p><p>McKinney, A.T. – Prison warden(?)
    Letters To : 1893 Jul 14
    
McMillan, Marion (A. M.)-Jane's cousin, a probate judge in Pollard, Alabama
Letters From:  1877 Sep 16
Letter To:  1877, Aug 25
Mentioned:  1877, May 6</p><p>McMillan, Mary-probably wife of Malcolm McMillan and relation to Jane Bowen.  Mentioned in Purity's letter from Florida.
Mentioned:  1881 May 1</p><p>McMillan, Neill-Jane Bowen's relative.  Deputy sheriff of Pollard, Alabama with whom the Hardins stayed under the name of Swain.
Mentioned:  1877, Jun 6, Dec 5, 20</p><p>McQueen-friend of Jane Hardin.
Mentioned:  1877, May 9</p><p>Moody, Dr. - Doctor in Red River County.
Mentioned:  1879 Apr 27</p><p>Morgan, J. B.-Killed by Hardin in Cuero in 1872.  
Mentioned: 1878 Jun 11</p><p>Newman (Numan), Sunny (Sonny)-friend of Bowens.
Mentioned:  1877 Dec 5, 20</p><p>Nixon, H. A. - Gonzales Attorney.
Letter From:  1890  Mar 7</p><p>Odom, Frankey (Frank)-Mattie Bowen Odom's son, born May 1880.  (Parsons, Bowen  140)
Mentioned:  1881 Mar 5, Apr 26, Dec 14; 1882 Jan 18, May 28; 1883 Feb 16</p><p>Odom, Mattie Bowen - (see also Mattie Bowen)-sister-in-law.  Married Oliver Odom December 1878.
Letters From:  1879 Mar 16, May 13, Jun 15, Jul 22; 1881 Mar 5, Apr 26, Dec 14; 1882 Jan 18, May 28, Oct 4; 1883 Feb 16
Mentioned:  1879, Mar 23; 1881 Aug 14</p><p>Odom, Oliver-married Jane's sister Mattie Bowen.  Is on trial in 1881 according to Mattie's letters.  Parsons reports he was indicted in 1878 for an 1874 murder.  He died June 22, 1881. (Parsons, Bowen 140)
Letter From:  1879 May 13
Mentioned:  1879 Feb 9, Mar 23, Jun 15, Jul 22; 1881 Mar 5, Apr 26</p><p>Outlaw, J. C.-guard through whom Hardin was able to slip out letters.
Mentioned:  1878 Dec 3, 8, 23, 28</p><p>Passmore, Ben-Bowen relation mentioned in letter from Joshua Bowen to Edward B. Bowen.
Mentioned:  1880 Jul 15,</p><p>Patterson, Paten (Peyton, Pate)-Mannen Clements was indicted October 17, 1877 for the killing of Patterson on July 25, 1872.  Clements was arrested December 19, 1877 and won acquittal in 1878.
Mentioned:  1878 Jan 29, Mar 17, May 30</p><p>Phillips , Bill (William) - husband of Nancy Bowen, Jane Hardin's sister. 
Mentioned:  1878  May 2?, Jun 29, Jul 14, Oct 21, 22/27; 1879 Feb 9, Mar 7, May 13[?]</p><p>Phillips, Nancy Bowen -sister-in-law, married to William Phillips. 
Mentioned:  1877 Sep 5, Oct 26, 1878 Jul 14, May 13; 1881 Apr 26; 1882 Apr 2; 1888 May 22</p><p>Powell,[?] Houston-acquaintance, prison inmate.
Mentioned:  1879 May 4,</p><p>Randle, J.P. - General store owner in Gonzales
   Letters To: 1894 - bill - May 9. Aug 4
   
Rauckedt - cousin to Mattie Odem</p><p>Renick, S. H.-attorney in Waco.  Defends Hardin in Webb trial and appeal.
Letters From:  1878  Apr 16
Mentioned:  1878  Mar 17, Apr 6, 19</p><p>Reynolds, Lieutenant-guarded Hardin on his way to Comanche for sentencing and on his way to Huntsville. 
Mentioned:  1878 Oct 4</p><p>Ringo, John - incarcerated in Austin jail at the same time as Hardin.
Mentioned:  1879 Apr 13, Jul 6</p><p>Reuter, Charles - owner Gonzales Ice Works.
    Letters From : 1894 Sept 1 (bill)</p><p>S., John-fellow inmate.  Debates with Hardin in the Debating Society defending the premise that women should have equal rights.
Mentioned:  1881 Jul 3</p><p>S., J. [John] G. [?], friend living in Thomasville, Georgia.  Identity unknown.
Letters To:  1876, Sep 8; </p><p>Sallie-possibly Jane's niece, Frank's daughter.
Mentioned:  1882 May 28</p><p>Schlikeisen, E.F. - Sold J.W. Hardin a horse.
    Letters From : 1894 Aug 10 (bill) 
    
Scott, J. B.-may be same as below.  Promises to be at Hardin's appeal.
Mentioned:  1878  May 2[?]</p><p>Scott, Mr. of Marlin-Mattie Hardin mentions him.  Possibly lawyer hired by Mr. Choat of Karnes County to represent Hardin in his appeal.
Mentioned:  1877 Nov 26</p><p>Shegog, Dr. J. M. - Uncle, married to Elizabeth Hardin's sister, Nan.  Lives in Ennis, Ellis County.
Mentioned:  1878 Apr 7; 1885 May 29; 1886 Aug 3</p><p>Shegog, Nan-Aunt, Elizabeth Hardin's sister living in Ennis.
Mentioned:  1877 May 9, Oct 10; 1878, Feb 17, Dec 3, 8; 1879 Sep 21; 1885 May 29; 1886 Aug 3; 1888 Feb 5</p><p>Shepard, Seth-lawyer.  Robert Hardin tried to hire for Hardin's Comanche County trial
Mentioned:  1877, Sep 9</p><p>Shroeder, Molly-Jennie Hardin's teacher.
Mentioned:  1887 Aug 28</p><p>Smith, Dick-Mentioned in letter from Bright Smith's mother.
Mentioned:  1882 May 1</p><p>Smith, Bright-brother-in-law.  Married Hardin's sister, Mattie.
Letters To:  1879 Mar 16
Mentioned:  1877, May 9, Sep 9, 15, Oct 26-27, Nov 21, 25, Dec 5, 29; 1878 Feb 26, May 30, Jun 15, 23, 27, Jul 4, 14, Oct 4, Oct 10, 20; 1879 Mar 2, Apr 27, Jul 30, Sep 21; 1880 Apr 24, May 27; 1882 Feb 26, May 1, May 25, Aug 13; 1886 Jan 3, Aug 3, 
Smith, L. J. - friend of Hardin's from Jacksonville, Florida.
Mentioned:  1878 Jun 23</p><p>Smith, Lillie-niece, first child of sister Mattie Smith born in 1878
Mentioned:  1878 Mar 11, Jun 15, Oct 10; 1879 Mar 2; 1880 Apr 24; 1886 Aug 3</p><p>Smith, M. A.-Probably Bright Smith's mother.  Bright is married to Hardin's sister, Mattie.
Letter From:  1882 May 1; 1886 Aug 3</p><p>Smith, Mattie Hardin-sister.  Married Bright Smith in 1876.  
Letters To:  1879 Feb 23 (note), Mar 16; 
Letters From:  1877 Sep 15, Nov 21, 25, Dec 29; 1886 Aug 3; 1893 Oct 17
Mentioned:  1877, May 9, Sep 9, 12, Oct 14, 26-27, Nov 21, Dec 5;  1878 Feb 15, 26, Mar 11, Mar 17, Jun 8, 15, 23, Jul 4, 9, 14, Aug 16, 30, 31, Oct 10, 20, Dec 8 1879 Mar 2, Jul 30, Sep 21; 1880 Apr 24; 1882 Feb 2, May 25, Aug 13; 1885 Nov 
22; 1886 Jan 3</p><p>Smith, J.F - County clerk- Brown Co.
    Letters from:  1893 May 29
    
Smither, Capt. J. G..-prison assistant superintendent.
Letters To:   1889 [?]; 1893 Oct 29, Nov ?; 1894 Feb 7
Mentioned:  1890 Apr 6; 1891 Aug 4</p><p>Steadman, Ed-Prison inmate who had helped John Ringo and George Cooley break out of the Lampasas County jail.
Mentioned:  1879 Apr 13</p><p>Stephens, J. D. (Stevens)-Prosecuting attorney at Hardin's Comanche County trial.
Mentioned:  1877 Oct 26, undated, Dec 5</p><p>Steward, Joe-Acquaintance in Austin.
Mentioned:  1878 Aug 28; 1879 Apr 13</p><p>Sunday, Joe-brother to Neill Bowen's second wife, Purity.  (Parsons, 46)
Mentioned:  1878, May 2?, Aug 2</p><p>Sutton faction-
Mentioned:  1877 May 6; 1878 Jun 15; 1879 Apr 13</p><p>Swain, Jane-see Jane Bowen Hardin.
Letters To:  1877 May 6, 9, Jun 6, Aug 25</p><p>Swain, Jennie-Acquaintance of the Hardins in Brenham.
Mentioned:  1877 May 9, Sep 12</p><p>Swain, J. H.-see John Wesley Hardin.  Takes alias after he flees Texas in late 1874.  He adopts the last name of the Brenham marshal, Harry Swain, who helped Hardin get out of Texas.
Letter From:  1876- May 12; 1877 (Millview, Florida) Jun 6, Aug 25
Letter To:   1875, Sep 25; 1876, Jan 24, 26, Mar 23, Apr 27, May 1, May 2, 12; 1877 May 9, Jun 6, Aug 25</p><p>Talmadge, Rev. T. De Witt-syndicated columnist.  Hardin is inspired by his teaching and sends clipping to Jane.
Mentioned:  1888 Mar 25 (with clippings)</p><p>Taylor, Billy-son of Pitkin Taylor who was killed by the Sutton faction in 1872.  With the help of Hardin, Billy along with his brother attacked Bill Sutton on a steamer in Indianola, Texas on March 11, 1874.  Billy Taylor killed Sutton's companion, Gabriel Slaughter.  In 1877, Taylor was in an Austin jail for this killing at the same time as Hardin.
Mentioned:  1877 May 6, May 9; 1878 Jan 29, Jun 15, 27</p><p>Taylor, James- Son of Pitkin Taylor born 1852 and a leader in the Sutton-Taylor feud.  Along with Hardin, killed Jack Helm July 1873.  With the help of Hardin, along with brother Billy Taylor, killed Bill Sutton on a steamer in Indianola, March 11, 1874.  Taylor himself was killed by a Sutton posse in Clinton, Texas on December 27, 1875. 
Mentioned:  1877 May 6, May 9, Oct 29</p><p>Taylor, J.M. - Friend of J.W. Hardin.</p><p>Letter from: 1894 Apr, 28. Oct 31
    
Taylor, Scrap-Lynched after Webb killing.
Mentioned:  1879 May 11</p><p>Templeton, Bill-prison inmate.
Mentioned:  1879 Apr 13</p><p>Tennille, Mrs. [Amanda Jane Billings]
Mentioned:  1877, May 6</p><p>Tennille, Tony-married Nannie Cobb.
Mentioned:  1877, May 6, Sept 5</p><p>TEXAS, STATE OF
    Letters To : 1893 Oct 17 (Cooke Co.); 1894 Aug 10 (Gonzales Co.), Oct 27 (Gonzales Co.),  Oct 31 (Gonzales Co.), Nov 1 (Gonzales Co.), Dec 16 (DeWitt Co. – Hardin/Billings marriage certificate)
    
Tom-Hardin writes Jane to tell Mannen that Tom is all right.
Mentioned:  1878 Oct 4</p><p>Turner, Mr.-J. H. Clements thanks for "kindness and indulgence" to Mannen Clements during his Austin incarceration.  
Mentioned:  1878  Jan 31</p><p>Turner, Sara -Cousin
Mentioned:  1879 July 30</p><p>Tyler, Marcus-Oliver Odom reports to Mannen Clements that Tyler has several indictments against him.
Mentioned:  1879 May 13</p><p>Unknown
Letter From:  1876 Jan 24</p><p>Vancleaves, Mat - Jane's sister Matt and her husband Oliver Odom live with the Vancleaves in 1879.</p><p>Vandegriff, Major-Ranger wrote Hardin from Austin that Jane had started for his mother's home in October 1878.
Mentioned:  1878  Oct 10, 21</p><p>Wad-Has been identified as Wes but the text of the letter indicates it is more likely written to a person living and working in the free world. The 1880 Gonzales County Census lists a Wadkin Ellis, a 45 year old farmer, living near the Bowens.
Letter To:  1882 Nov 26</p><p>Waller, Bill-Ranger that hunted Hardin after the Webb killing.
Mentioned:  1878 Oct 20</p><p>Webb, Charles-Deputy Sheriff of Brown County killed by Hardin on April 1874.  Hardin received a sentence for 25 years in the penitentiary for the killing.
Mentioned:  1877 Oct 26, 29, Nov 21, undated, Dec 5; 1888 Jun 24; 1889 Jul 14</p><p>West, M.L. – Bondsman in Floresville, TX.
    Letters From : 1894 Oct 15
    
Whattley, D.A. Superintendent of State Penitentiaries, Huntsville. 
    Letters From: 1891 Aug 4; 
    
White, Mr. - mentioned in letter from Mattie Odom in 1882.  He might move out west
Mentioned:  1882 Oct 4</p><p>Willard, E. E.-City Clerk in Jacksonville Florida who records Hardin's (alias Swain) payments on a stall in the meat market.
Letters From:  1876, May 1 (2)</p><p>Wilson, Frank-Deputy sheriff of Comanche County present at Webb killing.
Mentioned:  1877, Sep 9; 1878 Oct 4, Oct 27</p><p>Wingate, J.F. – Prison mate of J.W. Hardin
    Letters From : 1894 Oct 21</p><p>Wright family - Friends of Jane's.  Mattie Odom tells Jane to say hello 
Mentioned:  1881 Dec 14; 1882 Jan 18, Feb 26</p>  </scopecontent>
  <prefercite encodinganalog="524" id="aspace_e5754bcdc501f106d67737a9783fe5ea">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>John Wesley Hardin Papers, The Wittliff Collections, Texas State University.</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="aspace_2b31fbdc06c07f0ebfb6861e984f67dc">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Materials from the Wittliff Collections are made available for use in research, teaching, and private study.  The user assumes responsibility for determining copyright status, obtaining permission to publish, and abiding by U.S. copyright laws. <extref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:type="simple" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href ='https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu/research/visit/policies/publication.html'>https://www.thewittliffcollections.txstate.edu/research/visit/policies/publication.html</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess><controlaccess>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh85096166" source="lcsh">Outlaws</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Frontier and pioneer life -- Texas</subject>
    <genreform authfilenumber="sh99001488" source="lcsh">Correspondence</genreform>
    <persname authfilenumber="n79068394" source="lcnaf">Hardin, John Wesley, 1853-1895</persname>
  </controlaccess></controlaccess>
  <dsc type="in-depth"><c01 id="aspace_b5a5e26b28cef00e1c4bad202ac70547" level="series"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1874/1895" type="inclusive">1874-1895, undated</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_0b9f64b0e01d04b41df7c2a264b74533" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1874/1877" type="inclusive">1874-1877</unitdate><container id="aspace_4f54cf5d4d19be58f4fb5885487a1815" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_2964843e05b4541c854ff881c69ea6b2" parent="aspace_4f54cf5d4d19be58f4fb5885487a1815" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_979999173e8d9800045f144c168070e1"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Sept 8, 1874.  J.W. Hardin to J.G. Hardin</p><p>Sept 25, 1875.  Joseph DeMartini to J.H. Swain </p><p>Jan 24, 1876.  [Unknown] to J.H. Swain</p><p>Jan 2[6], 1876.  M.E. Kendrick to J.H. Swain</p><p>Mar 23, 1876.  L.M. Downing to J.H. Swain</p><p>Apr 27, 1876.  C. Jones to J.H. Swain</p><p>May 1, 1876.  E.E. Willard to J.H. Swain</p><p>May 1, 1876.  E.E. Willard to L.M. Downing</p><p>May 2, 1876.  B.R. Dinkins to J.H. Swain</p><p>May 12, 1876.  J.H. Swain to Mr. Benham</p><p>May 12, 1876.  [Unknown] to J.H. Swain</p><p>Sep 8, 1876.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>May 6, 1877.  Joshua Bowden to Jane Swain</p><p>May 9, 1877.  R.E. Barnette to J.H. Swain</p><p>Jun 6, 1877.  J.H. Swain to Jane Swain</p><p>Aug 25, 1877.  J.H. Swain to Jane Swain</p><p>Sep 5, 1877.  Mattie Bowen to Jane Hardin</p><p>Sept 8, 18[77].  J.W. Hardin to [Friend]  [Photocopy]</p><p>Sept 9, 1877.  Mattie Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Sept 9, 1877.  Elizabeth Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Sept 9, 1877.  Alie B. Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Sept 9, 1877.  Mattie Hardin to J.W. Hardin  [Missing]</p><p>Sept 12, 1877.  Mattie Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Sept 15, 1877.  Mattie Smith to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Sept 16, 1877.  Marion McMillan to Jane Swain[unknown]  Lizzie Cobb to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 13, 1877.  Doc J. An to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 14, 1877.  Mattie Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Oct 26, 1877.  Elizabeth Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 26, 1877.  William Bowen to Jane Hardin  [Missing w/note]</p><p>Oct 26, 1877.  Mattie Bowen to Jane Hardin</p><p>Oct 27, 18[77].  Elizabeth Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 29, 1877.  Mattie Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>[unknown]  A.J. Lipscomb to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Nov 21, 1877.  Mattie Smith to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Nov 25, 1877.  Mattie Smith to Jane Hardin</p><p>[unknown] Elizabeth Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Nov 26, 1877.  Mattie Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Dec 3, 1877.  A.C. Dikes to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Dec 5, 1877.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Dec 14, 1877.  Elizabeth Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Dec 20, 1877.  Mattie Bowen to Jane Hardin</p><p>Dec 29, 1877.  Mattie Smith to Jane Hardin</p><p>[unknown]  R.E. Barnette to Jane Hardin</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_2b7edc8cb19f881bbc514238005beba8" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1878/1878">1878</unitdate><container id="aspace_3382f788e7b35005128b468e59591dee" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_ae989db4e2bb98748b004459495b4b69" parent="aspace_3382f788e7b35005128b468e59591dee" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_4953fe84eba62f3a8ee2f0e205378e2a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Jan 15, 1878.  Elizabeth Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jan 29, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jan 31, 1878.  J.H. Clements to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Feb 15, 1878.  Elizabeth Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Feb 15, 1878.  J.H. Clements to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Feb 17, 1878.  Lizzie Cobb to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Feb 26, 1878.  Elizabeth Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Mar 11, 1878.  Lizzie Cobb to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Mar 14, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Mar 17, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Mar 9, 1878.  Mary C. Campbell to Jane Hardin</p><p>Mar 15, 1878.  John C. Godfrey &amp; W. B. Hardin to J.W. Hardin [Verso] Mar 26, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin &amp; Mother, Sisters &amp; Brothers</p><p>Mar 30, 1878.  Elizabeth Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Apr 6, 1878.  W.B. Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Apr 7, 1878.  John C. Godfrey to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Apr 16, 1878.  S.H. Renick to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Apr 19, 1878.  Mattie Bowen to Jane Hardin</p><p>Apr 29, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>May 18, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>May 2[1], 1878.  Mannen Clements to J.W. Hardin</p><p>May 30, 1878.  Elizabeth Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jun 1, 1878.  Mannen Clements to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jun 2, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jun 7, 1878.  Molly E. Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jun 8, 1878.  Nannie Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jun 11, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jun 15, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jun 23, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jun 27, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jun 29, 1878.  Mattie Bowen to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jul 4, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jul 9, 1878.  Nannie Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jul 14, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Aug 2, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Aug 3, 1878.  Mannen Clements to Jane Hardin</p><p>[unknown]  S.E.H. to Jane Hardin</p><p>Aug 16, 1878.  Elizabeth Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Aug 19, 1878.  Mattie Bowen to Jane Hardin</p><p>Aug 27, 1878.  Mannen Clements to Jane Hardin</p><p>Aug 28, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Aug 30, 1878.  Elizabeth Hardin to J.W. &amp; Jane Hardin</p><p>Aug 31, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Sept 11, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Sept 16, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Sept 17, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Sept 24, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Oct 4, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Oct 10, 1878.  Elizabeth Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Oct 20, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>[Oct 20, 1878].  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Oct 21, 1878.  Mannen Clements to Jane Hardin</p><p>[Oct 22] 1878.  John S. Vandegriff to J.W. Hardin [Verso] Oct 27, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Nov 17, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Dec 3, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Dec 8, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin &amp; Elizabeth Hardin</p><p>Dec 23, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Dec 28, 1878.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_e9ffd018e6c4e81bfc6057a066ff0c64" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1879/1879">1879</unitdate><container id="aspace_f20543746c617c9d1e9c262c7b653269" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_34692742e223e0b0c6aaa61245bb6048" parent="aspace_f20543746c617c9d1e9c262c7b653269" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_97a254a37d8f0256e8ae59b1b80879e6"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Jan 9, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jan 10, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jan 26, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Feb 9, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Feb 23, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Mar 2, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Mar 16, 1879.  Mattie Odom to Jane Hardin</p><p>Mar 16, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Mattie Smith &amp; Jane Hardin</p><p>Mar 23, 1879.  Mary A. Clements to Jane Hardin</p><p>Apr 13, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Apr 20, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Apr 27, 1879.  Elizabeth Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>May 4, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>May 11, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to M. Clements &amp; Jane Hardin</p><p>May 13, 1879.  Mattie Odom to Jane Hardin</p><p>May 13, 1879.  Oliver Odom to Jane Hardin</p><p>May 25, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin &amp; M. Clements</p><p>Jun 1, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jun 15, 1879.  Mattie Odom to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jun 19, 1879.  S.J. Clements to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jul 2, 1879.  M.J. Cobb to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jul 6, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin &amp; M. Clements</p><p>Jul 22, 1879.  Mattie Odom to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jul 27, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin &amp; M. Clements</p><p>Jul 30, 1879.  Elizabeth Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Aug 10, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin &amp; M. Clements</p><p>Aug 17, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin &amp; [Cousin]</p><p>Sept 21, 1879.  Elizabeth Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Sept 21, 1879.  Nannie Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Sept 21, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin &amp; Mollie and Cousin</p><p>Nov 2, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_1337959417cbd53bd65725fc8d69a2f6" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1880/1888" type="inclusive">1880-1888</unitdate><container id="aspace_64fe108b0c3c1a253ea481bb5629a312" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_557e0fc3d1f91bfc9c3322138b3a6acc" parent="aspace_64fe108b0c3c1a253ea481bb5629a312" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_85b33f6b49a8744ef399fe23abaef7aa"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Apr 24, 1880.  Nannie Hardin to Mollie Hardin</p><p>May 27, 1880.  Elizabeth Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jul 13, 1880.  Edward Bowen to copy book</p><p>July 15, 1880.  Joshua Bowen to Edward Bowen</p><p>Aug 30, 1880.  Elizabeth Hadin to Jane Hardin</p><p>March 5, 1881.  Mattie Odom to Jane Hardin</p><p>Apr 26, 1881.  Mattie Odom to Jane Hardin</p><p>May 1, 1881.  Purity Bowen to Jane Hardin</p><p>June 3, 1881.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jul 3, 1881.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Aug 14, 1881.  J.W Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Sept 25, 1881.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Dec 14, 1881.  Mattie Odom to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jan 18, 1882.  Mattie to Jane Hardin</p><p>Feb 26, 1882.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>[Feb-Mar] 1882.  Professor Peace and Scholars to [Unknown]</p><p>Apr 2, 1882.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>May [1] 1882.  M.A. Smith to [Daughter]</p><p>May [28] 1882.  Mattie Odom to Jane Hardin</p><p>Aug 13, 1882.  Elizabeth Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Sept 3, 1882.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Oct 1, 1882.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Oct 1, 1882.  Mattie Odom to Jane Hardin [Missing]</p><p>Oct 4, 1882.  Mattie Odom to Jane Hardin &amp; Mollie Hardin</p><p>Nov 26, 1882.  Neill Bowen to Wad</p><p>Feb 16, 1883.  Mattie Odom to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jan 6, 1884.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Dec 7, 1884.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>May 29, 1885.  J.M. Shegog, RE: Elizabeth Hardin's funeral</p><p>Aug 26, 1885.  J.W. Hardin to B. McCulloch</p><p>Sept 27, 1885.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Nov 22, 1885.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jan 3, 1886.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Mar 7, 1886.  J.W. Hardin to J. Hardin, Jr.</p><p>May 2, 1886.  J.W. Hardin to Jennie Hardin</p><p>Aug 3, 1886.  Mattie Smith to Jane Hardin</p><p>Sept 5, 1886.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Oct 3, 1886.  J.W. Hardin to Mollie Hardin</p><p>Nov 7, 1886.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Mar 27, 1887.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Apr 3, 1887.  J.W. Hardin to J. Hardin, Jr.</p><p>May 1, 1887.  J.W. Hardin to Jennie Hardin </p><p>Aug 28, 1887.  J.W. Hardin to Jennie Hardin</p><p>Sept 4, 1887.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Nov 6, 1887.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jan 22, 1888.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Feb 5, 1888.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Mar 25, 1888.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>May 22, 1888.  [F.M. Bond] to Jane Hardin</p><p>June 24, 1888.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Oct 7, 1888.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Dec 25, 1888.  Prison Playbill</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_4d7eb39a976e059fb483eccef8d50e4f" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1889/1893" type="inclusive">1889-1893</unitdate><container id="aspace_e2005da0ab104eadce458d8bef92a69f" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_4d906b5cf82b1f3015d6a3928330fd33" parent="aspace_e2005da0ab104eadce458d8bef92a69f" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d0f3abb36c396e6dfc8525c003045f1c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Jan 8 [1889].  J.W. Hardin to Molly Hardin</p><p>Jan 22 [1889].  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>[unknown]  J.W. Hardin to Captain Smithers</p><p>Feb 1, 1889.  J.W. Hardin to Texas Legislature</p><p>Apr 15, 1889.  C. Eckhardt &amp; Sons to Jane Hardin</p><p>May 5, 1889.  J.W. Hardin to Molly Hardin</p><p>July 14, 1889.  J.W. Hardin to Jennie Hardin</p><p>Oct 20, 1889.  J.W. Hardin to J. Hardin, Jr.</p><p>Dec 8, 1889.  J.W. Hardin to Jennie Hardin</p><p>Mar 7, 1890.  H.A. Nixon to J.E. Hooper</p><p>Apr 6, 1890.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Nov 2, 1890.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Apr 5, 1891.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Aug 4, 1891.  D.A. Whattley to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 25, 1891.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>[Sept] 11, [1891].  [J.W. Hardin] to Mollie Hardin</p><p>[unknown]  Mattie Odem to [Mr.] Rauckedt</p><p>[unknown]  Fannie King to Jane Hardin</p><p>[unknown]  Mollie Anglin to Jane Hardin</p><p>[unknown]  [Jas] Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jan 4, 1892.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin</p><p>Jan 8, 1892.  Fly &amp; McNeal to J.W. Hardin</p><p>[unknown]  Citizens of Gonzales to Gov. J.S. Hogg</p><p>[Jan 25, 1891].  Fly &amp; McNeal to J.W. Hardin</p><p>May 18, 1892.  Fly &amp; McNeal to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jul 17, 1892.  James Anderson to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Aug 21, 1892.  J.W. Hardin to Molly Hardin</p><p>Aug 28, 1892.  J.W. Hardin to J. Hardin, Jr.</p><p>Aug 30, 1892.  J.W. Hardin to [Unknown]  [Missing]</p><p>Sept 11, 1892.  J.W. Hardin to J.B. Cobb</p><p>Oct 24, 1892.  [Unknown] to W.J. Gary</p><p>Nov 6, 1892.  J.W. Hardin to J.B. Cobb</p><p>Nov 28, 1892.  Notice of death for Jane Hardin     </p><p>May 18, 1893.  [Unknown] to J.B. Cobb [Missing]</p><p>[unknown, 1893]  [J.W. Hardin] to J. Smither</p><p>May 29, 1893.  J.F. Smith to [Unknown]</p><p>Jun 29, 1893.  E. Howell to Mollie Hardin &amp; Jennie Hardin</p><p>Jul 14, 1893.  K.R. Blackshear to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jul 14, 1893.  K.R. Blackshear to A.T. McKinney</p><p>Oct 17, 1893.  Mattie Smith to State of Texas [Attached] Oct 17, 1893.  J.W. Hardin to State of Texas</p><p>Oct 29, 1893.  J.W. Hardin to Governor J.S. Hogg [Attached] Dec 24, 1891.  [County Clerk] to State of Texas</p><p>Oct 29, 1893.  J.W. Hardin to J.G. Smither</p><p>Nov 5, 1893.  J.W. Hardin to W.S. Fly</p><p>[unknown]  Nannie Hardin to [Unknown]</p><p>[unknown]  [J.W. Hardin] to State of Texas[unknown]  </p><p>[Unknown] to [Unknown]</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_62536fadac2d43503d6bbc9aa69d5dd3" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1894/1894">1894</unitdate><container id="aspace_867d6502515f496fd7c9ea0d95c61952" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_e6191ac0f73fb61dfe8217c527408e38" parent="aspace_867d6502515f496fd7c9ea0d95c61952" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_77e9cd0fffa4d2cf2cf232e73abddc92"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>[unknown, 1894]  J.W. Hardin to [Unknown]</p><p>[unknown]  D.C. Price &amp; Co. to [Unknown]</p><p>Jan 1, 1894.  J.W. Hardin to Governor J.S. Hogg</p><p>Jan 2, 1894.  Callie Lewis to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jan 9, 1894.  J.D. McCall to K.R. Blackshear</p><p>Jan 28, 1894.  J.S. Hardin to J.W. Hardin</p><p>[Feb, 1894]  Barnett Gibbs to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Feb 7, 1894.  K.R. Blackshear to J.G. Smither</p><p>Feb 28, 1894.  R.M. Glover to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Mar 6, 1894.  J.B. Ashe to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Mar 8, 1894.  J.D. Long to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Mar 27, 1894.  Tom Bell to R.M. Glover</p><p>Mar 28, 1894.  R.M. Glover to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Mar 30, 1894.  Tom Bell to R.M. Glover &amp; R.M. Glover to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Apr 13, 1894.  R.M. Glover to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Apr 14, 1894.  F.D. Bishop to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Apr 14, 1894.  Tom Bell to R.M. Glover</p><p>Apr 16, 1894.  R.M. Glover to J.W. Hardin</p><p>[Apr, 1894]  R.W. Finley to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Apr 28, 1894.  J.M. Taylor to J.W. Hardin</p><p>May 9, 1894.  J.P. Randle to J.W. Hardin</p><p>May 20, 1894.  John Lay to J.W. Hardin</p><p>May 23, 1894.  P. Levyson to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jun 22, 1894.  [Thom Lay] to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Aug 4, 1894.  J.P. Randle to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Aug 10, 1894.  E.F. Schlikeisen to State of Texas</p><p>Aug 10, 1894.  E.F. Schlikeisen to State of Texas</p><p>Aug 16, 1894.  J.B. Ashe to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Aug 22, 1894.  J.W. Hardin to J. Buchanan</p><p>Aug 23, 1894.  J.B. Ashe to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Sept 11, 1894.  Charles Reuter to [Unknown]</p><p>Sept 15, 1894.  Gilbert Book Co. to D. Cobb</p><p>Sept 20, 1894.  J.B. Ashe to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Sept 28, 1894.  Gilbert Book Co. to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 3, 1894.  John Taylor to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 4, 1894.  J.W. Hardin to J. Clements</p><p>Oct 4, 1894.  Mary Barnett to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 6, 1894.  M. Blackburn to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 7, 1894.  Louis Auguero to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 7, 1894.  Roman Auguero to M. Merrdosa</p><p>Oct 8, 1894.  Louis Auguero to [J.W. Hardin]</p><p>Oct 13, 1894.  La Opinion Del Pueblo, Vol. 1 No. 2[unknown]  [J.W. Hardin] to The People of Gonzalez County</p><p>Oct 15, 1894.  M.L. West to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 17, 1894.  R.M. Glover to [Unknown]</p><p>Oct 20, 1894.  Frank Kelso to R.R. Coleman</p><p>Oct 21, 1894.  J.F. Wingate to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 21, 1894.  Frank Howell to R. Coleman</p><p>Oct 22, 1894.  B. Bratton to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 27, 1894.  F.B. Houston to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 27, 1894.  J. Denson to State of Texas</p><p>[unknown]  [Denson] to [Unknown]</p><p>Oct 28, 1894.  N. Witt to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Oct 29, 1894.  F. Diedrich to [Kotzel]</p><p>[unknown]  [D.C. Price] to [Unknown]</p><p>Nov 1, 1894.  R.B. Hudson to State of Texas</p><p>Nov 1, 1894.  S.H. Cresap to State of Texas</p><p>Nov 2, 1894.  R.R. Coleman to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Nov 3, 1894.  W.E. Jones to Voters of Gonzales</p><p>[unknown]  [Unknown] to [Unknown]</p><p>Nov 20, 1894.  O.P. Krueger to Joe Barbisch</p><p>Dec 1, 1894.  R.M. Glover to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Dec 16, 1894.  Marriage certificate for Charles Billings and Mollie Hardin</p><p>Dec 30, 1894.  Callie Lewis to J.W. Hardin</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5a5203bb8ca676b7f5350827d9b69318" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1895/1895">1895</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d59c6cd005cb5e2f16417e2bf3d357e" label="Text" type="box">1</container><container id="aspace_3902391a3824fb6671b0ae7f478013c5" parent="aspace_7d59c6cd005cb5e2f16417e2bf3d357e" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_1a202995b5174fd3a5ed288ffb52e963"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Jan 11, 1895.  P.M. Smith to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jan 14, 1895.  A.O. Hamon &amp; Co. to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jan 14, 1895.  A.O. Hamon &amp; Co. to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jan 18, 1895.  [Unknown] to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jan 23, 1895.  Capt. Lewis to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jan 26, 1895.  [Unknown] to J.W. Hardin[unknown]  J.B. Miller to [J.W. Hardin] [Attached] [unknown] [Martin Hardin] to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Feb 5, 1895.  Annie Lewis to [Unknown]</p><p>Feb 5, 1895.  [A.D. Weston] to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Feb 10, 1895.  [J.D. Hargis] to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Feb 12, 1895.  J.B. Miller to J.W. Hardin[unknown]  Blank check from The Pecos Valley Bank</p><p>Feb 22, 1895.  W.C. McGown to J.W. Hardin[unknown]  Blank office form of U.S. Bateman</p><p>Feb 28, 1895.  W.H. Smith to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Mar 4, 1895.  Capt. Lewis to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Mar 4, 1895.  Bettie Lewis to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Mar 6, 1895.  Samuel Glover to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Mar 6, 1895.  J.H. Clements to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Mar 23, 1895.  Capt. Lewis to J.W. Hardin[unknown]  Business card of J.W. Hardin </p><p>Apr 6, 1895.  Felipe Leijas to [Unknown]</p><p>Apr 15, 1895.  [Unknown] to J.W. Hardin</p><p>May 27, 1895.  Injunction Writ [Unknown] to [Unknown]</p><p>[unknown]  Affidavit for change of venue[unknown]  F.B. Simmons to [Unknown]</p><p>[Jun 2, 1895]  [Unknown] to J.W. Hardin</p><p>[Jun 3, 1895]  [D.L.  Kemp] to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jun 16, 1895.  W.D. Allison to J.W. Hardin</p><p>[Jun 18, 1895]  R.M. Glover to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jul 11, 1895.  J.H. Flynh to J.W. Hardin &amp; [Unknown] to J.H. Flynh</p><p>Jul 7, 1895.  A.G. Weston to J.W. Hardin</p><p>Jul 28, 1895.  J.D. Hargis to J.W. Hardin[unknown] </p><p>[Unknown] to [Unknown]</p><p>Envelopes</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_ee685cb82cd23fb1d6acf75455100115" level="series"><did><unittitle>Law School Notes</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1886/1889" type="inclusive">1886-1889, undated</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ceb582161f58840d1e5ed6e50c67dfe0"><head>Series Description</head><p>This series contains hand-written legal exams and papers.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_562695fcd8b21a7f13cc0d715313d997" level="file"><did><unittitle>Law School Notes</unittitle><container id="aspace_479408f73063e70094d3455c47a7c980" label="Text" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_1e646ed3279821004cb14db04fa46ffd" parent="aspace_479408f73063e70094d3455c47a7c980" type="folder">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6b2b37e5049a8e4a91f24f51422491ea"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>"Questions on contracts and Sales Junior Law Class Jan 25, 1887"</p><p>"Different Actions at Common Law, and what recoverable byeach"</p><p>"Review Questions [on 4 Blackstone]"</p><p>"Examination in Blackstone '84 O.M. Roberts"</p><p>"Chief Justices of The Republic of Texas from 1836 to 1845"</p><p>"Feb 1884"</p><p>"Questions on Contracts &amp; Sales 1885"</p><p>"No. 64""Final Examination, June 6th 1886"</p><p>"Questions for the Senior Law Class, 30th Jan., 1889."</p><p>"Questions for the Junior Law Class"</p><p>"Junior Law Class 'Examination by O.M. Roberts' Feb 4 1886"</p><p>"Junior Law Class 'O.M. Roberts' not exact questions but boiled down"</p><p>"University of Texas Examination of the Junior Law Class, by O.M. Roberts, Professor, January 29, 1887"</p><p>"Examination Questions in Blackstone"</p><p>"[Provided] by O.M. Roberts Questions for Junior law class"</p><p>"Questions for the Senior Law Class, 30th Jan., 1889."</p><p>"Manslaughter is the unlawful killing"</p><p>"University of Texas.  Law Department. February 4th, 1889."</p><p>"University of Texas.  Law Department. February 5th, 1889."</p><p>"Second Semi-Annual Report of Upsilon Chapter of Sigma Nu"</p><p>"Sample Pages of Early Laws of Texas"</p><p>"Precedents and Rules of Pleading in Civil Actions"</p><p>"Sample Pages A treatise on the Civil Jurisdiction"</p><p>"Catalogue Gilbert Book Co. Saint Louis"</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_df0319cccbda0c10f8469f51e5b8d96f" level="series"><did><unittitle>Family Correspondence and Memorabilia</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1897/1931" type="inclusive">1897-1931, undated</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_3b347364da06ba4ca9e7e13247be1972"><head>Series Description</head><p>This series contains Hardin family correspondence and other memorabilia.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_cd8516234d9a3f346f5c37d8d4601fc1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Family Correspondence and Memorabilia </unittitle><container id="aspace_5fd0f02aeb8bd148db18ffd41544fac6" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_02ceb1d75067f3ddf5791c02a0c3d785" parent="aspace_5fd0f02aeb8bd148db18ffd41544fac6" type="folder">2</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_fb1677a6a97bc7736f7a10d26da9ed58"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>"Why Do You Swear?" signed by J.W. HardinPages from a small notebook, unsigned and undated</p><p>Pages from a small notebook, unsigned and undated</p><p>Invitation card for F.H. Cobb</p><p>Hotel-Charco advertisement</p><p>Iron City National Bank advertisement</p><p>Harper Illustrating Syndicate advertisement</p><p>The American Monthly Review of Reviews promotion dated December 14, 1897</p><p>London Crayon Portrait Co. promotion</p><p>Receipt of purchase from Fred Diedrich</p><p>"Flirtation poetry" by J.B. Cainey</p><p>"Programme" </p><p>Loose pages from a pocket Bible</p><p>[Oct 20, unknown][May Hardin] to John Hardin</p><p>Marriage license for John W Hardin and Lily Hause</p><p>"The Language System of Penmanship"</p><p>[Apr 15, unknown]  J.B. Cobb to John Hardin</p><p>Jan 17, 1902.  [Unknown] to John Hardin</p><p>Oct 17, 1910.  [Unknown] to John Hardin</p><p>Nov 2, 1931.  W.B. Teagarden to Mrs. Charles Billings</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_7a56adaeefb682de211b18f57032e9fa" level="series"><did><unittitle>Newspaper Articles</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1894/1950" type="inclusive">1894-1950, undated</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ae18994f695a60bb6e705e1c5660d7f3"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>This series contains clippings that relate to Hardin.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_882758a3c14aef3d5b851a6f873dbd6d" level="file"><did><unittitle>Newspaper Articles</unittitle><container id="aspace_da286490ba31707c4fd9b004e6367039" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_06ca73a91d749b038cc414d9db2614c5" parent="aspace_da286490ba31707c4fd9b004e6367039" type="folder">3</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_b725c705ad31f03554230097017b615a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Jan 1, [unknown].  "Hardin on Trial"</p><p>Jan 1, [unknown].  "Hardin on Trial"[Photocopy]</p><p>[unknown]  "Pleading For Pardon"[Photocopy]</p><p>[Sept 17, 1894]  [The Semi-Weekly Drag Net][Photocopy]</p><p>Oct 13, 1894.  Waelder Local. </p><p>[Oct 11, 1894]  [The Gonzales Inquirer][Photocopy]</p><p>Oct 12, 1894.  [The Semi-Weekly Drag Net][Photocopy]</p><p>Oct 13, 1894.  La Opinion Del Pueblo.[Photocopy]</p><p>Oct 13, 1894.  [The Gonzales Inquirer][Photocopy]</p><p>Oct 25, 1894.  The Semi-Weekly Drag Net.[Photocopy]</p><p>Oct 23, 1894.  [The Gonzales Inquirer][Photocopy]</p><p>[Nov 1, 1894]  [The Semi-Weekly Drag Net][Photocopy]</p><p>[Nov 1, 1894]  [The Gonzales Inquirer][Photocopy]</p><p>Nov 2, 1894.  The Semi-Weekly Drag Net.[Photocopy]</p><p>[Jan 9, 1895]  [The Kimble County Citizen][Photocopy]</p><p>[Apr 24, 1895]  [El Paso Daily Tribune][Photocopy]</p><p>May 4, 1895.  The Evening Tribune.[Photocopy]</p><p>June 13, 1895.  The Evening Tribune.[Photocopy]</p><p>Mar 3, 1930.  The San Antonio Light.[Photocopy]</p><p>Feb 8, 1937.  The San Antonio Light.[Photocopy]</p><p>Feb 24, 1938.  Kerrville Mountain Sun.[Photocopy]</p><p>Jan 8, 1950.  "Soft-hearted." The American Weekly.[Photocopy]</p></scopecontent></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_95f862ad7948bb28662530732e15ae49" level="series"><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1894/1950" type="inclusive">circa 1873-1887, undated</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_741a4e30b4b20e786c89a55e41893bf6"><head>Series Description</head><p>This series contains photographs of Hardin's family, many of the subjects are identified.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_5a592a91dadaa346f7d8f887557b3df9" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1873/1877" type="inclusive">circa 1873-1877, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_b3aa517b767c3241203e41554ce94052" label="Graphic Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_fc829231894326e486bfd3d32717c721" parent="aspace_b3aa517b767c3241203e41554ce94052" type="folder">4</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_d70dd8c45f1d0551ccc0e4cacc23024c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>John Wesley Hardin. c. 1873 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>John Wesley Hardin. c. 1873 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>John Wesley Hardin. c. 1873 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin.  c. 1885 [Tintype]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin.  c. 1885  [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin.  c. 1885  [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin.  c. 1885  [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin.  c. 1885  [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin.  c. 1885  [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin.  c. 1885  [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin and Molly. c. 1887 [Tintype]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin and Molly. c. 1887 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin and Molly. c. 1887 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin and Molly. c. 1887 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin and Molly. c. 1887 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin and Molly. c. 1887 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin and Molly. c. 1887 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jane Bowen Hardin and Molly. c. 1887 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Elizabeth Cobb. undated [Tintype] </p><p>Elizabeth Cobb. undated [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Bright Smith. undated [Tintype]</p><p>Bright Smith. undated [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Aunt Matt. undated [Albumen Print]</p><p>Joe Hardin. undated [Albumen Print]</p><p>Joe Hardin. undated [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Grandma Odim. undated [Tintype]</p><p>M. Lacey and son, J.W.H. undated  [Tintype]</p><p>M. Lacey and son, J.W.H. undated  [Photo reproduction]</p><p>M. Lacey and son, J.W.H. undated  [Photo reproduction]</p><p>M. Lacey and son, J.W.H. undated  [Photo reproduction]</p><p>John Wesley Hardin, Jr. undated  [Albumen Print]</p><p>John Wesley Hardin, Jr. undated  [Photo reproduction]</p><p>John Wesley Hardin, Jr. undated  [Photo reproduction</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_d02e5678ad5faff8fc397aac4c85e894" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_b3ffc9337b366c60a11dfc7267d02942" label="Graphic Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_0d1c30ddf3f726862ba6dc08f34b6241" parent="aspace_b3ffc9337b366c60a11dfc7267d02942" type="folder">5</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_011ae6108ba380e1a4eeb70fb5120ec4"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Molly Hardin Billings. [Albumen Print]</p><p>Molly Hardin Billings. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Molly Hardin Billings.  [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Victory, Otis, Edith, and Blanch Billings.  [Albumen Print]</p><p>Victory, Otis, Edith, and Blanch Billings. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>John Lyons. [Albumen Print]</p><p>John Lyons. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>John Lyons. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jennie Hardin Lyons.[Albumen Print]</p><p>Jennie Hardin Lyons. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jennie Hardin Lyons. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jennie Hardin Lyons. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jennie Hardin Lyons. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jennie Hardin Lyons. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jennie and Allie Lyons. [Albumen Print]</p><p>Matt Bowen. [Platinotype]</p><p>Matt Bowen. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Matt Bowen. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Matt Bowen. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Matt Bowen. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Matt Bowen. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Benny Bowen. [Albumen Print]</p><p>Benny Bowen. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Brown Bowen and Black Tom Caffole. [Tintype]</p><p>Brown Bowen and Black Tom Caffole. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Brown Bowen and Black Tom Caffole. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Brown Bowen and Black Tom Caffole. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Brown Bowen and Black Tom Caffole. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Josh Bowen. [Tintype]</p><p>Josh Bowen. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Josh Bowen. [Tintype]</p><p>Josh Bowen. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Josh Bowen. [Photo reproduction]</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6ece331dcfd3b869852abc7d45282c35" level="file"><did><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" type="inclusive">1878-1879, 1895, undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_30cd7befcd67522de8a389604ceabe48" label="Graphic Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_0ea3253092b0106cc6948893b8b55dcf" parent="aspace_30cd7befcd67522de8a389604ceabe48" type="folder">6</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_832e9102bb47d4ed53992ec786da009d"><head>Contents</head><p>Mr. Witte. undated [Albumen Print]</p><p>Mr. Witte. undated [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Nan Witte. undated [Albumen Print]</p><p>Mr. Witte. undated [Albumen Print]</p><p>Mr. Witte. undated [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jim Clements. undated [Tintype]</p><p>Jim Clements. undated [Photo reproduction] </p><p>Jim Clements. undated [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jim Clements. undated [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Manning Clements. undated [Photo reproduction] </p><p>Manning Clements. undated [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Joe Clements. undated [Tintype]  </p><p>John Wesley Hardin on slab. 1895 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>John Wesley Hardin on slab. 1895 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>John Wesley Hardin on slab. 1895 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>John Wesley Hardin on slab. 1895 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Information regarding. 1895. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Information regarding. 1895 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>John Selman. 1878 [Photo reproduction]</p><p>John Selman. 1878  [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Captain John Armstrong. undated [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Captain John Armstrong. undated  [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Jan 9, 1879.  J.W. Hardin to Jane Hardin [Photo reproduction]</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_a7c2911c222f9000909812f3c194ef48" level="file"><did><unittitle>undated</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_292303211c9232c2a99c67cb115df6be" label="Graphic Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_076bea07e9e5580302633513c6b79dc2" parent="aspace_292303211c9232c2a99c67cb115df6be" type="folder">7</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ece0b9aaa0bb92100811d04785063fb5"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Pierre Adolph Beasley. [Albumen Print]</p><p>Pierre Adolph Beasley. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Pierre Adolph Beasley. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Mrs. Helen Bulah M'Rose. [Photo reproduction]  </p><p>Mrs. Helen Bulah M'Rose. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Mrs. Helen Bulah M'Rose. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>Mrs. Helen Bulah M'Rose. [Photo reproduction]</p><p>[Rudolph Billings]  [Tintype] </p><p>[Rudolph Billings]  [Photo reproduction]</p><p>[Unknown] [Albumen Print]</p><p>[Unknown] [Photo reproduction]</p><p>[Unknown] [Photo reproduction]</p><p>[Unknown] [Albumen Print]</p><p>[Unknown] [Photo reproduction]</p><p>[Unknown] [Photo reproduction]</p><p>[Unknown] [Photo reproduction]</p><p>[Unknown] [Photo reproduction]</p><p>[Unknown and Unknown] [Albumen Print]</p><p>[Unknown] [Tintype]</p><p>[Unknown and Unknown] [Tintype]</p><p>[Unknown] [Tintype]</p><p>[Unknown] [Tintype]</p><p>[Unknown] [Tintype]</p><p>[Unknown] [Tintype]</p><p>[Unknown] [Tintype</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_18057e940c4c020be537cb4f9af7e549" level="file"><did><unittitle>Negatives </unittitle><container id="aspace_13788cabc486314271b519f3f10d40f7" label="Graphic Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_4e70515f07ccc0e2ef6a0550d22b678d" parent="aspace_13788cabc486314271b519f3f10d40f7" type="folder">8</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_73259d176e8dcd6a30fd85cfab3f86d9" level="series"><did><unittitle>John Wesley Hardin Collection Use Files</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_0d235e02dbbbcd47fb9ba4bb3e66ff0b" level="file"><did><unittitle>A-M</unittitle><container id="aspace_2ff7400c814d99e94c3385917bba34f3" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_94670e9d66efa3f78c8a26c0bf787411" parent="aspace_2ff7400c814d99e94c3385917bba34f3" type="folder">9</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c631a4dce50c1c40915ce17c9e6a085e" level="file"><did><unittitle>P</unittitle><container id="aspace_ca77cc9ee1a3a5f2bae7acc496545596" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_f3ffef1a7407a688de515cb0d94346a6" parent="aspace_ca77cc9ee1a3a5f2bae7acc496545596" type="folder">10</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_451ae8bbe8afc2500462fbfd56be1575" level="file"><did><unittitle>R-Z</unittitle><container id="aspace_28259b9b1b7eec6d179f52b764c03bc8" label="Mixed Materials" type="box">2</container><container id="aspace_aa991dce8d720bd6adf3cf3df13e9341" parent="aspace_28259b9b1b7eec6d179f52b764c03bc8" type="folder">11</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_3721d5b1e1112ac219a730e3f1d8e765" level="series"><did><unittitle>Photocopied Correspondence</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_21504ef1bfc0ea07211b2e96859e0f85"><head>Series Description</head><p>This collection contains the reference photocopies of the Hardin correspondence.</p></scopecontent><c02 id="aspace_2d2d56d12fb2777369a69d25afd375a5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photocopied Correspondence </unittitle><container id="aspace_d30eb724d206910c3d00a77c2510e745" label="Text" type="box">3</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
