<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601">
    <eadid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="identifier" mainagencycode="waps" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv11630" identifier="80444/xv11630">Cage
		444</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the James P. Leynse Papers
			 
			 <date encodinganalog="date" type="inclusive" normal="1960" certainty="circa">circa 1960s</date></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Leynse (James P.)
			 Papers</titleproper>
        <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding aid prepared by Barbara
			 Kovarik-Gahl</author>
        <sponsor encodinganalog="contributor">Funding for encoding this finding
			 aid was provided through a grant awarded by the National Endowment for the
			 Humanities.</sponsor>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Washington State University
			 Libraries: Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections (MASC)</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>Terrell Library</addressline>
          <addressline>Pullman, WA 99164-5610</addressline>
          <addressline>mascref@wsu.edu</addressline>
        </address>
        <date normal="1981" encodinganalog="date">© 1981</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation encodinganalog="description">Finding aid encoded by Mark
		  O'English 
		  <date normal="2003" encodinganalog="date">2003</date></creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in
		  <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.</langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="marc21">
    <did>
      <repository encodinganalog="852">
        <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections</corpname>
        <address>
          <addressline>Terrell Library</addressline>
          <addressline>Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA</addressline>
          <addressline> (509) 335-6691</addressline>
          <addressline>http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/</addressline>
          <addressline>mascref@wsu.edu</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="us" repositorycode="waps">Cage
		  444</unitid>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf" role="creator" rules="aacr2">Leynse, James P.</persname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" type="collection">James P. Leynse
		  Papers</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" normal="circa">circa
		  1960s</unitdate>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">2 containers.</extent>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">.75 linear feet of shelf space.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="520$a">Autobiography and novels, primarily
		  relating to his China experiences, also letters from his son,
		  Humphrey.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>Collection materials are in
		  <language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="5450_">
      <p>James P. Leynse was born in Middleburg, Holland, on March 20, 1890. At
		  an early age Leynse showed a talent for rhetoric and had ambitions as a stage
		  actor. His Dutch-Calvanist father challenged him to do more with his life and
		  this eventually led him to the University of Leiden to study for the ministry
		  in the Dutch Reformed Church. </p>
      <p>As soon as he was ordained, Leynse elected to serve as a missionary in
		  China. His church did not have any missions in China at that time; but this
		  stopped him only momentarily. He decided to seek affiliation with the
		  Presbyterian Board of Foreign Missions in the United States. The American
		  officials, however, were not satisfied with his education and required him to
		  study for two more years at Princeton University and be ordained once again.
		  </p>
      <p>Shortly after he completed his additional studies, his Dutch fiancee,
		  Anna Marie Groenendyk, came to America and they were married on June 21, 1920.
		  They sailed for China in December 1920 and for the next 29 years their home was
		  the Presbyterian Mission in Peking. It was there that their two sons, Humphrey
		  and Waldo, were born. </p>
      <p>Leynse's first three years in China were spent learning to read and
		  speak Mandarin Chinese at the College of Chinese studies. At this time Peking
		  was noted for its poverty, beggars, and disease. One of Leynse's first jobs was
		  the organization of kitchens which served free millet porridge to thousands of
		  the hungry. Leynse soon realized, however, that he was only treating a symptom
		  of the problem. Therefore, he wrote to Holland and asked his sister Francina
		  Leynse for help. She arrived in 1930 and for 15 years helped to establish and
		  run an industrial center where homeless women and children could learn a skill.
		  </p>
      <p>With the Japanese invasion and subsequent occupation of China, larger
		  problems loomed for the Leynses. At first the Japanese permitted Leynse to
		  continue the Peking Poor Relief Committee. Even though other foreigners were
		  being evacuated the Leynses stayed on in the hopes that the Japanese would
		  continue to overlook them. Late in 1941, they travelled to Japan in order to
		  secure passage to America for their younger son, Waldo. While in Japan they
		  were placed under house arrest and confined for a year and a half. With the aid
		  of Japanese friends they were released and returned to China only to be
		  recaptured and held at the British Embassy in Peking for the remainder of World
		  War II. </p>
      <p>During his captivity, Leynse was considerably weakened by bouts with
		  typhoid fever and "sprue" (a disease of the liver and intestines brought on by
		  malnutrition). Despite this ill health he stayed on in China after the Japanese
		  surrender to reorganize and reopen the mission kitchens and hospital. </p>
      <p>In 1946 "sprue" attacked him again and he became almost bedridden.
		  Owing to his long service and poor health the mission retired him in 1949. Upon
		  his retirement, Leynse settled in Claremont, California where he began to
		  write. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
      <p>The James P. Leynse papers consist of four manuscripts plus a small
		  correspondence file. Beauty for Ashes is an autobiography of his life in China
		  and was the principal source for the preceding biography. Before the Mayflower
		  and Dream Come True are novels concerning the lives of a Puritan family who
		  fled from England to Holland to escape English religious persecution in the
		  17th century. The family eventually became part of the group of Pilgrims who
		  sailed for America. Fly the Dragon is the fictional story of a Chinese boy
		  during the early 20th century who rebels against the ancient traditions of his
		  family and strikes out on his own. This story offers a view of Chinese society
		  and the struggle against the traditions which hindered Chinese modernization in
		  the 20th century. </p>
      <p>Leynse's autobiography is significant in that it provides a picture of
		  life in Peking and the surrounding countryside from the 1920s through the
		  1940s. Leynse encountered many of the individuals who molded the history of
		  China during the first half of the 20th century. His character sketches of
		  Chiang K'ai-shek, Madame Chiang, the last Ch'ing emperor Pu-yi, members of the
		  Nationalist government (T. V. Soong and others), Mao Tse-tung, Chou Enlai, and
		  Chu Teh are thoughtful and vividly drawn. Leynse's particular style and strong
		  viewpoint--that of a Western Christian missionary dedicated to helping the
		  Chinese people--do not obscure an interesting glimpse of China in poverty, war,
		  and revolution. </p>
      <p>Included in the last folder of the papers are letters received from
		  Leynse's son, Humphrey. This correspondence dates from the year 1964. </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
      <p>The collection is arranged in a single series. The correspondence (folder 5)  is arranged in chronological order.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <p>This collection is open for research use.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <p>[Item Description]. Cage
		444, James P. Leynse
		  Papers. Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections, Washington State University Libraries, Pullman, WA.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <p>The papers of James P. Leynse (MS 81-40) were separated from those of his son, Humphrey W. Leynse (MS 79-39) which were donated to the Washington State University Archives by Judith L. Leynse in August 1979. In 2007, Gary Endicott donated two additional manuscripts (China Tales and Forever China). These were added to the existing collection (MS 2007-4).</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="5441_">
      <p>The papers of James P. Leynse (MS 81-40) were separated from those of
		  his son, Humphrey W. Leynse (Cage 438: MS 79-39).</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <processinfo encodinganalog="583">
      <p>This collection was processed in August of 1981 by Barbara Kovarik-Gahl.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <controlaccess>
      <p>This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online
		  catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or
		  places should search the catalog using these headings.</p>
      <controlaccess>
        <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf" rules="aacr2" role="creator"> Leynse, James P. --Archives</persname>
        <persname source="lcnaf" rules="aacr2" role="subject" encodinganalog="600">Leynse, Humphrey W. (Humphrey William),
			 1921-1977</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Military</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Performing Arts</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">International Relations</subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <occupation source="lcsh" encodinganalog="656">
          Missionaries--China -- Correspondence
        </occupation>
        <occupation source="lcsh" encodinganalog="656">
          Missionaries--China -- Biography
        </occupation>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <title encodinganalog="630" source="lcnaf" rules="aacr2">
          Beauty for Ashes
        </title>
        <title encodinganalog="630" source="lcnaf" rules="aacr2">
          Before the Mayflower
        </title>
        <title encodinganalog="630" source="lcnaf" rules="aacr2">
          Dream Come True
        </title>
        <title encodinganalog="630" source="lcnaf" rules="aacr2">
          Fly the Dragon
        </title>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <p>The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in
		  the collection.</p>
      <c01 level="file">
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">1</container>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">
            <title>Beauty for Ashes</title>
          </unittitle>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
          <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">1 item.</extent>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="file">
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">2</container>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">
            <title>Before the Mayflower</title>
          </unittitle>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
          <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">1 item.</extent>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="file">
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">3</container>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">
            <title>Dream Come True</title>
          </unittitle>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
          <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">1 item.</extent>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="file">
        <did>
          <container type="box">2</container>
          <container type="folder">4</container>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">
            <title>Fly the Dragon</title>
          </unittitle>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
          <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">1 item.</extent>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="file">
        <did>
          <container type="box">2</container>
          <container type="folder">5</container>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1964</unitdate>
          <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">10
				items.</extent>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="file">
        <did>
          <container type="box">3</container>
          <container type="folder">6-9</container>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">
            <title>China Tales</title>
          </unittitle>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="file">
        <did>
          <container type="box">3</container>
          <container type="folder">10-13</container>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">
            <title>Forever China</title>
          </unittitle>
          <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>

