<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<!--Template updated 2011-05-11 by J. Allison-Bunnell in accordance with changes that resulted in Best Practices version 3.5-->
<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
<!--                              EADHEADER BEGINS HERE                           -->
<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
<!--Remember to name and save documents using the OCLC code + local filename. Documents that are revised/updated after initial submission much be submitted with precisely the same filename.-->

<ead> 
<!--The following section is header information that describes the finding aid-->
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" id="a0"> 
  	<eadid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="identifier" mainagencycode="waps" identifier="80444/xv187194" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv187194">NTE2ms2011_28.xml</eadid> 
	 <filedesc> 
		<titlestmt> 
			<titleproper encodinganalog="title">Preliminary Guide to the Save Our Summers Records
				<date encodinganalog="date" calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2000/2016">2000-2016</date></titleproper>
		  
			<titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Save Our Summers Records</titleproper>
		  
			<author encodinganalog="creator">Finding aid prepared by Cheryl Gunselman</author>
		</titlestmt> 
		<publicationstmt> 
		  
			<publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
			</publisher>
		  
			<date calendar="gregorian" encodinganalog="date" normal="2020">© 2020</date> 
		 
		</publicationstmt> 
	 </filedesc> 
	 <profiledesc> 
		<creation>Finding aid encoded by Suzanne James-Bacon.
			<date normal="2020" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2020</date></creation>
		
		<langusage>Finding aid written in English.
		  <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.</langusage> <descrules>Finding aid based
		on DACS 2nd Edition ( 
		<title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content
		  Standard</title>).</descrules> 
	 </profiledesc> 
  </eadheader> 
	
	<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
	<!--                         COLLECTION-LEVEL DESCRIPTION BEGINS HERE             -->
	<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
	
  <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="marc21"> 
	 <did id="a1"> 
		<repository> 
			<corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections</corpname>
		  
		   </repository> 
	 	<unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="us" repositorycode="waps" type="collection">MS.2011.28</unitid>
		
		<origination> 
			<corpname encodinganalog="110" role="creator" rules="rda">Save Our Summers</corpname> </origination> 
	 	<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Preliminary Guide to the Save Our Summers Records</unittitle>
		
	 	<unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" datechar="" certainty="" normal="2000/2016">2000-2016</unitdate>
		
	 	<physdesc> <extent encodinganalog="300$a">0.75 Linear feet of shelf space</extent>
		  <extent encodinganalog="300$a">2 Boxes + Digital files</extent>
		</physdesc>
	 	<abstract encodinganalog="5203_">This collection consists of correspondence, photographs, and miscellaneous items related to Save Our Summers.</abstract> 
	 	<physloc>(MASC staff use): MS.2011.28, 2-13-23-6; MS.2017.22, 1-38-12-12; borndigital_MS201722</physloc> 
		<langmaterial>Collection materials are in <language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
	 </did>
  	
		<bioghist encodinganalog="5451_" id="a2">
			<!--Enter ENCODINGANALOG value of 5450_ for biog. or 5451_ for historical note, or use <head> element-->
			<p>From the guide to the Save Our Summers Records, 1975-2004 (Collection number: Cage
				749):</p>
			<p>Save Our Summers (SOS), a nonprofit environmental advocacy group, was organized in
				1995 to raise public awareness about the environmental and health hazards of the
				agricultural practice of grass burning, and to strengthen regulations to protect
				public health and air quality. SOS was originally formed in response to practices in
				Spokane County, WA, and subsequently expanded its area of concern to include wheat
				stubble burning in the Palouse region.</p>
			<p>Patricia Hoffman, a retired veterinarian, founded this nonprofit volunteer
				organization in Spokane. SOS recruited volunteers through membership drives,
				advertisements in local newspapers, and public meetings. Many members and their
				families had personally experienced health problems linked to smoke and emissions
				from agricultural burning. SOS challenged government agencies and farmers to more
				effectively regulate, reduce, and halt the practice. SOS pursued these goals by
				holding meetings, writing letters, lobbying government officials, circulating
				petitions, distributing educational literature, and initiating legal action.</p>
			<p>At about the same time, the Clean Air Coalition (CAC) organized separately in
				Sandpoint, ID, to address similar agricultural burning on the Rathdrum prairie. The
				two groups made attempts to work together, but because most of the local organizing
				happened at neighborhood meetings, the geographical separation was problematic.
				Another group, Safe Air For Everyone (SAFE), was organized in 2001 following some of
				the worst burns on the Rathdrum prairie. SOS and SAFE worked cooperatively, using
				the court system in their efforts to end agricultural burning in the region.</p>
			<p>SOS filed lawsuits challenging government actions and public policies in Washington
				and Idaho. In 1999, the group initiated three lawsuits against Washington State
				Department of Ecology (DOE), and in 2000 filed suit against two State of Idaho
				departments, Agriculture and Environmental Quality.</p>
			<p>SOS filed its first case in Thurston County (WA) Superior Court, the jurisdiction in
				which the Washington DOE headquarters is located, on March 19, 1999. SOS claimed
				that DOE had violated the state Clean Air Act by making a voluntary agreement in the
				form of a memorandum of understanding (MOU) with the Washington Association of Wheat
				Growers (WAWG) to reduce pollution from field burning. SOS also alleged that the
				agency violated state rulemaking requirements and failed to fully consider the human
				and environmental health consequences of this agreement. Judge Richard Hicks
				observed that he failed to see how an agreement that moved growers in the direction
				of less burning was harmful. The courts also ruled that since the MOU between DOE
				and WAWG was a voluntary agreement, failure to reach the goals stated in the MOU
				were not punishable offenses.</p>
			<p>The second suit was filed in Thurston County Superior Court on August 11, 1999. SOS
				alleged that DOE was in violation of the state Open Records Act for failing to
				disclose key documents relevant to reduction of agricultural burning. Specifically
				at issue was a report by the WAWG about their public relations plan to garner
				support for their deal with DOE. DOE was cleared of wrongdoing, but the judge ruled
				that SOS was correct in filing the suit and ordered DOE to pay SOS's court costs and
				legal fees. The judge also directed SOS and DOE to reach an agreement on any
				additional documents requested by SOS.</p>
			<p>The third suit, initiated by SOS with families from Whitman County, WA and Kootenai
				County, ID, was filed in U.S. District Court in October 1999. They sought an
				immediate halt to field burning. SOS argued that DOE was in violation of the
				Americans with Disabilities Act (ADA). They argued that by failing to regulate the
				smoke generated by wheat-stubble burning, DOE was preventing access to public
				resources by people suffering from respiratory diseases severely aggravated by the
				smoke. A final ruling was delayed several times as the judge waited to hear from the
				U. S. Department of Justice over the question of jurisdiction in the case.
				Ultimately, SOS and all other parties in the suit agreed to resolution through a
				mediation process.</p>
		</bioghist> 
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_" id="a3">
			<p>This collection consists of correspondence, photographs, and miscellaneous items
				related to Save Our Summers. The collection includes paper documents and digital
				files (borndigital_MS201722).</p>
		</scopecontent> 
	 <arrangement encodinganalog="351" id="a4"> 
	 	<p>This is an unprocessed collection. Any arrangement reflects either a pre-existing order from the records' creators or previous custodians, or preliminary sorting performed by staff.</p> 
	 </arrangement> 
	 <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506" id="a14"> 
	 	<p>This collection is open and available for research use.</p>
	 </accessrestrict> 
	 <userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15"> 
	 	<p>Copyright restrictions may apply.</p>
	 </userestrict> 
	 <prefercite encodinganalog="524" id="a18"> 
	 	<p>[Item description] </p>
	 	<p>Preliminary Guide to the Save Our Summers Records, 2000-2016 (MS.2011.28) </p>
	 	<p>Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections, 
	 		Washington State University Libraries, Pullman, WA.</p> 
	 </prefercite> 
		<acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="a19">
			<p>Marc Fleisher, president of Save Our Summers NW (Moscow, ID), donated this collection
				to the Washington State University Libraries on behalf of the organization in
				multiple installments beginning in 2011 (MS.2011.28, MS.2017.22).</p>
		</acqinfo> 
	 <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="5441_" id="a6"> 
	 	<p>Save Our Summers Records 1975-2004 (Cage 749).</p>
	 </relatedmaterial> 
 
  	<!-- ooooooooooooooooooo     ACCESS POINTS     oooooooooooooooooooo -->
  	
	 <controlaccess id="a12"> 
		<p>This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online
		  catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or
		  places should search the catalog using these headings.</p> 
		<controlaccess> 
			<corpname role="subject" encodinganalog="610" rules="rda">Save Our Summers -- Records and correspondence.</corpname>
		</controlaccess> 
		<controlaccess> 
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Air quality management.</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Environmental protection.</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Burning of land -- Health aspects.</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Smoke -- Physiological effect.</subject>
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Pressure groups.</subject>		  
		</controlaccess> 
		<controlaccess> 
			<subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Environmental Conditions</subject> 
			<subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Environmental Activism</subject>		  
		</controlaccess> 
	 </controlaccess> 
  
  </archdesc> </ead>

