<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="dc" scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="waps" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv365325" encodinganalog="identifier" identifier="80444/xv365325">NTE2ms2006_05.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Preliminary Guide to the Gertrude M. and Roy E. Spencer Papers
 <date encodinganalog="date" normal="1941/1975" type="inclusive">1941-1975</date>
            </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Spencer (Gertrude M. and Roy E.) Papers</titleproper>
            <author encodinganalog="creator">Jacki Tyler</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections, Washington State University Libraries</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc</addressline>
               <addressline>Terrell Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 645610</addressline>
               <addressline>Pullman 99164-5610</addressline>
               <addressline>mascref@wsu.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc</addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>This accession includes four "log lifters" (two appear to be slate, one might be aluminum, and the third might be magnesium), as well as an empty box of a Spencer tape, and a lumber marker in box #2. Also, the scrapbook was disassembled, placed in folders, and re-boxed to prevent further damage.</p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-04-19</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>
            <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English </language>
         </langusage>
         <descrules>Finding aid based on
          DACS (<title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content Standard</title>), 2nd
          Edition.</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="marc21" type="inventory">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections, Washington State University Libraries</corpname>
            <address>
               <addressline>http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc</addressline>
               <addressline>Terrell Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 645610</addressline>
               <addressline>Pullman 99164-5610</addressline>
               <addressline>mascref@wsu.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc</addressline>
            </address>
         </repository>
         <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Preliminary Guide to the Gertrude and Roy Spencer Papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local" encodinganalog="100">Spencer, Roy E. </persname>
    
            <persname rules="dacs" source="local" encodinganalog="100">Spencer, Gertrude </persname>
         </origination>
    
         <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="US" repositorycode="waps">MS.2006.05</unitid>
         <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">6 linear feet</extent>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">4 boxes.</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1941/1975" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1941-1975</unitdate>
         <physloc>(MASC staff use) 2-8-1-1.</physloc>
         <langmaterial>Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
         <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">This collection contains papers of Gertrude M. (Bodean) and Roy E. Spencer, dated between 1941 and 1975.</abstract>
      </did>
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
    
         <p>This collection contains papers of Gertrude M. (Bodean) and Roy E. Spencer, dated between 1941 and 1975. The collection primarily consists of papers related to Gertrude and Roy's Pullman, WA businesses: Gertrude's Beauty Salon and Spencer Production and Sales Company, including financial statements and advertisements. The collection also contains a large scrapbook maintained by Gertrude Spencer for the Palouse chapter (number 21) of the Washington State Cosmetology Association, documenting events related to National Beauty Salon Week and the organization's public engagements.</p>
         <p>Preliminary Inventory:</p>
         <p>Box 1:
Business papers related to the finances of Gertrude's Beauty Salon, including balance sheets, between 1965 and 1974, and purchase order forms of Spencer Production and Sales Company, between 1950 and 1959.</p>
         <p>Box 2: 
Materials related to Spencer Production and Sales Company, including prepared financial statements (1965), correspondence, sales receipts, banking records, between 1958 to 1967, as well as a prepared financial statement (balance sheet) for both Roy E. and Gertrude M. Spencer in 1967. </p>
         <p>Box 3:
Correspondence, receipts, a client index, miscellaneous business papers, as well as various artifacts related to Spencer Production and Sales Company, between 1949 and 1962.</p>
         <p>Box 4:
Scrapbook (1955-1971) documenting the Washington State Cosmetology Association, with a focus on Palouse Chapter 21, including chapter meetings, community events, and charitable services. The scrapbook also covers several years of National Beauty Salon Week and related advertisements.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
    
         <p>This collection is open and available for research use.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
    
         <p>Donated to the Washington State University Libraries by Richard Old in 2001 (MS.2006.05).</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
    
         <p>Gertrude M. Bodean Spencer (1909-2002) was born Ephrata, Washington, to Martha (Pruitt) and H. D. Bodean. Roy E. Spencer (1910-1985) was born in Pullman, Washington, to Edward and Lula (Jordan) Spencer. Gertrude and Roy were married in 1940, and remained in Pullman were they each became proprietors of their own businesses. Gertrude was the owner and operator of  Gertrude's Beauty Salon and served as an active member of the Washington State Cosmetology Association. Roy owned and operated Spencer Production and Sales Company, which specialized in developing tools used in the timber industry. He invented the Spencer Tape Measure (patented 1962) that is still widely used in logging operations today.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
    
         <p>This is an unprocessed collection. Any arrangement reflects either a pre-existing order from the records' creators or previous custodians, or preliminary sorting performed by staff.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Business enterprises--Washington (State)</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Women-owned business enterprises--Archives</subject>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <subject source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690" altrender="nodisplay">Logging</subject>
            <subject source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690" altrender="nodisplay">Logging</subject>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <occupation source="lcsh" encodinganalog="656">Beauty operators</occupation>
         </controlaccess>
      </controlaccess>
  
   </archdesc>
</ead>

