<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<!--Template updated 2011-05-11 by J. Allison-Bunnell in accordance with changes that resulted in Best Practices version 3.5-->
<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
<!--                              EADHEADER BEGINS HERE                           -->
<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
<!--Remember to name and save documents using the OCLC code + local filename. Documents that are revised/updated after initial submission much be submitted with precisely the same filename.-->

<ead> 
<!--The following section is header information that describes the finding aid-->
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" id="a0"> 
  	<eadid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="identifier" mainagencycode="waps" identifier="80444/xv591247" url="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:80444/xv591247">NTE2ua2022_08.xml</eadid> 
	 <filedesc> 
		<titlestmt> 
			<titleproper encodinganalog="title">Preliminary Guide to the Washington State University Biomedical Communications Unit Electronic Media
				<date encodinganalog="date" calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1990-2019">1990s-2010s</date></titleproper>
		  
			<titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Washington State University Biomedical Communications Unit Electronic Media</titleproper>
		  
		  <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding aid prepared by Mark O’English</author>
		</titlestmt> 
		<publicationstmt> 
		  
			<publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
			</publisher>
		  
			<date calendar="gregorian" encodinganalog="date" normal="2022">© 2022</date> 
		 
		</publicationstmt> 
	 </filedesc> 
	 <profiledesc> 
		<creation>Finding aid encoded by Suzanne James-Bacon.
			<date normal="2021" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2022</date></creation>
		
		<langusage>Finding aid written in English.
		  <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.</langusage> <descrules>Finding aid based
		on DACS 2nd Edition ( 
		<title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content
		  Standard</title>).</descrules> 
	 </profiledesc> 
  </eadheader> 
	
	<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
	<!--                         COLLECTION-LEVEL DESCRIPTION BEGINS HERE             -->
	<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
	
  <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="marc21"> 
	 <did id="a1"> 
		<repository> 
			<corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections</corpname>
		  
		   </repository> 
		<unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="us" repositorycode="waps" type="collection">UA2022-08</unitid>
		
		<origination> 
			<corpname encodinganalog="110" role="creator" rules="rda">Washington State University. College of Veterinary Medicine. Biomedical Communications Unit</corpname> </origination> 
	 	<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Preliminary Guide to the Washington State University Biomedical Communications Unit Electronic Media</unittitle>
		
	 	<unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" datechar="" certainty="" normal="1990-2019">1990s-2010s</unitdate>
		
		<physdesc> <extent encodinganalog="300$a">3 Linear feet of shelf space</extent>
		  <extent encodinganalog="300$a">3 Boxes</extent>
		</physdesc>
			<abstract encodinganalog="5203_">Electronic media from the Washington State University
				College of Veterinary Medicine Biomedical Communications Unit. Includes videos,
				images, and documents created, collected, or published by the BCU, most from the
				early 1990s to late 2010s.</abstract> 
	 	<physloc>(MASC STAFF USE) 2-37-28-1</physloc> 
		<langmaterial>Collection materials are in <language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
	 </did>
  	
  	<bioghist encodinganalog="5451_" id="a2"><!--Enter ENCODINGANALOG value of 5450_ for biog. or 5451_ for historical note, or use <head> element-->		
			<p>The Biomedical Communications Unit (BCU) in the College of Veterinary Medicine dates
				to at least 1978 and the opening of Bustad Hall, when it housed carrels equipped for
				autotutorial instruction and facilities for production and broadcast of
				closed-circuit television for teaching. In 1981 it added photographic processing to
				its services. Eventually printing and production became a major part of its role,
				and it served as one the main campus printing centers for several decades. It was
				closed at the end of May, 2021.</p>		
	 </bioghist> 
	 <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_" id="a3"> 
			<p>The collection consists of electronic media which had been held at the BCU printing
				center. Many of the materials appear to be videos of veterinary medicine events, or
				of news stories related to them. The full contents of the collection remain to be
				evaluated. </p> 
			<p>Box 1 contains six video laser discs from the 1990s, with three accompanying manuals.
				Some of these appear to be commercial produced, and need evaluation. Also in Box 1
				are 275 DVDs, most in 5 plastic containers which maintain the order and arrangement
				in which they came to the archives. Most DVDs are labeled with title and/or date,
				and appear to be from the 1990s and 2000s. </p> 
			<p>The bulk of box 2 is 230 miniDV tapes from the 2000s. Many of the MiniDV tapes are in
				small cardboard boxes of six tapes each; those are how they came to MASC and those
				boxes retain the order that they came in. Also in the box are 6 VHS tapes, 2 u-matic
				tapes, and 3 VHS-C tapes, and six VHS tapes. Most of the items in these latter four
				formats are undated; the VHS range form 1996-2004. </p> 
			<p>Box 3 contains 24 hard drives, as well as a variety of power supplies which came with
				them. Most are labeled with dates, between 2004 and 2015. </p> 
	 </scopecontent> 
		<arrangement encodinganalog="351" id="a4">
			<p>This is an unprocessed collection. Any arrangement reflects either a pre-existing
				order from the records' creators or previous custodians, or preliminary sorting
				performed by staff. </p>
			<p>Materials are clustered by format, and the larger sets maintain their original (as of
				time of transfer) arrangement in most cases.</p>
		</arrangement> 
	 <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506" id="a14"> 
	 	<p>This collection is open and available for research use.</p>
	 </accessrestrict> 
	 <userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15"> 
	 	<p>Copyright restrictions apply.</p>
	 </userestrict> 
	 <prefercite encodinganalog="524" id="a18"> 
	 	<p>[Item description] </p>
	 	<p>Preliminary Guide to the Washington State University Biomedical Communications Unit Electronic Media, 1990s-2010s (UA2022-08) </p>
	 	<p>Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections, Washington State University Libraries, Pullman, WA.</p> 
	 </prefercite>  
	 <acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="a19"> 
			<p>Gary Turner donated these materials to the Washington State University Libraries in
				December of 2022, where it was retained as UA2022-08. Turner had inherited part of
				the BCU’s repurposed space, and had held no affiliation with the BCU.</p>
	 </acqinfo> 
	 <processinfo encodinganalog="583" id="a20"> 
			<p>Priority needs to be given to moving these materials from their current storage to
				archival drives for preservation purposes, which should then allow both evaluation
				and processing of the materials. </p>
			<p>Given the BCU’s role as an arm of Veterinary Medicine, it is possible we may want to
				parse these materials into VetMed materials and BCU materials. Other BCU materials
				were received in July of 2021 as UPC 2021-03, and should be evaluated for possible
				joint processing with this accession. </p>
	 </processinfo> 
	 <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="5441_" id="a6"> 
	 	<p>Other unprocessed BCU materials (generally printed formats rather than e-media) are held as UPC 2021-03.  MASC holds many Veterinary Medicine collections and accessions.</p>
	 </relatedmaterial> 
 
  	<!-- ooooooooooooooooooo     ACCESS POINTS     oooooooooooooooooooo -->
  	
	 <controlaccess id="a12"> 
		<p>This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online
		  catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or
		  places should search the catalog using these headings.</p> 
		<controlaccess> 
			<corpname role="subject" encodinganalog="610" rules="rda">Washington State University. College of Veterinary Medicine. Biomedical Communications Unit -- Records and correspondence</corpname>
		    <corpname role="subject" encodinganalog="610" rules="rda">Washington State University. College of Veterinary Medicine.</corpname>		  
			<corpname role="creator" encodinganalog="710" rules="rda">Washington State University. College of Veterinary Medicine.</corpname>		  
		</controlaccess> 
		<controlaccess> 
			<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Veterinary Medicine</subject>
		</controlaccess> 
		<controlaccess> 
			<subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Colleges and Universities</subject> 
			<subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Washington (State)</subject>		
		</controlaccess> 
	 </controlaccess> 
  	<!--A finding aid without a series or container list may end here.-->
  	
  </archdesc> </ead>

