<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="dc" scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="waps" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv597716" encodinganalog="identifier" identifier="80444/xv597716">NTE2ms1983_25.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Preliminary Guide to the Lavon M. Koger Papers
 <date encodinganalog="date" normal="1936/1982" type="inclusive">1936-1982</date>
            </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Koger (Lavon M.) Papers</titleproper>
            <author encodinganalog="creator">Jacki Tyler</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections, Washington State University Libraries</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc</addressline>
               <addressline>Terrell Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 645610</addressline>
               <addressline>Pullman 99164-5610</addressline>
               <addressline>mascref@wsu.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc</addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note>
               <p>**May contain confidential materials (student records, etc.)
*Includes artifacts (box 4)
*Box 8 contains a CV and a inventory list</p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2018-02-12</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>
            <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English </language>
         </langusage>
         <descrules>Finding aid based on
          DACS (<title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content Standard</title>), 2nd
          Edition.</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="marc21" type="inventory">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections, Washington State University Libraries</corpname>
            <address>
               <addressline>http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc</addressline>
               <addressline>Terrell Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 645610</addressline>
               <addressline>Pullman 99164-5610</addressline>
               <addressline>mascref@wsu.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc</addressline>
            </address>
         </repository>
         <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Preliminary Guide to the Lavon M. Koger Papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname rules="aacr" source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="100">Koger, L. M.</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="US" repositorycode="waps">MS.1983.25</unitid>
         <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">18 linear feet</extent>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">18 records cartons.</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1936/1982" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1936-1982</unitdate>
         <physloc>(MASC staff use) 2-14-1-4.</physloc>
         <langmaterial>Materials are in English.</langmaterial>
         <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">This collection contains the papers of Dr. Lavon M. Koger, Professor of Veterinary Medicine at Washington State University, between 1936 and 1982.</abstract>
      </did>
      <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
    
         <p>This is an unprocessed collection. Any arrangement reflects either a pre-existing order from the records' creators or previous custodians, or preliminary sorting performed by staff.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
    
         <p>This collection contains the papers of Dr. Lavon M. Koger, Professor of Veterinary Medicine at Washington State University, between 1936 and 1982. The collection primarily consists of papers related to Dr. Koger's time as a professor, including teaching materials, departmental documents, as well as photographs. The collection also contains materials such as notes, journals, newspaper clippings, and numerous professional publications. </p>
         <p>Preliminary Inventory:</p>
         <p>
Boxes 1-3:</p>
         <p>Teaching materials, research notes, lecture notes (from his time as a student at WSC), correspondence, departmental documents, newspaper clippings, diaries (1975-1979), and various professional publications, as well as photographs, overhead projector slides, and microscope slides (glass), 1936-1979.</p>
         <p>Box 4:</p>
         <p>Materials related to Dr. Koger's research and teaching, including photographs (slides, prints, and negatives), audiocassettes, film, as well as 3D glasses, and Viewmaster reels and viewer, 1960s-1970s.</p>
         <p>Box 5:</p>
         <p>Teaching materials, research notes (including the topics of pregnancy diagnosis in ewes and foot and mouth disease), correspondence, departmental documents, newspaper clippings, and various professional publications, as well as photographs and negatives, 1964-1978.</p>
         <p>Box 6:</p>
         <p>Research notes, department related forms, documents pertaining to the registration and licensing of controlled substances, multiple copies of Modern Veterinary Practice (February, 1978, Volume 59, Number 2), as well as negatives, 1970s.</p>
         <p>Boxes 7-8:</p>
         <p>Teaching materials, research notes (including the topics of shipping fever, DSMO, and Dwarfism in Bovines), correspondence, departmental documents, newspaper clippings, and various professional publications, as well as photographs (slides and negatives), curriculum vitae, and preliminary collection inventory, 1960s-1980s.</p>
         <p>Box 9:</p>
         <p>Papers related to Dr. Koger's research and sabbatical travels, including a research journal (containing various materials from his sabbatical), and copies of publications, 1970s. </p>
         <p>Boxes 10-11:</p>
         <p>Teaching materials, research notes, correspondence, departmental documents, newspaper clippings, and various professional publications, 1960s-1970s.</p>
         <p>Box 12: </p>
         <p>Professional publications including veterinary school directories, journals, and newsletters, as well as correspondence and student papers, 1960s-1970s.</p>
         <p>Box 13:</p>
         <p>Research notes, correspondence (including information about a veterinary school class of 1942 reunion), newspaper clippings, and various professional publications, 1960s-1970s.</p>
         <p>Box 14:</p>
         <p>Professional publications including veterinary school directories, journals, and newsletters, as well as correspondence and student papers, 1960s-1970s.</p>
         <p>Box 15:</p>
         <p>Papers related to the American Veterinary Medical Association, including meeting minutes, correspondence, and the AVMA Group Insurance Trust, 1960s.</p>
         <p>Boxes 16-18:</p>
         <p>Teaching materials, research notes, faculty documents, correspondence, and various professional publications, 1950s-1970s.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
    
         <p>Access to this collection is restricted (MASC staff review required in advance of researcher access). Please contact the repository for additional information.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
    
         <p>Received by Washington State University Libraries from Dr. Orville Frost in 1983 (MS.1983.25).</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
    
         <p>Lavon Marion Koger was born in Cove, Oregon, in 1915 to Harlan Alphin Koger and Esther Elva (Trueblood) Koger. He attended Eastern Oregon Normal School and Willamette University before coming to Washington State College (today Washington State University), where he received his Bachelor of Science degree in 1941 and his doctorate in Veterinary Medicine in 1942. Koger married Kathleen J. Conklin in 1942, and then worked as a general practice veterinarian until to 1964, including being the owner and operator of a clinic for nineteen years. In 1964, Koger returned to WSU as an Associate Professor of Veterinary Medicine. Throughout his career, Koger remained an active researcher and developed prostheses for horses. He also served as the president for regional chapters of the American Veterinary Medical Association (Southwest Idaho, Oregon, and Intermountain Western States), as well as a Section Officer of its national organization. Dr. Koger remained at WSU until his death in 1982.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Veterinarians--Archives</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Washington State University--Faculty--Archives</subject>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <subject source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690" altrender="nodisplay">Colleges and Universities</subject>
         </controlaccess>
      </controlaccess>
  
   </archdesc>
</ead>

