<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="dc" scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="waps" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv777251" encodinganalog="identifier" identifier="80444/xv777251">NTE2mssm_016.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Preliminary Guide to the Evelyn Hawes and Lon Johnson Papers
 <date encodinganalog="date" normal="1908/1985" type="inclusive">1908-1985</date>
            </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Hawes (Evelyn) and Lon Johnson Papers</titleproper>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections, Washington State University Libraries</publisher>
            <address>
               <addressline>http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc</addressline>
               <addressline>Terrell Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 645610</addressline>
               <addressline>Pullman 99164-5610</addressline>
               <addressline>mascref@wsu.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc</addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2019-04-09</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>
            <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English.</language>
         </langusage>
         <descrules>Finding aid based on
          DACS (<title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content Standard</title>), 2nd
          Edition.</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="marc21" type="inventory">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections, Washington State University Libraries</corpname>
            <address>
               <addressline>http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc</addressline>
               <addressline>Terrell Library</addressline>
               <addressline>P.O. Box 645610</addressline>
               <addressline>Pullman 99164-5610</addressline>
               <addressline>mascref@wsu.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>http://www.libraries.wsu.edu/masc</addressline>
            </address>
         </repository>
         <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Preliminary Guide to the Evelyn Hawes and Lon Johnson papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="100">Hawes, Evelyn (Evelyn Johnson)</persname>
    
            <persname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="100">Johnson, W. Lon</persname>
         </origination>
    
         <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="US" repositorycode="waps">MSSM.016</unitid>
         <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">22 linear feet</extent>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">23 boxes.</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate normal="1908/1985" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1908-1985</unitdate>
         <physloc>(MASC staff use): MS 1979-04: 2-7-17-2; MS 1987-41: 2-7-9-4 14; MS 1989-62: 2-5-4-4; MS1994-55: 2-13-19-3.
</physloc>
         <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">These materials were received in multiple installments, accessioned separately as described below.</abstract>
      </did>
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
    
         <p>These materials were received in multiple installments, accessioned separately as described below.</p>
         <p>MS 1979-04: This collection contains papers of author Evelyn Johnson Hawes (1915-1994), from 1975 to 1976. The collection consists of typed and handwritten literary manuscripts as well as editing notes, for Hawes' book Sail West to Death. The collection also contains both professional and personal incoming correspondence, and greeting cards sent to Hawes.</p>
         <p>MS 1987-41: This collection contains papers pertaining to the family and professional lives of author Evelyn Johnson Hawes (1915-1994) and her father, Judge William Lon Johnson (1882-1967), from 1891 to 1987. The collection's records for Johnson include materials related to his service as a state senator, the Lieutenant Governor, and a Superior Court Judge: speeches, a memoir, incoming and outgoing correspondence, a scrapbook of newspaper articles related to Johnson, photographs, and his birth and marriage certificate. The records for Hawes consist of personal and professional correspondence, family photographs, professional scrapbooks, teaching files, press materials, article manuscripts, audio tapes of lectures and interviews given by Hawes, and printed materials authored by others.</p>
         <p>MS 1989-62: This collection contains the papers for author Evelyn Johnson Hawes (1915-1994), from 1950 to 1971. It consists of manuscripts of Hawes' short stories and articles, correspondence with various editors, published versions of stories, unpublished articles on Seattle and the University of Washington, radio scripts for KHQ out of Colville, Washington, and family photographs.</p>
         <p>MS 1994-55: This collection contains papers of author Evelyn Johnson Hawes (1915-1994), from 1954 to 1992. It includes professional papers pertaining to copyright, research files, correspondence, article drafts and other manuscripts, published versions of short stories and articles, books by Hawes and others, teaching materials, and newspaper clippings (book reviews, etc.); it also includes some personal correspondence.</p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
    
         <p>This is an unprocessed collection. It has not yet been arranged.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
    
         <p>This collection is open and available for research use.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="5441_">
    
         <p>Evelyn Hawes Papers (Cage 226) http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/finders/cg226.htm; 
Lon Johnson Papers (Cage 195) http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/finders/cg195.htm</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
    
         <p>Author Evelyn Johnson Hawes (1915-1994) was born in Colville, Washington to W. Lon Johnson and Iva (Dickey) Johnson. She attended Washington State University and the University of Washington, receiving her bachelor's degree from UW in 1936. Hawes was a faculty member at several institutions, including the University of Washington, the University of Cincinnati, Canisius College, Amherst Central Adult School, and the State University of New York at Buffalo. Hawes' published works include many articles and stories, and several books: They Also Serve (1943), Proud Vision: The History of the Buffalo General Hospital, The First Hundred Years (1964), The Happy Land (1965), Boys Are All Right, But…(1965), A Madras-type Jacket (1967), and Six Nights a Week (1971). (see Cage 226)</p>
         <p>William Lon Johnson (1882-1967) served as an attorney in Colville, Washington, a Senator in the Washington State Legislature, the Lieutenant Governor of Washington State, and a Superior Court Judge for the state of Washington from 1913 to 1958.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <subject source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690" altrender="nodisplay">Literature</subject>
         </controlaccess>
      </controlaccess>
  
   </archdesc>
</ead>

