<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<!--Template updated 2011-05-11 by J. Allison-Bunnell in accordance with changes that resulted in Best Practices version 3.5-->
<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
<!--                              EADHEADER BEGINS HERE                           -->
<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
<!--Remember to name and save documents using the OCLC code + local filename. Documents that are revised/updated after initial submission much be submitted with precisely the same filename.-->

<ead> 
	<!--The following section is header information that describes the finding aid-->
	<eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" id="a0"> 
		<eadid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="identifier" mainagencycode="waps" identifier="80444/xv941697" url="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:80444/xv941697">NTE2ua1985_48.xml</eadid> 
		<filedesc> 
			<titlestmt> 
				<titleproper encodinganalog="title">Preliminary Guide to the ASWSU Office Files
					<date encodinganalog="date" calendar="gregorian" era="ce" certainty="" normal="1979/1984">1979-1984</date></titleproper> 		   		  <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">ASWSU Office Files</titleproper>
				
				<author encodinganalog="creator">Finding aid prepared by Mark O'English</author>
			</titlestmt> 
			<publicationstmt> 
				
				<publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
				</publisher>
				
				<date calendar="gregorian" encodinganalog="date" normal="2022">© 2022</date> 
				
			</publicationstmt> 
		</filedesc> 
		<profiledesc> 
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by Suzanne James-Bacon.
				<date normal="2021" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2022</date></creation>
			
			<langusage>Finding aid written in English.
				<language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.</langusage> <descrules>Finding aid based
						on DACS 2nd Edition ( 
						<title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content
							Standard</title>).</descrules> 
		</profiledesc> 
	</eadheader> 
	
	<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
	<!--                         COLLECTION-LEVEL DESCRIPTION BEGINS HERE             -->
	<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
	
	<archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="marc21"> 
		<did id="a1"> 
			<repository> 
				<corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections</corpname>
				
			</repository> 
			<unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="us" repositorycode="waps" type="collection">UA1985-48</unitid>
			
			<origination> 
				<corpname encodinganalog="110" role="creator" rules="rda">Associated Students of Washington State University</corpname> </origination> 
			<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a"> Preliminary Guide to the ASWSU Office Files</unittitle>
			
			<unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" datechar="" certainty="" normal="1979/1984">1979-1984</unitdate>
			
			<physdesc> <extent encodinganalog="300$a">6.5 Linear feet of shelf space</extent>
				<extent encodinganalog="300$a">7 Boxes</extent>
			</physdesc>
			<abstract encodinganalog="5203_">Office files from the ASWSU from 1979-1984. Including board of directors documents and reprints.</abstract> 
			<physloc>(MASC STAFF USE) 2-36-10-3</physloc> 
			<langmaterial>Collection materials are in <language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
		</did>
		
		<bioghist encodinganalog="5451_" id="a2"><!--Enter ENCODINGANALOG value of 5450_ for biog. or 5451_ for historical note, or use <head> element-->		
			<p>The ASWSU (Associated Students of Washington State University) Activities Center serves the university by organizing, directing and generally over-seeing many campus-related student group activities. Administering of student organizations includes constant evaluation and advisement. </p><p>The Activities Center was established with approval of the Board of Regents in the Spring of 1947 in answer to student and faculty demands. It began operation during the fall semester of that year. The goal of the Activities Center was to enable a joint student-faculty coordination and participation in student and campus life. The student-faculty cooperative effort was to be augmented by a staff of professionals through whose help the Activities Center was "to bring efficiency and direction by coordinating and guiding existing student organizations, by assisting new groups in developing new programs, an by aiding individual students in planning a balanced program of activities." (As observed in a Review of Student Activities Center Program, April, 1948). </p><p>At the time the Activities Center was organized, most of the social activities and student involvement in campus life were coordinated by living groups. As students' living arrangements gradually became more diffuse, the Activities Center became a more important central focal point coordinating their activities. The Activities Center, therefore, became a place of general guidance, assistance and counseling for student committees and concerns. Furthermore, it became a central repository for committee records where evaluations of past activities could be used for recommendations of procedures for future efforts. In this regard, on an annual basis, evaluations of past activities could be used for recommendations of procedures for future efforts. In this regard, on an annual basis, evaluative reports are filed with the Activities Center so that evaluations of the programs can be made; these reports are filed by Committee Chairmen, as well as by faculty advisors to individual committees. </p><p>The Activities Center also played a supplemental role in reorganization of the student government. Prior to the formation of the Activities Center, and for some time after it began, the major student government organizational structure was the class governments. However, in time, and especially during the decade of the 1960s, the ASWSU (an organization of all students) superseded the class government system, and the class governments were discontinued in 1968. For the Activities Center this has meant that the role of the students, in directing and actually involving themselves in the workings of the Activities Center, has increased. What was once a joint student-faculty arrangement, in conjunction with professional administrators, has become more of a joint effort between students and professionals.</p>		
		</bioghist> 
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_" id="a3"> 
			<p>Office files from the ASWSU from 1979-1984. Including board of directors documents, articles of incorporation, and reprints. The collection is amalgamated files of President and others. </p>
		</scopecontent> 
		<arrangement encodinganalog="351" id="a4"> 
			<p>This is an unprocessed collection. Any arrangement reflects either a pre-existing order from the records' creators or previous custodians, or preliminary sorting performed by staff. </p><p>Files are mostly unorganized. Some are wrapped together but for the most part remain in no particular order. Box 3 contains applications related to organizations on campus from the Fall of 1978-Spring of 1979. Box 4 contains newspaper clippings and other administrative material. </p>
		</arrangement> 
		<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506" id="a14"> 
			<p>This collection is open and available for research use.</p>
		</accessrestrict> 
		<userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15"> 
			<p>Copyright restrictions apply.</p>
		</userestrict> 
		<prefercite encodinganalog="524" id="a18"> 
			<p>[Item description] </p>
			<p> Preliminary Guide to the ASWSU Office Files, 1979-1984 (UA1985-48) </p>
			<p>Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections, Washington State University Libraries, Pullman, WA.</p> 
		</prefercite> 
		<acqinfo encodinganalog="541" id="a19"> 
			<p>This material was transferred to WSU Libraries' MASC by Candy (last name unrecorded) of ASWSU on September 10, 1985 and retained as UA1985-48.</p>
		</acqinfo> 
		
		
		<!-- ooooooooooooooooooo     ACCESS POINTS     oooooooooooooooooooo -->
		
		<controlaccess id="a12"> 
			<p>This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online
				catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or
				places should search the catalog using these headings.</p> 
			<controlaccess> 
				<corpname role="subject" encodinganalog="610" rules="rda">Associated Students of Washington State University -- Records and correspondence</corpname>
			</controlaccess> 
			<controlaccess> 
				<subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Washington (State)</subject> 
				<subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Colleges and Universities</subject>		  
			</controlaccess> 
		</controlaccess> 
		<!--A finding aid without a series or container list may end here.-->
		
	</archdesc> </ead>

