<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.BARTONCODEX</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Lincoln Collection, Barton Codex Manuscripts<date>1829-1940</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by VMB, 2008; GMG, MEB, 2019</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Abraham Lincoln, Stephen Douglas and the Civil War</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Religion and Theology</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KEF, 2019</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to the Lincoln Collection, Barton Codex Manuscripts<date>1829-1940</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by VMB, 2008; GMG, MEB, 2019</author>
      <p>© 2019 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Lincoln Collection. Barton Codex Manuscripts</unittitle>
      <unitdate label="Dates" type="inclusive">1829-1940</unitdate>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">12.5 linear feet (19 boxes, 1 volume)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">Bound materials collected and compiled by William E. Barton, a pastor in Oak Park, Illinois, who published and lectured on Abraham Lincoln. The collection includes books, booklets, scrapbooks, pamphlets, published addresses, and periodicals. Of particular interest is the volume titled Lincoln and His Cabinet. These codex manuscripts form part of the William E. Barton Collection of Lincolniana. </abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>This collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <altformavail><head>Digital Images</head> <p>Original documents, texts, and images represented by digital images linked to this finding aid are subject to U. S. copyright law. It is the user's sole responsibility to secure any necessary copyright permission to reproduce or publish documents, texts, and images from any holders of rights in the original materials.</p><p>The University of Chicago Library, in its capacity as owner of the physical property represented by the digital images linked to this finding aid, encourages the use of these materials for educational and scholarly purposes.  Any reproduction or publication from these digital images requires that the following credit line be included:  Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p><p>Commercial publication projects require the permission of the University of Chicago Library and may be subject to a use fee. To order publication-quality reproductions, or for permission to copy or use any part of the digital images attached to this finding aid for any commercial purposes, please contact the Special Collections Research Center.</p><p>The images presented here may include materials reflecting the attitudes, language, and stereotypes of an earlier time period. These materials are presented as historical resources in support of study and research. Inclusion of such materials does not constitute an endorsement of their content by the University of Chicago.</p><p>The University of Chicago Library appreciates hearing from anyone who may have information about any of the images in this collection.</p></altformavail>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Lincoln Collection. Barton Codex Manuscripts,  [Box #, Folder #], Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.
</p>
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Biographical Note</head>
        <p>The Rev. William Eleazar Barton, born on June 28, 1861 (d. December 30, 1930) was one of the early twentieth century's most prominent writers and lecturers on the life of Abraham Lincoln. Born in Sublette, Illinois, in the same year Lincoln assumed the presidency, Barton grew up in an environment heavily influenced by reverence for Lincoln. He began undergraduate studies at Berea College in 1881 and graduated in 1885. However, during his senior year Barton decided to join the ministry and was ordained on June 6, 1885. On July 23, 1885 Barton married Esther Treat Bushnell. Together they would have 5 children. Barton returned to school and earned his divinity degree from the Oberlin Theological Seminary in 1890. He served parishes in Tennessee, Ohio, and Massachusetts before becoming the pastor of the First Congregational Church of Oak Park, Illinois, a position he held until his retirement in 1924. In 1928, Barton accepted an appointment as lecturer at Vanderbilt University in Nashville, Tennessee, where he also organized and served as pastor of the Collegeside Congregational Church.</p>
        <p/>
        <p>Barton's work as a writer produced a number of denominational manuals and a series of books presenting the wisdom and parables of a character he named Safed the Sage. For the last ten years of his life, however, Barton was best known to the public as a prolific author and lecturer on Abraham Lincoln. His publications about Lincoln included The Soul of Abraham Lincoln (1920), The Paternity of Abraham Lincoln (1920), The Life of Abraham Lincoln (1925), The Great and Good Man (1927), The Women Lincoln Loved (1927), and The Lincoln of the Biographers (1930).</p>
        <p/>
        <p>In the course of compiling material for his writings and talks, Barton visited Lincoln sites in Kentucky, Indiana, and Illinois; interviewed surviving Lincoln relatives and acquaintances; and traveled as far as California and England to collect information and conduct genealogical research on the ancestry of the Lincoln family. While acquiring a large collection of books, periodicals, pamphlets, manuscripts, and ephemera related to Lincoln and the Civil War era, Barton also purchased privately or at auction historical materials amassed by other Lincoln collectors such as John E. Burton and Osborn H. Oldroyd.</p>
        <p/>
        <p/>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The Barton Codex Manuscripts is made up of bound materials compiled by William E. Barton, a pastor in Oak Park, Illinois, who published and lectured on Abraham Lincoln extensively. Barton also maintained connections with fellow Lincoln experts and carried out multiple research projects that delved into the many facets of Lincoln's life, times, and family history. This collection divided into six series: ministry; books; theater; booklets, pamphlets and periodicals; published addresses, lectures and research papers; and lastly, scrapbooks. Of particular interest is the volume titled Lincoln and His Cabinet. These codex manuscripts form part of the William E. Barton Collection of Lincolniana. </p>
      </scopecontent>
      
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="https://www.lib.uchicago.edu/h/ead-topic-browse">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Barton, William Eleazar, 1861-1930</persname>
        <persname>Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865</persname>
        <persname/>
        <subject>Collectors and collecting -- United States</subject>
        <subject>American Civil War, 1861-1865</subject>
        <subject>Church History</subject>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series I: Barton Ministry</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>This series contains materials related to Barton's career in the Ministry, including books, sermons and sermon notes, clippings and articles. </p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>First Presbyterian Church Board of Trustees Minutes, Springfield, Illinois, 1829-1866</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Press notices of sermons and addresses by William E. Barton, news-clippings and notes tipped in, 1894-1907</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Notes and correspondence, from ledger of church finances, 1903-1915</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Actual ledger of church finances 1903-1915</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">1-2</container>
            <unittitle>Addresses and articles on ministry, containing correspondence, reprints, and clippings, 1911-1928</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Order for Evening Worship, Boston: F. H. Gilson Company, 1892. Notes and news-clippings tipped in, 1911-1928</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Addresses and articles on education, containing interleaved notes, articles, and reprints, 1913-1926</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Papers removed from Addresses and articles on education, 1913-1926</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Church programs and bulletins from Lent, Holy Week, and Easter, 1914-1923</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>"Sermon Outline", sermon notes and outlines (of Barton's), 1915</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Clippings removed from "Sermon Outline", 1915</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Bound clippings from Barton's column "The Making of the New Testament," 1915-1917</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Notes and news-clippings in volume titled "Annual Handbook, Central Congregational Church," 1915</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Calendar, contains interleaved notes and news-clippings, 1917</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Ministry programs and bulletins, 1897-1922</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>Program from the Boston Congregational Club Forefathers Festival (at which Barton spoke), December 21, 1897</item>
                <item>Barton, William E. "Our Fight for the Heritage of Humanity," sermon published by the Men's Bible Class, Congregational Church, Oak Park, Illinois, 1917</item>
                <item>Bulletin for service at First Congregational Church, Oak Park, Illinois, where Barton delivered the sermon, "The Abiding Influence of George Washington," 1920</item>
                <item>Barton, William E. "Theodore Roosevelt," sermon, 1920</item>
                <item>Bulletin for service at First Congregational Church, Oak Park, Illinois, where Barton delivered the sermon, "Theodore Roosevelt," 1920</item>
                <item>Information for visitors to the Parish Church of St. Nicholas, Great Yarmouth, 1923</item>
                <item>The Open Court: A Monthly Magazine, vol. XXXVIII (No. 9), 1922</item>
                <item>The Open Court: A Monthly Magazine, vol. XXXVII (No. 10), 1922</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E., Theodore G. Soares, and Sidney Strong. Su Ultima Semana: La Historia de la Pasion y Resurrection de Jesus, Chihuahua: Imprenta Palmore, 1921</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Bound clippings regarding Barton's lecture series titled "The Religion of the Ancient Poets," 1923</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series II: Books</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="volume">BartonCdx1</container>
            <unittitle>Abraham Lincoln and His Cabinet: A Collection of Autographs, 1851-1889</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Worcester, J.E. Elements of History, Ancient and Modern, includes note by Barton, 1833</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence of Robert Weidensall. prepared by the Illinois Historical Records Survey Project in 1940, correspondence dates from 1861-1865</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Hale, Edward E. Seven Spanish Cities. Boston: Roberts Brothers, 1883, with letter from Barton, 1923</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. Lieutenant William Barton of Morris County, New Jersey, and his Descendants. Oak Park, Ill.: Vaile Press, 1900</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Mary Lincoln: A letter to Her Cousin Elizabeth Todd Grimsly, letter written on September 29, 1861, privately printed, 1917</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. Abraham Lincoln and His Books, Marshall Field and company, 1920</unittitle><daogrp><resource label="start"/> <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/bartoncodex-0005-001" role="application/pdf"> <daodesc><p>View digitized documents.</p></daodesc></daoloc> <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/> </daogrp>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Wilson, Clarence True. John Wilkes Booth: Thirty-Eight Years a Fugitive, includes correspondence, 1922?</unittitle><daogrp><resource label="start"/> <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/bartoncodex-0005-002" role="application/pdf"> <daodesc><p>View digitized documents.</p></daodesc></daoloc> <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/> </daogrp>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. Abraham Lincoln, American, etched book and letter, 1923</unittitle><daogrp><resource label="start"/> <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/bartoncodex-0005-003" role="application/pdf"> <daodesc><p>View digitized documents.</p></daodesc></daoloc> <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/> </daogrp>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Lincoln, Waldo. History of the Lincoln Family, Worcester Massachusetts Commonwealth Press, 1923</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">6</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. Esther T. Barton: A Biographical Sketch. Foxboro, Mass.: Pine Knoll, 1926</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">6</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Townsend, William H. Lincoln in His Wife's Home, 1926</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">6</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Grimsley, Elizabeth Todd. Six Months in the White House, 1926-1927</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">6</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. The Women Lincoln Loved, printer's dummy, autographed copy, Bobbs-Merrill, 1927</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">6</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Smith, T.V. Lincoln, Living Legend, The University of Chicago Press, 1940</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">7</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Baber, Adin. Nancy Hanks of "Undistinguished Families—Second Families", typed and mimeographed by C. Gerald Brann, Bloomington IN, c. 1959</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">7</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Index to Adin Baber, Nancy Hanks of "Undistinguished Families, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">7</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Baber, Adin. Nancy Hanks, The Destined Mother of a President, privately printed by author, Kansas, Illinois, 1963</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">8</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Blair, Montgomery. Not General Grant, manuscript presented to Hon. Gideon Welles, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series III: Theater</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>This series contains manuscripts of plays and other documents related to the theater.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">8</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Day, Robert. Anne Rutledge: life, love, immortality, play manuscript and correspondence, 1922</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">8</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Hermann, Lüdke. "Abraham Lincoln," a play translated from German by Robert L. Floyd, 193-?</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">8</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>"A Folk Festival: Out of the Wilderness, the New Salem Years of Abraham Lincoln." Compiled by the workers of the Writers' program of the Work Projects Administration in Illinois, play presented at New Salem state park, 1940</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">8</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Neff, Elizabeth. "Abraham Lincoln as a Character in American and English drama," Master of Arts thesis, University of Oklahoma, 1942</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">8</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>McNett, Marie. Cradle of Glory: A Drama in Three Acts, play manuscript, 1948</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series IV: Booklets, Pamphlets, and Periodicals</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">9</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Irwin, Benjamin F. Lincoln's Religious Belief, clipped from Illinois State Journal, 1874</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">9</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Herndon, W.H. A Brief Analysis of Lincoln's Character. letter to J.E. Remsburg, 1887</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">9</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>"Unwritten History: The Secret Movement to Supersede Abraham Lincoln in '64." The New York Sun, includes unpublished letters of Horace Greeley, Charles Sumner, Secretary Chase, 1889</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">9</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>MacDonald, Edward. Old Capp's Hill and Burial Ground with Historical Sketches, Industrial School Press, 1895</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">9</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>"The Centennial Celebration of the Old Mud-Meeting House near Harrodsburg, Kentucky." August 25, 1900</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">9</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Conant, Alban Jasper. Painter of Lincoln and Other Great Men, New York Times, 1913 and A Portrait Painter's Reminiscences of Lincoln, McClure's Magazine 32:512-516, 1909-1913</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">9</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Clark, L. Pierce. Psychologic Study of Abraham Lincoln, booklet reprinted from The Psychoanalytic Review, Vol III No. I, 1921</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">9</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Martin, James M. A Defense of Lincoln's Mother: Open Letter to William E. Barton, manuscript of letter originally published in Minneapolis Journal, includes correspondence, 1921</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">9</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. "Lincoln, The Young Rail Splitter," Official Magazine North American young Men's Christian Association, includes correspondence, 1922</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">10</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. Mord Lincoln, the Woman Hater, published in the Open Court, May 1924</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">10</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Townsend, William Henry. "Lincoln the Litigant," American Bar Association Journal, includes typewritten copies of article and revision for separate publication, 1924</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">10</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Malone, Thomas J. Lincoln, "Like Washington, Was a Miller," published in The Northwestern Miller 145:6 551-569, 1926</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">10</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>City of Norwich Official Guide booklet. Includes postcards, notes, correspondence, 1927.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">10</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Carter, Mary D. "Putting First Things First," Southern Churchman, 1929</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">10</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>The Abraham Lincoln Association. Lincoln in the Year 1855: Being the Day-by-Day Activities of Abraham Lincoln During that Year, The Abraham Lincoln Association, 1929; The Abraham Lincoln Association. Lincoln in the Year 1856: Being the Day-by-Day Activities of Abraham Lincoln During that Year, The Abraham Lincoln Association, 1929</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">10</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>The Abraham Lincoln Association. Lincoln in the Year 1858: Being the Day-by-Day Activities of Abraham Lincoln During that Year, The Abraham Lincoln Association, 1929</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">10</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>The Abraham Lincoln Association. Lincoln in the Year 1859: Being the Day-by-Day Activities of Abraham Lincoln During that Year, The Abraham Lincoln Association, 1929</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">10</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>The Abraham Lincoln Association. Lincoln in the Year 1860: Being the Day-by-Day Activities of Abraham Lincoln During that Year, The Abraham Lincoln Association, 1929</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">11</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Catalogue of Herndon-Weik Lincoln Collection. Contains correspondence, 1933</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">11</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>"Lincoln Booklet Dedicated to Dr. Wm. Barton." Children's compositions in manuscript, 19--?</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series V: Published Addresses, Lectures, and Research Papers</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">11</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Lincoln, Abraham. Lincoln's first address ("His Temperance Lecture", 1842</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">11</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Lincoln, Abraham. Collection of public addresses, Kansas, 1859</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">11</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Everett, Edward. "Address following battle at Gettysburg", 1863</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">11</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>John H. Surratt. "The Assassination of Lincoln with an Account of the Several Plots for his Abduction," lecture delivered December 6, 1870, printed in Washington Star December 8, 1870</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">11</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. "Message to a Young Man," published address delivered at the forty-third anniversary of the Boston YMCA, 1894</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">12</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Lincoln, Abraham. Reproduction of original book compiled by Lincoln consisting of newspaper clippings of Lincoln's speeches, includes explanatory note by J. McCan Davis, 1903</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">12</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Berstorff, Count J. Abraham Lincoln as the Germans Regarded Him, public address, 1913</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">12</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Ballantine, Dr. W. G. Lincoln—America's greatest product, published lecture, 1919</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">12</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. "Lincoln and Illinois" addresses at Chicago Union League Club, Quincy Illinois, and Illinois State Historical Society, includes correspondence between Barton and event organizers, 1921</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">12</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. "The Man Who Married Lincoln's Parents", address at Harrodsburg, Kentucky, includes clippings and correspondence, 1922</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">12</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Blair, Francis G. Newton Bateman, an address given in dedication of the Newton Bateman school, includes manuscript, clippings, correspondence and event pamphlet, 1922</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">12</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Kaufman, M.S. "Abraham Lincoln, The Friend of God and Man", sermon delivered at the National Soldiers' home in California, 1922</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">12</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>McCamant, Wallace. Manuscript of lecture Lincoln in the Winter of 1861, includes correspondence, 1922</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">12</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Shaw, James. "A neglected episode in the life of Abraham Lincoln," address delivered before the Illinois State Historical Society at Springfield, 1922</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">12</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. Lincoln and Chicago, public address at Chicago historical Society, February 10, 1922, includes event pamphlet and related writings, 1922-1924</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">13</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. "Abraham Lincoln, Kentucky Mountaineer", address delivered at Berea College, 1923</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">13</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>"Lincoln and the Newspapers", a published address by Charles T. White, 1923</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">13</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>"Dr. Barton as a Father," toast delivered by his son Robert Barton, March 12, 1924</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">13</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Graves, Walter. Abraham Lincoln and the Common Virtues, includes lecture manuscript and correspondence, 1924</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">13</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Fortune, William. Address on Lincoln before Southwestern Indiana Historical Society, includes correspondence and clippings, 1925.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">13</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. "The enduring Lincoln," published address delivered in Urbana, Illinois, includes clippings and correspondence, 1928</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">13</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Henderson, Manfred. "The Handwriting of Lincoln: A Study in Identification," Los Angeles, California, 1931</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">13</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Scherger, George Lawrence. "Lincoln—a man for the ages", lecture, 1932</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">13</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Lutz, Phillip. "We stand on sacred soil today" and "The fourth of July in Lincoln's time and today", public addresses, 1935</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">13</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>"The Name and Family of Lincoln," research compiled by the Media Research Bureau, Washington D.C., 1936?</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series VI: Scrapbooks</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>The majority of Barton's scrapbooks consist of published texts into which he pasted folded newspaper clippings, prints, and notes. For additional scrapbooks see Lincoln Collection. Barton Scrapbooks.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">14</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Lincoln Versus Douglas scrapbook. Includes clippings and handwritten notes, 1850-1860</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">14</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Set of clippings titled "Epitaph on the XXXVII Congress: Anti-Lincoln Tract," 1862</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">14</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Cartoons from Fun, London, 1862-1869</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">14</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Untitled scrapbook filled with hand-written notes, an excerpt from John Wilkes Booth's diary, prints, and photocopied manuscripts, 1865-1925</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">14</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Set of clippings titled "Recollections of Lincoln," 1866-1904</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">14</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Catalogue of relics owned by William E. Barton and Esther T. Barton, his wife, in William Barton's hand, which also contains a reprint of Barton's "Quest of an Ancestor" from The New England Magazine, 1898</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">14</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Abraham Lincoln's Religion. William H. Herndon, includes correspondence, public lecture, and clippings of article, 1911</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">14</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Set of clippings titled "The Parentage of Abraham Lincoln by D.J. Knotts" and subtitled "Articles affirming that he was the son of John C. Calhoun," 1911</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">15</container>
            <container type="folder">1-2</container>
            <unittitle>William E. Barton, "Church Music," loose and bound articles on religious music, 1913-1929</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">15</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Addresses and articles on the fine arts, mostly reviews (by Barton and others) of painters and paintings, from The Advance, 1914-1915</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">15</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Papers removed from Addresses and articles on the fine arts, 1913-1915</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">15</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>The Physiognomy of Lincoln, and An Old Likeness of Lincoln, by Truman H. Bartlett, includes clippings and correspondence with William E. Barton, 1917-1921</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">15</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>"Providential Presidents" by John M. Vandermeulen, includes correspondence between Vandermeulen and Barton, 1918-1923</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">15</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Abraham Lincoln: A Study of his Personality, by Thomas Power O'Connor, includes mounted clippings from the London Daily Telegraph, August 2-3, 1920</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">16</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Abraham Lincoln as I Knew Him by John H. Littlefield n.p. c. 1891, includes clippings and correspondence, correspondence 1920</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">16</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Lincoln's First Nomination. Scrapbook includes clippings of writings by Chauncey M. Depew and funeral service materials for Jessie Harvey Robinson (d. 1918), 1920</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">16</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Mather, Otis M. "Old Hodgenville," clippings from the La Rue County Herald, 1920</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">16</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Reviews of William E. Barton's the Paternity of Abraham Lincoln. Clippings pasted over "He Shall Seek Peace", 1920-1921</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">16</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Lincoln: Anne Routledge. Clippings, photographs and correspondence, 1920-1922?</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">16</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. "Aunt Sallie Saunders, an interview with the youngest sister of Ann Rutledge," published interview, clippings, and memorial pamphlet, 1921-1922</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">16</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>The Parents of Abraham Lincoln, includes clippings, correspondence, and typewritten manuscript, 1922</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">17</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. The American Pulpit on the Death of Lincoln, includes manuscript later published in The Open Court, 1923</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">17</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Collection of Lincoln letters and articles written by Nathaniel Howard from the Cleveland Plain Dealer, 1924</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">17</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>"Force or Consent as Basis of American Government" by Dr. Mary Scrugham, includes correspondence and published debate between William H. Townsend and Dr. Scrugham, 1924</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">17</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Fitz Henry, Charles. "The Human and Divine in Lincoln, with Letters," Peoria Journal transcript, correspondence, and photograph, 1926</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">17</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Rindlaub, Martin Philip. Abraham Lincoln with reminiscences of the Freeport Debate and the Chicago Convention, includes original manuscript, correspondence, and photos, Kiwanis Magazine, 1926</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">17</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Where Lincoln Attended Church by Rev. Joseph R. Sizoo, published in The National Republic, also includes The Lincoln Pew by L.W. Allen and notes by Barton, 1926</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">18</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Untitled scrapbook of newspaper clippings about Lincoln assassination, 1865</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">18</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Newspaper clippings removed from untitled scrapbook, 1930-1941</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">19</container>
            <unittitle>Barton, William E. Jesse Head, scrapbook includes typewritten and manuscript articles, correspondence, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
