<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.BONNEY</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Bonney Family Correspondence<date>1860-1864, 1868</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by BB, 1964; MEH, 2005</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Abraham Lincoln, Stephen Douglas and the Civil War</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Military, War and Veterans</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KEF, 2006</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to the Bonney Family Correspondence<date>1860-1864, 1868</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by BB, 1964; MEH, 2005</author>
      <p>© 2006 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Bonney Family. Correspondence</unittitle>
      <unitdate label="Dates" type="inclusive">1860-1864, 1868</unitdate>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">0.25 linear feet (1 box)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">The Bonney Family Civil War Letters collection is comprised of 48 letters written to their parents by Daniel, James, and Seth Bonney, soldiers in Massachusetts regiments during the Civil War. With the exception of one letter from Seth, written in 1868, the correspondence in the collection falls within the period 1860-1864, and describes the various experiences of the three brothers in camp, field, prison, and hospital.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Bonney Family. Correspondence, [Box #, Folder #], Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Biographical Note</head>
        <p>Daniel, Seth and James Bonney served in Massachusetts regiments during the Civil War. Seth Bonney, who was with the 26th Massachusetts Volunteers, wrote from Ship Island, Mississippi, Savannah, New Orleans, and from Virginia, Nebraska, and Pennsylvania. Daniel Bonney, with the 15th Massachusetts Volunteers, served in Maryland and Virginia, where he was wounded; several of his letters were written from Army hospitals in Washington, D.C., and Baltimore. James Bonney, also with the 15th Massachusetts Regiment, was captured in 1861, and spent some time in a prison camp at Richmond, Virginia. After an exchange of prisoners, he spent two years in the Commissary Department of a parole camp at Annapolis. Finally he returned to his regiment in April, 1864, and soon afterwards was reported wounded or killed.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The body of this collection is comprised of 48 letters, totaling some 150 pages, which were written to their parents by Daniel, James, and Seth Bonney, who were soldiers in Massachusetts regiments during the Civil War. With the exception of one letter from Seth, written in 1868, the correspondence in the collection falls within the period 1860-1864, and describes the various experiences of the three brothers in camp, field, prison, and hospital.</p>
        <p>The collection includes, in addition to the letters written by the Bonney brothers, a letter to James Bonney from Henry Putnam, written at a camp near Yorktown, Virginia, a letter from Samuel Hogkins, in the Adjutant General&#146;s Office, to John Bonney, about James, who was reported to be both dead and alive but gravely wounded, and a copy of the orders appointing James clerk, and instructing him to report for duty at the parole camp.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="https://www.lib.uchicago.edu/h/ead-topic-browse">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Bonney, Daniel</persname>
        <persname>Bonney, James</persname>
        <persname>Bonney, Seth</persname>
        <subject>Soldiers -- Massachusetts -- Correspondence</subject>
        <geogname>United States -- History, Civil War -- 1861-1865</geogname>
        <geogname>United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865, Personal Narratives</geogname>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">1</container>
          <unittitle>Letters from Seth Bonney</unittitle>
          <note>
            <list>
              <item>To James Bonney, about a job, 3p, 1860, September 22</item>
              <item>To Daniel Bonney, 2 p. (Fall of 1861)</item>
              <item>(no place) 2 p. 1861 (October?) 22</item>
              <item>Camp Chase, 2 p. Lowell 1861, November 10</item>
              <item>Constitution, anchored off Ship Island, Miss. 2 p. 1861, December 5</item>
              <item>Ship Island, 4 p. 1862, February 12</item>
              <item>Camp Constitution, 4 p. Ship Island 1862, April 10</item>
              <item>Pass Sontre (Near mouth of Mississippi) 1 p.  1862, April 11</item>
              <item>Camp Constitution, Ship Island 3 p. 1862, April 14</item>
              <item>Fort Jackson, 5 p. 1862, May 27</item>
              <item>Savannah, Georgia, 2 p. 1862, June 18</item>
              <item>New Orleans, p. 4 1862, August 4</item>
              <item>Camp near Cedar Creek, Va. 1 p. 1862, November 6</item>
              <item>New Orleans, 4 p. 1862, November 13</item>
              <item>New Orleans, 2 p. 1863, February 23</item>
              <item>Omaha Barracks, Nebraska, 2 p.  1864, May 7</item>
              <item>?, Va., 2 p. 1864, July 23</item>
              <item>Camp in the field two miles from Buryville, Pa., 4 p. 1864, August 20</item>
              <item>Camp on Republican River, Nebraska, 1 p. 1868, November </item>
            </list>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">2</container>
          <unittitle>Letters from Daniel Bonney</unittitle>
          <note>
            <list>
              <item>Co. B, No. 15 reg., pickett gard. 4 miles west of Camp Foster, Poolsville, Md., 4 p. 1861, September 22</item>
              <item>Co. B, 15th Regt., Camp Foster, Poolesville, Md., 4 p.1861, November 7</item>
              <item>Hampton, Va., 4 p. 1862, April 2</item>
              <item>Pine Woods, Va., 4 p. 1862, May 17</item>
              <item>Beverdam Creek, Va., 4 p. 1862, May 25</item>
              <item>Fair Oaks, Va., 2 p. 1862, June 22</item>
              <item>Bolivar Heights, Va., 3 p. 1862, October 9</item>
              <item>Bolivar Heights, Va., 3 p. 1862, October 19</item>
              <item>Worington, Va., 4 p. 1862, November 13</item>
              <item>Campbell Hospital, Washington, D.C., 1 p. 1862, December 20</item>
              <item>Campbell Hospital, Washington, D.C., 3 p. 1862, December 26</item>
              <item>U.S. Army General Hospital, 94 Camden Street, Baltimore, Md., 3 p. (1863) January 9</item>
              <item>U.S. Army General Hospital, 94 Camden Street, Baltimore, Md., 1 p. (1863) (January ?)</item>
              <item>U.S. Army General Hospital, 94 Camden Street, Baltimore, Md., 3 p. 1863, February 12</item>
            </list>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">3</container>
          <unittitle>Letters from James Bonney</unittitle>
          <note>
            <list>
              <item>Relay Station, Washington Junction, 4 p. 1861 May 2</item>
              <item>Headquarters, 15th Massachusetts Regiment, Camp Haloramo, Co. C., Washington, D.C., 4 p. 1861 August 14</item>
              <item>Corp. Bs Picket, No. 5, on East Shore of Potomac, 4 p. 1861 September 8</item>
              <item>Richmond, Va. (Prison camp), 4 p. (1861)	December 22</item>
              <item>Richmond, Va. (Prison camp), 4 p. (1862)	February 18</item>
              <item>Capitol Building, Washington D.C., 2 p. 1862, February 28</item>
              <item>Camp Sangston, 2 p. 1862, December 22</item>
              <item>Commissary Department, Parole Camp, Annapolis, Md., 3 p. (1863) February 1</item>
              <item>Commissary Department, Parole Camp, Annapolis, Md., 3 p. (1863) February 15</item>
              <item>Commissary Department, Parole Camp, Annapolis, Md., 3 p. 1863, April 1</item>
              <item>Commissary Department, Parole Camp, Annapolis, Md., 2 p. 1863, May 15</item>
              <item>Commissary Department, Parole Camp, Annapolis, Md. 1 p. 1863, June 11</item>
              <item>Headquarters, Provost Guards, Gilmore House, Calvert Street, Baltimore, Md., 4 p. 1863, August 8</item>
              <item>Commissary Department, Parole Camp, Annapolis, Md., 4 p. 1863, December 25</item>
              <item>Camp 15th Massachusetts Volunteers, 2 p. 1864, April 20</item>
              <item>Special Orders 119, appointing James Bonney Clerk, and instructing him to report for duty to Lieutenant James H. Grinnell, A. C. Subsistence of Camp Parole, by order of Lieutenant Colonel George Sangster, June 26, 1863</item>
              <item>Samuel Hodgkins, Adjt Genls Office, Washington, D.C., to John Bonney, n.p. about James Bonney, wounded or killed. 2 p. 1864, June 10</item>
              <item>Henry Putnam, Camp near Yorktown, Va., to James Bonney, n.p.4 p. 1862, March 11</item>
            </list>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
