<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.CHAMBERSCS</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Caleb Stockton Chambers Collection<date>1832-1833</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by TH, 2015</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KEF, 2016</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to the Caleb Stockton Chambers Collection<date>1832-1833</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by TH, 2015</author>
      <p>© 2016 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Chambers, Caleb Stockton. Collection</unittitle>
      <unitdate label="Dates" type="inclusive">1832-1833</unitdate>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English;
</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">0.25 linear feet (1 box)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">Caleb Stockton Chambers (born circa 1815) was a student in Washington, Pennsylvania, presumably at Washington &amp; Jefferson College.  This collection contains a selection of letters written to Chambers by his family members in 1832 and 1833.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Chambers, Caleb Stockton. Collection, [Box #, Folder #], Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Biographical Note</head>
        <p>Caleb Stockton Chambers was born in late 1815 or early 1816 to Arthur and Elainor Chambers.  He was baptized at the Presbyterian Church of the Upper West Conogogheaue on February 25, 1816.  Nothing is known of his early life, but judging from the letters in this collection, Chambers was raised in a very religious household.  He later went on to college in Washington, Pennsylvania.  It is unknown which college he was attending when he received these letters, as no direct mention is made, but it may have been Washington &amp; Jefferson College.  The school was established in 1781 by John McMillan, Thaddeus Dod, and Joseph Smith, three Presbyterian missionaries.  As the most prominent college in the city and with its religious foundations, it is likely Chambers attended.  </p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The Caleb Stockton Chambers Collection contains 6 items.  These items are all letters written to Stockton from various members of his family – including his father, Arthur, his mother, Elainor, and his grandmother, Jane McFarland - while he was at college in Washington, PA.  Five of the letters are silked.  The letters date from late 1832 to mid-1833.  All letters are arranged in chronological order. ;</p>
        <p>;</p>
        <p>The collection was previously part of the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection.;</p>
        <p>;</p>
        <p/>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/scrc/findingaids/topics.php">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Chambers, Caleb Stockton</persname>
        <occupation>College students -- Pennsylvania -- History -- 19th century</occupation>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">1</container>
          <unittitle>Letters, 1832-1833</unittitle>
          <note>
            <list>
              <item>Letter: Elainor Chambers to Caleb Chambers, December 5, 1832</item>
              <item>Letter: Elainor Chambers to Caleb Chambers, January 8, 1833</item>
              <item>Letter: Unknown to Caleb Chambers, January 30, 1833</item>
              <item>Letter: Jane McFarland to Caleb Chambers, February 23, 1833</item>
              <item>Letter: Arthur Chambers, Elainor Chambers to Caleb Chambers, June 18, 1833</item>
              <item>Letter: Arthur Chambers to Caleb Chambers, July 29, 1833</item>
            </list>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
