<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.COULTER</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the John Merle Coulter Papers<date>1845-1929</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by HS, 1968; MH, 2005</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Biological Sciences and Ecology</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KEF, 2006</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to the John Merle Coulter Papers<date>1845-1929</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by HS, 1968; MH, 2005</author>
      <p>© 2006 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Coulter, John Merle. Papers</unittitle>
      <unitdate label="Dates" type="inclusive">1845-1929</unitdate>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">2.0 linear feet (4 boxes)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">John Merle Coulter (1851-1928), botanist and chair of the Botany Department of the University of Chicago, 1896-1926. The Papers contain the correspondence and personal papers of Coulter’s parents, relating mainly to a brief missionary tour to China. The collection also includes letters and school mementos, drafts of many of Coulter's postwar lectures and articles, and miscellaneous papers relating to his activities during the last five years of his life.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Coulter, John Merle. Papers</p>
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Biographical Note</head>
        <p>John Merle Coulter (1851-1928), was born in China to Presbyterian missionaries  Moses and Caroline Coulter. According to official records at Hanover College and Indiana University, he received an AB (1870) and honorary PhD (1884) from Hanover College and an honorary PhD (1884) from Indiana University.</p>
        <p>Coulter served as Professor of Natural Sciences at Hanover College from 1874 to 1879 and Professor of Biology at Wabash College from 1879 to 1891. From 1891 to 1893, he was President of Indiana State University, then of Lake Forest College, from 1893-1896. In 1896, he became Chair of the Botany Department at the University of Chicago, where he remained until his retirement in 1925. In retirement, Coulter worked with the Boyce Thompson Institute for Plant Research in Yonkers, New York.</p>
        <p>In addition to his academic appointments, Coulter served as Assistant Geologist and Botanist for the Hayden Survey of what is now Yellowstone National Park (1872) and, in 1875, co-founded the Botanical Bulletin, soon renamed the Botanical Gazette. A staunch evolutionist and Presbyterian, he had a particular interest in the correlation of science and religion.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The John M. Coulter Papers contain the correspondence and personal papers of Coulter's parents.  These items relate mainly to the brief missionary tour of the Coulters at the Presbyterian Mission at Ningbo, China, which was terminated by Moses Coulter's death in 1853. The collection also includes letters and school mementos, drafts of many of Coulter's postwar lectures and articles, and miscellaneous papers relating to his activities during the last five years of his life.  These activities included a trip to China and Japan in 1923, a project to write biographies for college students of important men of science, and the directorship of Boyce Thompson Institute for Plant Research at Yonkers, New York.  </p>
        <p>The collection is divided into two series. Series I includes letters and personal papers evidently preserved by Mrs. Caroline E. Coulter relating mainly to the brief missionary tour of the Coulters at the Presbyterian Mission at Ningbo, China, which was terminated by Moses Coulter's death in 1853. Series II comprises the principal portion of the collection is made up of letters and school mementos preserved by John M. Coulter’s mother and his mother-in-law, Anna M. Gaylord, drafts of many of Coulter's postwar lectures and articles, and miscellaneous papers relating to his activities during the last five years of his life: a trip to China and Japan in 1923, a project to write biographies for college students of important men of science, and the directorship of Boyce Thompson Institute for Plant Research at Yonkers, New York.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="https://www.lib.uchicago.edu/h/ead-topic-browse">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Coulter, John Merle, 1851-1928</persname>
        <corpname>Geological and Geographical Survey of the Territories (U.S.)</corpname>
        <corpname>Yellowstone National Park</corpname>
        <occupation>Botanists</occupation>
        <occupation>Missionaries</occupation>
        <occupation>Missionaries -- China</occupation>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series I:	Moses and Caroline Coulter Papers</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>This series includes letters and personal papers evidently preserved by Mrs. Caroline E. Coulter. They relate mainly to the brief missionary tour of the Coulters at the Presbyterian Mission at Ningbo, China, which was terminated by Moses Coulter's death in 1853. The highlight of this portion of the collection is a small group of letters written to Mrs. Coulter by friends still in Ningbo following her return to the United States in 1854 with her two small sons, John and Stanley (sometimes referred to as "Diddi" in the letters). These letters describe the continuing activities of the mission in the mid- and late 1850's and early 1860's and give some picture of the attitudes of the missionaries themselves.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Commonplace Book: "To Mrs. Cara E. Coulter from her Affectionate Husband Moses S. Coulter." Contains: 1) Essays by Moses Coulter, June-July, 1845. 2) Journal of a Voyage from New York to China kept by Caroline Coulter, 1849. 3) "The Battle," a poem by Moses Coulter, 1846.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Diaries of Moses Coulter, Sept. 4, 1848-Jan. 1, 1849: Lettered "A" and "B".</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Will of Moses S. Coulter, Sept. 30, 1851.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Letters to and from Moses S. Coulter.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Fragment of a letter describing Moses Coulter's last illness, c. 1853. (The letter is unsigned, but it appears to be in Caroline Coulter's hand.)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Mr. and Mrs. H. V. Rankin. 15 letters, 1854-1861.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Joseph K. Wright. 6 letters, 1853-1859.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Mr. and Mrs. R. Q. Way. 9 letters, 1854-1870.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Dr. and Mrs. D. B. McCartee. 8 letters, 1855-1874.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Mrs. E. A. Goddard. 2 letters and one fragment, 1856-57.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Mr. and Mrs. A. P. Hopper. 2 letters, 1859.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Other missionary letters: Caroline A. Cobhold[?]. 1 letter, June 13, 1855. Unsigned. 1 letter, May 29, 1863.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Jane Coulter to her daughter-in-law (Caroline) and her grandson, letters, 1853-1868.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Postcards addressed to Caroline Coulter from John Coulter and members of his family. 18 cards, none dated.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>John Coulter's children to their grandmother, Caroline Coulter, none dated.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous. 3 letters, 1 telegram.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>Letters by Caroline Coulter. 3.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series II:	Papers of John M. Coulter</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>This series comprises the principal portion of the collection is made up of letters and school mementos preserved by John M. Coulter’s mother and his mother-in-law, Anna M. Gaylord, drafts of many of Coulter's postwar lectures and articles, and miscellaneous papers relating to his activities during the last five years of his life: a trip to China and Japan in 1923, a project to write biographies for college students of important men of science, and the directorship of Boyce Thompson Institute for Plant Research at Yonkers, New York.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">18</container>
            <unittitle>Letters addressed to John Coulter by friends of his mother and by relatives. 4 letters, 1859-76.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">19</container>
            <unittitle>John M. Coulter to Caroline E. Coulter. 9 letters, 1872-79. 1862-70.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">20</container>
            <unittitle>John M. Coulter to Caroline E. Coulter and Georgie Gaylord Coulter. 3 letters, 1879-84.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">21</container>
            <unittitle>John M. Coulter to Georgie Gaylord [Coulter]. 7 letters, 1872-73.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">22</container>
            <unittitle>John M. Coulter to Caroline E. Coulter. 11 letters, 1872-73.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">23</container>
            <unittitle>John Coulter to Caroline E. Coulter. 6 letters, May-June, 1903.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">24</container>
            <unittitle>John Coulter to Caroline E. Coulter. 9 letters, July-August, 1903.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">25</container>
            <unittitle>John Coulter to Caroline E. Coulter. 12 letters, Sept.-Nov., 1903.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">26</container>
            <unittitle>Others in family to Caroline Coulter. 8 letters, June-Oct., 1903.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">27</container>
            <unittitle>Georgie Coulter to her mother, Anna M. Gaylord. 18 letters, May-Oct., 1903.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">28</container>
            <unittitle>John M. Coulter to Caroline Coulter. 22 letters, Oct., 1905 - March, 1906.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">29</container>
            <unittitle>Other members of family to Caroline Coulter. 2 letters, Nov., 1905.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">30</container>
            <unittitle>Georgie Coulter to Anna M. Gaylord. 21 letters, 1905-06.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">31</container>
            <unittitle>John M. Coulter to Caroline E. Coulter. 3 letters.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Compositions by John M. Coulter: "Lines dedicated to my mother on her 34th birthday, Mar. 24, 1862." "Description of Waveland Collegiate Institute." Feb., 1863.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Student Notebook: English Literature.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Reports of Standing: Hanover College, 1866, 1868, 1870 (5 reports)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Certificate of Marriage: John M. Coulter to Georgie M. Gaylord. Jan. 1, 1874. Pasted in front of a copy of The Marriage Gift by James Petrie.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Botanical Gazette, edited by John M. and M. Stanley Coulter: Mailing list for 1889 and miscellaneous papers.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Notebooks (2). Notes made on European trips of 1903 and 1905. (Back of 1905-06 notebook contains cancelled draft of an article on Asa Gray.)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>China -Japan Trip (1923-24): Itinerary.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>China-Japan Trip (1923-24): Postcards, photographs, and clippings.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Boyce Thompson Institute: Birthday greeting, Nov. 20, 1926, signed by members of staff. Copy of Contributions, Jan. 1, 1925.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Encyclopedia Britannica, correspondence concerning articles for. Sept., 1928.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Notices.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Telegrams of sympathy. Testament of Hyde Park Men's Club.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Letters of sympathy.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Coulter's lapsed life insurance policy. Correspondence with Mutual Life Insurance, by Merle Coulter (son), Dec., 1928-Jan., 1929.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2 </container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Letter to Merle Coulter, concerning his share in estate.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>List of addresses and papers</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>The Botanical Opportunity</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Botany as a National Asset</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Development of Botany in the United States</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>The Evolution of Botanical Research</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>The Evolution of Plants</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>The Future of Botany</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>The New Botany</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>The Biological Background of Religious Education</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>The Case for Religions</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Christianity and Science</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>The Cooperation of Science and Religion</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Evolution and Christianity (another version of folder 12)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Evolution and its Explanations (reprint from Christian Century, May 22, 1922.)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>The History of Organic Evolution</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>The Meaning of Evolution</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>The Methods and Results of Science</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">18</container>
            <unittitle>The Need for Cooperation</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">19</container>
            <unittitle>Original Exploration of Yellowstone National Park</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">20</container>
            <unittitle>Our National Park</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">21</container>
            <unittitle>The Personal Faith of a Scientist</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">22</container>
            <unittitle>The Present Status of Organic Evolution</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">23</container>
            <unittitle>The Role of Science in Modern Civilization</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3 </container>
            <container type="folder">24</container>
            <unittitle>The Science of Religion</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Welcoming talk: "It is a great pleasure to the Institute Staff to welcome this group of Chemists..."</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Welcoming talk: "It is a great pleasure to welcome this group of pathologists..."</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Boyce Thompson Institute for Plant Research</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Boyce Thompson Institute for Plant Research (another version)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Research at the Boyce Thompson Institute</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Work of the Boyce Thompson Institute</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence: Otis Caldwell to John M. Coulter.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence with scientists concerning source material for biographies.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">8.5</container>
            <unittitle>Writings, 1896-1916</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>	"The Botanical Outlook," 1895</item>
                <item>	"The Embryo Sac and Embryo of Gnetum Gnemon," 1908</item>
                <item>	"Evolutionary Tendencies among Gymnosperms," 1909</item>
                <item>	"Inheritance Through Spores," 1916</item>
                <item>	"Some College Fallacies," 1900	</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Liberty Hyde Bailey, Ms of Coulter's biography.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Hugo De Vries, Ms of Coulter's biography.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Rafinesque, Ms of Coulter's biography.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>The International Mission of Universities.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>The New Spirit.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Book reviews for Science: General Botany by C. Stuart Gager Flora of the Panama Canal Zone by Paul C. Stanley.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Report: International Congress of Plant Sciences.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>Report: Philadelphia Symposium.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>Report: American Electrotheraputic Association, 37th Annual Meeting.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">18</container>
            <unittitle>Report: Winter Potatoes (about Dr. F. E. Denny)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">19</container>
            <unittitle>Daily Science News Bulletin, May 15, 1926 (notice of an article by Coulter in Science.)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">20</container>
            <unittitle>List of Books from the Library of John M. Coulter.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">21</container>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous Newspaper Clippings.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">22</container>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous Photographs.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">23</container>
            <unittitle>Part of a letter, unaddressed and unsigned (8 pages, unnumbered) describing "a short visit to Pootoo." (Probably to Caroline Coulter).</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">24</container>
            <unittitle>Letter: C. F. Cowan to Leila Garritt, with Photograph (unidentified).</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">25</container>
            <unittitle>Miscellaneous fragments and sheets: most in JMC's hand, but back of one drawing bears note with signature M.S.C.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
