<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.CRMS264</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to Jens Christian Bay, Scrapbook on Pulitzer Prizes in Journalism<date>1935</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by SCRC</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Journalism</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KEF, 2009</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to Jens Christian Bay, Scrapbook on Pulitzer Prizes in Journalism<date>1935</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by SCRC</author>
      <p>© 2009 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Bay, Jens Christian. Scrapbook on Pulitzer Prizes in Journalism</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" label="Dates">1935</unitdate>
      <unitid type="inclusive" label="MS_No">Crerar Ms 264</unitid>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">1 volume</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">Bound volume of newspaper clippings compiled by Jens Christian Bay concerning primarily the Pulitzer Prize. Includes articles on general information and recipients. The volume also includes clippings on lynching, chivalry, Southern American culture, and international politics.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The manuscript is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Jens Christian Bay. Scrapbook on Pulitzer Prizes in Journalism, Crerar Ms 264, Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The volume contains general information about the Pulitzer Prize, lists of its recipients and recipients of other journalism prizes between the 1890s and the 1930s, and newspaper clippings. The remainder of the items are copies of articles labeled with their identifying information and the year submitted for the Pulitzer Prize.  Others are articles clipped directly from newspapers that are not otherwise labeled.  These include Pulitzer prize-winning political cartoons editorials, and investigative pieces from the 1920s and 1930s.  While many of the articles seem to be unrelated to other items in the volume, there are several series of related articles from the same newspaper.  These include: stories about the 1934 America’s Cup from the New York Herald-Tribune; stories about prisoner abuse in Trenton, New Jersey from the New York Evening Post; and stories about lynching, chivalry, and Southern culture from the Montgomery Advertiser.  The articles in the second half of the volume tend to be focused on international politics and U.S. foreign policy.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:</p>
        <archref>
          <unittitle>http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html</unittitle>
        </archref>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Jens, Christian Bay, 1871-1962</persname>
        <corpname>Pulitzer Prizes -- History</corpname>
        <genreform>Scrapbooks</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="volume">1</container>
          <unittitle>Crerar Ms 264</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
