<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.CRMS97</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to Bayard Taylor Holmes, The Castor Oil Bean Poison<date>circa 1905</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by SCRC</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Medicine</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KEF, 2009</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to Bayard Taylor Holmes, The Castor Oil Bean Poison<date>circa 1905</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by SCRC</author>
      <p>© 2009 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Holmes, Bayard Taylor. The Castor Oil Bean Poison</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" label="Dates">circa 1905</unitdate>
      <unitid type="inclusive" label="MS_No">Crerar Ms 97</unitid>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">1 volume</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">Manuscript on the symptoms and effects of castor oil bean poisoning. Written on the back typed letters from Holmes's office. Two pencil illustrations, pasted in.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The manuscript is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Biographical Note</head>
        <p>Bayard Taylor Holmes was born in North Hero, Vermont in 1852. He received a BS from the Paw Paw Institute, near Aurora Illinois, in 1874. After teaching for several years in Illinois schools, in 1883, he received an MD from Chicago’s Homeopathic Medical College. Holmes also studied and interned at Cook County Hospital and the College of Physicians and Surgeons, and remained associated with both institutions as a physician and educator in later years. </p>
        <p>Holmes was publicly active as an advocate of improved medical education and as a lecturer on public health at Hull House. In 1895, he was the Populist Party candidate for Mayor of Chicago. He retired teaching and medical practice in 1908, to care for his son Ralph, who suffered from “dementia praecox,” the contemporary term for schizophrenia. Holmes also devoted his retirement to research and writing about schizophrenia. He died in 1924 in Fairhope, Alabama.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Holmes, Bayard Taylor. The Castor Oil Bean Poison, Crerar Ms 97, Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library   </p>
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>Holograph essay on the symptoms and effects of castor bean poisoning.  Written on the back of identical, typed (mimeographed?) letters from Holmes' office.  Two pencil illustrations, pasted in.  </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:</p>
        <archref>
          <unittitle>http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html</unittitle>
        </archref>
        <archref>
          <unittitle>Crerar Mss 83, 91-99</unittitle>
        </archref>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Holmes, Bayard, 1852-1924</persname>
        <subject>Poisons</subject>
        <genreform>Manuscripts, Medical</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container/>
          <unittitle>Crerar Ms 97</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
