<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.CRMS116</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to Edward Kidder, Receipts for Pastry and Cookery<date>circa 1730</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by SCRC</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by ML, 2008</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to Edward Kidder, Receipts for Pastry and Cookery<date>circa 1730</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by SCRC</author>
      <p>© 2008 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Kidder, Edward. Receipts for Pastry and Cookery</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" label="Dates">circa 1730</unitdate>
      <unitid type="inclusive" label="MS_No">Crerar Ms 116</unitid>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">69 p. (19 cm.)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">Handwritten cookbook, based upon classes at Edward Kidder's London cooking school.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>Open for research.  No restrictions.</p>
      </accessrestrict> <altformavail>
        <head>Digital Images</head>
        <p>Original documents, texts, and images represented by digital images linked to this finding aid are subject to U. S. copyright law. It is the user's sole responsibility to secure any necessary copyright permission to reproduce or publish documents, texts, and images from any holders of rights in the original materials.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library, in its capacity as owner of the physical property represented by the digital images linked to this finding aid, encourages the use of these materials for educational and scholarly purposes.  Any reproduction or publication from these digital images requires that the following credit line be included:  Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p>
        <p>The images presented here may include materials reflecting the attitudes, language, and stereotypes of an earlier time period. These materials are presented as historical resources in support of study and research. Inclusion of such materials does not constitute an endorsement of their content by the University of Chicago.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library appreciates hearing from anyone who may have information about any of the images in this collection.</p>
      </altformavail>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from this collection, the preferred citation is: Kidder, Edward, Receipts for Pastry and Cookery, Crerar Ms 116, [Box #, Folder #], Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>Handwritten cookbook, based upon classes at Edward Kidder's London cooking school.  Printed on facing page [title page missing?]: "To all young ladies at Edw. Kidders Pastry School in Little Lincoln's Inn-feilds [sic], are taught all sorts of pastry and cookery, Dutch-hollow works, &amp; butter works on Thursday, Fridays-Saturday..."  Ex libris: "A. Adams-Reilly," and "Howard Levis."  Bound in calf.  Binder's title: "Manuscript Cookery Book, ca. 1730."  See also Edward Kidder, Receipts for Pastry and Cookery, (London: 1740).  </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="https://www.lib.uchicago.edu/h/ead-topic-browse">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Kidder, E. (Edward), 1665 or 6-1739</persname>
        <subject>Cookery, English -- Early works to 1800
</subject>
        <subject>Recipes -- Early works to 1800</subject>
        <genreform>Recipes
</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container/>
          <unittitle>Crerar Ms 116</unittitle>
          <daogrp><resource label="start"/> <daoloc label="image" href="https://storage.lib.uchicago.edu/pres/2023/pres2023-0334.pdf" role="application/pdf"> <daodesc><p>View digitized manuscript.</p></daodesc></daoloc> <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/> </daogrp> </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
