<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.CRMS25</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to Louis Pasteur, Letter<date>1881</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by SCRC</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Medicine</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by ML, 2008</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to Louis Pasteur, Letter<date>1881</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by SCRC</author>
      <p>© 2008 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Pasteur, Louis. Letter</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" label="Dates">1881</unitdate>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" label="MS_No">Crerar Ms 25</unitdate>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>French</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">3 p. (27.5 cm.)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">I) Handwritten letter in French, from Louis Pasteur, Paris, to an unidentified man, November 27, 1881, on the subject of his vaccine;  II) Keepsake cardboard folder containing "Une ‚vocation charmante et inattendue des dans pr‚coses de Pasteur," in reference to reproductions of portrait drawings of M. &amp; Mlle. Roch, 1839, "dessin‚ par Pasteur a l'ƒge de 16 ans et demi..."  </abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The manuscript is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <altformavail>
        <head>Digital Images</head>
        <p>Original documents, texts, and images represented by digital images linked to this finding aid are subject to U. S. copyright law. It is the user's sole responsibility to secure any necessary copyright permission to reproduce or publish documents, texts, and images from any holders of rights in the original materials.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library, in its capacity as owner of the physical property represented by the digital images linked to this finding aid, encourages the use of these materials for educational and scholarly purposes.  Any reproduction or publication from these digital images requires that the following credit line be included:  Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p>
        <p>Commercial publication projects require the permission of the University of Chicago Library and may be subject to a use fee. To order publication-quality reproductions, or for permission to copy or use any part of the digital images attached to this finding aid for any commercial purposes, please contact the Special Collections Research Center.</p>
        <p>The images presented here may include materials reflecting the attitudes, language, and stereotypes of an earlier time period. These materials are presented as historical resources in support of study and research. Inclusion of such materials does not constitute an endorsement of their content by the University of Chicago.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library appreciates hearing from anyone who may have information about any of the images in this collection.</p>
      </altformavail>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Pasteur, Louis, Letter, Crerar Ms 25,  Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>I) Handwritten, signed letter in French, from Louis Pasteur, Paris, to an unidentified man, November 27, 1881,on the subject of his vaccine;  II) Keepsake cardboard folder containing "Une ‚vocation charmante et inattendue des dans pr‚coses de Pasteur," in reference to reproductions of portrait drawings of M. &amp; Mlle. Roch, 1839, "dessin‚ par Pasteur a l'ƒge de 16 ans et demi..."  </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/scrc/findingaids/topics.php">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Pasteur, Louis, 1822-1895</persname>
        <corpname>Institut Pasteur (Paris, France)</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container/>
          <unittitle>Crerar Ms 25</unittitle>
          <daogrp>
            <resource label="start"/>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/crms-25" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View manuscript.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
          </daogrp>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
