<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.CRMS94</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to Bayard Taylor Holmes, Outline of the Conditions of a Laboratory Building or Buildings for the Laboratories of Cook County, Especially Those of Cook County Hospital<date>1917</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by SCRC</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Medicine</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KF, 2009</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to Bayard Taylor Holmes, Outline of the Conditions of a Laboratory Building or Buildings for the Laboratories of Cook County, Especially Those of Cook County Hospital<date>1917</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by SCRC</author>
      <p>© 2008 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Holmes, Bayard Taylor. Outline of the Conditions of a Laboratory Building or Buildings for the Laboratories of Cook County, Especially Those of Cook County Hospital</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" label="Dates">1917</unitdate>
      <unitid type="inclusive" label="MS_No">Crerar Ms 94</unitid>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">1 volume</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">Consists of typed carbon copy assessment of laboratory conditions at Cook County, prepared for the Council of the Chicago Medical Society by a committee of the Association of County Hospital Laboratory Employees, headed by Dr. Holmes, 1917 Oct. 9. Also includes TLS from Holmes to Dr. Adam Szwajkart, Superintendent, Psychopathic Hospital, and to Dr. John Nuzum, Pathologist, Cook County Hospital, 1917 Nov. 13.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Holmes, Bayard Taylor, Outline of the Conditions of a Laboratory Building or Buildings for the Laboratories of Cook County, Especially Those of Cook County Hospital, Crerar Ms 94, [Box #, Folder #], Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Biographical Note</head>
        <p>Bayard Taylor Holmes was born in North Hero, Vermont in 1852. He received a BS from the Paw Paw Institute, near Aurora Illinois, in 1874. After teaching for several years in Illinois schools, in 1883, he received an MD from Chicago’s Homeopathic Medical College. Holmes also studied and interned at Cook County Hospital and the College of Physicians and Surgeons, and remained associated with both institutions as a physician and educator in later years. </p>
        <p>Holmes was publicly active as an advocate of improved medical education and as a lecturer on public health at Hull House. In 1895, he was the Populist Party candidate for Mayor of Chicago. He retired teaching and medical practice in 1908, to care for his son Ralph, who suffered from “dementia praecox,” the contemporary term for schizophrenia. Holmes also devoted his retirement to research and writing about schizophrenia. He died in 1924 in Fairhope, Alabama.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>I) Typed carbon copy assessment of laboratory conditions at Cook County, prepared for the Council of the Chicago Medical Society by a committee of the Association of County Hospital Laboratory Employees, headed by Dr. Holmes, October 9, 1917.  Illustrated with blueprint of Cook County Hospital, folded in;  II) Letter from Bayard Holmes to Dr. Adam Szwajkart, Superintendent, Psychopathic Hospital, and to Dr. John Nuzum, Pathologist, Cook County Hospital, on work at his Psychopathic Resarch Lab at Cook County Hospital, November 13, 1917, T.L.S. </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:</p>
        <archref>
          <unittitle>http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html</unittitle>
        </archref>
        <archref>
          <unittitle>Crerar Mss 83, 91-99</unittitle>
        </archref>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Holmes, Bayard, 1852-1924</persname>
        <corpname>Cook County Hospital (Chicago, Ill.)</corpname>
        <subject>Medical laboratories</subject>
        <genreform>Blueprints</genreform>
        <genreform>Architectural drawings</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container/>
          <unittitle>Crerar Ms 94</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
