<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.GILKEYCW</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Charles Whitney Gilkey Papers<date>1923-1941</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by MH, 2005</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Religion and Theology</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by SV, 2006</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to the Charles Whitney Gilkey Papers<date>1923-1941</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by MH, 2005</author>
      <p>© 2006 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Gilkey, Charles Whitney. Papers</unittitle>
      <unitdate label="Dates" type="inclusive">1923-1941</unitdate>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English.</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">.25 linear ft. (1 box)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">The Charles Whitney Gilkey papers contain correspondence primarily concerning the University Chapel, and the Committee on the Presidency of the University (1928-1929).  The collection also contains the minutes of the Commission for the Study of Moral and Religious Influence and Agencies in Higher Education, as well as several published articles by Gilkey.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>No restrictions. </p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Gilkey, Charles Whitney. Papers, [Box #, Folder #], Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Biographical Note</head>
        <p>The Dean of Rockefeller Memorial Chapel and representative of the University of Chicago, Charles W. Gilkey was born in Massachusetts on 3 July 1882. His parents were James H. Gilkey, and Mary Lottie Johnson.  Gilkey's brother James Gordon also entered the ministry and became a reverend.
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Educated in the United States, Gilkey also pursued graduated studies in Europe:
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Harvard, A.B. 1903, A.M. 1904
</p>
        <p>Union Theological Seminary, B.D., 1908
</p>
        <p>Universities of Berlin and Marburg, 1908-1909
</p>
        <p>United Free DH. Coll. Glasgow, 1909-1910
</p>
        <p>New Coll. Edinburgh and Oxford University 1909-10
</p>
        <p>Hon. D.D. Williams 1925; Hillsdale College, 1925; Yale, 1927; Brown, 1928; Harvard, 1929; Colby, 1931
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>In 1910 the Hyde Park Baptist Church ordained Gilkey as their pastor and he remained there for 18 years.  He married Geraldine Brown, a graduate of the University of Chicago (1911) on 26 July 1915.  Together they had a daughter, Mary Jane, and a son, Langdon Brown. The family lived in Hyde Park, Chicago during the school year and summered in Maine. 
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Gilkey acted as a Trustee of the University of Chicago from 1919-1929. In 1928 he accepted the position of Dean of the Rockefeller Memorial Chapel of the University, which he would hold until 1947. Gilkey aimed to make Rockefeller Chapel a place of multi-denominational worship with a strong core of participants. This was a difficult task, he admitted, because the students stayed at the university only four years. 
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Gilkey also served as the Associate Dean of the Divinity School and represented the University in the position of the "Professor of Preaching of the University of Chicago Divinity School" at Princeton, Yale, Cornell, Chicago, Toronto, Wellesley, Stanford, Purdue, Harvard, Wellesley, and the University of Washington. The University appointed Gilkey the Barrows Lecturer to India, 1924-1925
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Geraldine devoted herself to the YWCA as the national president and served as the vice-president of the United Council of Church Women in addition to opening the Gilkey home to students at the University.
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Gilkey announced his retirement in June 1947. The Gilkey's retired to Massachusetts from which they continued to travel and lecture. A student scholarship, the "Charles and Geraldine Gilkey Fund" was established to honor him and his wife.  Mr. Gilkey passed away in Massachusetts in March 1968.
</p>
        <p>
</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The Charles Whitney Gilkey papers contain correspondence primarily concerning the University Chapel, and the Committee on the Presidency of the University (1928-1929).  The collection also contains the minutes of the Commission for the Study of Moral and Religious Influence and Agencies in Higher Education, as well as several published articles by Gilkey.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="https://www.lib.uchicago.edu/h/ead-topic-browse">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Gilkey, Charles Whitney, 1882-1968
</persname>
        <persname>Rosenwald, Julius, 1862-1932
</persname>
        <persname>Rockefeller, John D. (John Davison), 1874-1960
</persname>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">1</container>
          <unittitle>Correspondence about the University Chapel</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">2</container>
          <unittitle>Correspondence of the Committee on the Presidency of the University (1928-1929), Charles W. Gilkey, Chairman</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">3</container>
          <unittitle>Correspondence-Miscellaneous. Letters from Julius Rosenwald, John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Max Mason</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">4</container>
          <unittitle>Minutes of the Commission for the Study of Moral and Religious Influence and Agencies in Higher Education, 1923</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">5</container>
          <unittitle>Published articles by Charles W. Gilkey</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">6</container>
          <unittitle>"The Beloved Community of Memory and Hope," Semi-Centennial Sermon, September 28, 1941</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
