<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.HUNTCRAIK</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Leigh Hunt and Craik Family Collection<date>1849-1889</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by TH, 2015</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject/>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KEF, 2016</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to the Leigh Hunt and Craik Family Collection<date>1849-1889</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by TH, 2015</author>
      <p>© 2016 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Hunt, Leigh, and Craik Family. Collection</unittitle>
      <unitdate label="Dates" type="inclusive">1849-1889</unitdate>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">0.25 linear feet (1 box)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">Leigh Hunt (1784-1859) English critic, essayist, poet, and writer.  George Lillie Craik (1798-1866), Scottish writer and literary critic; Jannette Craik (1791), George’s spouse; and Mary Craik (1826-1887), English novelist and poet. This collection contains correspondence between members of the Craik family and Leigh Hunt, probably written from 1849 to 1889. </abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The collection is open for research. </p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Hunt, Leigh, and Craik Family. Collection, [Box #, Folder #], Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Biographical Note</head>
        <p>George Lillie Craik, a Scottish writer and literary critic, was born in Kennoway, Fife, Scotland in 1798 to William Craik and Paterson Lillie.  One of Craik’s brothers was Scottish Hebraist and theologian, Henry Craik.  George Craik was educated at the University of St. Andrews, and moved to London in 1824.  Shortly after, in 1826, Craik married Jannette Dempster.  Together they had a number of children, including novelist Georgiana Craik.  In 1849, George L. Craik was appointed Professor of English Literature and History at Belfast. Craik died in 1866.</p>
        <p/>
        <p>James Henry Leigh Hunt was an English critic, essayist, poet, and writer.  Hunt was born in London on October 19, 1784 to Isaac Hunt and Mary Shewell who had fled the US because of their loyalist sympathies during the American Revolution. Hunt was educated at Christ’s Hospital in the UK.  His first publication of poems was published in 1801.  Between 1808 and 1821, Hunt occupied the editorship of a number of newspapers and magazines.  During that time, he continued to write and publish literature and poetry. In 1809, Leigh Hunt married Marianne Kent.  Together they had 10 children.   Hunt later died on August 28, 1859.</p>
        <p/>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The Leigh Hunt and Craik Family Collection contains nine signed letters from members of the Craik Family to Leigh Hunt.  Six of the letters are signed “Geo L Craik,” but it is unclear whether this is George Lillie Craik, the Scottish essayist, or his nephew, Henry Craik’s son, also named George Lillie Craik.  Two are signed “Mary Craik.”  It is presumed that these letters are from Dinah Maria Craik, the wife of George Lillie Craik, the younger.  Also included is one letter signed from Jannette Craik, George Lillie Craik’s (the essayist) wife.  Most of the letters are undated, though the dates available place the letters 1849-1889.</p>
        <p/>
        <p>The collection was previously part of the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection.</p>
        <p/>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/scrc/findingaids/topics.php">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Craik, George Lillie 1798-1866</persname>
        <persname>Craik, Dinah Maria 1826-1887</persname>
        <persname>Hunt, Leigh 1784- 1859</persname>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">1</container>
          <unittitle>Correspondence, 1849-1889, undated</unittitle>
          <note>
            <list>
              <item>Letter from Geo L Craik to Leigh Hunt, June 18, 1849.</item>
              <item>Letter from Geo L Craik to Leigh Hunt, January 24, 1889.</item>
              <item>Letter from Geo L Craik to Leigh Hunt, date unknown.</item>
              <item>Letter from Geo L Craik to Leigh Hunt, date unknown.</item>
              <item>Letter from Geo L Craik to Leigh Hunt, date unknown.</item>
              <item>Letter from Geo L Craik to Leigh Hunt, date unknown.</item>
            </list>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">2</container>
          <unittitle>Correspondence, undated</unittitle>
          <note>
            <list>
              <item>Letter from Jannette Craik to Leigh Hunt, date unknown. </item>
              <item>Letter from Mary Craik to Leigh Hunt, date unknown. </item>
              <item>Letter from Mary Craik to Leigh Hunt, date unknown. </item>
            </list>
          </note>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
