<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.NICKERSONA</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Aaron Nickerson Collection<date>1839-1860</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by TH, 2016</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject/>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KEF, 2016</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to the Aaron Nickerson Collection<date>1839-1860</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by TH, 2016</author>
      <p>© 2016 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Nickerson, Aaron. Collection</unittitle>
      <unitdate label="Dates" type="inclusive">1839-1860</unitdate>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">0.25 linear feet (1 box)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">Aaron Nickerson was a settler who moved to Texas from the northern states shortly after the Texas Revolution and the creation of the Republic of Texas (1836-1845).  The collection includes letters he sent to Lizzie Swartwout, a Michigan woman from 1839 to1860.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <altformavail>
        <head>Digital Images</head>
        <p>Original documents, texts, and images represented by digital images linked to this finding aid are subject to U. S. copyright law. It is the user's sole responsibility to secure any necessary copyright permission to reproduce or publish documents, texts, and images from any holders of rights in the original materials.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library, in its capacity as owner of the physical property represented by the digital images linked to this finding aid, encourages the use of these materials for educational and scholarly purposes.  Any reproduction or publication from these digital images requires that the following credit line be included:  Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p>
        <p>Commercial publication projects require the permission of the University of Chicago Library and may be subject to a use fee. To order publication-quality reproductions, or for permission to copy or use any part of the digital images attached to this finding aid for any commercial purposes, please contact the Special Collections Research Center.</p>
        <p>The images presented here may include materials reflecting the attitudes, language, and stereotypes of an earlier time period. These materials are presented as historical resources in support of study and research. Inclusion of such materials does not constitute an endorsement of their content by the University of Chicago.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library appreciates hearing from anyone who may have information about any of the images in this collection.</p>
      </altformavail>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Nickerson, Aaron. Correspondence, [Box #, Folder #], Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Biographical Note</head>
        <p>Little is known of the author of the letters in this collection, Aaron Nickerson.  From the contents of the collection, he moved to La Grange, Texas, from a northern state (possibly Michigan) in 1839.  The Texas Revolution had ended in 1836, and many settlers were moving to the state as it emerged as an independent republic.  Lizzie, Aaron’s correspondent in this collection, lived in Jackson, Michigan, though information on her life is sparse as well.  The letters in the collection range from 1839 to 1860, covering almost all of Texas’ shift from independent republic to state, including the Mexican-American war (1846-1847).  </p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The Aaron Nickerson Collection contains four letters written by Aaron Nickerson to Lizzie Swartwout.  The letters largely concern Aaron’s move to La Grange, Texas and his life in his new home.  Of particular interest in the letters are mention of an itinerant phrenologist and Nickerson’s contracting of typhoid fever.  Nickerson also writes of his concern for Lizzie’s health should she come to join him in Texas.  Judging from the tone of the letters and the salutations, Lizzie was very close with Nickerson, perhaps his wife.  Two of the letters are dated from 1839, and the remaining three are dated in 1860.  Also included in the collection are four envelopes addressed to Swartwout.  All letters are arranged chronologically.  </p>
        <p>The collection was previously part of the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection.</p>
        <p/>
        <p/>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/scrc/findingaids/topics.php">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Nickerson, Aaron, fl. 19th cent.</persname>
        <persname>Swartwout, Lizzie, fl. 19th cent.</persname>
        <persname/>
        <subject>Typhoid fever -- United States -- History -- 19th century</subject>
        <subject>Phrenology -- United States -- History -- 19th century</subject>
        <subject/>
        <geogname>La Grange (Tex.) -- History -- 19th century</geogname>
        <geogname>Texas -- Social life and customs</geogname>
        <geogname>Texas -- History -- 1810-1821 – Sources</geogname>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">1</container>
          <unittitle>Correspondence, 1839-1860</unittitle>
          <note>
            <list>
              <item>Letter from Aaron Nickerson to Lizzie Swartwout, December 3, 1839</item>
              <item>Letter from Aaron Nickerson to Lizzie Swartwout, December 25, 1839</item>
              <item>Letter from Aaron Nickerson to Lizzie Swartwout, February 28 – March 1, 1860</item>
              <item>Letter from Aaron Nickerson to Lizzie Swartwout, August 29, 1860</item>
              <item>Envelopes for letters to Lizzie Swartwout, 1839-1860</item>
            </list>
          </note>
          <daogrp>
            <resource label="start"/>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/nickersona-0001-0001" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View digitized documents.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
          </daogrp>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
