<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.SCHAFFNER</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Joseph Halle Schaffner Collection in the History of Science<date>1642-1961</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by JL, RWA, 1976; KT, 2007</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Biological Sciences and Ecology</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Chemistry</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Physical Sciences, Astronomy and Astrophysics</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Mathematics</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KEF, 2007, 2012</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to the Joseph Halle Schaffner Collection in the History of Science<date>1642-1961</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by JL, RWA, 1976; KT, 2007</author>
      <p>© 2007 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Schaffner, Joseph Halle, Collection in the History of Science</unittitle>
      <unitdate label="Dates" type="inclusive">1642-1961</unitdate>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English
French</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">3.5 linear feet (6 boxes)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">Contains correspondence and other documents from or related to prominent scientists. Includes the Marie Curie Correspondence with Charlotte Kellogg (ca. 1921-1929) and Curie Memorabilia, the Charles Darwin and Darwin Family Correspondence, the Albert Einstein-Walther Mayer Correspondence (1930-1933) and Einstein Photographs, the Isaac Newton Collection (1642-1727), and Miscellaneous Scientific Manuscripts (1744, 1777, 1820). The Joseph Halle Schaffner Papers (1943-1961) are also included and contain material relating to Schaffner's activities as a collector and how the collections were used by scholars and in exhibits.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <altformavail>
        <head>Digital Images</head>
        <p>Original documents, texts, and images represented by digital images linked to this finding aid are subject to U. S. copyright law. It is the user's sole responsibility to secure any necessary copyright permission to reproduce or publish documents, texts, and images from any holders of rights in the original materials.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library, in its capacity as owner of the physical property represented by the digital images linked to this finding aid, encourages the use of these materials for educational and scholarly purposes.  Any reproduction or publication from these digital images requires that the following credit line be included:  Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p>
        <p>The images presented here may include materials reflecting the attitudes, language, and stereotypes of an earlier time period. These materials are presented as historical resources in support of study and research. Inclusion of such materials does not constitute an endorsement of their content by the University of Chicago.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library appreciates hearing from anyone who may have information about any of the images in this collection.</p>
      </altformavail>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Schaffner, Joseph Halle, Collection in the History of Science, [Box #, Folder #], Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Biographical Note</head>
        <p>Joseph Halle Schaffner (1897-1972) spent most of his life in his native Chicago as director of the clothing-manufacturing firm Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. He formed several collections reflecting both literary and historical interests. His greatest collecting passion was the history of science, and he bequeathed to the University of Chicago an extraordinary collection of several hundred scientific and medical rare books and manuscripts. 
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Schaffner acquired fine copies of great books, many in contemporary or presentation bindings or from the libraries of great scientists. He relished the excitement of competing for a particularly rare item, especially since he was so often successful; and he exemplifies the zealous, generous bibliophile whose high standards and discriminating taste have enriched the holdings of American research libraries. Schaffner's passion for collecting also resulted in the acquisition of some important manuscripts and correspondence of notable scientists. 
</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The Schaffner Collection is divided into six series. The first four are distinct collections of the manuscripts of Madame Marie Curie, Charles Darwin, Albert Einstein, and Sir Isaac Newton. Also included are a group of miscellaneous manuscripts removed from various volumes in the Joseph Halle Schaffner Collection of printed books. The history of the collection is documented in the Joseph Halle Schaffner Papers, the sixth series of this collection, which consists primarily of records relating to his activities as a collector and records of the use made of the collection during his lifetime by scholars and in exhibitions. For a different and more personal perspective on the collector’s life the reader is referred to another collection in the University of Chicago Library, the Carl Sandburg - Joseph Halle Schaffner Correspondence.
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Series I: Curie-Kellogg Correspondence and Curie Memorabilia
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>When Pierre and Marie Curie first published their work on radium in the 1890s, they decided they would seek no profit from their discovery though even then its great commercial potential was apparent. As a consequence of this decision, they labored under a great financial handicap. When the American journalist, Marie Meloney interviewed Mme. Curie after the First World War, she was astonished to learn that the work of the French scientist was hampered by a shortage of radium (Mme. Curie had about a gram in her laboratory at that time) while in the United States some fifty grams were stockpiled around the country. Out of this meeting and this promise grew the Marie Curie Radium Fund, through which the women of American presented Mme. Curie with a gram of radium. Charlotte Kellogg (Mrs. Vernon Kellogg), an author and friend of Meloney, worked on the fund raising drive, and a warm friendship developed between her and Mme. Curie. During the French scientist’s visit to the United States in 1921 to accept the gram of radium, Curie had been persuaded by Meloney to write on her own life and the life of her deceased husband, Pierre. In 1923 Charlotte Kellogg and her husband translated this autobiographical account into English. Another gram of radium was given in 1929, this time for the establishment of radium therapy services in Mme. Curie’s native Warsaw.
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>The Schaffner Collection includes: ten pieces of correspondence by Marie Curie (nine originals and one typescript copy); typescript copies of Einstein’s eulogy of Curie, her 1921 speech of acceptance for the radium gift, and Charlotte Kellogg’s memoir of Mme. Curie; photographs of Charlotte Kellogg and Marie Meloney; and assorted memorabilia.
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Series II: Charles Darwin Correspondence
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>The Darwin correspondence contains material written and received by Darwin and his family from 1869 to 1904.
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Series III: Albert Einstein - Walther Mayer Correspondence and Einstein Photographs
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>The letters from Albert Einstein to Walther Mayer constitute an important body of documentation touching on both the development of the Unified Field Theory and the dramatic personal events experienced by these two men during the years of the Nazi rise to power. The association of Einstein with the talented Austrian mathematician began during the late 1920s in Germany. Though Mayer is often spoken of as Einstein’s assistant and though his role was largely that of providing the mathematical apparatus necessary to the elaboration of the new theory, Einstein himself referred to their joint achievement as “our theory” and praised Mayer in the highest terms: “It is he who produced all my calculations; his skill is fantastic.” During a period of growing political turbulence in Germany when Einstein was traveling and, later, when he had gone into exile, the friendship and collaboration of the two men was carried on largely by mail. The letters give indications of the keenly felt personal turmoil of the two before they both finally settled at the Institute for Advanced Study at Princeton in 1933.
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>By letter, during the years 1930 to 1933, Einstein and Mayer collaborated on what has been called Einstein’s “most ambitious theory” and a “triumph of human spirit over the chaos of the universe.” Following the announcement of the Unified Field Theory in 1931, Mayer explained the significance of the joint accomplishment:
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>The general relativity theory suffered from a dualism: adequate for gravitation, it harbored the electro-magnetic field as a foreign body, and its formulas Professor Einstein had to introduce artificially, as it were.
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>This dualism is abolished in the new theory, which subsumes both gravitation and electricity under one comprehensive theory of the same architecture throughout.
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>The Joseph Halle Schaffner Collection of Scientific Manuscripts includes some eighty letters, mostly from the crucial 1930-33 period, from Einstein to Mayer and a number of photographs of the two men.
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Series IV: 	Sir Isaac Newton, 1642-1727
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>The material pertaining to Newton includes manuscripts, notes, letters, and diagrams by and about Newton.
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Series V: Miscellaneous Scientific Manuscripts
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>The Miscellaneous Manuscripts include notes, a translation, and a letter dated from 1744 to 1820.
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Series VI: Schaffner Collection Records
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>The Joseph Halle Schaffner Papers (1943-1961) are also included and contain material relating to Schaffner's activities as a collector and how the collections were used by scholars and in exhibits.
</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:</p>
        <archref>
          <unittitle>http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html</unittitle>
        </archref>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Schaffner, Joseph Halle
</persname>
        <persname>Beccaria, Giambatista, 1716-1781
</persname>
        <persname>Curie, Marie, 1867-1934
</persname>
        <persname>Darwin, Charles, 1809-1882
</persname>
        <persname>Einstein, Albert, 1879-1955
</persname>
        <persname>Kellogg, Charlotte
</persname>
        <persname>Mayer, W. (Walther), b. 1887
</persname>
        <persname>Newton, Isaac, Sir, 1642-1727
</persname>
        <persname>Pepys, Samuel, 1633-1703
</persname>
        <persname>Volta, Alessandro, 1745-1827
</persname>
        <subject>Collectors and collecting - United States
</subject>
        <subject>Science - History</subject>
        <occupation>Scientists</occupation>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series I:	Marie Curie - Charlotte Kellogg Correspondence and Curie Memorabilia</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Madame Marie Curie, 1867-1934. Correspondence with Charlotte Kellogg (Mrs. Vernon Kellogg) ca. 1921-29 and Curie memorabilia.</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>MC, Paris, to [Marie Meloney], 31 January 1921. TL [carbon copy], 2 p.</item>
                <item>CK, 17 March 1921. Form letter to raise funds for the first gram of radium. TLS [carbon copy], 1 p.</item>
                <item>Plans for presentation of the first gram of radium to MC by President Harding, 18 May 1921. TD [carbon copy], 2 p.</item>
                <item>Printed invitation to presentation of the first gram of radium to MC, 20 May 1921</item>
                <item>Seating plan for the presentation of the first gram of radium to MC, 20 May 1921. TD [initialed by Robert Woods Bliss, President Harding’s Chief of Protocol], 1 p.</item>
                <item>MC, Paris, to CK, 22 May 1921. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>MC, New York, to CK, Washington, D.C., 23 June 1921. ACS [postcard]</item>
                <item>MC, Paris, to CK, 22 May 1922. ALS, 4 p.</item>
                <item>MC, Paris, to CK, Carmel, California, 6 January 1923. TLS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>MC, Paris, to CK, Paris, [10 November 1925]. ALS, 2 p.</item>
                <item>MC, Brussels, to CK, Brussels, 7 July 1928. ALS [with envelope addressed "Mrs. Vernon Kellogg"], 2 p.</item>
                <item>MC, Paris, to CK, Paris, 9 November 1928. ACS [postcard]</item>
                <item>MC, Paris, to CK, Paris, 24 December 1928. ACS [note on printed calling card]</item>
                <item>Printed invitation to the presentation of the second gram of radium to MC, 29 October 1929</item>
                <item>MC, National Academy of Sciences, 30 October 1929. Speech accepting the second gram of radium from the President of the United States. TD, 1 p.</item>
                <item>MC, Paris, to CK. ACS [Christmas card with autograph note]</item>
                <item>Albert Einstein. Testimony to MC and her work. TD [carbon copy], 1 p.</item>
                <item>CK, Carmel, California. An intimate picture of Madame Curie. From diary notes covering a friendship of fifteen years. TD [carbon copy], 11 p.</item>
                <item>Photograph of CK.</item>
                <item>Photograph of Marie Meloney</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series II:	Charles Darwin Correspondence </unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Charles Darwin, 1809-1882, and Darwin family. Correspondence, ca. 1869-1904.</unittitle>
            <daogrp>
              <resource label="start"/>
              <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/schaffner-0001-002" role="application/pdf">
                <daodesc>
                  <p>View digitized documents.</p>
                </daodesc>
              </daoloc>
              <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
            </daogrp>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>Darwin, Charles. AD, 1 p. Six lines on a narrow strip of blue paper. Fragment of the Ms. of The Formation of Vegetable Mould through the Action of Worms.</item>
                <item>Darwin, George, Cambridge, to "Fanny," 17 December 1893. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf. A letter of transmittal for the above described document of his father, Charles Darwin</item>
                <item>Maxwell, Herbert, New Brunswick, to "Mrs. Darwin," 21 May 1904. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf.</item>
                <item>Hooker, Joseph Dalton, Sunningdale, to "My dear Darwin," 1 October 1902. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>Galton, Francis, London, to George Darwin, 20 June 1901. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf.</item>
                <item>Darwin, Charles, Bromley, Kent, to an unknown person, 30 May [1869]. ALS, 5 p., 2 leaves folded</item>
                <item>Darwin, Charles, Cambridge, to Miss Buckley, 16 August 18-. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>Darwin, Charles, Beckenham, Kent, to [Dr. Karl Scherzer ?], 13 February 1877. ALS, 4 p., 1 leaf folded</item>
                <item>Darwin, Charles, Beckenham, Kent, to the editor of The Spectator, 11 January 1873, LS, 3 p.</item>
                <item>Darwin, Charles, Bromley, Kent, to an unknown person, 18 September 1868. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf folded</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series III:	Albert Einstein Correspondence and Photographs</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">3-43</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein, correspondence with Walther Mayer, 1930-33, and others, 1925-46, and Einstein photographs.</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE, [?], to WM, 23 July 1930. ALS, 1 1/2 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE to WM, 5 May 1931. ALS, 1 1/4 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE to WM, 19 May 1931. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE to WM, 4 November 1931. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM, 18 November 1931. ALS, 1 1/2 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE to WM, 19 November 1931. ALS, 1 1/4 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE to WM, 23 November 1931. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE, Pasadena, to WM, 3 January 1932. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM, 14 January 1932. ALS, 3 1/2 p., 3 leaves</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE, Pasadena, to WM, 20 January 1932. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM, 6 February 1932. ALS, 2 1/4 p., 2 leaves</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE, [Pasadena], to WM, 7 February 1932. ALS, 3 p., 3 leaves</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM, 13 February 1932. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE to WM, 23 February 1932. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE to WM, 1 May 1932. ALS, 1 1/2 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE, [Oxford], to WM, 5 May 1932. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE, [Oxford], to WM, Caputh bei Potsdam, 11 May 1932. Envelope addressed to "Prof. Dr. W. Mayer" at Caputh b. Potsdam with Ms. notes by Einstein on back flap. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE, [Oxford], to WM, 14 May 1932. ALS, 1 1/2 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE, Caputh, to WM, 17 November 1932. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE to WM, 8 December 1932. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE, Caputh, to WM, 9 December 1932. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE, Antwerp, to WM, 11 December 1932. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE, "Oukl." ?, 7 January 1933. ALS, 4 p., 1 leaf folded</item>
                <item>AE to WM, 8 January 1933, with added letter by Elsa Einstein to WM. ALS, 4 p., 1 leaf</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE, Pasadena, to WM, 20 January 1933. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM, 21 January 1933. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM, 14 February 1933. ALS, 1 1/4 p., 1 leaf.</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE, Pasadena, to WM, 23 February 1933. ALS, 1 1/2 p., 2 leaves. With Ms. note on verso of second leaf</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM, 2 May 1933. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE to WM, 11 June 1933. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE to WM, ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf, "Kurz nachdem der Brief..."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM, "Dem Glücklichen schlägt kein Datum." ALS, 2 p., 2 leaves, "Ich habe hier eine wunderbare Ruhe..."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">18</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM, "Dienstag." ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf, "Herrliche Einsamkeit auf der Heide!"</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM, ALS, 3 p., 3 leaves, "Dieser Aufenthalt ist wirklich enorm..."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE, Brussels, to WM, "Mittwoch." Letterhead; "Club de la Fondation Universitaire." ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf folded, "Meine Betrachtung war durch einen..."</item>
                <item>AE, Brussels, to WM, "19.X." Letterhead; "Club de la Fondation Universitaire." ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf folded. Pencil notes on back, "Beim Nachdenken auf der..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM, "Montag." ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf, "Millikan war da. Ich dampfe..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM, "21.XII." ALS, 4 p., 1 leaf folded, "Ich glaube nun fest daran..."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM, "Montag." ALS, 3 p., 3 leaves, "Besten Dank für Ihren Brief. Die Andeutung am Ende..."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE, Portland, to WM, "13.XII," with letter by Elsa Einstein, Portland, to WM. ALS, 4 p., together on 2 leaves, "Nach tüchtigen Stürmen ist es nun wieder warm..."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf, Ich danke Ihnen sehr für Ihre schöne..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf, "Vielen Dank für den Brief. Wie haben wir dies..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM, "18. II." ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf, "Es ist mir unterdessen völlig klar geworden..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM, "11. V." ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf, "Haben Sie die Bemerkung auf der Enveloppe..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf folded, "Nun hab ich viel Zeit gehabt..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf, "Ich sende Ihren Widerlegungsbrief mit."</item>
                <item>AE to WM, "Donnerstag." ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf, "Das Ergebnis Ihrer..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM, "Montag." ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf, "Morgen enden die Sitzungen - gottlob."</item>
                <item>AE to WM, "Donnerstag Abend." ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf, "Das Bedenken, welches ich gegen die neue Interpretation..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf, "Es gibt doch ein..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM, "Dienstag." ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf, "Meine Deduktion aus der..."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM. "Samstag." ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf, "Ich habe gestern Ihre Rechnung..."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf, "Ich danke Ihnen für die zusätzliche Rechnung..."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM, "Samstag Abend." ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf, "Ich habe jetzt begriffen..."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM. ALS, 2 p., 2 leaves. With Ms. notes on back of second leaf, "Sie hatten insofern recht..."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf. With "Mayer" written on back, "Es ist sogar sicher, dass man..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM, "Montag." ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf, "Ich habe viel an den Gleichungen..."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Envelope addressed to WM. No stamp or postmark, torn and mended with scotch tape</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE, [Oxford ?], to WM, "3.VI.," [1933]. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE to WM. ALS on a slip of paper 21.5 cm. x 6.5 cm, "Ich sende das Manuskript..."</item>
                <item>AE, Nassau Point, Peconic, N.Y., to WM, 9 August 1938. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE to WM, 1 January 1930. ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf, plus photocopy of p. 2</item>
                <item>AE, Cristobal, to WM. AL, 1 p., 1 leaf. "Ich hab jetzt einen guten Ansatz..."</item>
                <item>AE, Princeton, to "Frau Helli," 31 October 1948. TLS, with autograph PS, 1 p., 1 leaf</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE, Zurich, to WM, Berlin, [Postmarked 5 November 1930]. ACS, "Ich hab schon viel Sehnsucht..."</item>
                <item>AE, [Berlin letterhead], to WM. AL, 1 p., 1 leaf, "Es muss doch noch etwas..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM. AL, on half sheet of paper, 20.5 cm. x 15.5 cm, "Ich weiss jetzt, wie wir..."</item>
                <item>AE to Else Einstein. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf, "Lindemann hat mich gestern..."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf, with Ms notes on back</item>
                <item>AE to [WM ?]. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf. First line of letter in mathematical equation; second line begins; "Setzt man hierin die Werte..."</item>
                <item>AE. AD, 1 p., 1 leaf, "Wie drückt sich diese Zerlegung..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM. AL, 1 1/2 p., 1 leaf, "Es ist nicht gut, dass Sie..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM, 28 January 1933. AL, 2 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>AE to WM, 30 May 1933. ALS, 1 1/2 p., 1 leaf</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM. AL, on half sheet, 21.5 cm x 14 cm, "Der zweite Fall der..."</item>
                <item>AE to "Helli." ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf, "Ich machete Ihnen noch gins..."</item>
                <item>AE. AD, 1 p., 1 leaf, 21.5 cm x 21.5 cm, "Salting der natürlichsten Feldgleichungen..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM. "Montag." ALS, 2 p., 1 leaf folded, "Aus Versehen habe ich den..."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein- Walter Mayer Correspondence</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to WM. AL, 1 1/2 p., 1 leaf, "Ich habe viel über die Frage..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM, Caputh. ACS [neither stamp nor postmark; Ms note on back], "Bitte schicken Sie Separata Ihrer..."</item>
                <item>AE, Berlin, to WM, Vienna, 10 January 1930. ACS.</item>
                <item>Einstein, Else, [from aboard S.S. Belgenland], to Mrs. Walther Mayer, and AE to same. ACS written by both Albert and Else Einstein, 2 sides on "Red Star Line" card; signed by both</item>
                <item>AE to WM, Berlin. Envelope addressed by Einstein to Mayer with Ms notes on back flap beginning;, "Ihre Gleichung ist doch richtig..."</item>
                <item>AE to WM, Vienna. Envelope addressed by Einstein to Mayer with Ms notes on back flap beginning; "Statt...kann man..."</item>
                <item>AE. AD, 1 p., 1 leaf. A page of mathematical equations; one third down the page is the line "Eukl. Fall im beschleunigten[?] System"</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein Photographs</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>Portrait photograph of Albert Einstein (marked [A] in pencil on back) with inscription "From Helli Mayer..." 12.5 cm x 17.5 cm</item>
                <item>Photograph of AE (seated) with two other men (one standing, one seated). (Marked [B] in pencil on back.) 24 cm x 30.5 cm</item>
                <item>Photograph of AE and two other men at Mt. Wilson Observatory, Pasadena, 1930. (Marked [C] in pencil on back.) 20.5 cm x 25.5 cm</item>
                <item>Photograph of AE and WM at Pasadena. (Marked [D] in pencil on back.) 20.5 cm x 25.5 cm</item>
                <item>Photograph of AE and WM at Pasadena. (Marked [E] in pencil on back.) With inscription (in hand of Else Einstein?) "Albert mit Dr. Mayer..." 20.5 cm x 25.5 cm</item>
                <item>Photograph of AE and WM on sailboat near Potsdam. (Marked [F] in pencil on back.) 30 cm. x 23.5 cm. "Prof. Albert Einstein und sein Mitarbeiter Dr. Maier."</item>
                <item>Reproduction of a cartoon (California, 1930?) showing Albert Einstein and Walther Mayer seated before a blackboard</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">18</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopies of 28 letters from Walther Mayer to Albert Einstein, 1930-1933</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>Mayer, Walther, Vienna, to Albert Einstein, 27 July 1930. ALS, 2 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Caputh, to AE, 11 May 1931. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Vienna, to AE, 4 November 1931, ALS, 2 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Vienna, to AE, 5 November 1931. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Vienna, to AE, 19 November 1931. ALS, 2 p.</item>
                <item>WM to AE, 12 December 1931. ALS, 4 p.</item>
                <item>WM, to AE, 2 February 1932. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>WM to AE, 3 February 1932. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Berlin, to AE, 28 April 1932. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Caputh, to AE, 6 May 1932. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Caputh, to AE, 18 May 1932. ALS, 2 p. "Sie schlagen als..."</item>
                <item>WM to AE, 18 May 1932. ALS, 1 p. "Es lassen sich..."</item>
                <item>WM, [Schwielowsee?], to AE, 9 August 1932. ALS, 2 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Caputh, to AE, 19 August 1932. ALS, 2 p.</item>
                <item>WM to AE, 20 August 1932. ALS, 2 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Caputh, to AE, 22 August 1932. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Caputh, to AE, 23 August 1932. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Caputh, to AE, 26 August 1932. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>WM to AE, 27 August 1932. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Caputh, to AE, 13 November 1932. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Purkersdorf near Vienna, to AE, 17 November 1932. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Purkersdorf near Vienna, to AE, 26 November 1932. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Purkersdorf near Vienna, to AE, 6 December 1932. ALS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Purkersdorf, to AE, 10 December 1932. ALS, 2 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Le coq, to AE, 27 May 1933. ALS, 3 p.</item>
                <item>WM, Coq sur mer, to AE, 29 May 1933. ALS, 2 p., "Was ich Ihnen..."</item>
                <item>WM, Le coq, to AE, 29 May 1933. ALS, 2 p, "Diesmal möcht ich..."</item>
                <item>AE to "Herr v. Mendelssohn," 2 September 1925. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE. ADS, 1 p., 1 leaf, with Ms. notes on back</item>
                <item>Manuscript headed "Gruss an Amerika" in AE’s handwriting and signed by him, believed to be the text of the remarks he made on radio when he arrived in the U.S. in December of 1930. On the reverse side are mathematical calculations</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE to Dr. Hald, 24 March 1944. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>Einstein thanks Hald for the gift of some sweets and praise the Russian war effort</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE. ADS, 1 p., 1 leaf. Document deals with dangers of atomic weapons and need for international peace</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE, Princeton, to Joseph H. Schaffner, New York, 17 October 1946. TLS, 1 p., 1 leaf</item>
                <item>A letter of thanks from Einstein for Schaffner’s gift of a book</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>A framed photograph of Einstein by Yousof Karsh. Given by Einstein to Schaffner. The following inscription is written on the mat below the photograph; "To Mr. Joseph Schaffner with kind regards A. Einstein, 50."</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Albert Einstein Photos framed together</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>AE, Princeton, to Bertold Neuer, New York, 26 October 1934. TLS, 1 p.</item>
                <item>Einstein thanks Neuer for a piano</item>
                <item>Photograph clipped from a magazine showing AE playing the violin</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series IV: 	Sir Isaac Newton, 1642-1727</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Of an universall language (rough draft plus more finished draft) and other writings (genealogical notes; Latin phrases and English equivalents in a different hand). N.d., Autograph Ms (in a small notebook)</unittitle>
            <daogrp>
              <resource label="start"/>
              <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/schaffner-0003-007" role="application/pdf">
                <daodesc>
                  <p>View digitized documents.</p>
                </daodesc>
              </daoloc>
              <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
            </daogrp>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>For making portable furnaces, including a rough diagram. N.d. Autograph Ms. Four pages on two leaves, folded</unittitle>
            <daogrp>
              <resource label="start"/>
              <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/schaffner-0003-008" role="application/pdf">
                <daodesc>
                  <p>View digitized documents.</p>
                </daodesc>
              </daoloc>
              <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
            </daogrp>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Manuscript on pyrotechny, illustrated with diagrams. N.d. Autograph Ms. Two pages on one folio leaf, folded</unittitle>
            <daogrp>
              <resource label="start"/>
              <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/schaffner-0003-009" role="application/pdf">
                <daodesc>
                  <p>View digitized documents.</p>
                </daodesc>
              </daoloc>
              <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
            </daogrp>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Manuscript on certain chemical operations, "A Londoner acquainted with Mr. Boyle and Dr. Dickinson, affirmed that...ye oyle or spirit might be taken as sold in shops...," with the draft of a short letter mentioning Pepys on the reverse side. N.d. Autograph Ms. Two pages on one leaf</unittitle>
            <daogrp>
              <resource label="start"/>
              <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/schaffner-0003-010" role="application/pdf">
                <daodesc>
                  <p>View digitized documents.</p>
                </daodesc>
              </daoloc>
              <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
            </daogrp>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Description of an instrument for determining the angular distance of the moon from any fixed star with chronological/theological notes on the reverse side. N.d. Autograph Ms. Two pages on one leaf</unittitle>
            <daogrp>
              <resource label="start"/>
              <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/schaffner-0003-011" role="application/pdf">
                <daodesc>
                  <p>View digitized documents.</p>
                </daodesc>
              </daoloc>
              <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
            </daogrp>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Brief passage in Latin on the invention of the calculus (Begins; "Non quisnam hanc vel illam methodum invenerit...) on scrap of paper 2.5 inches by 7.5 inches. N.d. Autograph Ms.</unittitle>
            <daogrp>
              <resource label="start"/>
              <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/schaffner-0003-012" role="application/pdf">
                <daodesc>
                  <p>View digitized documents.</p>
                </daodesc>
              </daoloc>
              <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
            </daogrp>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Pepys, Samuel to Sir Isaac Newton, 21 December 1693. ALS, two pages on one leaf</unittitle>
            <daogrp>
              <resource label="start"/>
              <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/schaffner-0003-013" role="application/pdf">
                <daodesc>
                  <p>View digitized documents.</p>
                </daodesc>
              </daoloc>
              <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
            </daogrp>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Conduitt, John. "Memorandums relating to Sr. Isaac Newton given me by Mr. Abraham De Moivre in Novr. 1727." Autograph Ms. Five pages on two leaves</unittitle>
            <daogrp>
              <resource label="start"/>
              <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/schaffner-0003-014" role="application/pdf">
                <daodesc>
                  <p>View digitized documents.</p>
                </daodesc>
              </daoloc>
              <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
            </daogrp>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Bonval, B. de, La Haye, to Sir Isaac Newton, 22 August, [1697?]. ALS, 1 p., 1 leaf</unittitle>
            <daogrp>
              <resource label="start"/>
              <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/schaffner-0003-015" role="application/pdf">
                <daodesc>
                  <p>View digitized documents.</p>
                </daodesc>
              </daoloc>
              <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
            </daogrp>
            <note>
              <p>Sir Isaac Newton, manuscripts, See Series VII: Oversize</p>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series V: Miscellaneous Scientific Manuscripts</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>John Carver. Notes on mathematical and geometrical problems from Sir Isaac Newton’s Principia and other works. September 7-February 1, 1820</unittitle>
            <daogrp>
              <resource label="start"/>
              <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/schaffner-0003-016" role="application/pdf">
                <daodesc>
                  <p>View digitized documents.</p>
                </daodesc>
              </daoloc>
              <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
            </daogrp>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>[Siussi, Johannes Fracisco]. Translation notes and diagram from M. D’Alembert, Traite de l’equilibre, Paris; David, 1744</unittitle>
            <daogrp>
              <resource label="start"/>
              <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/schaffner-0003-017" role="application/pdf">
                <daodesc>
                  <p>View digitized documents.</p>
                </daodesc>
              </daoloc>
              <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
            </daogrp>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">18</container>
            <unittitle>Alessandro Giuseppe Antonio Anastasio Volta, Conte, 1745-1827, Como, to Padre G. B. Beccaria. A.L.S., 1 p. From Alessandro Volta, Lettere...Sull’Aria Infiammabile Nativa Della Paludi... Milano; Giuseppe Marelli, 1777</unittitle>
            <daogrp>
              <resource label="start"/>
              <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/schaffner-0003-018" role="application/pdf">
                <daodesc>
                  <p>View digitized documents.</p>
                </daodesc>
              </daoloc>
              <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
            </daogrp>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series VI: Schaffner Collection Records</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Records pertaining to the history of the Schaffner Collection. The Curie manuscripts</unittitle>
            <note>
              <p>See also Series VII: Oversize</p>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Records pertaining to the history of the Schaffner Collection. The Darwin manuscripts</unittitle>
            <note>
              <p>See also Series VII: Oversize</p>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Records pertaining to the history of the Schaffner Collection. The Einstein manuscripts</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Records pertaining to the history of the Schaffner Collection. The Newton manuscripts</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>The Huntington Library exhibition of Newton manuscripts, January-May, 1943</unittitle>
            <note>
              <p>See also Series VII: Oversize</p>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Ralph Elliot, Correspondence with Schaffner regarding Newton’s "Of an universall language."</unittitle>
            <note>
              <p>See also Series VII: Oversize</p>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Henry P. McComber, Correspondence with Schaffner regarding the Babson Institute Newton Collection and the Schaffner Newton Collection, 1954-61</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Sir Lawrence Bragg, the Royal Society of London, H. M. Adams, Librarian of Trinity College, Cambridge, England, and others, correspondence regarding Schaffner and other Newton manuscripts</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series VII: Oversize</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">6</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Sir Isaac Newton, manuscripts</unittitle>
            <daogrp>
              <resource label="start"/>
              <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/schaffner-0006-001" role="application/pdf">
                <daodesc>
                  <p>View digitized documents.</p>
                </daodesc>
              </daoloc>
              <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
            </daogrp>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>Dictionary of Latin phrases and An account of the charges of the mint in coyning and paying into the receipt of his majestie’s exchequer the new monies of the sixth general remain. In custom-made box of half red morocco</item>
                <item>An account of the charges of the mint in coyning and paying into the receipt of his majestie’s exchequer the new monies of the sixth general remain. 1 April 1696. Autograph Ms. 1 p., 1 leaf, folded. Signed by Newton and others</item>
                <item>A Latin phrase book with the first entry under the English heading "Abate" and the last under the heading "Conduct." N.d. Autograph Ms. 5 p., 3 leaves</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">6</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Records pertaining to the history of the Schaffner Collection. The Curie manuscripts</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">6</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Records pertaining to the history of the Schaffner Collection. The Darwin manuscripts</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">6</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>The Huntington Library exhibition of Newton manuscripts, January-May, 1943</unittitle>
            <note>
              <p>See also Series VII: Oversize</p>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">6</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Ralph Elliot, Correspondence with Schaffner regarding Newton’s "Of an universall language."</unittitle>
            <note>
              <p>See also Series VII: Oversize</p>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
