<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.MS626</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to George Manning, <emph render="italic">Adventures of a Half Guinea.</emph> Manuscript,<date>1823</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by KEF, 2017</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Literature and Poetry</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KEF, 2017</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to George Manning, <emph render="italic">Adventures of a Half Guinea.</emph> Manuscript,<date>1823</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by KEF, 2017</author>
      <p>© 2017 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Manning, George, <emph render="italic">Adventures of a Half Guinea.</emph> Manuscript (Ms 626)</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" label="Dates">1823</unitdate>
      <unitid type="inclusive" label="MS_No">Codex Ms 626</unitid>
      <langmaterial label="Language">Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">1 volume; 41 x 27 cm.</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract"> The author's draft of an unfinished and unpublished novel. Codex Ms 626.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The manuscript is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <altformavail>
        <head>Digital Images</head>
        <p>Original documents, texts, and images represented by digital images linked to this finding aid are subject to U. S. copyright law. It is the user's sole responsibility to secure any necessary copyright permission to reproduce or publish documents, texts, and images from any holders of rights in the original materials.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library, in its capacity as owner of the physical property represented by the digital images linked to this finding aid, encourages the use of these materials for educational and scholarly purposes.  Any reproduction or publication from these digital images requires that the following credit line be included:  Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p>
        <p>Commercial publication projects require the permission of the University of Chicago Library and may be subject to a use fee. To order publication-quality reproductions, or for permission to copy or use any part of the digital images attached to this finding aid for any commercial purposes, please contact the Special Collections Research Center.</p>
        <p>The images presented here may include materials reflecting the attitudes, language, and stereotypes of an earlier time period. These materials are presented as historical resources in support of study and research. Inclusion of such materials does not constitute an endorsement of their content by the University of Chicago.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library appreciates hearing from anyone who may have information about any of the images in this collection.</p>
      </altformavail>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
    this collection, the preferred citation is: Manning, George, <emph render="italic">Adventures of a Half Guinea.</emph> Manuscript, Codex Ms 626, Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>At the end of the satirical opening dedication, "To John Doe and Richard Roe," the author signed his name and indicated the time and place of composition: "63 Edgeware Road/Decr 1823." The printed parish records of St. George's Church, Hanover Square, which is in the vicinity of Edgeware Road, London, list a George Manning, who in November 1829 received a license to marry Anna Heurtley. This is probably the George Manning who wrote this text, but nothing more is known about him. Manning suggests in the preface that he is employed in the legal profession, perhaps as a clerk or secretary.</p>
        <p><emph render="italic">Adventures of a Half Guinea</emph> is modeled on Charles Johnstone's <emph render="italic">Chrysal; or, the Adventures of a Guinea</emph> which appeared in four volumes from 1760 to 1765, and was reprinted several times. <emph render="italic">Chrysal</emph> featured a gold guinea coin as "narrator" of several satirical tales of how it passed from the pockets of one greedy man to another.</p>
        <p>The Manning work is a rough draft, in the author's hand, with many corrections and erasures. It is very incomplete, with parts out of sequence. Either Manning did not finish these chapters, or we do not have all that he wrote.</p>
        <p>Folio, 41 x 26 cm.</p>
        <p>126 leaves, fully foliated in pencil. An older foliation in ink runs as follows: 18-72, 308-309, 197-225, which correspond to the penciled foliation of 34-72, 90-91, and 96-124. Presumably leaves formerly numbered 73-196 and 226-307 are missing.</p>
        <p>Modern blue-cloth binding of the University f Chicago Library. (T. Bentley Duncan, 1973)</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="https://www.lib.uchicago.edu/h/ead-topic-browse">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Manning, George, fl. 1823</persname>
        <genreform>Manuscripts, English</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="volume">1</container>
          <unittitle>Codex Ms 626</unittitle>
          <daogrp>
            <resource label="start"/>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/ms626-0001-001-01" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View digitized documents.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/ms626-0001-001-02" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View digitized documents.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
          </daogrp>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
