<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
<eadheader audience="internal">
<eadid>ICU.SPCL.PARKERE</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Guide to the Eugene Parker Papers<date>1948-2018</date></titleproper>
<author>Finding aid prepared by MA, 2022</author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt><publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher></publicationstmt>
<notestmt>
<note><p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p></note>
<note><p><subject>Physical Sciences, Astronomy and Astrophysics</subject></p></note>
</notestmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding aid encoded by AG, 2022</creation>
<langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>

<frontmatter audience="external">
<titlepage>
<publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
<titleproper>Guide to the Eugene Parker Papers<date>1948-2018</date></titleproper>
<author>Finding aid prepared by MA, 2022</author>
<p>© 2022 University of Chicago Library</p>
</titlepage>

</frontmatter>

<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Descriptive Summary</head>
<unittitle label="Title">Parker, Eugene. Papers</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" label="Dates">1948-2018</unitdate>


<langmaterial>Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
<physdesc label="Size">12.5 linear feet (18 boxes)</physdesc>
<repository label="Repository"><address>
<addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
<addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
<addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
<addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
</address></repository>
<abstract label="Abstract">Eugene Parker was an astrophysicist and University of Chicago professor best known for predicting the existence of solar wind. In addition to heliophysics, Parker also studied cosmic rays and magnetic fields. The collection includes Parker’s email correspondence; scientific and personal photographs; reprints of Parker’s scientific publications from 1952 to 2016; lecture notes and overhead projector slides from Parker’s courses; materials related to astrophysicist Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar; scientific publications written by others; and Parker’s awards and diplomas. Materials date between 1948 and 2018, with the bulk of material dating between 1952 and 2011.</abstract>
</did>

<descgrp><head>Information on Use</head>
<accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>This collection is open for research with the exception of material in Series X. This series contains Parker’s letters of recommendation, which are restricted for 80 years from the date of record creation.</p></accessrestrict>

<prefercite><head>Citation</head><p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Parker, Eugene. Papers, [Box #, Folder #], Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p></prefercite>

<bioghist><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Eugene Newman Parker was born on June 10, 1927 in Houghton, Michigan. His father, Glenn Parker, worked as an engineer at Chrysler and his mother, Helen Parker (MacNair) worked as a homemaker. Parker earned a B.S. in Physics from Michigan State University in 1948 and a PhD from the California Institute of Technology in 1951.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>In 1954, Eugene married Niesje Parker. The couple had one son, Eric Parker, and one daughter, Joyce Marie Parker.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>After finishing his PhD, Parker worked at the University of Utah as an instructor and assistant professor. He was hired by the University of Chicago in 1955, where he worked for the rest of his career. In 1958, Parker published his prediction of the existence of solar wind, a continuous outpouring of charged particles flowing from the sun at a million miles per hour. His idea was met with widespread skepticism from fellow physicists, including the reviewers of the paper and the editor of the publication. Parker’s prediction was verified, however, when NASA’s Mariner II spacecraft encountered a flow of solar particles during its flight to Venus in 1962.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>In addition to heliophysics, Parker also studied cosmic rays and magnetic fields. His four books include Interplanetary Dynamical Processes (1963), Cosmical Magnetic Fields: Their Origin and Their Activity (1979), Spontaneous Current Sheets in Magnetic Fields, with Applications to Stellar X-rays (1994), and Conversations on Electric and Magnetic Fields in the Cosmos (2007). He retired in 1995 but continued to teach and publish work in the following decades.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Parker won numerous awards throughout his career, including the National Medal of Science, the Kyoto Prize, and the American Physical Society Medal for Exceptional Achievement in Research. He was member of the National Academy of Sciences and served as chair for the Academy’s astronomy section. In 2017, NASA named its solar probe the Parker Solar Probe in his honor, marking the first time NASA named a spacecraft after a living person.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Eugene Parker died in Chicago on March 15, 2022 at the age of 94.</p></bioghist>
<scopecontent><head>Scope Note</head><p>The Eugene Parker Papers are organized into ten series: Series I: Personal; Series II: Correspondence; Series III: Writing; Series IV: Teaching; Series V: Professional Associations and Events; Series VI: Writing by Others; Series VII: Awards, Honors, and Degrees; Series VIII: Audiovisual; Series IX: Oversize; and Series X: Restricted. The collection includes Parker’s email correspondence; reprints of Parker’s scientific publications from 1952 to 2016; lecture notes and overhead projector slides from Parker’s courses; materials related to astrophysicist Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar; scientific publications written by others; scientific and personal photographs; and Parker’s awards and diplomas. Materials date between 1948 and 2018, with the bulk of material dating between 1952 and 2011.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series I, Personal, contains biographical and autobiographical information on Parker and ephemera.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series II, Correspondence, contains Parker’s letters, handwritten notes, and printed emails, including correspondence related to the Parker Solar Probe.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series III, Writing, contains Parker’s thesis manuscript, reprinted papers, reports, articles, publications, and pamphlets. Reprinted papers are ordered roughly chronologically. All other writing is organized chronologically following the reprinted papers.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series IV, Teaching, contains Parker’s lecture notes and overhead projector slides from the 2000s and 2010s. Materials are organized alphabetically according to the lecture title.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series V, Professional Associations and Events, contains materials related to Parker’s professional life, such as newsletters, bulletins, dinner lists and menus, and symposium programs. Organizations include but are not limited to the Instrument Society of America, the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, and the NATO Advanced Study Institute on Solar and Astrophysical Magnetohydrodynamic Flows. Materials are arranged chronologically.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series VI, Writing by Others, contains materials concerning other astrophysicists and scientific publications not written by Eugene Parker. Materials are divided into two subseries:&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Subseries 1, Materials Related to Other Astrophysicists, contains reprints by and memorials to Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar, reprints and correspondence with Joseph Lemaire, and reprints by Sydney Chapman. Materials are arranged alphabetically according to the last name of the astrophysicist. &#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Subseries 2, Scientific Publications, contains copies of the publication The Planetary Report (1983-1985) and other scientific articles and pamphlets, including materials published by NASA. Materials are arranged roughly chronologically.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series VII, Awards, Honors, and Degrees, contains awards, medals, and degrees granted to Parker, as well as his university degrees, diplomas, certificates, and acceptance speeches. Material are arranged chronologically according to the award date.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series VIII, Audiovisual, contains Parker’s scientific and personal photographs from 1965 to 2000 and a DVD recording of a workshop.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series IX, Oversize, contains oversized materials such as framed awards, diplomas, and honorary degrees. Materials are organized according to size.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series X, Restricted, contains Parker’s letters of recommendation, which are restricted for 80 years from the date of record creation. Materials are organized chronologically.</p></scopecontent>
<relatedmaterial><head>Related Resources</head>
<archref><extref href="https://www.lib.uchicago.edu/h/ead-topic-browse">Browse
finding aids by topic.</extref></archref><archref><unittitle>Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar Papers&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Peter Meyer Papers&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>David N. Schramm Papers&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Lalitha Chandrasekhar Papers&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Edwin B. Frost Papers&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>George Ellery Hale Papers&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>George van Biesbroeck Papers&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Henry Gordon Gale Papers&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>University of Chicago Division of the Physical Sciences Records&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>University of Chicago Yerkes Observatory Logbooks and Notebooks&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle/></archref>
     </relatedmaterial>
<controlaccess><head>Subject Headings</head>
<persname>Parker, E.N. (Eugene Newman), 1927-2022&#13;</persname><persname>Chandrasekhar, S. (Subrahmanyan), 1910-1995&#13;</persname><persname/>
<corpname>National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA)&#13;</corpname><corpname>University of Chicago. Department of Astronomy and Astrophysics&#13;</corpname><corpname>American Physical Society&#13;</corpname><corpname>National Academy of Sciences (U.S.)</corpname>
<subject>Astrophysics&#13;</subject><subject>Astrophysicists&#13;</subject><subject>Solar wind</subject>




</controlaccess>
</descgrp>


<dsc type="combined">
<head>INVENTORY</head>

<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series I: Personal</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>This series contains biographical and autobiographical information on Parker and ephemera.</p>
</scopecontent>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1 </container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Biographical Information, CV, and Correspondence, 1997-2013</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1 </container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Solar Eclipse Viewers, 1991</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1 </container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Images from the Chandra X-Ray Observatory Calendar, 2001</unittitle></did></c02>
</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series II: Correspondence</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>This series contains Parker’s letters, handwritten notes, and printed emails, including correspondence related to the Parker Solar Probe.</p>
</scopecontent>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1 </container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Correspondence, 1990-2016</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1 </container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Correspondence Related to Parker Solar Probe, 2009</unittitle></did></c02>
</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series III: Writing</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>This series contains Parker’s thesis manuscript, reprinted papers, reports, articles, publications, and pamphlets. Reprinted papers are ordered roughly chronologically. All other writing is organized chronologically following the reprinted papers.</p>
</scopecontent>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1 </container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 1-44, 1952-1961</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1 </container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 45-75, 1960-1964</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1 </container>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 76-97, 1963-1966</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">2 </container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 98-124, 1965-1968</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">2 </container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 125-142, 1968-1970</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">2 </container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 143-184, 1969-1975</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">2 </container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 185-201, 1974-1977</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">3 </container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 202-228, 1978-1982</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">3 </container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 229-259, 1981-1985</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">3 </container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 260-276, 1985-1987</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">3 </container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 277-291, 1987-1989</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">3 </container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 292-301, 1989-1990</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 302-319, 1990-1993</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 320-336, 1992-1996</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 337-340, 1996</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 341-349, 1994-1996</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 350-354, 1995-1997</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 355-361, 1996-1997</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 361-376, 1997-2000</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 377-389, 1999-2002</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 390-392, 2001-2004</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 391-396, 2002-2006</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 394-408, 2006-2012</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 410, 2013</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>Reprinted Papers 411-412, 2016</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Thesis Manuscript — Interstellar Dust and Gas Clouds, 1951</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Research on Global Warming, circa 1990s [1/2]</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Research on Global Warming, circa 1990s [2/2]</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Assessing the Changing Moods of the Sun and the Climate of Earth, 1999</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>A History of the Solar Wind Concept, 2001</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>Parker Wind, 2008</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>Hydrodynamics and the Kinetic Treatment of a Collisionless Atmosphere, 2008</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle>Solar Activity: From Galileo’s Sunspots to the Heliosphere, 2009</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">9</container>
<unittitle>The Legacy of Jack Eddy, 2010</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">10</container>
<unittitle>Wherefore Physics? 2011</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">11</container>
<unittitle>Physics and the World, circa 2011</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">12</container>
<unittitle>Diverse Scientific Contributions, undated</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<container type="folder">13</container>
<unittitle>Citations and Notes, undated</unittitle></did></c02>
</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series IV: Teaching</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>This series contains Parker’s lecture notes and overhead projector slides from the 2000s and 2010s. Materials are organized alphabetically according to the lecture title.</p>
</scopecontent>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>The Applicability of Hydrodynamics — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2000s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>A Brief History of the Dynamo Concept — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2000s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Cosmic Rays and Space Travelers — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector, circa 2006</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Discovery and Investigation of Solar Magnetism — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2000s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Electromagnetic Preliminaries and Ongoing Developments in Plasma Physics — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2010s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>Fifty Years of Galactic Magnetic Field — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2000s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>Galileo and the Physics of the Heliosphere — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2000s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle>History of the Solar Wind — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2000s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">9</container>
<unittitle>The Legacy of Jack Eddy — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2000s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">10</container>
<unittitle>The Microworld of the Solar Corona — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2000s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">11</container>
<unittitle>Pathological Science in Physics Today — Article and Lecture Notes, circa 2000s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">12</container>
<unittitle>Poynting Theorem and Introduction to Plasma Physics and Sociology — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2000s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">13</container>
<unittitle>The Secret Life of Magnetic Fields — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2000s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">14</container>
<unittitle>Solar Magnetism — Book Outline, Lecture Notes, and Overhead Projector Slides, 2008 [1/2]</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">15</container>
<unittitle>Solar Magnetism — Book Outline, Lecture Notes, and Overhead Projector Slides, 2008 [2/2]</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">16</container>
<unittitle>Solar Wind — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2008</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">17</container>
<unittitle>Space Exploration and Cosmic Rays — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2000s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<container type="folder">18</container>
<unittitle>Sun, Earth, and Magnetic Fields — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2000s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Untitled — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides on Solar Wind, circa 2000s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>What are Stellar and Galactic Dynamos to do Without Turbulent Diffusion of Magnetic Fields? — Lecture Notes and Overhead Projector Slides, circa 2005</unittitle></did></c02>
</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series V: Professional Associations and Events</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>This series contains materials related to professional association and events, such as newsletters, bulletins, dinner lists and menus, and symposium programs. Organizations include but are not limited to the Instrument Society of America, the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, and the NATO Advanced Study Institute on Solar and Astrophysical Magnetohydrodynamic Flows. Materials are arranged chronologically.</p>
</scopecontent>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>The Instrument Society of America Events Newsletter, 1963</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Ryerson Astronomical Society Club Dinner Lists, 1979</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>The American Academy of Arts and Sciences Bulletin, 1989</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>University of Oslo Annual Report and Annual Party Materials, 1990</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>NATO Advanced Study Institute on Solar and Astrophysical Magnetohydrodynamic Flows Dinner Menu, 1995</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle>Nobel Laureates from the Chicago Physics Department and the Research Institutes Booklet, 1995</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">9</container>
<unittitle>Challenging the Paradigm: The Legacy of Galileo Symposium Program, 2009</unittitle></did></c02>
</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series VI: Writing by Others</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>This series contains materials concerning other astrophysicists and scientific publications not written by Eugene Parker. The first subseries contains reprints by and memorials to Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar, reprints and correspondence with Joseph Lemaire, and reprints by Sydney Chapman. Materials are arranged alphabetically according to the last name of the astrophysicist. The second subseries contains copies of the publication The Planetary Report (1983-1985) and other scientific articles and pamphlets, including materials published by NASA. Materials are arranged roughly chronologically. </p>
</scopecontent>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 1:  Materials Related to Other Astrophysicists</unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">10</container>
<unittitle>Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar Reprints and Memorials, 1975-2010 [1/6]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">11</container>
<unittitle>Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar Reprints and Memorials, 1975-2010 [2/6]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">12</container>
<unittitle>Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar Reprints and Memorials, 1975-2010 [3/6]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">13</container>
<unittitle>Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar Reprints and Memorials, 1975-2010 [4/6]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">14</container>
<unittitle>Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar Reprints and Memorials, 1975-2010 [5/6]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<container type="folder">15</container>
<unittitle>Subrahmanyan Chandrasekhar Reprints and Memorials, 1975-2010 [6/6]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Sydney Chapman Reprints, 1971</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Joseph Lemaire Reprints and Correspondence, 1973-2008</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 2:  Scientific Publications </unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Scientific Reprints and Articles, 1952-2009 [1/2]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Scientific Reprints and Articles, 1952-2009 [2/2]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Advertising Pamphlet for Fourth Edition of Exploration of the Universe, 1982</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>Science and Creationism: A View from the National Academy of Sciences, 1984</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>The Planetary Report Magazine, 1983-1984</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle>Physics World with Survey Thank You Note sent to Eugene Parker, 1999</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">9</container>
<unittitle>Ian Lerche — Cosmic Connections: A Scientific Autobiography, 2005</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">10</container>
<unittitle>NASA Publications, 1979-2018</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>

</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series VII: Awards, Honors, and Degrees</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>This series contains awards, medals, and degrees granted to Parker, as well as his university degrees, diplomas, certificates, and acceptance speeches. Material are arranged chronologically according to the award date.</p>
</scopecontent>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">11</container>
<unittitle>B.S. — Michigan State University, 1948</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">12</container>
<unittitle>Election to National Academy of Sciences Documents, 1967</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">13</container>
<unittitle>American Geophysical Union John Adam Fleming Award Programs, 1968</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">14</container>
<unittitle>NASA Apollo Achievement Award, 1969</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">15</container>
<unittitle>Michigan State University Commencement Documents, 1975</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<container type="folder">16</container>
<unittitle>Chapman Medal Presidential Address Transcript, 1979</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">10</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>California Institute of Technology Alumni Award, 1980</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">10</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>National Medal of Science Election Documents, 1989</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">10</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Bowie Medal Photograph and Announcement, 1989-1990 [1/2]</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">10</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Bowie Medal Photograph and Announcement, 1989-1990 [2/2]</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">10</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>American Geographical Union Parker Lecture Certificate, 1991</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">10</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>MIT Hannes Alfvén Lecturer Award, 1992</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">10</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>Kyoto Prize Materials, 2003 [1/3]</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">10</container>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle>Kyoto Prize Materials, 2003 [2/3]</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">10</container>
<container type="folder">9</container>
<unittitle>Kyoto Prize Materials, 2003 [3/3]</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">10</container>
<container type="folder">10</container>
<unittitle>American Physical Society Exceptional Achievement Ceremony and Reception Program, 2018</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">10</container>
<container type="folder">11</container>
<unittitle>National Research Council Space Studies Board Certificate of Appreciation, undated</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container type="box">11</container>
<unittitle>Michigan State University Jonathan L. Snyder Society Award, 2003</unittitle></did></c02>
</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series VIII: Audiovisual</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>This series contains Parker’s scientific and personal photographs from 1965 to 2000 and a DVD recording of a workshop.</p>
</scopecontent>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">12</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Personal and Scientific Photographs, 1965-2000</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">12</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>DVD — Parker Workshop on Magnetic Reconnection — São Paulo, Brazil, 2014</unittitle></did></c02>
</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series IX: Oversize</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>This series contains oversized materials such as framed awards, diplomas, and honorary degrees. Materials are organized according to size.</p>
</scopecontent>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>American Geophysical Union Recognition of Eminence, 1962</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics Space Science Award, 1964</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>National Academy of Sciences Diploma, 1967</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>American Geophysical Union John Adam Fleming Award, 1968</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Utrecht University Honorary Doctorate and Ceremony Photographs, 1986</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>National Medal of Science Diploma, 1989</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>Oslo University Honorary Doctorate, 1991</unittitle>
</did></c02>
     <c02>
          <did>
               <container type="box">13</container>
               <unittitle>Framed NASA Public Service Award, 2017</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">14</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Det Norske Videnskaps-Akademi Member Diploma, 1988</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">14</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>American Physical Society Exceptional Achievement in Research Prize, 2018</unittitle>
</did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">14</container>
 <unittitle>Framed Village of Flossmoor Commendation, 2017</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">15</container>
<unittitle>American Physical Society James Clerk Maxwell Award, 2003</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container type="box">15</container>
<unittitle>European Physical Society Hannes Alfvén Award, 2012</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container type="box">15</container>
<unittitle>National Observatory of Athens Moon Chart, 2013</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container type="box">16</container>
<unittitle>Kyoto Prize, 2003</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container type="box">16</container>
<unittitle>Kyoto Prize Album of Memories</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container type="box">17</container>
<unittitle>Seven Wise Men of the World in Cosmology Greek Award, Case, and Medal 2008 </unittitle></did></c02>
</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series X: Restricted</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>This series contains Parker’s letters of recommendation which are restricted for 80 years from the date of record creation. Materials are organized chronologically.</p>
</scopecontent>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">18</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Letters of Recommendation, 2002-2006</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">18</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Letters of Recommendation, 2007-2009</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">18</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Letters of Recommendation, 2010-2012</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">18</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Letters of Recommendation, 2013-2015</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">18</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Letters of Recommendation, 2016-2017</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">18</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>Letters of Recommendation, circa 2010s</unittitle></did></c02>
</c01></dsc>
</archdesc></ead>
