<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.MS149</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to Samuel Harrison, <emph render="italic">Sermon Notes on the Apostles’ Creed.</emph> Manuscript,<date>1672</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by MP, 2019</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Early Western Manuscripts (pre-1700)</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Religion and Theology</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by MP, 2019</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to Samuel Harrison, <emph render="italic">Sermon Notes on the Apostles’ Creed.</emph> Manuscript,<date>1672</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by MP, 2019</author>
      <p>© 2019 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Harrison, Samuel, <emph render="italic">Sermon Notes on the Apostles’ Creed.</emph>  Manuscript (Ms 149)</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" label="Dates">1672</unitdate>
      <unitid type="inclusive" label="MS_No">Codex Ms 149</unitid>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">1 volume; 17 x 12 cm</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">Notes for sermons by Samuel Harrison, the rector of Oving, Buckinghamshire, from 1672-1682. Text in English. Codex Ms 149.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The manuscript is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <altformavail>
        <head>Digital Images</head>
        <p>Original documents, texts, and images represented by digital images linked to this finding aid are subject to U. S. copyright law. It is the user's sole responsibility to secure any necessary copyright permission to reproduce or publish documents, texts, and images from any holders of rights in the original materials.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library, in its capacity as owner of the physical property represented by the digital images linked to this finding aid, encourages the use of these materials for educational and scholarly purposes.  Any reproduction or publication from these digital images requires that the following credit line be included:  Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p>
        <p>Commercial publication projects require the permission of the University of Chicago Library and may be subject to a use fee. To order publication-quality reproductions, or for permission to copy or use any part of the digital images attached to this finding aid for any commercial purposes, please contact the Special Collections Research Center.</p>
        <p>The images presented here may include materials reflecting the attitudes, language, and stereotypes of an earlier time period. These materials are presented as historical resources in support of study and research. Inclusion of such materials does not constitute an endorsement of their content by the University of Chicago.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library appreciates hearing from anyone who may have information about any of the images in this collection.</p>
      </altformavail>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
          this collection, the preferred citation is: Harrison, Samuel, <emph render="italic">Sermon Notes on the Apostles’ Creed.</emph>   Manuscript, Codex Ms 149, Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Biographical Note</head>
        <p>Samuel Harrison was born in Hartwell, Buckinghamshire, where his father was rector of the local church. On December 4, 1661, he was matriculated at Magdalen Hall, Oxford. In 1665 he received a baccalaureate from Wadham College, followed by a Master's degree in 1668. He became rector of Oving, Buckinghamshire in 1672. After ten years he was transferred to a position at Waddesdon, where he is recorded as continuing to serve as late as 1706.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The notebook is in octavo format and contains 114 leaves, mostly foliated, with some pages left blank. The leaves are paper in a contemporary leather binding with gold border decorations on front and back covers. Text is in English with some writing in Greek (e.g. on page 169) and Hebrew (e.g. 205). Notes are in the author’s hand, except few comments in a very shaky script (e.g. on 30, 84). The notes for each sermon begin with a biblical quotation, followed by musings on its meaning in the original context and a paragraph headed “Application,” which aims to demonstrate the continued relevance of the biblical teachings.</p>
        <p>
          <extref href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/ewm-0149-desc">Additional description.</extref>
        </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="https://www.lib.uchicago.edu/h/ead-topic-browse">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Harrison, Samuel, b. 1648</persname>
        <subject>Apostles’ Creed -- Early works to 1800</subject>
        <genreform>Manuscripts, English</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="volume">1</container>
          <unittitle>Codex Ms 149</unittitle>
          <daogrp>
            <resource label="start"/>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/ewm-0149" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View manuscript.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
          </daogrp>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
