<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.TUFTS</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the James Hayden Tufts
                                                Papers<date>1908-1942</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by SV, 2006</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the
                                                copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>University of Chicago - Founding and Early History</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Politics, Public Policy and Political Reform</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Philosophy</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by SV, 2006</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to the James Hayden Tufts
                                Papers<date>1908-1942</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by SV, 2006</author>
      <p>© 2006 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Tufts, James Hayden. Papers</unittitle>
      <unitdate label="Dates" type="inclusive">1908-1942</unitdate>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English.</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">2 linear feet (4 boxes)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">James Hayden Tufts (1862-1942) was on the faculty
                                of the Department of Philosophy at the University of Chicago from
                                1892-1930. He was Dean of the Senior Colleges (1898-1904), Dean of
                                Faculties and Vice-President of the University (1924-26), Acting
                                President of the University (1925-26), and editor of the
                                International Journal of Ethics (1914-1930). The Tufts Papers
                                include professional correspondence (1909-1942); philosophy
                                outlines, notes and lectures; drafts of Tufts' memoirs; papers
                                concerning the City Club of Chicago Committee on Housing Conditions
                                (1908-13); and documents related to the Illinois Committee on Social
                                Legislation (1912-17).</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from this collection, the preferred
                                        citation is: Tufts, James Hayden. Papers, [Box #, Folder #],
                                        Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago
                                        Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Biographical Note</head>
        <p>James Hayden Tufts (1862-1942) was on the faculty of the
                                        Department of Philosophy at the University of Chicago from
                                        1892-1930. In 1905 he was appointed Chairman of the
                                        Philosophy Department, a position he held until his
                                        retirement from the University in 1930. In addition to
                                        departmental duties, he was Dean of the Senior Colleges
                                        (1898-1904), Dean of Faculties and Vice-President of the
                                        University (1924-26), Acting President of the University
                                        (1925-26), and editor of the International Journal of Ethics
                                        (1914-1930).</p>
        <p>Born in Monson, Massachusetts, James Tufts was educated at his
                                        father's grammar school and subsequently at Amherst College
                                        (B.A., 1883), Yale Divinity School (B.D., 1889), and the
                                        University of Freiburg (Ph.D., 1892). After graduating from
                                        Yale, he accepted a teaching position in the Department of
                                        Philosophy at the University of Michigan. During a holiday
                                        visit to his home in Massachusetts, he received an
                                        invitation to call on his former professor, William Rainey
                                        Harper, at Yale. Sharing with Tufts his plans for a new
                                        university in Chicago, Harper invited him to join the
                                        faculty. Tufts resigned from the University of Michigan,
                                        married Cynthia Whitaker, and set sail for Germany to begin
                                        one year of study at the University of Freiburg, with the
                                        agreement that he would be in Chicago, prepared to teach, by
                                        August, 1892. While in Germany, Tufts and Harper
                                        corresponded frequently [Tufts' letters to Harper, dating
                                        from 1890-92, are in Box XV, Folder 12 of the William Rainey
                                        Harper Personal Papers]. At Harper's request, Tufts provided
                                        information about various candidates for positions at the
                                        University, and he advised Harper on acquisitions for the
                                        Philosophy Library.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The Tufts Papers include professional correspondence (1909-1942);
                                        philosophy outlines, notes and lectures; drafts of Tufts'
                                        memoirs; papers concerning the City Club of Chicago
                                        Committee on Housing Conditions (1908-13); and documents
                                        related to the Illinois Committee on Social Legislation
                                        (1912-17).</p>
        <p>Series I: General Correspondence, ranges from 1909-1917, with the
                                        exception of five business letters dating from 1937-1942. A
                                        considerable portion consists of recommendations and advice
                                        to students on various aspects of their academic or
                                        professional careers. Among the letters from students, those
                                        of Matilda Castro are especially interesting; their
                                        correspondence was richer, livelier, and more extensive than
                                        that between Tufts and any other student. Her letters of
                                        1912-1914, while an instructor of Philosophy at Bryn Mawr
                                        College, characterize that institution during the
                                        administration of President Thomas. Cynthia Whitaker Tufts
                                        died in 1920. James Tufts and Matilda Castro were married in
                                        1923. </p>
        <p>Many letters recommending women students, or those requesting
                                        prominent applicants for positions, illustrate prevailing
                                        attitudes toward women in academia. The difficulties women
                                        faced in securing teaching positions are shown in Tufts'
                                        correspondence with Dagney Sunne (Box I, Folder 1-2).</p>
        <p>There is virtually no correspondence with colleagues of a purely
                                        academic nature, and correspondence between Tufts and
                                        members of the University community is sparse. He wrote to
                                        Marion Talbot of his anger at the Trustees' denial in 1916
                                        of an honorary degree to Jane Addams. Tufts had a long and
                                        close association with John Dewey and George Herbert
                                        Mead-both were with him in the Department of Philosophy at
                                        Ann Arbor, and both were recommended by him to Harper. There
                                        are four letters in the collection from John Dewey. Two of
                                        these concern rewriting Ethics, jointly authored with Tufts
                                        in 1908 (the letters, dated 1909 and 1916, are in Box I,
                                        Folders 1 and 8 respectively); another expresses Dewey's
                                        attitudes about teaching, and his wish to retire after
                                        twenty-five years of it. The fourth letter, dated December
                                        8, 1909, is an invitation to Mrs. Tufts. The only letter
                                        from George Herbert Mead (November 28, 1911) deals at length
                                        with departmental news; Mead mentions in it a discussion
                                        with Josiah Royce of philosophical idealism.</p>
        <p>Series II: Academic Papers contains outlines and lecture notes
                                        for his philosophy classes; drafts of sermons and public
                                        addresses; a bibliography of Tufts' works; and a bound
                                        volume of salutary letters presented to Tufts by the
                                        Philosophy Club at his retirement dinner in 1930. There is
                                        also correspondence with Dagobert Runes and Ralph Winn from
                                        1941-42, regarding Tufts' minor collaboration in The
                                        Dictionary of Philosophy, a work never published. A
                                        paper-"Ethics,&#148; develops Tufts' interest in social
                                        ethics; there are also drafts on the philosophy of law and
                                        unionization.</p>
        <p>Series III: Personal Memoirs, contains texts written after Tufts'
                                        retirement in 1930. They were never completed. Beginning
                                        with a genealogy of the Tufts family, the memoirs describe
                                        Tufts' student years, his experiences at the University of
                                        Chicago, and involvements in social reform organizations.
                                        Two chapters were edited by Matilda Castro Tufts for
                                        inclusion in a commemorative volume published after Tufts'
                                        death.</p>
        <p>The style of the memoirs is simple and engaging. He vividly
                                        recounts his experiences in Grand Forks County, North Dakota
                                        as a minister for the Baptist Home Missions Board. These
                                        autobiographical excepts provide a glimpse of the
                                        University's early years: Tufts describes Harper's plans for
                                        the University; contrasts Harper's presidency with that of
                                        his successor, Harry Pratt Judson; and offers biographical
                                        sketches of many contemporaries on the University Faculty.
                                        He outlines the concerns of the Board of Trustees under
                                        President Ernest Dewitt Burton. Tufts was disturbed by the
                                        lack of fraternity between students and professors that he
                                        found at the University of Chicago; early in his Chicago
                                        career, he became Dean of the Senior Colleges (1898-1904)
                                        because he felt that an administrative position might
                                        provide opportunity for interaction with students "along
                                        somewhat different lines from those in the classroom." He
                                        was a member of the faculty committee to elect a new
                                        president after Harry Pratt Judson's retirement in 1922,
                                        served as Vice-President and Dean of the Faculties of the
                                        University from 1924-26, and toured cities across the
                                        country with A. A. Stagg to stimulate alumni contributions
                                        during the University's development campaign of 1924-26.</p>
        <p>Series IV documents Tufts&#146; social and political
                                        activities. He served the City Club of Chicago Committee on
                                        Housing Conditions as Chairman in 1910, and as keynote
                                        speaker ("Housing in Illinois Cities," Box IV, Folder 2) at
                                        the 14th annual meeting of the Illinois State Conference of
                                        Charities and Correction in 1909. Among his collaborators on
                                        a study of housing congestion in Chicago's suburbs were
                                        Sophonisba Breckenridge and Edith Abbott of the University
                                        of Chicago. The Committee's research culminated in an
                                        exhibit in 1913 detailing housing conditions in Chicago.</p>
        <p>In 1915 Tufts was president of the Illinois State Committee on
                                        Social Legislation; composed of 28 independent agencies,
                                        this committee served primarily to lobby for the passage of
                                        social reform legislation and for the enforcement of laws
                                        and ordinances. Drafts of many of the laws which the
                                        Committee supported are contained in Box IV.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>The following related resources are located in the Department of
                                        Special Collections:</p>
        <archref>
          <unittitle>http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html
                                        </unittitle>
        </archref>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Tufts, James Hayden, 1862-1942</persname>
        <persname>Castro, Mathilde</persname>
        <persname>Dewey, John, 1859-1952</persname>
        <persname>Mead, George Herbert, 1863-1931</persname>
        <corpname>City Club of Chicago</corpname>
        <corpname>University of Chicago-History</corpname>
        <corpname>Illinois. Committee on Social Legislation</corpname>
        <subject>Social legislation -- Illinois</subject>
        <subject>Philosophy -- Study and teaching</subject>
        <subject>Housing</subject>
        <subject>Illinois -- Social conditions</subject>
        <occupation>Social reformers</occupation>
        <occupation>Philosophers</occupation>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series I: General Correspondence</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>1909-1911</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>1912 (January-June)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>1912 (July-December)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>1913</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>1914</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>1915</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>1916 (January-June)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>1916 (July-December)</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>1917-1942</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Condolences received by Matilda Castro
                                                  Tufts at the death of JHT</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series II: Academic Papers</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Course outlines for
                                                  philosophy</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Notes on philosophers;
                                                  Abelard-Fichte</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Notes on philosophers;
                                                  Grotius-Hutcheson</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Notes on philosophers;
                                                  Kant-Mandeville</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Notes on philosophers;
                                                  Plato-Shaftsbury</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Notes on philosophers;
                                                  Utilitarianism-Miscellaneous</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Notes on ethics and
                                                  anthropology</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>"The Philosopher in the Den,"
                                                  1920</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>"Albion Woodbury Small," 1926; "The Path
                                                  of Life," c. 1928</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>"Claims as the Field of Law" "The
                                                  Facts"</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Correspondence with Dogobert Runes and
                                                  Ralph Winn, 1941-42; editing for a philosophy
                                                  dictionary, never published</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>"Ethics," 1941</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Bibliography of James Hayden
                                                  Tufts</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Presentation book given to Tufts by his
                                                  students at retirement dinner, 1930</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series III: Personal Memoirs</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>JHT Autobiography; outline and
                                                  notes</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>"Some Reflections"</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>"Childhood and Family"-edited
                                                  drafts</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>"Childhood and Family"-final
                                                  draft</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>"Four Horses that I
                                                  know"-holograph</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>"Monson Town," part 1</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>"Monson Town," part 2</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>"Monson Town," part 3</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>"Amherst College," edited
                                                  draft</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>"Amherst College," final
                                                  draft</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Graduate study; 1887-88</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>"Some Impressions of the University of
                                                  Michigan, 1889-91"</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Germany, 1891-92</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>"Harper's Plan"</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Biographies of early faculty members of
                                                  the University</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>John Dewey</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>W. R. Harper; Harry Pratt
                                                  Judson</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">18</container>
            <unittitle>E. D. Burton, election and
                                                  administration</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">19</container>
            <unittitle>General Topics</unittitle>
            <note>
              <list>
                <item>"University Publicity in the Early
                                                  Years"</item>
                <item>"I Study Administration and Administrators,
                                                  1904-07"</item>
                <item>"Wartime"</item>
              </list>
            </note>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">20</container>
            <unittitle>The American College; general
                                                  considerations</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">21</container>
            <unittitle>"Chicago; I Study the City"</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">22</container>
            <unittitle>Personal experiences and anecdotes, early
                                                  years</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">23</container>
            <unittitle>"Clothing Arbitration,"
                                                  1919-20</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">24</container>
            <unittitle>Cynthia Whitaker Tufts; In Memoriam,
                                                  1920</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">25</container>
            <unittitle>James Hayden Tufts; In Memoriam,
                                                  1942</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <container type="folder">26</container>
            <unittitle>Photos, correspondence, and texts from
                                                  Tufts' memorial service for inclusion in the
                                                  memorial volume</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series IV: Social and Political
                                                Activities</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>City Club of Chicago; Pamphlets,
                                                  1908-14</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Articles and notes by Tufts on Illinois
                                                  housing; articles by E. Abbott and S. Breckenridge
                                                  on "The Housing Problem in Chicago"; Joliet in
                                                  Photographs</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Pamphlets on the Housing Movement in
                                                  other states</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>City Club Committee on Housing
                                                  Conditions; Correspondence, 1908-09</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>City Club Committee on Housing
                                                  Conditions; Correspondence, 1910-13</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>City Club Committee on Housing
                                                  Conditions; Correspondence, Minutes, 1908-1912,
                                                  including "Housing in Illinois Cities" and other
                                                  reports</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>City Club Committee on Housing
                                                  Conditions; notes and outlines for Housing
                                                  Exhibition</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>City Club Committee on Housing
                                                  Conditions; Miscellaneous</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Illinois Committee on Social Legislation;
                                                  Miscellaneous pamphlets</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Illinois Committee on Social Legislation;
                                                  Miscellaneous pamphlets, By-laws, minutes and
                                                  agenda of meetings, 1912-16</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Illinois Committee on Social Legislation;
                                                  Miscellaneous pamphlets, Reports of the
                                                  Committee</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Illinois Committee on Social Legislation;
                                                  Miscellaneous pamphlets, Correspondence,
                                                  1912-13</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Illinois Committee on Social Legislation;
                                                  Miscellaneous pamphlets, 1914-17</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Illinois Committee on Social Legislation;
                                                  Miscellaneous pamphlets, drafts of legislation on
                                                  minimum wage</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Illinois Committee on Social Legislation;
                                                  Miscellaneous pamphlets, drafts of legislation on
                                                  regulation of messenger services; compensation of
                                                  prisoners' families; state colony for care of
                                                  epileptics and the feeble-minded; wage loans,
                                                  etc</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>Illinois Committee on Social Legislation;
                                                  Miscellaneous pamphlets, The Women's Legislative
                                                  Congress of Illinois, December 10-12,
                                                  1914</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
