<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.VEBLEN</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Thorstein Veblen Papers<date>1895-1930</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by EMS, 1992; MH, 2003</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Economics and Business</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by SV, 2006</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to the Thorstein Veblen Papers<date>1895-1930</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by EMS, 1992; MH, 2003</author>
      <p>© 2006 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Veblen, Thorstein. Papers</unittitle>
      <unitdate label="Dates" type="inclusive">1895-1930</unitdate>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English.</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">0.25 linear ft. (1 box)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">Thorstein Veblen, economist, writer, teacher.  The Thorstein Veblen Papers consist primarily of personal correspondence.  The collection also includes an off-print of the article, "Some Neglected Points in the Theory of Socialism," and notes titled "Spencer's Principles of Sociology (manuscript and typescript).</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <altformavail>
        <head>Digital Images</head>
        <p>Original documents, texts, and images represented by digital images linked to this finding aid are subject to U. S. copyright law. It is the user's sole responsibility to secure any necessary copyright permission to reproduce or publish documents, texts, and images from any holders of rights in the original materials.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library, in its capacity as owner of the physical property represented by the digital images linked to this finding aid, encourages the use of these materials for educational and scholarly purposes.  Any reproduction or publication from these digital images requires that the following credit line be included:  Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p>
        <p>Commercial publication projects require the permission of the University of Chicago Library and may be subject to a use fee. To order publication-quality reproductions, or for permission to copy or use any part of the digital images attached to this finding aid for any commercial purposes, please contact the Special Collections Research Center.</p>
        <p>The images presented here may include materials reflecting the attitudes, language, and stereotypes of an earlier time period. These materials are presented as historical resources in support of study and research. Inclusion of such materials does not constitute an endorsement of their content by the University of Chicago.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library appreciates hearing from anyone who may have information about any of the images in this collection.</p>
      </altformavail>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Veblen, Thorstein. Papers, [Box #, Folder #], Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Biographical Note</head>
        <p>Thorstein Veblen was born in 1857 in Cato, Wisconsin.  He received an A.B. from Carleton College (1880), and a Ph.D. from Yale University (1884).  Veblen was a fellow at Cornell University (1891-1892), and at the University of Chicago (1892-1893).
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Veblen remained at the University of Chicago as a reader in political economy (1893-1894). He became associate professor at the University (1894-1896), instructor (1896-1900), and assistant professor (1900-1906).  From 1906 to 1909, Veblen was associate professor of economics at Stanford University.  Upon leaving Stanford, he worked as a lecturer in economics at the University of Missouri (1911-1918).  He co-founded the New School for Social Research in 1919, lecturing there until 1926.  Veblen also served as the managing editor for the Journal of Political Economy from 1896 to 1905.
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Veblen published many books, of which the best known is The Theory of the Leisure Class: An Economic Study in the Evolution of Institutions (1899).  The book did not become highly regarded among academics until after Veblen's death.  Some of Veblen's other published works include: The Instinct of Workmanship and the State of the Industrial Arts (1914), Imperial Germany and the Industrial Revolution (1915), and An Inquiry Into the Nature of Peace and the Terms of Its Perpetuation (1917). Several collections of Veblen's work were published posthumously, including: Essays in Our Changing Order (1934), and What Veblen Taught: Selected Writings of Thorstein Veblen (1936).  Veblen is also the subject of many books.  
</p>
        <p>
</p>
        <p>Thorstein Veblen died in 1929.
</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The Thorstein Veblen Papers consist of primarily of personal correspondence.  The collection also includes an off-print of the article, "Some Neglected Points in the Theory of Socialism," and notes titled "Spencer's Principles of Sociology (manuscript and typescript).</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/scrc/findingaids/topics.php">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Veblen, Thorstein, 1857-1929</persname>
        <subject>Economic-United States-History</subject>
        <subject>Sociology-United States-History</subject>
        <geogname>United States-Social Conditions</geogname>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">1</container>
          <unittitle>Correspondence, 1895-1930</unittitle>
          <daogrp>
            <resource label="start"/>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/veblen-001-001" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View digitized documents.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
          </daogrp>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">2</container>
          <unittitle>Article and Notes, undated</unittitle>
          <note>
            <list>
              <item>Off-print, "Some Neglected Points in the Theory of Socialism"</item>
              <item>Notes, "Spencer's Principles of Sociology"</item>
            </list>
          </note>
          <daogrp>
            <resource label="start"/>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/veblen-001-002" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View digitized documents.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
          </daogrp>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
