<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.MS155</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to <emph render="italic">Homilies and Religious Treatises,</emph> Manuscript,<date>early 15th century</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by KEF, 2019</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Early Western Manuscripts (pre-1700)</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Religion and Theology</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KEF, 2019</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to <emph render="italic">Homilies and Religious Treatises,</emph> Manuscript,<date>early 15th century</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by KEF, 2019</author>
      <p>© 2019 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title"><emph render="italic">Homilies and Religious Treatises.</emph>  Manuscript (Ms 155)</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" label="Dates">early 15th century</unitdate>
      <unitid type="inclusive" label="MS_No">Codex Ms 155</unitid>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>Latin</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">1 volume, 19 x 14 cm.</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">A compilation of miscellaneous sermons and religious treatises, written in a single hand on Italian paper. Includes: Commendatio de vita solitaria by St. Pietro Damiani; 51 homilies of St. Augustine; several short sermons by St. Ephraim of Syria; anonymous essays on the virtues and seven mortal sins; a life of St. Hieronymus by St. Cyril; a treatise entitled Meditatione; and a fragment of De institutione novitiorum by Hugo of St. Victor. Text in Latin. Codex Ms 155.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The manuscript is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <altformavail>
        <head>Digital Images</head>
        <p>Original documents, texts, and images represented by digital images linked to this finding aid are subject to U. S. copyright law. It is the user's sole responsibility to secure any necessary copyright permission to reproduce or publish documents, texts, and images from any holders of rights in the original materials.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library, in its capacity as owner of the physical property represented by the digital images linked to this finding aid, encourages the use of these materials for educational and scholarly purposes.  Any reproduction or publication from these digital images requires that the following credit line be included:  Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p>
        <p>Commercial publication projects require the permission of the University of Chicago Library and may be subject to a use fee. To order publication-quality reproductions, or for permission to copy or use any part of the digital images attached to this finding aid for any commercial purposes, please contact the Special Collections Research Center.</p>
        <p>The images presented here may include materials reflecting the attitudes, language, and stereotypes of an earlier time period. These materials are presented as historical resources in support of study and research. Inclusion of such materials does not constitute an endorsement of their content by the University of Chicago.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library appreciates hearing from anyone who may have information about any of the images in this collection.</p>
      </altformavail>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from this collection, the preferred citation is: <emph render="italic">Homilies and Religious Treatises.</emph> Manuscript,  Codex Ms 155, Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The manuscript is in quarto format and consists of 228 leaves of coarse thick paper with several watermarks ( e.g. fols. 60, 81, 129, 151, 166, 168). Text is rubricated and written in two columns by one hand, except for the Latin hymns on fols. 226-228, written in a later hand.</p>
        <p>The subdivisions of the text are:</p>
        <list>
          <item>I. St. Pietro Damiani, “Commendatio de vita solitaria,” fols. 1-3</item>
          <item>II.	St. Augustine, 51 homilies, fols. 3-128</item>
          <item>III.	St. Ephraim of Syria, short sermons including “De beatitude animarum,” “De praemiis beatorum,” “De paenitentia,” “De die Judicii,” “De computatione,” “De virginitate animae,” and “Oratio,” fols. 129-157</item>
          <item>IV.	Anonymous, “De virtutibus” and “De septem vitiis principalibus,” fols. 158-172</item>
          <item>V.	St. Cyril, Bishop of Jerusalem, “De miraculis S. Hieronymi,” fols. 173-194</item>
          <item>VI.	Ps.-St. Bernard of Clairvaux, “Meditatione,” fols. 196-218</item>
          <item>VII.	Hugo of St. Victor, “De institutione novitiorum” chapters 1-11, fols. 218-225</item>
          <item>VIII.	Texts of a few Latin hymns in a later hand, fols. 226-228</item>
        </list>
        <p>
          <extref href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/ewm-0155-desc">Additional description</extref>
        </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="https://www.lib.uchicago.edu/h/ead-topic-browse">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Jerome, Saint, -419 or 420</persname>
        <persname>Cyril, Saint, Bishop of Jerusalem, approximately 315-386</persname>
        <persname>Peter Damian, Saint, 1007?-1072</persname>
        <persname>Ephraem, Syrus, Saint, 303-373</persname>
        <persname>Augustine, of Hippo, Saint, 354-430</persname>
        <genreform>Manuscripts, Latin (Medieval and modern)</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="volume">1</container>
          <unittitle>Codex Ms 155</unittitle>
          <daogrp>
            <resource label="start"/>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/ewm-0155-01" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View cover (front)-fol. 57r.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/ewm-0155-02" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View fols. 57v-117r.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/ewm-0155-03" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View fols. 117v-177r.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/ewm-0155-04" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View fols. 177v-cover (back.)</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
          </daogrp>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
