<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.MS798</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to Jean Marie Cahusac, <emph render="italic">Lettres de Mr. Cahusac, Américain, Juge de Paix à Fleurance,</emph>  Manuscript,<date>1806-1836</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by MP, 2019</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Politics, Public Policy and Political Reform</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>Latin America</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KEF, 2019</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to Jean Marie Cahusac, <emph render="italic">Lettres de Mr. Cahusac, Américain, Juge de Paix à Fleurance,</emph>  Manuscript,<date>1806-1836</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by KEF, 2019</author>
      <p>© 2019 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Cahusac, Jean Marie, <emph render="italic">Lettres de Mr. Cahusac, Américain, Juge de Paix à Fleurance.</emph> Manuscript (Ms 798)</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" label="Dates">1806-1836</unitdate>
      <unitid type="inclusive" label="MS_No">Codex Ms 798</unitid>
      <langmaterial>Documents in 
          <language>French</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">1 volume, 22 x 18 cm.</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">Copies of 94 pieces of correspondence and other documents concerning the travels of Cahusac to the United States, Guadalupe, St. Thomas, and Haiti. Text in French. Codex Ms 798.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The manuscript is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <altformavail>
        <head>Digital Images</head>
        <p>Original documents, texts, and images represented by digital images linked to this finding aid are subject to U. S. copyright law. It is the user's sole responsibility to secure any necessary copyright permission to reproduce or publish documents, texts, and images from any holders of rights in the original materials.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library, in its capacity as owner of the physical property represented by the digital images linked to this finding aid, encourages the use of these materials for educational and scholarly purposes.  Any reproduction or publication from these digital images requires that the following credit line be included:  Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p>
        <p>Commercial publication projects require the permission of the University of Chicago Library and may be subject to a use fee. To order publication-quality reproductions, or for permission to copy or use any part of the digital images attached to this finding aid for any commercial purposes, please contact the Special Collections Research Center.</p>
        <p>The images presented here may include materials reflecting the attitudes, language, and stereotypes of an earlier time period. These materials are presented as historical resources in support of study and research. Inclusion of such materials does not constitute an endorsement of their content by the University of Chicago.</p>
        <p>The University of Chicago Library appreciates hearing from anyone who may have information about any of the images in this collection.</p>
      </altformavail>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Wigmore Abbey chronicle and Brut chronicle. Manuscript,  Codex Ms 798, Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>
          The manuscript is assembled in quarto format with 136 paper leaves in a half-vellum binding with marbled boards. Each page is ruled with 24 lines. The text is written by one hand in brown ink. Each item is numbered in a red pencil which has also annotated letter 33 (on fol. 50r). 17 of the items are marked by bookmarks inserted by a later owner, with brief notes in French about the contents of the marked items.
        </p>
        <p> </p>
        <p>
          The text consists of 94 items, mostly copies letters written or received by Jean Marie Cahusac. The items are organized chronologically with dates ranging from August 30, 1806 to July 7, 1836. The contents include accounts of Cahusac's travels throughout Europe, the United States, and the French West Indies; Cahusac's opinions on governance and religion in those regions; personal letters to family members and friends; petitions to political figures, including notably the Marquis de La Fayette; and finally, a letter to King Louis Philippe.
        </p>
        <p> </p>
        <p>Title page (1r) </p>
        <p>
          1: Fleurance, le 30 aout, 1806. à Mr. Darbas, à New York (états-unis D’amérique.) (2r-3v)
        </p>
        <p>
          2: 9 Novembre, 1807. à Gregoire Cabusac, mon frere, élève de L’école Polytechnique, à Paris. (4r-6r)
        </p>
        <p>3: 10 Mars, 1808. au Même. (6v-8r) </p>
        <p>4: 25 Juillet, 1808. au Même. (8r-10r) </p>
        <p>
          5: Septembre, 1808. Lettre écrite pour mon père, à son excellence le comte de Cessac, ministre d’état, Gouverneur de l’école impériale Polytechnique, à Paris. (10v-11r)
        </p>
        <p>
          6: 28 Octobre, 1808. Lettre écrite pour mon Frère, élève de l’école Polytechnique, à Monsieur Romieu, professeur des mathématiques au Licée de Toulouse. (11v-12r)
        </p>
        <p>
          7: 14 Novembre, 1808. Lettre écrite pour le même, à Son excellence Le Comte de Cessac, ministre D’état, Gouverneur de L’école Polytechnique, à Paris. (12v-13v)
        </p>
        <p>
          8: Décembre, 1808. Lettre écrite pour le même, à Mr. Romieu, professeur de mathématiques, au Lycée de Toulouse. (14r-14v)
        </p>
        <p>
          9: 29 Mars, 1809. Lettre écrite pour mon père, à son excellence le comte de Cessac, ministre d’état, Gouverneur de l’école impériale Polytechnique. (14v-15v)
        </p>
        <p>10: Juillet, 1809. au Même. (16r) </p>
        <p>
          11: 1er aout, 1809. à Monsieur le Conseiller d’état, Directeur Général de la Caille D’amortissement, à Paris. (17v)
        </p>
        <p>
          12: Novembre, 1810. à Monsieur le receveur des Domaines Nationaux, à auets. (18r-19v)
        </p>
        <p>
          13: 19 octobre, 1812. à Monsieur Lébe, négociant, à Bordeaux. (20r-20v)
        </p>
        <p>
          14: 6 février, 1813. à Monsieur Le Greffier de la Justice de Paix du Canton de Sr. Marlory. (20v-21v)
        </p>
        <p>
          15: 4 mars, 1813. à Monsieur Durban, Négociant à Charlestown, Caroline du Sud, états-unis D’amérique. (22r-23r)
        </p>
        <p>
          16: Aout, 1813. à Made. Vignolles, ma belle Sœur, à Sa Campagne de Bordères. (23r-24v)
        </p>
        <p>17: 27 Decembre, 1813. à D. P. (25r-25v) </p>
        <p>
          18: 1er mai, 1814. à Mr. Lébe, négt. à Bordeaux. (26r-28r)
        </p>
        <p>
          19: 9 Septembre, 1814. Pétition adressée à MM. Le Président et les Membres de la Chambre des Députés des Départemens, à Paris. (28r-29r)
        </p>
        <p>
          20: 16 octobre, 1814. à Monsieur Raynouard, membre de L’institut, et de La Chambre des Députés des Départemens, à Paris. (29v-32r)
        </p>
        <p>
          21: Rapport de Mr. Rigaud de Lisle, au Nom de la commission des Pétitions de la chambre des Députés, sur la Pétition des Citoyens de Fleurance du 9 Sep'bre dernier. Séance du VI Novembre 1814. (32r-33r)
        </p>
        <p>
          22: Janvier, 1815. à Monsieur Le Procureur du Roi près le Tribunal civil du W. arrond. à Lectoure. (33v-36r)
        </p>
        <p>23: 1er février, 1815. au Même. (36r-37r) </p>
        <p>
          24: Décision de Monseigneur Le Chancelier de France. (37r)
        </p>
        <p>
          25: mai, 1815. Observations indéxées par moi à la Suite de mon Vôte sur L'acte additionnel aux constitutions de L'empire, présenté, le 22 avril dernier, à L'acceptation du Peuple Français. (37v-38r)
        </p>
        <p>
          26: aôut, 1815. à Monsieur Rouquette, négociant, a La Nouvelle Orléans. (Louisiana.) (38r-40r)
        </p>
        <p>
          27: octobre, 1816. au Même. [A note at the bottom of 42r explains that the writer found out after sending this letter that its intended recipient had drowned himself in the Mississippi River.] (40r-42r)
        </p>
        <p>
          28: 31 Juillet 1817. Pétition à Monsieur Le Préfet du Département du Gers. (Mr. de Lascours.) (42v-44r)
        </p>
        <p>
          29: 15 mai, 1819. à Mon Neveu Lassale, à Bordeaux. (44v-47r)
        </p>
        <p>
          30: 25 Janvier, 1820. Pétition à la Chambre des Députés des Départemens, à Paris. (47v-49r)
        </p>
        <p>
          31: 25 Janvier, 1820. à Monsieur Le Marquis de Lafayette, membre de la Chambre des Deputés, à Paris. (49v-50r)
        </p>
        <p>
          32: 25 Janvier, 1820. à Monsieur Le Exacteur du Constitutionnel, à Paris. (50v-51r)
        </p>
        <p>
          33: Copie de La Lettre que m'a écrite Mr. de Lafayette, membre de La Chambre des Députés, au Sujet de La Pétition que je lui adressai le 25 Janvier dernier. Paris, la 13 février, 1820. [The note preceding the date is underlined in red pencil with a note that reads, "inédit"] (50r-50v)
        </p>
        <p>
          34: 30 Juillet, 1820. Lettre écrite pour ma femme à Made. Vignolles, Sa Sœur, à Sa Campagne de Bordères. (51r-52v)
        </p>
        <p>
          35: 15 aout, 1822. à Monsieur Le Curé de Brugnens. (52v-53v)
        </p>
        <p>
          36: 18 février, 1824. à Monsieur Percin, à Fleurance. (54r-54v)
        </p>
        <p>Quatre Lettres écrites de Bordeaux. (55r) </p>
        <p>37: 1re Lettre, du 7 mai, 1824. (55r-56r) </p>
        <p>38: 2e Lettre, du 13 mai, 1824. (56v-57v) </p>
        <p>39: 3e Lettre, du 21 mai, 1824. (58r-60r) </p>
        <p>
          40: 4e et dernière Lettre de Bord.x du 25 mai, 1824. (60r-62v)
        </p>
        <p>
          41: 6 Juillet, 1825. à Monsieur Momejean, prêtre, ancien curé constitutionnel, retire à Fleurance. (63r-65v)
        </p>
        <p>
          42: 3 octobre, 1825. à Monsieur Moliés, conseiller à la cour royale D'agen. (65v-67r)
        </p>
        <p>
          43: D.bre 1825. à Monsieur Le Préfet du Département du Gers. (67r-68v)
        </p>
        <p>
          44: 14 Janvier, 1826. à Monsieur Le Vicomte de Suseau, Sous Préfet du 2e. arrondissement, à Lecloure. (69r-70v)
        </p>
        <p>
          45: 12 mai, 1826. à Madame de Panebeuf, à Brechan. (71r-72r)
        </p>
        <p>46: 14 mai, 1826. à La Même. (72v-73v) </p>
        <p>
          47: 16 mai, 1826. à Monsieur Le Comte de Lary Latour (74r-74v)
        </p>
        <p>
          48: 7 Janvier, 1827. à Monsieur Molié, conseiller à la cour Royale D'agen. (74v-76r)
        </p>
        <p>
          49: Janvier, 1827. à Monsieur Le Curé Moméjean, à Fleurance. (76v-77r)
        </p>
        <p>
          50: 10 aout, 1828. à Monsieur Molié, conseiller à la cour Royale D'agen. (77v-78r)
        </p>
        <p>
          51: Belair, le 22 Juillet, 1829. à Monsieur Le Juge de paix du Canton de Fleurance. (78v-79r)
        </p>
        <p>
          52: Septembre, 1829. Pétition à Monsieur Le Préfet du Département du Gers. (79v-80r)
        </p>
        <p>
          53: 21 octobre, 1829. à Madame Neuve Vignolles, à Bordeaux. (80r-82r)
        </p>
        <p>54: 3 Novembre, 1829. à La Même. (82v-84r) </p>
        <p>55. 13 Novembre, 1829. à La Même. (84v-86v) </p>
        <p>56. 24 Décembre 1929. à La Même. (86v-88r) </p>
        <p>57. 10 Janvier, 1830. à La Même. (88r-90r) </p>
        <p>58. 29 Janvier, 1830. à La Même. (90r-91v) </p>
        <p>59. 4 mars, 1830. à La Même. (92r-95r) </p>
        <p>60. 8 mars, 1830. à La Même. (95v-97v) </p>
        <p>
          61. 5 Septembre 1830. à Monsieur Le Général Lafayette, Commandant Général des Gardes Nationalles de France. (97-99r)
        </p>
        <p>
          62. 7 Septembre, 1830. Pétition que j'ai été chargé de rédiger et qui a été adressée à Messieurs Le Président et Les Membres de la Chambre des Députés de France, à Paris. (99v-101r)
        </p>
        <p>
          63. 13 Septembre, 1830. à Mr. Le Garde des Sceaux, ministre Secrétaire D'état au Département de la Justice, à Paris. [The text on fols. 101v and 102r is crossed out, and fols. 101 and 102 have been stuck together with a red adhesive. They remain partially stuck together and torn.]. (101r-103r)
        </p>
        <p>
          64: 20 Novembre, 1830. à Monsieur Bouet, juge d'instruction près le Tribunal du 2e arrondissement, à Lectoure. (103v-104r)
        </p>
        <p>65: 30 Novembre, 1830. au Même. (104v-106r) </p>
        <p>
          66: 4 Mars, 1831. à Monsieur Le Maire de la ville de Fleurance, président du Bureau de Bienfaisance du Canton de Fleurance. (106r-107v)
        </p>
        <p>
          67: 27 mai, 1831. à Monsieur Le ministre des finances, à Paris. (108r)
        </p>
        <p>
          68: 11 juin, 1831. à Monsieur Bouet, juge d'instruction à Lectoure. (108v-109r)
        </p>
        <p>
          69: 27 juillet, 1831. Le Commissaire ordonnateur du Bureau de Bienfaisance du Canton de Fleurance. à Monsieur Le Maire de la ville de Fleurance, président du dit Bureau. (109v-110r)
        </p>
        <p>
          70: 4 aout, 1831. à Monsieur L'administrateur du Trésor royal, chargé de la Direction des Cautionnemens. (110v)
        </p>
        <p>
          71: 29 octobre 1831. à Monsieur Le Commandant de La Garde Nationale de Fleurance. (111r)
        </p>
        <p>
          72: 11 Janvier 1832. à Monsieur Vignolles, neveu, à Bordeaux. (111v-112v)
        </p>
        <p>
          73: 17 mars, 1832. à Monsieur Le Maire de la ville de Fleurance, Président du Bureau de Bienfaisance. (113r-114r)
        </p>
        <p>
          74: 12 octobre, 1832. à Monsieur Morlau, mon beau père, au St. Puy. (114v-115r)
        </p>
        <p>
          75: 19 octobre 1832. à Monsieur Morlau, mon beau père, au St. Puy. (115v-117r)
        </p>
        <p>
          76: Janvier 1833. à Monsieur Morlau, mon beau père, au St. Puy. (117v-119v)
        </p>
        <p>
          77: 28 fevrier, 1833. à Monsieur Justin Moli, agent de change, à Condons. (119v-122r)
        </p>
        <p>78: 8 avril, 1833. au Même. (122r-123r) </p>
        <p>
          79: 1er Juillet, 1834. à Monsieur Bouet, juge d'instruction, à Lectoure. (123r-124r)
        </p>
        <p>
          80: 2 aout, 1834. à Madame Bouet, à Lectoure. (124r-124v)
        </p>
        <p>
          81: 6 aôut, 1834. à Monsieur Bouet, juge d'instruction, à Lectoure. (125r)
        </p>
        <p>
          82: 6 aôut 1834. à Monsieur Le Procureur du Roi près le Tribunal de Lectoure. (125v)
        </p>
        <p>
          83: 8 aôut, 1834. à Monsieur Sylvain Dupuy, à Fleurance. (126r)
        </p>
        <p>
          84: 12 aôut, 1834. à Monsieur Drouillard, à Condons. (126v)
        </p>
        <p>
          85: 17 Septembre, 1834. à Monsieur Vignolles, neveu, Négociant à Bordeaux. (127r-128r)
        </p>
        <p>
          86: 30 Septembre, 1834. à Monsieur Drouillard, à Condons. (128r-129r)
        </p>
        <p>
          87: 30 Septembre, 1834. à Monsieur Bouet, juge d'instruction, à Lectoure. (129r-130r)
        </p>
        <p>
          88: 11 octobre, 1834. à Madame Bouet, à Lectoure. (130r-131r)
        </p>
        <p>
          89: Discours prononcé, à ma première audience de Juge de Paix, le 11 aôut 1834, aux Justiciables présents à la de. audience. (131v-132r)
        </p>
        <p>
          90: 12 Janvier, 1835. à Monsieur Vignolles, neveu, négt. à Bordeaux. (132v-133r)
        </p>
        <p>
          91: 1er Juin, 1835. à Mr. Vignolles Neveu, Négt. à Bordeaux. (133v-134v)
        </p>
        <p>92: 23 Janvier, 1836. au Même. (134v-135r) </p>
        <p>
          93: 28 février 1836. à Madame Neuve Vignolles, à Bordeaux. (135v-136r)
        </p>
        <p>
          94: 7 Juillet, 1836. adresse à Sa Majesté Louis Philippe, roi des Francais. (136r-136v)
        </p>
        <p>
          <extref href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/ewm-0798-desc">Additional description</extref>
        </p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="https://www.lib.uchicago.edu/h/ead-topic-browse">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Cahusac, Jean Marie, b. 1779?</persname>
        <geogname>United States -- Description and travel</geogname>
        <geogname>West Indies, French -- Description and travel</geogname>
        <geogname>Lesser Antilles -- West Indies, French</geogname>
        <genreform>Manuscripts, French</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="volume">1</container>
          <unittitle>Codex Ms 798</unittitle>
          <daogrp>
            <resource label="start"/>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/ewm-0798-01" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View manuscript, part 1.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/ewm-0798-02" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View manuscript, part 2.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/ewm-0798-03" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View manuscript, part 3.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <daoloc label="image" href="http://pi.lib.uchicago.edu/1001/scrc/md/ewm-0798-bookmarks" role="application/pdf">
              <daodesc>
                <p>View bookmarks.</p>
              </daodesc>
            </daoloc>
            <arc from="start" to="image" show="new" actuate="onrequest"/>
          </daogrp>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
