<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.IHOUSECOUNCIL</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the University of Chicago International House Council Records<date>1959-1984</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by EMS, 1992; RG, 2002</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject>University of Chicago - Student Life and Athletics</subject>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KEF, 2006</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to the University of Chicago International House Council Records<date>1959-1984</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by EMS, 1992; RG, 2002</author>
      <p>© 2007 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">University of Chicago. International House Council.  Records</unittitle>
      <unitdate label="Dates" type="inclusive">1959-1984</unitdate>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">0.5 linear feet (1 box)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">The International House Council Records consist of minutes of Council meetings (1970-1972), copies of the Chicago Compass, International House Board of Governors minutes (1959-1973), correspondence, memoranda, and other records of the Council.</abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: University of Chicago. International House Council.  Records, [Box #, Folder #], Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library</p>
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Historical Note</head>
        <p>International House at the University of Chicago was constructed in 1932 at 1414 East 59th Street through the support of John D. Rockefeller, Jr.  His hope was “to promote international understanding and friendship of the people of Chicago and the Middle West towards nations and cultures other than their own.”  The co-educational residence was designed by Holabird and Roche, and built out of Indiana limestone in the gothic style.  It could house over 500 students and was administered by a Board of Governors consisting of members of the faculty and representatives of the Chicago business community. </p>
        <p>The idea for International House began in 1910 at Columbia University through the work of Harry E. Edmonds.  International Houses were built in New York (1924); Berkeley, California (1930); Boston, and Paris.  The goals of International House were (1) to provide educational facilities for students of different nationalities and races, (2) to promote understanding and friendship among students of diverse national, cultural, and social backgrounds, and (3) to serve as a cultural facility for the foreign students at the University of Chicago and other educational institutions in the Chicago area.</p>
        <p>Members of the International House organized dances, film festivals, lecture series, debates, and forums.  The International House Council at the University of Chicago was one of the governing bodies of International House, along with the Board of Governors and the Senate.</p>
        <p>The majority of the papers in this collection concern events of the early 1970s.  In the spring of 1971 I-House announced the firing of part of its maid staff in an effort to economize.  This led to active student protests, including picketing, and a call for more student participation in I-House budget-making.  This led to the formation of the I-House Senate, which was composed of the I-House Governors and the I-House Council.  Moreover, this event led to student membership on I-House Governors Committees, student attendance at I-House Governors meetings, increased budgets for activities such as film festivals, and a preservation of I-House cafeteria service.  In the winter of 1972 students passed a referendum for co-ed housing, which was resisted by some students and led to changes in the amount of power given to I-House Council.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The International House Council Records consist of minutes of Council meetings (1970-1972), copies of the Chicago Compass, International House Board of Governors minutes (1959-1973), correspondence, memoranda, and other records of the Council.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/scrc/findingaids/topics.php">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <corpname>University of Chicago -- History</corpname>
        <corpname>University of Chicago -- Administration</corpname>
        <corpname>University of Chicago -- Graduate students</corpname>
        <corpname>University of Chicago -- Student housing</corpname>
        <corpname>University of Chicago -- Students</corpname>
        <corpname>International House (Chicago, Ill.). Council</corpname>
        <corpname>International House (Chicago, Ill.). Board of Governors</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">1</container>
          <unittitle>Constitution of International House, 1970</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">2</container>
          <unittitle>Council Minutes, 1971-1972</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">3</container>
          <unittitle>Council Social Events</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">4</container>
          <unittitle>Council correspondence and referenda</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">5</container>
          <unittitle>Board of Governors minutes</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">6</container>
          <unittitle>Resident Protest materials</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">7</container>
          <unittitle>Chicago Compass, 1971-1974</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">8</container>
          <unittitle>Senate materials, 1972-1973</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">9</container>
          <unittitle>Lists of residents, 1972, 1974</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
      <c>
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">10</container>
          <unittitle>miscellaneous</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
