<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader audience="internal">
    <eadid>ICU.SPCL.LANDAHL</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the Karen Landahl Papers<date>1940-2004</date></titleproper>
        <author>Finding aid prepared by SR, 2017; AG 2017</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p>
        </note>
        <note>
          <p>
            <subject/>
          </p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by AG, 2017</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter audience="external">
    <titlepage>
      <publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
      <titleproper>Guide to the Karen Landahl Papers<date>1940-2004</date></titleproper>
      <author>Finding aid prepared by SR, 2017; AG 2017</author>
      <p>© 2017 University of Chicago Library</p>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head>Descriptive Summary</head>
      <unittitle label="Title">Landahl, Karen. Papers</unittitle>
      <unitdate label="Dates" type="inclusive">1940-2004</unitdate>
      <langmaterial>Documents in <language>English</language></langmaterial>
      <physdesc label="Size">25 linear feet (50 boxes)</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository">
        <address>
          <addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
          <addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
          <addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
          <addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract">Karen Landahl (1951-2003) was a linguist who taught at the University of Chicago, in the Department of Linguistics, from 1982 to 2003. She was also the Academic Director of the Language Labs and Archives and the Language Faculty Resource Center, and the Associate Dean for Computing and Language Technologies at the University. The materials in this collection include teaching materials for the courses she taught, a range of academic papers on various topics in the field of linguistics and speech pathology, and material related to her own research on early language development, craniofacial anomalies, and Japanese phonetics. This collection would be of interest to researchers interested in developments in the field of linguistics and communications disorders between 1980 and 2000. </abstract>
    </did>
    <descgrp>
      <head>Information on Use</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access</head>
        <p>The collection is open for research, with the exception of material in Series IX, Restricted. This series contains restricted personnel and financial information, grant proposals with social security numbers, evaluative student material, and medical information. Materials in Box 38 are restricted for 50 years from date of record creation. Materials in Box 39 are restricted for 80 years from date of record creation. Materials in Boxes 40-50 are restricted indefinitely.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Citation</head>
        <p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Landahl, Karen. Papers, [Box #, Folder #], Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p>
      </prefercite>
      <bioghist>
        <head>Biographical Note</head>
        <p>Karen Landahl was born on December 20, 1951, to John and Betty Landahl of Tinley Park, Illinois. Her family moved to Flossmoor in 1960, where she attended Homewood-Flossmoor High School. Upon graduation she studied at St. Olaf College, spending her junior year in Oxford. She earned her B.A. in Linguistics in 1974. In 1976 she received an M.A. and in 1982 a Ph.D. from Brown University, both in Linguistics. Her dissertation was entitled "The Onset of Structured Discourse: A Developmental Study of the Acquisition of Language." She examined how five children learned to speak through interactions with parents and caretakers and presented a major challenge to the dominant theories of Noam Chomsky and Steven Pinker. According to her dissertation advisor, Philip Lieberman, Professor of Linguistics at Brown University, she was one of the first people to show that children have different styles of acquiring language.&#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>While working on her dissertation she pursued a second major area of interest as a consultant and a collaborative researcher in Chicago at the Center for Craniofacial Anomalies at the University of Illinois Medical Center. Her work here focused on the effects of Crouzon and Apert syndromes on speech production.&#13;</p>
        <p>Following a National Science Foundation Postdoctoral Fellowship in Speech Communications at MIT in 1981-2, she returned to Illinois and took a position as an assistant professor at the University of Chicago.  &#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>At the University of Chicago she worked on the connections between phonetics, computers, and language learning. In the 1990s, with her student Yukari Hirata, she researched the use of the Visipitch software program in language learning. With this program, students could watch how pitch rises and falls when a native speaks a language, and then learn to imitate it. Landahl had a wide variety of other linguistic interests, including the study of linguistic "others" such as feral children, sign-language using chimps and humans without tongues or with cleft palates, and the origins of human language. &#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>She was diagnosed with cancer in 2000 and her illness rendered her unable to speak. As a result, she moved from classroom teaching to spearhead a program in educational technology as Associate Dean for Computing and Language Technologies. Here she used her knowledge of speech perception and production to become a leader in the use of computers in language teaching.&#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>She died on February 2, 2003.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent>
        <head>Scope Note</head>
        <p>The collection is organized into nine series, and span the period 1940-2004. The bulk of the collection dates from 1970 to 1990. &#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>Series I, Personal, contains a partial copy of Landahl's curriculum vitae and cartoon clippings.&#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>Series II, Correspondence, contains a small collection of personal and professional correspondence. Materials are arranged alphabetically by correspondent.&#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>Series III, Research, contains materials related to Landahl's research activities. This series is organized into five subseries:&#13;</p>
        <p>Subseries I, Child Language Development, contains materials related to early language development and Landahl's doctoral dissertation project. This subseries contains transcripts of speech samples, as well as statistical analysis.&#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>Subseries II, Craniofacial Anomalies, contains materials connected to Landahl's work at the Center for Craniofacial Anomalies at the University of Illinois Medical Center. &#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>Subseries III, Japan Visipitch Research Project, contains materials relating to Landahl's study of the use of computers to teach Japanese phonemes and intonation. The bulk of this subseries is made up of tabulated data from research subjects.&#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>Subseries IV, General, contains unlabeled and miscellaneous research materials and notes, as well as materials from several smaller projects on glossectomy, teaching Norwegian, and aprodosia. &#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>Subseries V, Index Cards, contains several card files of index cards. These contain notes on dialectical variations, a phonology and phonetics glossary, as well as cue cards from research projects.   &#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>Series IV, Writing, contains photocopies and reprints of articles and chapters authored or co-authored by Landahl. Materials are arranged chronologically.&#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>Series V, Writings by Others, contains photocopies and reprints of a range of academic papers on various topics in the field of linguistics and speech pathology. These include early language development, glossectomy, acoustic perception, and foreign language learning. Materials are arranged alphabetically by author.&#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>Series VI, Professional Activities, contains materials related to Landahl's participation in workshops and conferences. Materials are arranged chronologically.&#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>Series VII, Teaching, contains materials connected to Landahl's teaching career at the University of Chicago. The series contains syllabi, copies of reading materials, lab assignments and instructions, and ungraded student work. Materials are arranged chronologically, with general files of photocopied readings gathered at the end of the series.&#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>Series VIII, Oversize, contains two folders of enlarged research data. &#13;</p>
        <p>&#13;</p>
        <p>Series IX, Restricted, contains restricted personnel and financial information, grant proposals with social security numbers, evaluative student material, and medical information. Materials in Box 38 are restricted for 50 years from date of record creation. Materials in Box 39 are restricted for 80 years from date of record creation. Materials in Boxes 40-50 are restricted indefinitely.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <relatedmaterial>
        <head>Related Resources</head>
        <p>
          <archref>
            <extref href="https://www.lib.uchicago.edu/h/ead-topic-browse">Browse finding aids by topic.</extref>
          </archref>
        </p>
        <archref>
          <unittitle>Language Laboratories and Archives. Records.&#13;</unittitle>
        </archref>
        <archref>
          <unittitle>McQuown, Norman A., Papers</unittitle>
        </archref>
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subject Headings</head>
        <persname>Landahl, Karen Louise, 1951-</persname>
        <corpname>University of Chicago. Department of Linguistics</corpname>
        <subject>Apert's syndrome&#13;</subject>
        <subject>Crouzon's disease&#13;</subject>
        <subject>Craniofacial dysostosis&#13;</subject>
        <subject>Language acquisition&#13;</subject>
        <subject>Language acquisition--Computer-assisted learning&#13;</subject>
        <subject>Language acquisition--Testing&#13;</subject>
        <subject>Linguistics</subject>
      </controlaccess>
    </descgrp>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>INVENTORY</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series I: Personal </unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Curriculum Vitae (Partial), October, 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Cartoon Clippings, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series II: Correspondence</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>ASHA Convention, June-August, 1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Farley, Anne, 1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>General (Professional), 1978-2002</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Hemphill, Rachel, 1996</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Lieberman, Philip, 1977</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>NATO Advanced Study Institute, 1988</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Peterson-Falzone, Sally, 1977-1980</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Speech Research Workshop, 1998-1999</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Public Computing, University of Chicago, 1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series III: Research </unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Subseries I: Early Child Language Development</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">1</container>
              <container type="folder">12</container>
              <unittitle>PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Statistical Information and Analysis Notes, circa 1977-1979</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">1</container>
              <container type="folder">13</container>
              <unittitle>PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Transcripts - "Anna", 52-103 weeks, 1978-1979</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">1</container>
              <container type="folder">14</container>
              <unittitle>PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Transcripts - "Damien", 52-103 weeks, 1978-1979</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">2</container>
              <container type="folder">1</container>
              <unittitle>PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Transcripts - "Duff", 53-104 weeks, 1979-1980 [1/3]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">2</container>
              <container type="folder">2</container>
              <unittitle>PhD Dissertation, Brown University – Transcripts – "Duff", 1979-1980 [2/3]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">2</container>
              <container type="folder">3</container>
              <unittitle>PhD Dissertation, Brown University – Transcripts – "Duff", 1979-1980 [3/3]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">2</container>
              <container type="folder">4</container>
              <unittitle>PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Transcripts - "Kate", 53-104 weeks, 1978-1979 [1/2]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">2</container>
              <container type="folder">5</container>
              <unittitle>PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Transcripts - "Kate", 53-104 weeks, 1978-1979 [1/2]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">2</container>
              <container type="folder">6</container>
              <unittitle>PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Transcripts - "Megan", 53-104 weeks, 1977-1978</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">2</container>
              <container type="folder">7</container>
              <unittitle>PhD Dissertation, Brown University - Transcripts - "Julia", 53-104 weeks, 1977-1978</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">3</container>
              <container type="folder">1</container>
              <unittitle>PhD Dissertation, Brown University – Phonemic Inventories, 1989</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Subseries II: Craniofacial Anomalies</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">3</container>
              <container type="folder">2</container>
              <unittitle>Apert study report - Draft fragments, 1979-1980</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">3</container>
              <container type="folder">3</container>
              <unittitle>Apert Crouzon – Proposal with Modifications, 1986-1987</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">3</container>
              <container type="folder">4</container>
              <unittitle>Apert Crouzon – Notes, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">3</container>
              <container type="folder">5</container>
              <unittitle>Apert Crouzon, Vocal Tract Modelling, Notebook, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">3</container>
              <container type="folder">6</container>
              <unittitle>"Tammy" – Spectograms, March, 1997</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">3</container>
              <container type="folder">7</container>
              <unittitle>"Rachel" – Spectograms, March, 1997</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">3</container>
              <container type="folder">8</container>
              <unittitle>"Joe" – Spectograms, March, 1997</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">3</container>
              <container type="folder">9</container>
              <unittitle>"Ken" – Spectograms, March, 1997</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">3</container>
              <container type="folder">10</container>
              <unittitle>Spectograms (Alba Type), undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">3</container>
              <container type="folder">11</container>
              <unittitle>Spectograms with Flashcards, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">3</container>
              <container type="folder">12</container>
              <unittitle>Spectograms and Notes, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">4</container>
              <container type="folder">1</container>
              <unittitle>Session Transcript with Utterance and Phoneme List, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">4</container>
              <container type="folder">2</container>
              <unittitle>Flashcards – Stops and Liquids, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">4</container>
              <container type="folder">3</container>
              <unittitle>"The Template" – undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">4</container>
              <container type="folder">4</container>
              <unittitle>Research Protocol Guide, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Subseries III: Japanese Language Learning</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">4</container>
              <container type="folder">5</container>
              <unittitle>Japanese Teaching Manuals, 1989-1990</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">4</container>
              <container type="folder">6</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Miscellaneous, 1989-1992</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">4</container>
              <container type="folder">7</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Spectograms, 1990-1992</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">4</container>
              <container type="folder">8</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Records, 1994</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">4</container>
              <container type="folder">9</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study - Bibliography, circa 1990</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">4</container>
              <container type="folder">10</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #112, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">4</container>
              <container type="folder">11</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #113, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">5</container>
              <container type="folder">1</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #114, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">5</container>
              <container type="folder">2</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #115, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">5</container>
              <container type="folder">3</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #122, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">5</container>
              <container type="folder">4</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #123, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">5</container>
              <container type="folder">5</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #124, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">5</container>
              <container type="folder">6</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #125, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">6</container>
              <container type="folder">1</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #131, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">6</container>
              <container type="folder">2</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #132, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">6</container>
              <container type="folder">3</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #133, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">6</container>
              <container type="folder">4</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #134, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">6</container>
              <container type="folder">5</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #135, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">6</container>
              <container type="folder">6</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #211, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">7</container>
              <container type="folder">1</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #212, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">7</container>
              <container type="folder">2</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #213, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">7</container>
              <container type="folder">3</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #214, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">7</container>
              <container type="folder">4</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #215, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">7</container>
              <container type="folder">5</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #222, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">7</container>
              <container type="folder">6</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #223, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">7</container>
              <container type="folder">7</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #224, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">7</container>
              <container type="folder">8</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #225, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">8</container>
              <container type="folder">1</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #226, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">8</container>
              <container type="folder">2</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #227, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">8</container>
              <container type="folder">3</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #231, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">8</container>
              <container type="folder">4</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #232, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">8</container>
              <container type="folder">5</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #233, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">8</container>
              <container type="folder">6</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #234, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">8</container>
              <container type="folder">7</container>
              <unittitle>Japan Visipitch Study – Subject #235, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">8</container>
              <container type="folder">8</container>
              <unittitle>Project Mayumi - Experiment Sound Files, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Subseries IV: General</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">9</container>
              <container type="folder">1</container>
              <unittitle>Midwest Clinical Phonology Meeting, Lincoln, Nebraska, 1987 [1/2]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">9</container>
              <container type="folder">2</container>
              <unittitle>Midwest Clinical Phonology Meeting, Lincoln, Nebraska, 1987 [2/2]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">9</container>
              <container type="folder">3</container>
              <unittitle>Glossectomy Project – Landahl and Karnell, 1987 [1/4]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">9</container>
              <container type="folder">4</container>
              <unittitle>Glossectomy Project – Landahl and Karnell, 1987 [2/4]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">9</container>
              <container type="folder">5</container>
              <unittitle>Glossectomy Project – Landahl and Karnell, 1973-1992 [3/4]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">9</container>
              <container type="folder">6</container>
              <unittitle>Glossectomy Project – Landahl and Karnell, 1973-1992 [4/4]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">10</container>
              <container type="folder">1</container>
              <unittitle>MacNorsk Project – Notes on Norwegian, undated [1/3]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">10</container>
              <container type="folder">2</container>
              <unittitle>MacNorsk Project – Notes on Norwegian, 1996-1997 [2/3]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">10</container>
              <container type="folder">3</container>
              <unittitle>MacNorsk Project – Notes on Norwegian, 1996-1997 [3/3]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">10</container>
              <container type="folder">4</container>
              <unittitle>MacNorsk Project, Interactive Norwegian, ScandiLingFest, 1992-1995</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">10</container>
              <container type="folder">5</container>
              <unittitle>General – Acoustics Data [1/2]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">10</container>
              <container type="folder">6</container>
              <unittitle>General – Acoustics Data [2/2]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">10</container>
              <container type="folder">7</container>
              <unittitle>General - Scatter Plots, A, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">11</container>
              <container type="folder">1</container>
              <unittitle>General - Scatter Plots, F, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">11</container>
              <container type="folder">2</container>
              <unittitle>General - Scatter Plots, G, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">11</container>
              <container type="folder">3</container>
              <unittitle>General - Scatter Plots, I, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">11</container>
              <container type="folder">4</container>
              <unittitle>General - Scatter Plots, J, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">11</container>
              <container type="folder">5</container>
              <unittitle>General - Scatter Plots, K, undated [1/3]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">11</container>
              <container type="folder">6</container>
              <unittitle>General - Scatter Plots, K, undated [2/3]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">11</container>
              <container type="folder">7</container>
              <unittitle>General - Scatter Plots, K, undated [3/3]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">11</container>
              <container type="folder">8</container>
              <unittitle>General - Scatter Plots, L, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">12</container>
              <container type="folder">1</container>
              <unittitle>General – Research data and Cluster Graphs, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">12</container>
              <container type="folder">2</container>
              <unittitle>General – Cluster Graphs, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">12</container>
              <container type="folder">3</container>
              <unittitle>General - Original Pitch Contours, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">12</container>
              <container type="folder">4</container>
              <unittitle>General – Scatter Plots and Tables, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">12</container>
              <container type="folder">5</container>
              <unittitle>General – Data and graphs, 1989</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">12</container>
              <container type="folder">6</container>
              <unittitle>General – Data and graphs, 1973</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">12</container>
              <container type="folder">7</container>
              <unittitle>General – Data Tables, undated [1/2]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">12</container>
              <container type="folder">8</container>
              <unittitle>General – Data Tables, undated [2/2]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">13</container>
              <container type="folder">1</container>
              <unittitle>General – Research Papers, 1992-1998 [1/2]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">13</container>
              <container type="folder">2</container>
              <unittitle>General – Individual-based pronunciation training in Japanese - IRB, proposals, and reports, 1997-1999</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">13</container>
              <container type="folder">3</container>
              <unittitle>General - Aprosodia Tape Transcript, 1995</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">13</container>
              <container type="folder">4</container>
              <unittitle>General – CHAT Transcript System Notes, 1995</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">13</container>
              <container type="folder">5</container>
              <unittitle>General - Misperception Analysis, 1998</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">13</container>
              <container type="folder">6</container>
              <unittitle>General - Fundamental Problems in Phonetics Notebooks, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">13</container>
              <container type="folder">7</container>
              <unittitle>General - Linguistics Experiment, 1994</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">13</container>
              <container type="folder">8</container>
              <unittitle>General - Perception of stops in the environment of liquids - Blank consent forms, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">13</container>
              <container type="folder">9</container>
              <unittitle>General - Perception of stops in the environment of liquids - Results, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unittitle>Subseries V: Index Cards</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">13</container>
              <container type="folder">10</container>
              <unittitle>Index Cards – Conversation Analysis, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">14</container>
              <container type="folder">1</container>
              <unittitle>Word Flashcards - /b/ and /p/, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">14</container>
              <container type="folder">2</container>
              <unittitle>Word Flashcards - /b/ and /p/, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">14</container>
              <container type="folder">3</container>
              <unittitle>Index Cards and slides - Graphs, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">15</container>
              <unittitle>Index Card File - Masters, A-G, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">16</container>
              <unittitle>Index Card File - Masters, H-P, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">17</container>
              <unittitle>Index Card File - Masters, Q-Z, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">18</container>
              <unittitle>Index Card File - Glossarial Handbook, Hamp and Landahl, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">19</container>
              <unittitle>Index Card File - Scripts and Books, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">20</container>
              <unittitle>Index Card File - Catalog Codes, Lab , Computer Tapes, and Music, undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">21</container>
              <unittitle>Index Card File - Languages and Dialects, undated [1/2]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">22</container>
              <unittitle>Index Card File - Languages and Dialects, undated [2/2]</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">23</container>
              <unittitle>Index Card File – Articles and Tape , undated</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03>
            <did>
              <container type="box">23</container>
              <unittitle>Includes audiocassette tape, "Imitations."</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series IV: Writing</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Effect of Aberrant Supralaryngeal Vocal Tracts on Transfer Function – Landahl and Peterson-Falzone – Speech and Language: Advances in Basics Research and Practice, circa 1975</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>On the Role of Invariant Acoustic Properties and Context Dependent Cues – Landahl and Blumstein – Brown University, circa 1975</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Identification by adults of vowel sounds produced by an infant – Landahl and Mikos – Brown University Working Papers in Linguistics, 1977</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Formant Frequency Patterns in Anomalous Supralaryngeal Vocal Tracts – Landahl and Robinson – Brown University Working Papers in Linguistics, Vol III, 1977-1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Cues for Interpreting Early Child Speech – Speech Communication Papers, Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1979</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Abnormal Laryngeal Vocal Quality in Ectodermal Dysplasia – Archives of Otolaryngology, May, 1981</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Review: Speech and Language, Norman J. Lass – Contemporary Psychology, Vol 27.6, 1982</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Congenital Malformation of the Speech Tract in Humans and its Developmental Consequences – Landahl and Gould, 1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>The /b/-/w/ Contrast and Considerations of Syllable Duration – Landahl and Maxwell - Papers from the Nineteenth Regional Meeting, Chicago Linguistics Society, 1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Imitation in Phonological Acquisition – Landahl, Rasco, Gould, and Mishra - University of Chicago Working Papers in Linguistics, 1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Abstracts, Miscellaneous, circa 1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Phoneticxs Entries – Encyclopedia Britannica Micropaedia, 1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Development of the Vowel Space in Children with Apert Syndrome – Landahl and Hasner, circa 1987</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Fundamental Frequency Anchors and Bands – Landahl and Lierberman, circa 1989</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Acoustic Invariance in Glossectomee Speech - Landahl and Karnell, January 31, 1991</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">24</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>Comparison of Fundamental Frequency and Perturbation Measurements – Landahl, Karnell, and Hall - Journal of Voice 9.4, December, 1995</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Craniofacial Anomalies and the Evolution of Human Speech – Typescript with edits, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Effects of Congenital Malformations on Speech Development – Landahl and Peterson-Falzone, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Fourier and Linear Predictive Analyses of Aberrant Vowel Formants – Landahl and Peterson-Falzone - Proceedings of the 18th Congress of the International Association of Logopedics and Phoniatrics, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Imitation in Early Language Development – Presentation, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Otisis Media, Sensory Deprivation, and Speech Sound Perception – Proposal – Landahl and Gould, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Questioning the Continuum: The Use of V[r/l][d/g] Evidence in Gestural Theories of Speech Perception – Landahl, Hemphill, Hirata, Lowenstein, and Dainora, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>The Stop-Glide Contrast and Considerations of Phonetic Context – Landahl and Maxwell - MIT Speech Communications Working Papers, Vol III, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>"Syndromes" of Linguistic Development – Landahl, Farley, and Ziolkowski, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Notebooks and miscellaneous notes, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series V: Writing by Others</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Anderson, S., and R. Port – Evidence for Syllable Structure, Stress, and Juncture from Segmental Durations – Journal of Phonetics, 1994</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Bates, E., and B. Macwhinney - Competition, Variance and Language Learning, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Bever, T. – Normal Acquisition Processes Explain the Critical Period for Language Learning, 1981</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Bever, T. – Psychologically Real Grammar Emerges Because of Its Role in Language Acquisition, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Billings, S., and K. Gruber - Systematicity and Speaker Variation in Acoustic Realization, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Bless, H., and Faber – Videostroboscopic Evaluation of the Larynx - Ear, Nose and Throat Journal, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>Blumstein, S. – Acoustic Invariance in Speech Production – Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, October 1979</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>Blumstein, S., and K.N. Stevens – Phonetic Features and Acoustic Invariance - Cognition, 1981</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">18</container>
            <unittitle>Boysson-Bardies and Vihman – Adaptation to Language: Evidence from Babbling and First Words in Four Languages, 1991; and Boysson-Bardies, Sagart, and Durand - Discernible Differences in the Babbling of Infants According to Target Language, 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">19</container>
            <unittitle>Brentari – American Sign Language Phonology – undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">20</container>
            <unittitle>Broad, D.J. – Toward Defining Acoustic Phonetic Equivalence - Phonetica, 1976</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">25</container>
            <container type="folder">21</container>
            <unittitle>Browman, C.P., and L. Goldstein – Articulatory Phonology, 1992</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Brown, W.S., T. Murry, and D. Hughes – Comfortable Effort Level: An Experimental Variable – Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, September 1976</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Bull, D., R. Eilers, and D. Oller – Infants Discrimination of Intensity Variation into Multisyllabic Stimuli - Journal of the Acoustic Society of America, 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Carden, G., and A. Levitt – Evidence for Phonetic Processing of Cues to Place of Articulation: Perceived Manner Affects Perceived Place - Perception and Psychophysics, 1981</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Cohn, A. – Quantitative Characterization of Degree of Coarticulation in CV Tokens, 1987</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Cole, R. – Listening for Mispronunciations: A measure of what we hear during speech – Perception and Psychophysics, 1973</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Copper and Eady - Metrical Phonology in Speech Production - Journal of Memory and Language, 1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Darden, B.J. – A Critical Look at Natural Phonology, and Explanation and Reality in Phonology, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Delattre, P. – Some Factors of Vowel Duration and Their Cross-Linguistic Validity, 1962</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Denton, J., Y. Hirata, and S. Sogslanova – Reassessment: Liquid Stop Sequences, 1998</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Dommelan, W. – Acoustic parameters in Human Speaker Recognition - Language and Speech, 1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Duanmu, S. – Syllabic Weight and Syllabic Duration – Phonology, 1994</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Eimas, P., E. Jusczyk, and J. Vigorito – Speech Perception in Infants – Science, 1971</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Eimas, P. and J. Miller – Studies on the Categorization of Speech by Infants – Cognition, 1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Elfenbein, Waziri, and Morris - Verbal Communication Skills of Six Children with Craniofacial Anomalies - Cleft Palate Journal - Photocopy, offprint, notes, and clipping, 1981-1988</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Emanuel, F.W., and D.T Counihan – Some Characteristics of Oral and Nasal Air Flow During Plosive Consonant Production, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>Erbaugh, M. – Pre-Narrative Roots of Time Reference in Child Mandarin, July 1989</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>Farley, A. – Acoustic Cues to Discourse Units: A Study of Paragraph Marking, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">18</container>
            <unittitle>Flege, J. and H. Hillenbrand – Limits on Phonetic Accuracy in Foreign Language Speech Production - Journal of the Acoustic Society of America, 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">19</container>
            <unittitle>Fowler, Rubin, Remez, and Turvey – Implications for Speech Production of a General Theory of Action, 1980</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">20</container>
            <unittitle>Fowler, C. – An Event Approach to the Study of Speech Perception from a Direct-Realist Perspective – Journal of Phonetics, 1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">21</container>
            <unittitle>Fowler, Best, and McRoberts – Young Infants' Perception of Liquid Coarticulatory Influences on Following Stop Consonants – Perception and Psychophysics, 1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">22</container>
            <unittitle>Frege, Gottlob - On sense and Reference (1892) - The Logic of Grammar, 1975</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">23</container>
            <unittitle>Fujimara, O. – Methods and Goals of Speech Production Research – Language and Speech, 1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">24</container>
            <unittitle>Fujimara, O., and J. Lovins – Syllables as Concatenative Phonetic Units - Syllables and Segments, 1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">25</container>
            <unittitle>Gay, T. – Temporal and Spatial Properties of Articulatory Movements - The Cognitive Representation of Speech, 1981</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">26</container>
            <unittitle>Georgian, Logemann, and Fisher – Compensatory Articulation Patterns of a Surgically Treated Oral Cancer Patient - Journal of Speech and Hearing Disorders, 1982</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">27</container>
            <unittitle>Gilbert, J. – Acoustical Features of Children's Vowel Sounds, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">28</container>
            <unittitle>Goldstein, M. – Speech without a Tongue - The Journal of Speech Disorders, March 1940</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">29</container>
            <unittitle>Grice, H.P. – Logic and Conversation – The Logic of Grammar, 1975</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">30</container>
            <unittitle>Han and Weitzman - Acoustic Features of Korean /P, T, K/, /p, t, k/ and /ph, th, kh/1 - Phonetica, 1970</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">31</container>
            <unittitle>Hardcastle, W.J. – Some Observations on the Tense-Lax Distinciton in Initial Stops in Korean - Journal of Phonetics (fragment), 1973</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">32</container>
            <unittitle>Hillin, W.A., M. Fry and R. Hershman – Computer Recognition of Spoken Digits Based on Six Nonacoustic Measures – Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1965</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">33</container>
            <unittitle>Hirose, Lee, and Ushijima - Laryngeal Control in Korean Stop Production - Journal of Phonetics (fragment), 1974</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">34</container>
            <unittitle>House and Fairbanks – The Influence of Consonant Environment Upon the Secondary Acoustical Characteristics of Vowels - Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1952</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">35</container>
            <unittitle>Institute for Academic Technology - "Technology in Higher Education" series - Multiple articles, 1989-1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">26</container>
            <container type="folder">36</container>
            <unittitle>Isshiki, N. and R. Ringel – Air Flow during the Production of Selected Consonants – Journal of Speech and Hearing Research, 1964</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Jakobson, Fant, Halle – Preliminaries to Speech Analysis: The Distinctive Features and their Correlates, 1967</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Johnson, K. – Multiple papers, 1998 and undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Karnell, Michael P. - Curriculum vitae and multiple articles, 1982-1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Kazazis, K. – Dismantling Greek Diglossia (fragment), undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Kewley-Port, D. and D.B. Pisoni – Identification and Discrimination of Rise Time: Is it Categorical or Noncategorical? – Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, April 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Kewley-Port, D. - Time-Varying Features as Correlates of Place of Articulation in Stop Consonants – Journal of the Acoustic Society of America, January 1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Klein, Martin J. - The Physics of J. Willard Gibbs in His Time - Physics Today, 1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Kurowski, K. and S.E. Blumstein – Perceptual Integration of the Murmur and Formant Transitions for Place of Articulation in Nasal Consonants - Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, August 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Ladefoged, P. and D.E. Broadbent – Information Conveyed by Vowels - Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1957</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Lehiste, I., and D. Meltzer – Vowel and Speaker Identification in Natural and Synthetic Speech, 1971</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Levitt, A. et al – Context Effects in Two-Month-Old Infants' Perception of Labiodental/Interdental Fricative Contrasts - Journal of Experimental Psychology, Human Perception and Performance, 1988</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Lieberman, P. – On the Development of Vowel Production in Young Children – Child Phonology, Volume I: Production, 1980</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Lieberman, A. and Mattingly - The Motor Theory of Speech Perception Revised – Cognition, 1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Lieberman, Cooper, Shankweller, and Kennedy – Perception of the Speech Code - Psychological Review, 1967</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Lindblom, B. – Spectographic Study of Vowel Reduction - Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1963</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>Local, J. – Syllabification and Rhythm in Non-Segmental Phonology, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>Lotto, Kluender, and Holt - Animal Models of Speech Perception Phenomena, Chicago Linguistic Society, 1997; and Perceptual Compensation for Coarticulation by Japanese Quail, Journal of the Acoustic Society of America, 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">18</container>
            <unittitle>Lumsden, C.J. – Neuronal Group Selection and the Evolution of Hominid Cranial Capacity – Journal of Human Evolution, 1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">19</container>
            <unittitle>MacWhinney, B. – Hungarian Language Acquisition as an Exemplificaiton of a General model of Grammatical Development, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">20</container>
            <unittitle>MacWhinney, B. – Competition and Cooperation in Language Processing, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">21</container>
            <unittitle>Maddieson, I. – Phonetic Cues to Syllabification, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">22</container>
            <unittitle>Maddieson, I. and K. Precoda – Syllable Structure and Phonetic Models, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">23</container>
            <unittitle>Malmberg, B. – The Phonetic Basis for Syllable Division, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">24</container>
            <unittitle>Makashay, M.J and K. Johnson – Surveying Auditory Space Using Vowel Formant Data, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">25</container>
            <unittitle>Mann, Virginia – Influence of Preceding Liquid on Stop Consonant Perception – Perception and Psychophysics, 1980</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">26</container>
            <unittitle>Mann, Virginia – Distinguishing Universal and Language-Dependent Levels of Speech Perception: Evidence form Japanese Listners' Perception of English "I" and "r" - Cognition, 1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">27</container>
            <unittitle>Massaro, D. and W. Idsom – The Role of Perceived Duration in the Identification of Vowels - Journal of Phonetics, 1980</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">28</container>
            <unittitle>Miller, James D. – Auditory Processing of the Acoustic Patterns of Speech –Arch Otolaryngol, 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">29</container>
            <unittitle>Miller and Eimas - Studies on the Categorization of Speech by Infants - Cognition, 1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">30</container>
            <unittitle>Miller, R.L. – Nature of the Vocal Cord Wave - Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1959</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">27</container>
            <container type="folder">31</container>
            <unittitle>Mochizuki-Sudo, M. and S. Kiritani – Production and Perception of Stress-Related Durational Patterns in Japanese Learners of English, - Journal of Phonetics, 1991</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Ohala, John J. – Multiple articles, 1974-1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Ohman, Sven E. G. – Numerical Model of Coarticulation – Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1967</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Oller, D.K. and B.L. Smith – Effect of Final-Syllable Position on Vowel Duration in Infant Babbling – Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1977</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Palmer, J.M. – Dynamic Palatography - Phonetica, 1973</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Parker, E. and R. Diehl – Identifying Vowels in CVC Syllables: Effects of Inserting Silence and Noise - Perception and Psychophysics, 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Pike – Phonetic Symbolism, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Pos, van der Kamp, and Plomp - Perceptual and Physical Space of Vowel Sounds - Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1969</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Rakerd, B. – Vowels in Consonantal Context are Perceived More Linguistically than are Isolated Vowels: Evidence from an Individual Differences Scaling Study – Perception &amp; Psychophysics, 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Rentschler and Mann – The Effects of Glossectomy on Intelligibility of Speech and Oral Perceptual Discrimination - Journal of Oral Surgery, 1980</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Repp, B. – Phonetic Trading Relations and Context Effects: New Experimental Evidence for a Speech Mode of Perception - Psychological Bulletin, 1982</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Rosenberg, A.E. – Effect of Glottal Pulse Shape on the Quality of Natural Vowels – The Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1970</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Rothenberg, M. – A New Inverse-Filtering Technique for Deriving the Glottal Air Flow Waveform during Voicing – Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Schouten and Pols – Vowel Segments in Consonantal Contexts: A Spectral Study of Coarticulation - Part I - Journal of Phonetics, 1979</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Skelly, Donaldson, Fust, and Townsend - Changes in Phonatory Aspects of Glossectomee Intelligibility Through Vocal Parameter Maniuplation - Journal of Speech and Hearing Disorders, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Smith, Allen, Warren, and Hall - The Consistency of the Pressure-Flow Technique for Assessing Oral Port Size - Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>Smith, R. – Edwin P. Hubble and the Transformation of Cosmology - Physics Today, 1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>Soli, S.D. – The Role of Spectral Cues in Discrimination of Voice Onset Time Differences – Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">18</container>
            <unittitle>Sondhi, M. – "Model for Wave Propagation in a Lossy Vocal Tract," and "Measurement of the Glottal Waveform" - Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1974 and 1975</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">19</container>
            <unittitle>Stark, J., Lindblom, B. and Sundberg, J. – APEX an Articulatory Synthesis Model for Experimental and Computational Studies of Speech Production - Current Research in Speech Physiology, 1998</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">20</container>
            <unittitle>Stathopoulos, E.T. – Oral Air Flow during Vowel Production of Children and Adults - Cleft Palate Journal, 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">21</container>
            <unittitle>Stevens, Kenneth N., et al. - "Perturbation of Vowel Articulations by Consonantal Context: An Acoustical Study," and "Invariant Cues for Place of Articulation in Stop Consonants," 1963 and 1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">22</container>
            <unittitle>Straight, H.S. – Auditory versus. Articulatory Phonological Processes and Their Development in Children - Child Phonology, 1980</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">23</container>
            <unittitle>Subtelny and Worth - Intraoral Pressure and Rate of Flow during Speech - Journal of Hearing and Speech Research, 1966</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">24</container>
            <unittitle>Suomi, K. – On Spectral Coarticulation in Stop-Vowel Syllables: Implications for Automatic Speech Recognition – Journal of Phonetics, 1987</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">25</container>
            <unittitle>Terrace, Pettito, Sanders, and Bever – Can an Ape Create a Sentence? - Science, 1979</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">26</container>
            <unittitle>Trullinger, R.W., and F.W. Emanuel – Airflow Characteristics of Stop-Plosive Consonant Productions of Normal-Speaking Children – Journal of Speech and Hearing Research, 1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">27</container>
            <unittitle>van Hattum and Worth – Air Flow Rates in Normal Speakers, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">28</container>
            <unittitle>Wakita, H. – Instrumentation for the Study of Speech Acoustics, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">28</container>
            <container type="folder">29</container>
            <unittitle>Walley and Carrell – Onset Spectra and Formant Transitions in the Adult's and Child's Perception of Place of Articulation in Stop Consonants - Journal of Acoustical Society of America, 1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">29</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Warren, Donald W. – Multiple articles, 1964, 1981, and undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">29</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Weintraub, Mesulam, and Kramer – Disturbances in Prosody: A Right-Hemisphere Contribution to Language - Archives of Neurology, 1981</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">29</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Werker and Tees – Developmental Changes across Childhood in the Perception of Non-native Speech Sounds – Canadian Journal of Psychology, 1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">29</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>White, J.P. – Acoustic and Perceptual Characteristics of Electronic Artificial Larynges - Dissertation, 1994</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">29</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Winters, S., and K. Johnson – An Exemplar-Based Model of Silent-Center Syllable Perception, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">29</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Zwicker, Flottorp, and Stevens – Critical Band Width in Loudness Summation - Journal of the Acoustical Society of America, 1957</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series VI: Professional Activities</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">29</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Conference presentations – Papers, overhead projector transparencies, and slides 1979-1987 and undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">29</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Conference presentations - Papers 1985-1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">29</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Conference presentations - Abstracts, papers, and correspondence, 1985-1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">29</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Origin of Human Language, Cortona, Italy – Programs and Group Photograph, 1988</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">29</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Chicago Linguistic Society 33 – Schedules, presentation, and overhead projector transparencies, April, 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series VII: Teaching</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">30</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Experimental Phonetics – Readings, 1961-1994</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">30</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Teaching Notes – Child Phonology, 1982</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">30</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 304 – Syntax I – Student Assignments, 1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">30</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 304 – Syntax I – Readings and student papers, 1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">30</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Student lab results, 1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">30</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 301 – Introduction to Linguistics – Student Papers, 1988</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">30</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 306 – Phonetics – Student labs, 1988</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">30</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 306 – Phonetics – Student term papers, 1988</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">30</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 306 – Phonetics – Student Assignments and Labs, 1988</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">31</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 306 – Phonetics – Student Labs, 1988</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">31</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 306 – Phonetics – Student Labs, 1988</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">31</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 306 – Phonetics – Quizzes, 1988</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">31</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 306 – Phonetics – Quizzes and Instructions, 1988-1991</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">31</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Photograph - Karl-Eric, May 1988</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">31</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Introduction to Language Development - Readings evaluations, 1989</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">31</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Anne Farley - Phonological Acquisition Exam and Dissertation Proposal, "The Role of Imitation in Language Acquisition," 1989-1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">31</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 306 - Phonetics – Notes and Quizzes, Student Lists, 1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">31</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 306 - Phonetics – Labs, Course Plans, Readings, 1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">32</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 306 - Phonetics – Labs, Quizzes and Assignments, 1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">32</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Eunlim Kim - Study and dissertation proposals, 1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">32</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Bob Mitchell - M.A. Paper Proposal, Progress Reports, and 7-inch reel-to-reel audiotape, 1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">32</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 200/300 - Talking Computers and Visible Speech for Language Study - Syllabi and readings, 1991</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">32</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 200/300 - Talking Computers and Visible Speech for Language Study - Readings, 1991</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">32</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 200/300 - Talking Computers and Visible Speech for Language Study - Readings, 1991</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">32</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Caroline Wiltshire - Phonetics Minor Exam Reading List, January 1991</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">32</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Kenneth Cordes - M.A. Thesis, "Interactions between Consonants and Tones in Taiwanese Hokkien," 1991</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">33</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Convocation program, June 14, 1991</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">33</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 469, Phonetics/Phonology Interface - Draft syllabus (1996) and photocopied articles, 1981-1996</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">33</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Applied Phonetics Instruction Manual, 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">33</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 206/306, Phonetics - Syllabus, lab manual, lab assignments, photocopied articles, and phonetics wheel, 1992-1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">33</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 306 – Phonetics – Lab Manual, Lab Assignments, and Quizzes, 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">33</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Linguistics 306 – Phonetics – Lab Demonstration, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">33</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Phonetics – Group Lab Work and student notecards, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">33</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Phonetics, Major Field Exam - Reading lists, reading abstracts, and photocopied articles, 1993-1998</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">33</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Taping instructions - undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">33</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Early speech research bibliography - Photocopied articles, 1952-1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">34</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Early speech research bibliography - Photocopied articles, 1970-1980</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">34</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Early Work on Vowel Perception and Motor Theory bibliography - Photocopied articles, 1946-1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">34</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Imitation bibliography - Photocopied articles, mainly just page 1, 1961-1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">34</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Imitation bibliography - Photocopied index cards and articles, and offprints, 1971-1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">34</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Imitation bibliography - Photocopied articles, 1957-1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">34</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Imitation bibliography - Photocopied articles, 1957-1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">34</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Imitation bibliography - Photocopied articles, 1957-1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">35</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Imitation bibliography - Photocopied articles, 1969-1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">35</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopied articles and offprints, 1946-2004</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">35</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopied articles and chapters, 1960-1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">35</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopied articles and chapters, 1967-1995</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">35</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopied articles and offprints, 1974-1982</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">35</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopied articles and chapters, 1981-1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">36</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopied articles and chapters, 1976-1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">36</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopied articles and chapters, 1982-1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">36</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopied articles and chapters, 1981-1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">36</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopied articles and chapters, 1981-1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">36</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopied articles and chapters, 1973-1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">36</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopied articles and chapters, 1979-1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">36</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopied articles and chapters, 1967-1982</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">36</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopied articles and chapters, 1987-1992</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">36</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Photocopied articles and conference papers, 1986-1995</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series VIII: Oversize</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">37</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Vowel Data Graphs, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">37</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Vowel Data Graphs and Spectograms, circa 1977</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle>Series IX: Restricted</unittitle>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>This series contains restricted personnel and financial information, grant proposals with social security numbers, evaluative student material, and medical information. Materials in Box 38 are restricted for 50 years from date of record creation. Materials in Box 39 are restricted for 80 years from date of record creation. Materials in Boxes 40-50 are restricted indefinitely.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">38</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Personnel Records, UIC Medical Center, 1977</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">38</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Modeling of Abnormal Vocal Tracts - Grant proposal, circa 1982</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">38</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Imitation in Phonological Acquisition - Study proposals, 1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">38</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Travel reimbursement forms, 1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">38</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Language Lab - GW Instruments purchase orders, invoices, and warranties, 1986-1993</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">38</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Japanese Visi-Pitch - Financial reports, 1989-1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">38</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>ESPS/Waves+ - Purchase packet, 1998</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">38</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Workshop budgets, 1999</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">38</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>The Structure of Sound as an Information Channel - National Science Foundation proposal, correspondence, and CVs, 1999-2000</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">39</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Grant application, circa 1982</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">39</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Hearing and Perception in Cleft Palate Infants - Grant application, 1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">39</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Speech Production Studies in Craniofacial Anomalies - Grant application, correspondence, notes, progress reports, and photocopied articles, 1983-1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">39</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Replacement of acoustic spectrum analyzer - Grant application, Campus Research Board, 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">39</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Otitis Media, Sensory Deprivation and Speech Sound Perception - Grant applications, 1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">39</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Speech Production in Craniofacial Anomalies - Grant application, 1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">39</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Speech Production in Craniofacial Anomalies - Grant application, 1987</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">39</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Masters Thesis - Angela Hasner, 1987</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">39</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Introduction to Linguistics - Graded student work, 1988</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">39</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Student papers, labs, and grades, 1988-1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">39</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Dissertation proposal - Anne Farley, 1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">39</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Dissertation introduction - Eunlim Kim, 1990</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">40</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Ectrodactyly-Ectodermal Dysplasia - Clefting (ECC) - Case notes, 1958-1979</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">40</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - F-, 1968-1974 and undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">40</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - F- 2 months, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">40</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Apert patient data and spectrograms, 1972-1976</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">40</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Apert patient data and spectrograms, 1972-1977</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">40</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms, 1973</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">40</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data - Crouzon #3493, Crouzon #3589, and Apert #1949, 1977</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">40</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Apert #1909, 1972</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">40</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Apert #1949, 1972</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">40</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Apert #1949, 1977-1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">41</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Apert #1949, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">41</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Apert #1013, 1974</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">41</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Apert #984, 1975</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">41</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Apert #984, 1977</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">41</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Apert #2183, 1975</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">41</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Apert #2183, 1977</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">42</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Apert #2023, 1973</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">42</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Apert patient images, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">42</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Crouzon #3493, 1977</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">42</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Crouzon #3493, 1974</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">42</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Crouzon #3589, 1973</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">42</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Crouzon #3589, 1974</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">42</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Crouzon #3589, 1977-1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">42</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Crouzon #2033, 1972</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">43</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - Crouzon #2033, 1973</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">43</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Center for Craniofacial Anomalies - Forms and notes, 1975-1976</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">43</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Center for Craniofacial Anomalies - Directory and patient data, 1976-1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">43</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Center for Craniofacial Anomalies - Patient data, correspondence, and signed permission forms for audio recording of underage children, 1983-1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">43</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Parents' or Guardians' permission for audio recording of underage child - Signed forms, 1983-1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">43</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Center for Craniofacial Anomalies - Cleft Palate Clinic - Patient data, 1984-1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">43</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Tape transcripts - D-, 1975-1979</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">43</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Tape transcripts - D-, 1977-1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">43</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Tape transcripts - D-, 1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">43</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Tape transcripts - J-, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">43</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Tape transcripts - M-, 1979-1980</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">44</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Tape transcripts - M-, 1980-1981</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">44</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Tape transcripts - S-, 1977-1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">44</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Tape transcripts - S-, 1977-1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">44</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Tape transcripts - S-, 1977-1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">44</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Tape transcripts - S-, 1977-1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">44</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Tape transcripts - S-, 1977-1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">44</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Patient addresses, taping instructions, and correspondence, circa 1983-1987</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">44</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Tape transcripts - A-, 1984-1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">44</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Tape transcripts and notes - C-, 1985-1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">44</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Center for Craniofacial Anomalies - Patient data - E-, 1984-1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">45</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Tape transcripts - E-, 1984-1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">45</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - G-, 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">45</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Patient notes and tape transcripts - K-, 1983-1985</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">45</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Patient notes and tape transcripts - K-, 1983-1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">45</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Patient notes - K-, 1985-1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">45</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Patient notes and tape transcripts - K-, 1985-1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">45</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>I.E.P. and correspondence - U-, 1987</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">45</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - W-, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">45</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - W-, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">45</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - S- and D-, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">45</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - p + + contexts, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">45</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms, 1983-1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">46</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">46</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">46</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">46</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">46</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data - Graphs, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">46</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data - A-, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">46</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data - D-, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">46</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data - H-, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data - M-, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data - M-, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data, 1991</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and spectrograms - "L- 017-049," 1995</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and graphs - "J- 050-082," undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and graphs - "J- 83-116," undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data and graphs - "L- X013-X016, 001-016," undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Test script for alda, alga, arda, arga - K-, J-, T-, and R-, circa 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data - "4 speakers' formant values for graphs," April 16, 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - "[da] - [ga] for 4 speakers," circa 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - J, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - J-, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - "J-, Master Spects, 5/28," undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - "J- appended stops masters," circa 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">47	</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - "J- LPC and FFT," circa 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - K, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - "K- appended stops - masters," circa 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - "K- LPC and FFT," circa 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - "R- AL and AR appended masters," circa 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - "R- appended stops masters," circa 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - "R- LPC and FFT," undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - T, and notes, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - "T- appended stops - masters," circa 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - "T- LPC and FFT," undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Patient data - "Certain measurements for entry into composite data file," undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Presentation graphs and overhead projector transparencies, circa 1997</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms - Stops and liquids, Y-, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Spectograms, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Perceptual test - Instructions and notes, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">48</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Testing consent forms, 1998</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
            <unittitle>Photographs and negatives of patient's mouths, 1985-1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
            <unittitle>Patient X-Rays - C-, 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
            <unittitle>Patient X-Rays - Apert #1909, 1972-1975</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
            <unittitle>Center for Craniofacial Anomalies - Patient X-Rays - E-, 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
            <unittitle>Center for Craniofacial Anomalies - Patient X-Rays - E-, 1984</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
            <unittitle>Center for Craniofacial Anomalies - Patient images - G-, 1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
            <unittitle>Patient X-Rays - Crouzon #3493, 1974-1977</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
            <unittitle>Patient X-Rays - Apert #1013, 1974</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
            <unittitle>Patient X-Rays - Apert #984, 1975-1978</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
            <unittitle>Patient X-Rays - Apert #1949, 1973-1977</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
            <unittitle>Patient X-Rays - Apert #2183, 1975</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
            <unittitle>Center for Craniofacial Anomalies - Patient X-Rays - R-, 1983</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
            <unittitle>Center for Craniofacial Anomalies - Patient images - R-, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
            <unittitle>Patient X-Rays - Crouzon #2023, 1973</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
            <unittitle>Patient X-Rays - Crouzon #2033, 1972-1973</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
            <unittitle>Patient X-Rays and notes - Crouzon #3589, 1974</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">49</container>
            <container type="folder">17</container>
            <unittitle>Center for Craniofacial Anomalies - Photographs of patients - U- and A-, 1986</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02>
          <did>
            <container type="box">50</container>
            <unittitle>Teeth molds, undated</unittitle>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
