<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
<eadheader audience="internal">
<eadid>ICU.SPCL.LAVESG</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
<titleproper>Guide to the Gerhardt Laves Papers<date>1916-1982</date></titleproper>
<author>Finding aid prepared by MA 2022</author>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt><publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher></publicationstmt>
<notestmt>
<note><p>© The contents of this finding aid are the copyright of the University of Chicago Library</p></note>
<note><p><subject>Anthropology and Ethnology</subject></p></note>
</notestmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding aid encoded by AG 2022</creation>
<langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>

<frontmatter audience="external">
<titlepage>
<publisher>University of Chicago Library</publisher>
<titleproper>Guide to the Gerhardt Laves Papers<date>1916-1982</date></titleproper>
<author>Finding aid prepared by MA 2022</author>
<p>© 2022 University of Chicago Library</p>
</titlepage>

</frontmatter>

<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Descriptive Summary</head>
<unittitle label="Title">Laves, Gerhardt. Papers</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" label="Dates">1916-1982</unitdate>


<langmaterial>Documents in <language>English&#13;
Bardi</language></langmaterial>
<physdesc label="Size">58.25 linear feet (14 boxes)</physdesc>
<repository label="Repository"><address>
<addressline>Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center</addressline>
<addressline>University of Chicago Library</addressline>
<addressline>1100 East 57th Street</addressline>
<addressline>Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.</addressline>
</address></repository>
<abstract label="Abstract">Gerhardt Laves (b. July 15, 1906, d. March 14, 1993) was a linguist who conducted research on several Aboriginal languages in Australia, taught at Indian boarding schools in Navajo Nation, also known as Diné Bikéyah or Navajoland, and worked at various Chicago institutions. This collection contains materials from Laves’ personal and professional life, including his linguistic notes on the Bardi language and photographs. Also included are language resources, publications, and maps from Laves’ employment in Navajo Nation. The collection contains documents and photographs from Laves’ work at the International Harvester Company and the Chicago Police Department, materials related to the Hyde Park and Kenwood neighborhoods, and documents related to Laves’ involvement at the University of Chicago. Additionally, the collection includes Laves’ photographs, film negatives, and glass slides documenting family and professional activities. Materials date between 1916 and 1982, with the bulk of materials dating between 1916 and 1949.</abstract>
</did>

<descgrp><head>Information on Use</head>
<accessrestrict><head>Access</head><p>This collection is open for research.</p></accessrestrict>
<userestrict><head>Restrictions on Use</head><p>The note cards in Series V, Research on the Bardi Language, have suffered significant water damage and as a result are extremely fragile. Papers are brittle and should be handled with care. &#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Photographs in Series III, Subseries 3 related to the Chicago Police Department photographs are warped. The majority of the photographs and film negatives in Series VI, Photographs, are also warped.</p></userestrict>
<prefercite><head>Citation</head><p>When quoting material from
this collection, the preferred citation is: Laves, Gerhardt. Papers, [Box #, Folder #], Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center, University of Chicago Library.</p></prefercite>

<bioghist><head>Biographical Note</head><p>Gerhardt Laves was born in Chicago on July 15, 1906. His father, Kurt Laves (1866-1944), a professor of mathematics and astronomy, was one of the University of Chicago’s founding faculty members. His mother, Luise, née Moshagen (1872-1957), worked as a homemaker. Both Kurt and Luise Laves were born in Germany. Gerhardt Laves attended Ray Elementary School and the University of Chicago Laboratory Schools. He completed a bachelor’s degree in history and anthropology in 1927 and a master’s degree in anthropology in 1929, both at the University of Chicago.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Laves pursued further graduate education at the University of Chicago, where he worked with linguist Edward Sapir. From 1929-1931, he conducted linguistic research in northern and western Australian Aboriginal communities. In total, Laves studied six languages: Gumbaynggir (also Kumbainggar or Gumbangeri); Karajarri; Bardi; Koreng (or Goreng); Matngele (or Madngele); and Ngan'gimerri (also Nangiomeri or Nanggumiri).&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Following his fieldwork, Laves married Maxine Laves, née Lichtenstein (1910-1999), in 1932. They had four children: Jean Hellie (Laves), Barbara Beasley (Laves), Elizabeth Marcuson (Laves), and Edward “Ted” Laves. In 1933, Laves moved to New Haven to continue his doctoral studies in linguistics at Yale University, but never completed a PhD. &#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>The family spent 1935 to 1939 in Navajo Nation, also known as Diné Bikéyah or Navajoland, in New Mexico, where Laves taught in at least three Indian boarding schools, prepared reports materials on Diné bizaad, the Navajo language, and researched soil conservation practices. Established and funded by the federal government, Indian boarding schools were designed to eradicate linguistic and cultural bonds within Indigenous communities by separating children from their families and forcefully assimilating them into settler colonial culture. Conditions at such schools were emotionally, physically, and sexually abusive and often involved forced child labor, rampant disease and malnourishment, and overcrowding. The schools where Laves taught include Wingate Vocational High School, Torreon School, and Shiprock Indian Boarding School. &#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>When the family returned to Chicago in 1939, Laves worked for the International Harvester Company preparing instructional brochures and visual aids until 1961. From about 1961 to 1971, Laves worked for the Chicago Police Department writing copy and designing visual aids for CPD exhibits and brochures in the Public Information Division. &#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Gerhardt Laves died in Chicago on March 14, 1993 at the age of 86.</p></bioghist>
     <scopecontent>
          <head>Content Warning</head>
          <p>This collection includes materials reflecting the attitudes, language, and stereotypes of an earlier time period. These materials are presented unaltered as historical resources in support of study and research. Inclusion of such materials does not constitute an endorsement of their content by the University of Chicago.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander users should be aware that this finding aid and materials in the collection may contain images and names of deceased persons.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Please contact us if you encounter problematic description of, or access to, materials about Aboriginal, Torres Strait Islander, or Diné (Navajo) people by notifying staff in person or via the <extref href="https://www.lib.uchicago.edu/scrc/visiting/contact/">contact form</extref> on our website.&#13;</p>
     </scopecontent>
     
     <scopecontent><head>Scope Note</head><p>&#13;</p><p>The Gerhardt Laves Papers are organized into seven series: &#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series I, Personal; &#13;</p><p>Series II, Correspondence; &#13;</p><p>Series III, Professional Life and Associations; &#13;</p><p>Series IV, Publications by Others; &#13;</p><p>Series V, Research on the Bardi Language; &#13;</p><p>Series VI, Photographs; &#13;</p><p>Series VII, Oversize.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>The collection contains materials from Laves’ personal and professional life, including his linguistic notes on the Bardi language and photographs; language resources, publications, and maps from Laves’ employment in Navajo Nation; documents and photographs from Laves’ work at the International Harvester Company and the Chicago Police Department; materials related to the Hyde Park and Kenwood neighborhoods; documents related to Laves’ involvement at the University of Chicago; and Laves’ photographs, film negatives, and glass slides documenting family and professional activities. Materials date between 1916 and 1982, with the bulk of materials dating between 1916 and 1949.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series I, Personal, contains materials related to the Laves’ family life, including Gerhardt and Maxine Laves’ passports; daughters Jean and Elizabeth’s wedding invitations; and two short plays written and performed by childhood friends of the Laves children. Materials are arranged chronologically.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series II, Correspondence, contains Gerhardt Laves’ correspondence with anthropologist Lester Hiatt, congressional representative Abner J. Mikva, and the Australian Institute of Aboriginal Studies. Materials are arranged roughly chronologically.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series III, Professional Life and Associations, contains materials from various occupations, institutions, and organizations in Gerhardt Laves’ professional life. Materials are divided into five subseries according to the organization and sorted roughly chronologically, following the trajectory of Laves’ involvement.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Subseries 1, Materials related to Navajo Nation, contains documents from Laves’ employment at Indian boarding schools in New Mexico during the 1930s, including language reference resources, reports on soil conservation practices, school bulletins, and several copies of The Navajo Service News.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Subseries 2, International Harvester Company, contains materials from Laves’ employment at the company during the 1940s, including brochures, pamphlets, company publications, training manuals, and employee recruitment materials.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Subseries 3, Chicago Police Department, contains materials from Laves’ work with the CPD from the 1960s and 1970s, including informational brochures and publications, as well as his photographic collection of police department activities, exhibits, and events.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Subseries 4, Hyde Park and Kenwood Neighborhood Materials, contains published materials related to the history of Hyde Park and Kenwood in the 1960s and 1970s, including a pamphlet on the so-called urban renewal years, information on Ray Elementary School, and Hyde Park Historical Society materials on the cable car station renovation.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Subseries 5, University of Chicago, contains materials from Gerhardt Laves’ part-time employment at the University during the 1970s, possibly working as a typist or translator for scholarly work, as well as informational material on the Returning Scholars Program.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series IV, Publications by Others, contains Laves’ collection of published sociological studies and newspaper articles. Materials are arranged chronologically.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series V, Research on the Bardi Language, contains Laves’ notes from his linguistic research in the Bardi community in Australia during the late 1920s and early 1930s. Please note that while Laves used the term “Barda” in his documentation, the standard spelling for the language and the community is Bardi. Materials remain in their original groupings and order. Please note that the note cards have suffered significant water damage and as a result are extremely fragile. Papers are brittle and should be handled with care.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series VI, Photographs, contains pre-1920s photographic glass plates by Laves’ father, Ulrich; Laves’ personal and research-related photographs from the 1910s-1930s; and Laves family and vacation photographs from the 1970s. Materials remain in their original groupings and order, and are arranged roughly chronologically.&#13;</p><p>&#13;</p><p>Series VII, Oversize, contains oversize publications and maps. Materials are sorted according to size.&#13;</p><p/></scopecontent>
<relatedmaterial><head>Related Resources</head>
<archref><extref href="https://www.lib.uchicago.edu/h/ead-topic-browse">Browse
finding aids by topic.</extref></archref><archref><unittitle>University of Chicago. Department of Anthropology. Records&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Current Anthropology Records, 1957-1987&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Robert Redfield Papers, 1917-1958&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Fred Eggan Papers, 1870-1991&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Norman A. McQuown Papers, 1850-2004&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Native American Educational Services. Rose Robinson. Papers, 1936-1993&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Native American Educational Services Robert V. Dumont, Jr. Papers, 1942-2000&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Walter Bartky Papers, 1940-1947&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Century of Progress International Exposition Publications, 1933-1934&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Fairfax M Cone Papers, 1947-1971&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Hyde Park-Kenwood Community Conference Records, 1895-2011&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle>Hyde Park Historical Society Collection, 1830-2009&#13;</unittitle></archref><archref><unittitle/></archref>
     <archref><unittitle>See also the following <extref href="https://aiatsis.gov.au/research/guides-and-resources">resources at the Australian Institute of Aboriginal and Torres Strait Islander Studies Library</extref>:</unittitle></archref>   
     <archref><unittitle>Papers of Gerhardt Laves, MS 2188 and MS 2189</unittitle></archref>
     <archref><unittitle><extref href="https://iats.ent.sirsidynix.net.au/client/en_AU/external/search/detailnonmodal.detail.mainpanel.fielddisplay.linktonewsearch?qu=LAVES_G01">Laves’ language sound recordings, accession no. A004068</extref></unittitle></archref>
     <archref><unittitle><extref href="https://collection.aiatsis.gov.au/austlang/search">AIATSIS Collection’s AustLang Database</extref></unittitle></archref>
</relatedmaterial>
<controlaccess><head>Subject Headings</head>

<corpname>International Harvester Company&#13;</corpname><corpname>University of Chicago. Department of Anthropology&#13;</corpname><corpname/>
<subject>Anthropology--Australia&#13;</subject><subject>Bardi language&#13;</subject><subject>Boarding schools--United States&#13;</subject><subject>Chicago (Ill.). Police Department&#13;</subject><subject>Linguistics--Australia&#13;</subject><subject>Navajo Indians--Education&#13;</subject><subject>Navajo language&#13;</subject><subject>Navajo Nation, Arizona, New Mexico &amp; Utah&#13;</subject><subject>Police--United States&#13;</subject><subject>Urban renewal&#13;</subject><subject/>
<geogname>Hyde Park (Chicago, Ill.)&#13;</geogname><geogname>Kenwood (Chicago, Ill.)</geogname>



</controlaccess>
</descgrp>


<dsc type="combined">
<head>INVENTORY</head>

<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series I: Personal</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>Series I contains materials related to the Laves’ family life, including Gerhardt and Maxine Laves’ passports; daughters Jean and Elizabeth’s wedding invitations; and two short plays written and performed by childhood friends of the Laves children. Materials are arranged chronologically.</p>
</scopecontent>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>“Don’t Crush” Kwikpak mailing labels, 1916</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Gerhardt and Maxine Laves transcripts, 1923-1943</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Maxine Laves Vassar College transcript, 1971</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Jean and Elizabeth wedding announcements and invitations, 1961</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Maxine and Gerhardt Laves passports, 1970-1976</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>Gerhardt Laves University of Chicago Returning Scholar grades, 1975-1976</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>School of the Art Institute of Chicago welcome brochure, 1977</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle>Two short plays “The Inca” and “Treasure in the Andes,” undated</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">9</container>
<unittitle>Gerhardt Laves Blank Stationary, undated</unittitle></did></c02>
</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series II: Correspondence</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>Series II contains Gerhardt Laves’ correspondence with anthropologist Lester Hiatt, congressional representative Abner J. Mikva, and the Australian Institute of Aboriginal Studies. Materials are arranged roughly chronologically.</p>
</scopecontent>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">10</container>
<unittitle>Correspondence with Prof. Lester R. Hiatt, 1930-1982</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">11</container>
<unittitle>Correspondence with Congressman Abner J. Mikva, 1971</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">12</container>
<unittitle>Correspondence -- Australian Institute of Aboriginal Studies, 1979-1980</unittitle></did></c02>
</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series III: Professional Life and Associations</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>Series III contains materials from various occupations, institutions, and organizations in Gerhardt Laves’ professional life. Materials are divided into five subseries according to the organization and sorted roughly chronologically, following the trajectory of Laves’ involvement.</p>
</scopecontent>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 1:  Materials related to Navajo Nation </unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">13</container>
<unittitle>Fellowship Application Materials, 1932-1934</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">14</container>
<unittitle>Laves Reports on Navajo Language and Soil Conservation, 1936-1939</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">15</container>
<unittitle>Reference Manual for Guide Book to the Navajo Country materials, 1937-1939</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">16</container>
<unittitle>Guide Book to the Navajo Country II c/2 A-C, 1939</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">17</container>
<unittitle>Guide Book to the Navajo Country II c/2 D-L, undated</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>“Reference Data on Navajo Writing,” 1939</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>“Navajo and Hopi Directory,” 1939</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>“Navajo Consonants,” circa 1939</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>The Navajo Service News, vol. 2, no. 6, 1937</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>The Navajo Service News, vol. 2, no. 8, 1937</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>The Navajo Service News, vol. 2, no. 9, circa 1930s</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>The Navajo Service News, vol. 2, no. 10, circa 1930s</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle>The Navajo Service News, vol./no. unknown, circa 1930s</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">9</container>
<unittitle>Navajo Service School Bulletin, no. 3, “Land Management in the Navajo Area,” circa 1930s</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 2: International Harvester Company</unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">10</container>
<unittitle>Tractor Farming, 1940</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">11</container>
<unittitle>International Harvester Company brochures and pamphlets, 1940-1941 [1/2]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">12</container>
<unittitle>International Harvester Company brochures and pamphlets, 1940-1941 [2/2]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">13</container>
<unittitle>International Harvester speeches, 1945-1946</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">2</container>
<container type="folder">14</container>
<unittitle>International Harvester reports and pamphlets, 1946 [1/2]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">3</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>International Harvester reports and pamphlets, 1946 [2/2]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">3</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>International Harvester correspondence, 1944-1949</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">3</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>International Harvester conference materials, 1948</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">3</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>International Harvester course materials, 1949</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">3</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Recruitment of college graduates for International Harvester, 1949</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">3</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>Instructor’s Guide for Construction Equipment Division, International Harvester Company, circa 1940s</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">3</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>International Harvester informational pamphlets, circa 1940s</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">3</container>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle>International Harvester Education and Personnel materials, circa 1940s</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">3</container>
<container type="folder">9</container>
<unittitle>International Harvester engine training manuals, circa 1940s</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 3: Chicago Police Department</unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Law and Disorder: the Chicago Convention and its Aftermath, 1968</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Chicago Police Department informational brochures and Laves résumé, 1968-1971</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Chicago Police Department tours – black and white photographs, circa 1960s</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Chicago Police Exhibit Cruiser – black and white photographs, 1964 [1/3]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Chicago Police Exhibit Cruiser – black and white photographs, 1964 [2/3]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>Chicago Police Exhibit Cruiser – black and white photographs, 1964 [3/3]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>Police Department exhibits – black and white photographs, circa 1963 [1/2]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle>Police Department exhibits – black and white photographs, circa 1963 [2/2]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">9</container>
<unittitle>Chicago police in action – black and white photographs, circa 1963</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">10</container>
<unittitle>Photographs of Chicago police chief, circa 1960s</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">11</container>
<unittitle>Chicago Police Department – black and white photographs, circa 1960s</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 4: Hyde Park and Kenwood Neighborhood Materials</unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">12</container>
<unittitle>“The Hyde Park Kenwood Urban Renewal Years,” 1967</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">13</container>
<unittitle>Ray Elementary School Documents, 1972-1976 [1/2]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">14</container>
<unittitle>Ray Elementary School Documents, 1972-1976 [2/2]</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">4</container>
<container type="folder">15</container>
<unittitle>Hyde Park Historical Society cable car station renovation and restoration, 1979</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>


<c02 level="subseries">
<did><unittitle>Subseries 5: University of Chicago</unittitle></did>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Gerhardt Laves Hour Log Notebooks, circa 1972</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>International Union of Anthropological and Ethnological Sciences Information for Authors 1973</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>University of Chicago Returning Scholars Program information, 1975-1976</unittitle></did></c03>
<c03>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Anthropology at Chicago brochure, 1979</unittitle></did></c03>
</c02>

</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series IV: Publications by Others</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>Series IV contains Laves’ collection of published sociological studies and newspaper articles. Materials are arranged chronologically.</p>
</scopecontent>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Published Book Review by Gerhardt Laves, reprint, 1935</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>“Parenthood in a Free Nation,” University of Chicago Parent Education Project, 1954</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>H.G. Barnett, Being a Palauan, 1960</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle>“Vocabulary of ‘A Decade,’” circa 1960s</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">9</container>
<unittitle>Sociology reprints, 1967-1977</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">10</container>
<unittitle>The German Tribune, 1977</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">5</container>
<container type="folder">11</container>
<unittitle>Philip M. Glick, “The Politics of Conservation,” reprint, 1982</unittitle></did></c02>
</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series V: Research on the Bardi Language</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>Series V contains Laves’ notes from his linguistic research in the Bardi community in Australia during the late 1920s and early 1930s. Please note that while Laves used the term “Barda” in his documentation, the standard spelling for the language and the community is Bardi. Materials remain in their original groupings and order. Please note that the note cards have suffered significant water damage and as a result are extremely fragile. Papers are brittle and should be handled with care.</p>
</scopecontent>

<c02>

<did>
<container type="box">6</container>
<unittitle>Bardi Notes, no.1 – no.3, circa 1929-1931</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container type="box">7</container>
<unittitle>Bardi Notes, no.4 – no.6, circa 1929-1931</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container type="box">8</container>
<unittitle>Bardi Notes, no.6 (continued) – unnumbered [1/3], circa 1929-1931</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container type="box">9</container>
<unittitle>Bardi Notes, unnumbered [2/3] – unnumbered [3/3], circa 1929-1931</unittitle></did></c02>
</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series VI: Photographs</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>Series VI contains pre-1920s photographic glass plates by Laves’ father, Ulrich; Laves’ personal and research-related photographs from the 1910s-1930s; and Laves family and vacation photographs from the 1970s.</p>
<p>Laves numbered and labeled many of his photographs and stored them in groups of ten. Not all prints and films encompassed by group labels are present. Though often separated between photographic prints and films, some prints and films are grouped together. Materials remain in their original order and groupings with their original labels, and are arranged roughly chronologically. </p>
<p>Handwritten captions on some print backings contain racist stereotypes about Aboriginal individuals and communities, as well as hypotheses about featured individuals’ ethnic makeup. These materials are presented unaltered as historical resources in support of study and research. Inclusion of such materials does not constitute an endorsement of their content by the University of Chicago.</p>
<p>Box 10 includes photos of Laves family and friends; gatherings, holidays, and trips; the city of Chicago; University of Chicago; landscape photos; and photos from Laves’ research trip to Australia. This box includes prints and postcards labeled “Odd Prints” from 1926-1931; prints and films labeled G1-G54; prints and films labeled 101-570; and prints and postcards filed under “Select Prints” and “Repeat Prints.”</p>
<p>Names of individuals photographed during Laves’ research in Australia and their print number in Box 10 include:</p>
     <list>
          <item>Philip Shannon (466, 471, 517, 545)</item>
          <item>Lockland A. Macdonald; Myers Delaney; Mick Dougall; Billy Monklave (468)</item>
          <item>Jack Larry (466)</item>
          <item>Billy Monblond (471)</item>
          <item>Jack Cameron (520)</item>
          <item>George Yoke; Florence Shannon Macdonald (526)</item>
     </list>
<p>Box 11 includes images from sea voyages in Australia; encampments and supplies; Australian plants, animals, and landscapes; churches; photos in and around Lagrange, Cape Leveque, Lombadina Mission (in contemporary Lombadina and Djarindjin); Albany; Ulgundahi Island, and Sandon; and group and individual photos of Aboriginal adults and children, including individuals identified as members of the Karajarri community (spelled in Laves’ materials Karadjeri) and the Yawuru community (spelled in Laves’ materials Yuwari). This box includes films and prints labeled 601-1280 and films and prints labeled “Unfiled Film.”</p>     
<p>Names of individuals photographed during Laves’ research in Australia and their print number in Box 11 include:</p>
     <list>
          <item>Arthur (615, unnumbered prints in “Unfiled Film”)</item>
          <item>Timothy (615, 812, unnumbered print in “Unfiled Film”)</item>
          <item>Father Augustin Spangenberg (667, 680, unnumbered print in “Unfiled Film”</item>
          <item>Anton; Malachy; Gerard; Agnes; Philomena (667)</item>
          <item>Joe, Martin (686)</item>
          <item>Mr. Porter; Miss Stirling (795)</item>
          <item>Plytie (831, unnumbered print in “Unfiled Film”)</item>
          <item>Tommy (833, 853)</item>
          <item>Teddy, child of Tommy (853, 858, 859, 861)</item>
          <item>Sandy (853)</item>
          <item>Lucy, sister of Tommy (853, 859, 861)</item>
          <item>Frank (909)</item>
          <item>Peter (929, unnumbered print in “Unfiled Film”)</item>
          <item>Sandy (940, unnumbered print in “Unfiled Film”)</item>
          <item>Sam (944)</item>
          <item>Moses Waibog (1084)</item>
          <item>Annie, Mrs. Freddy Winmer (1099)</item>
          <item>The sister of Simon Williams (1104)</item>
          <item>Lockland A. Macdonald (labeled 467 under “Unfiled Film”)</item>
          <item>Alpré; Yanie (unnumbered print in “Unfiled Film”)</item>
     </list> 
</scopecontent>

<c02>

<did>
<container type="box">10</container>
<unittitle>Personal and Research Photographs and Negatives, 1916-1931 [1/2]</unittitle>
     <note>
          <list>
               <item>See series description for more information.</item>
          </list>
     </note>
</did></c02>
<c02>


<did>
<container type="box">11</container>
<unittitle>Personal and Research Photographs and Negatives, 1916-1931 [2/2]</unittitle>
     <note>
          <list>
               <item>See series description for more information.</item>
          </list>
     </note>
</did></c02>
     
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">12</container>
<unittitle>Glass Slide Negatives, 1916-1932</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">12</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Empty Glass Slide Envelopes</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<unittitle>Glass Slide Negatives, 1916-1932</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Ulrich Laves pre-1920s glass negatives packaging</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Empty Photograph Envelopes, circa 1927</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Film Negatives and Photos, 1976 [1/4]</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Film Negatives and Photos, 1976 [2/4]</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Film Negatives and Photos, 1976 [3/4]</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>Film Negatives and Photos, 1976 [4/4]</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">13</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>Unfiled film, undated</unittitle></did></c02>
</c01>


<c01 level="series">
<did><unittitle>Series VII: Oversize</unittitle></did>
<scopecontent><p>Series VII contains oversize publications and maps. Materials are sorted according to size.</p>
</scopecontent>

<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">14</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>International Harvester Dealer News, 1947</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">14</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>“Corruption of Chicago Police,” LIFE magazine, 1968</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>
<did>
<container type="box">14</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>The New York Times Book Review, 1970</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container>Oversize Folder 1</container>
<unittitle>Department of Agriculture Soil Conservation Service Maps</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container>Oversize Folder 1</container>
<unittitle>Preliminary Base Map Navajo and Zuni Reservation, Navajo District, 1936</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container>Oversize Folder 1</container>
<unittitle>San Juan River Watershed in Colorado, Arizona, Utah and New Mexico, 1938</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container>Oversize Folder 1</container>
<unittitle>Little Colorado River Watershed in Arizona and New Mexico, 1938</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container>Oversize Folder 1</container>
<unittitle>Rio Grande Watershed, 1938</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container>Oversize Folder 2</container>
<unittitle>Department of the Interior Office of Indian Affairs Maps</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container>Oversize Folder 2</container>
<unittitle>Navajo Country: Utah, Colorado, Arizona, and New Mexico, 1937</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container>Oversize Folder 2</container>
<unittitle>A Historical and Geographical Map of the Navajo Country, 1938</unittitle></did></c02>
<c02>

<did>
<container>Oversize Folder 2</container>
<unittitle>A Historical and Geographical Map of the Navajo Country, 1938</unittitle></did></c02>
</c01></dsc>
</archdesc></ead>
