<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 ead.xsd" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader audience="internal" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601">
   <eadid mainagencycode="US-txwabkc" countrycode="US" identifier="Baylor University/The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society/SKCA/41550/20220527082717" encodinganalog="856$u">urn:taro:baylor.kc.40060</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
   <titleproper>Soviet Union Masons Subject Files, <date normal="1978/1991" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">Inclusive: 1978-1991, Bulk: 1991.</date>
</titleproper>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<date normal="2022-05-27" encodinganalog="260$c" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">May 27, 2022</date>
<publisher>Baylor University, The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society</publisher>
</publicationstmt>
<notestmt>
<note>
<p>© 2022 The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society. All rights reserved.</p>
</note>
</notestmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding Aid was generated by The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society staff, using the STAR Knowledge Center for Archives (SKCA) task that automatically creates EAD files from the Archive's SKCA catalog records.
</creation>
<langusage><language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>


<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Collection Summary</head>
<repository encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository">
<corpname>Baylor University, <subarea>The Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society</subarea>
</corpname>
<extref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.baylor.edu/kestoncenter/" xlink:type="simple">http://www.baylor.edu/kestoncenter/</extref>
</repository>
<unitid encodinganalog="099" repositorycode="US-txwabkc" countrycode="US" label="Accession Number">60</unitid>
<origination label="Creator">
<corpname encodinganalog="110" source="lcnaf">Keston Institute, 1969 -</corpname></origination>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245" label="Title">Soviet Union Masons Subject Files</unittitle>
<unitdate normal="1978/1991" encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">Inclusive: 1978-1991, Bulk: 1991.</unitdate>
<physdesc encodinganalog="300$a">
<extent label="Quantity">1 folder</extent>
</physdesc>
<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract">The Soviet Union Mason Subject Files contain articles and a book chapter that detail the presence of Masons within the Soviet Union. They appear to cover the Masons’ presence in the late 20th century and include some other historical details.
</abstract>
<langmaterial encodinganalog="546$a" label="Language of the Material"><language langcode="rus">Russian</language></langmaterial>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech encodinganalog="340">
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Good.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>Communism with the named changed to Keston College in 1974, collected and publicized details about religious persecution behind the Iron Curtain, becoming “the voice of the voiceless.” After the collapse of communism in the 1990s, Keston College moved to Oxford and downsized due to
decreased funding. The name eventually changed to Keston Institute. In 2007, the Institute transferred the Keston Archive and Library to the newly created Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society at Baylor University.</p><p>Keston collected, verified, translated, and disseminated
information received from believers in the Soviet Union, Poland, Romania, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Yugoslavia, Bulgaria and other communist countries. The Keston Archive and Library housed numerous letters, petitions, reports and underground publications (Samizdat) from believers of various
denominations along with officially published books and periodicals.</p><p>The Keston Center collected five documents detailing the presence of Masons within the Soviet Union. These documents span from 1978-1991, with the bulk of the content from 1991.</p><p>Russian Freemasonry began after the first
quarter of the 18th century with "lodges set by British, German and Dutch” (Kuzmishin). In 1772, Russian Masons had their first ethnically Russian Provincial Grand Master, Ivan Yelagin. Freemasonry was banned during a short period at the turn of the 19th century. Although Alexander I ruled during
the legalization of Freemasonry, he banned it in 1822 over allegations that organizations with Masonic ties were plotting a coup. Specifically, his edict prevented the majority of Masonic members  who were public servants from being involved with Masonic groups. In 1905, “the Council of the Grand
Order of Eastern France opened lodges in Moscow and St. Petersburg” (Smetanina and Kadik). Around that time, Masonic groups adopted a political nature as evidenced by the Supreme Council of Russian Masons’ abandonment of many identifying characteristics of Freemasons in 1910. After the fall of
Soviet rule, French Masons helped their Russian brethren with the re-formation of the Grand Lodge of Russia. In 2001, the Russian Regular Grand Lodge broke from the Grand Lodge of Russia. Eventually, at least two more groups joined the Russian Regular Grand Lodge, and “in 2008, [it became] the
United Grand Lodge of Russia” (Kuzmishin).</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520$b">
   <head>Scope and Content</head>
   <p>The Soviet Union Mason Subject Files include articles from newspapers and a magazine, as well as a chapter from a book. They appear to provide details of the Masons’ presence during the late 20th century and also contain other historical details.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement encodinganalog="351">
<head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The Keston Center received the Soviet Union Mason materials in one folder organized chronologically. The current filing system has been preserved.</p>
   <p>The Soviet Union Mason Subject Files are organized in one series: I. General.</p>
</arrangement>
<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
<head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to the Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public
domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the
public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
<head>Use/Re-use Restrictions</head>
<p>The collection is open for research.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
<head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Soviet Union Masons Subject Files, Box #, Folder #, Keston Center for Religion, Politics, and Society, Baylor University.</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession No. 60.</p></acqinfo>
<processinfo encodinganalog="583">
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Described by Larisa Seago.</p>
<p>Archivist''s Notes:  The Keston Center is grateful to Tesia Juraschek for her assistance in preparing this finding aid.</p>
</processinfo>
<descgrp>
<head>Related Resources</head>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544">
<head>Related references</head>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://www.thesquaremagazine.com/mag/article/202004russian-freemasonry/." xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Kuzmishin, Eugene L. “Russian Freemasonry.” The Square. The Square Magazine. Accessed December 13, 2021.</extref>
</bibref>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://brill.com/fileasset/downloads_products/31789_Brochure.pdf." xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Smetanina, S. I., and Vadim Kadik. Freemasonry in Russia: Early Sources from the Russian State Archive of Ancient Acts, Moscow. Moscow: IDC
Publishers, n.d. Accessed December 13, 2021.</extref>
</bibref>
</relatedmaterial>
</descgrp>
</descgrp>
<controlaccess>
<head>Index Terms</head>
<controlaccess>
<head>Subjects (Organizations)</head>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Keston College -- Archives.</corpname>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Keston Institute -- Archives.</corpname>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Subjects</head>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Freemasonry -- Soviet Union -- History -- 20th century.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Freemasons -- Russia (Federation).</subject>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Genres</head>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Articles.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.)</genreform>
</controlaccess>
</controlaccess>
<dsc type="combined">

<c01 id="recSUMASONSF.level1.000007353" level="series">
<did>
<unitid>1</unitid>
<unittitle>General</unittitle>
<unitdate normal="1978/1991" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1978-1991</unitdate>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech>
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Good.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>The series contains a group of articles and one chapter that detail the presence of Masons in the Soviet Union.</p><p>The series is in good condition.</p>
</bioghist>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession No. 60.</p></acqinfo>
</descgrp>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Masons. General</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1978 September, 1989, 1991</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>

