<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="dc" scriptencoding="iso15924">
      <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="waww" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv774485" encodinganalog="identifier" identifier="80444/xv774485">HTMWCMss717.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the Lisa Uddin Papers <date encodinganalog="date" calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2004/2014" type="inclusive">2004-2014</date>
            </titleproper>
            <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Uddin (Lisa) Papers</titleproper>
            <author encodinganalog="creator">Dana Bronson</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Whitman College and Northwest Archives</publisher>
            <date encodinganalog="date" calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2021">2021</date>
            <address>
               <addressline>345 Boyer Avenue</addressline>
               <addressline>Walla Walla, WA 99362</addressline>
               <addressline>Archives@whitman.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/</addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2021-01-20</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>
            <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">Finding aid written in English.</language>
         </langusage>
         <descrules>Finding aid based on
          DACS (<title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content Standard</title>), 2nd
          Edition.</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="marc21" type="inventory">
      <did>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
         <repository>
            <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Whitman College and Northwest Archives</corpname>
            <address>
               <addressline>345 Boyer Avenue</addressline>
               <addressline>Walla Walla, WA 99362</addressline>
               <addressline>Archives@whitman.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/</addressline>
            </address>
         </repository>
         <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Lisa Uddin Papers</unittitle>
         <origination label="creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="no2012066211" source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="100">Uddin, Lisa</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="US" repositorycode="waww">WCMss.717</unitid>
         <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">3 linear feet</extent>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">3 record cartons</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">23 cds</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">1 videocassettes</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2004/2014" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">2004-2014</unitdate>
         <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">Lisa Uddin is a professor of Art History and Visual Culture Studies at Whitman College. The Lisa Uddin Papers consists of the research materials for <title render="italic">Zoo Renewal: White Flight and the Animal Ghetto</title>, a design history of zoological parks in the United States. The collection spans from approximately 2004-2014, and contains ephemera and research materials from zoos in Detroit, Atlanta, Washington D.C., Seattle, San Diego, Portland, Rochester, Providence, Baltimore, and Toronto.</abstract>
      </did>
      <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
    
         <p>Collection is open for research.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
    
         <p>Donated to the Whitman College and Northwest Archives by Lisa Uddin on May 23, 2019. The accession number associated with this donation is 2018-048.</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <bioghist encodinganalog="5450_">
    
         <p>Lisa Uddin was born on June 5, 1974 in Toronto, Ontario. She earned a Bachelor's degree in North American Studies from McGill University, a Master's degree in media Studies from Concordia University (Montreal), and a Master's and Ph.D. in Visual and Cultural Studies from the University of Rochester. Before moving to Walla Walla, she held research fellowships at the Smithsonian Institution, Brown University, the University of Minnesota, and taught at the Corcoran College of Art and Design in Washington D.C. She began working as a professor of Art History and Visual Culture Studies at Whitman College in 2012.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <phystech>
    
         <p>Born-digital and audiovisual materials have not been transferred and may not be available to researchers. Researchers may request access copies.  To request that material be transferred please contact the Whitman College and Northwest Archives</p>  
      </phystech>
      <processinfo encodinganalog="583">
    
         <p>Material was transferred into archival boxes, but original folders were retained. No system of arrangement has been imposed below the collection level.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
    
         <p>The Lisa Uddin Papers consists of the research materials for <title render="italic">Zoo Renewal: White Flight and the Animal Ghetto</title>, a design history of zoological parks in the United States. The collection spans from approximately 2004-2014, and contains ephemera and research materials from zoos in Detroit, Atlanta, Washington D.C., Seattle, San Diego, Portland, Rochester, Providence, Baltimore, and Toronto. The collection includes visitor guides and maps, brochures, postcards, souvenir books and videos, print and radio advertisements, magazine and newspaper clippings, wildlife conservation documentaries, annual reports, institutional correspondence and management records, architectural drawings, and photographs. </p>
         <p>The collection reflects Uddin's particular interest in the revitalization of the U.S. zoo space and institutional identity in the 1960s and 1970s as it pertains to urbanization, wildlife conservation, and American race relations. </p>  
      </scopecontent>
      <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
    
         <p>Because of the assembled nature of this collection, copyright status varies across the collection. Copyright is assumed to be held by the original creator or current repository of individual items in the collection; these items are expected to pass into the public domain 120 years after their creation. The Whitman College and Northwest Archives is not authorized to grant permission to publish or reproduce materials from this collection.</p>  
      </userestrict>
      <controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Zoos--Design and construction</subject>
            <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Zoos--Symbolic aspects</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh2010118558" source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Wildlife conservation--United States</subject>
            <subject authfilenumber="sh98001733" source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Urban parks</subject>
         </controlaccess>
      </controlaccess>
  
   </archdesc>
</ead>

