<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="dc" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv88189" identifier="80444/xv88189" mainagencycode="waww" encodinganalog="identifier">HTM_WCMss99.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the Walla Walla Union-Bulletin photographs<date calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1949/2010" type="inclusive"/></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Walla Walla Union-Bulletin photographs</titleproper>
        <author encodinganalog="creator">Colby Dragon</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Whitman College and Northwest Archives</publisher>
        <date encodinganalog="date" calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20102022">2010, 2022</date>
        <address>
          <addressline>345 Boyer Avenue</addressline>
          <addressline>Walla Walla, WA 99362</addressline>
          <addressline>Archives@whitman.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>https://library.whitman.edu/archives/</addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-03-21</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn" encodinganalog="language">Finding aid written in English.</language>
      </langusage>
      <descrules>Finding aid based on DACS (Describing Archives: A Content Standard), 2nd Edition.</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="marc21" type="inventory">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Whitman College and Northwest Archives</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Walla Walla Union-Bulletin photographs</unittitle>
      <origination>
        <corpname rules="rda" source="local" encodinganalog="110">Walla Walla Union-Bulletin</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid countrycode="US" repositorycode="waww" encodinganalog="099">WCMss.099</unitid>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">92.6 linear feet</extent>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">95 small flat boxes and 7 filing cabinets</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1949/2010" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1949-circa 2010</unitdate>
      <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">The Walla Walla Union-Bulletin photographs houses the negatives and prints taken by newspaper photographers documenting people, places, and events of the Walla Walla Valley from 1949 to circa 2010. The Walla Walla Union-Bulletin is a daily newspaper providing coverage of Walla Walla Valley since 1938.</abstract>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn" encodinganalog="546">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <p>The negatives from the years 1949 to 1969 are open for research. The negatives from the 2021-001 accession, dating circa 1960 to circa 2010, are closed for research until further processing occurs.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <p>The negatives and photographs dating from circa 1960 to circa 2010 were donated to the Whitman College and Northwest Archives by Dian Ver Valen, editor of the WWUB, on 2021 May 21.  The accession number associated with this donation is 2021-001. The negatives from 1949 to 1969 were donated prior to 1985, and there is no known accession information regarding this earlier donation.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="5451_">
      <p>The Walla Walla Bulletin began publishing as a daily newspaper in Walla Walla, Washington in 1906. Four year later in 1910, John G. Kelly purchased the Bulletin and remained its publisher for 45 years. Kelly purchased the Walla Walla Morning Union in 1934. The Bulletin and the Union continued to be separate operations for a time, only publishing joint Union-Bulletin issues on Sundays beginning on May 27, 1934. On January 16, 1938 the first daily issue of the Walla Walla Union-Bulletin was published. In October 1971, the Seattle Times Company purchased the Union-Bulletin.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
      <p>The Walla Walla Union-Bulletin photographs, which date from 1949 to circa 2010, houses the negatives and prints of the Walla Walla Union-Bulletin newspaper. The negatives in this collection were taken by newspaper photographers capturing local people, places, and events, some of which were included in newspaper articles written about life in the Walla Walla Valley.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
      <p>The donor retains copyright of these materials but has allowed the Whitman College and Northwest Archives to create reproductions for non-commercial, educational uses including, but not limited to, personal research and scholarship. Permission to publish or reproduce materials in this collection for commercial purposes, including, but not limited to, publication, sale or advertisement, must be secured from the Walla Walla Union-Bulletin.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <processinfo>
      <p>In the 1980s, minimal processing work occured for the portions of the collection covering 1949 to 1969. Negatives were rehoused in acid-free boxes, organized into rough chronological order, and a small portion of them were rehoused in acid-free sleeves. The vast majority of these negatives remain in their original sleeves. The 2021-001 accession, which dates from circa 1960 to 2010, has recieved no processing interventions at this time.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Journalism</subject>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>

