<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601">
    <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="mthi" identifier="80444/xv25369" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv25369" encodinganalog="identifier">MTLohforestanderson.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the Forrest Anderson Oral
			 History Project 
			 <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2010/2011" encodinganalog="date">2011-2014</date></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Forrest Anderson Oral
			 History Project</titleproper>
        <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding aid prepared by Anneliese
			 Warhank</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher"> Montana Historical Society
			 Research Center </publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline> Helena, MT </addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation> Finding aid encoded by Anneliese Warhank 
		  <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2014">2014</date></creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in<language encodinganalog="language" langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn"> English</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" type="guide" relatedencoding="marc21" encodinganalog="341$c">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Montana Historical Society, Research Center Archives</corpname>
        <subarea encodinganalog="852$b">Archives</subarea>
        <address>
          <addressline>225 N. Roberts</addressline>
          <addressline>PO Box 201201</addressline>
          <addressline>Helena MT 59620-1201</addressline>
          <addressline>(406) 444-2681</addressline>
          <addressline>mhslibrary@mt.gov</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="us" repositorycode="mthi"> OH
		  2314</unitid>
      <origination>
        <corpname source="lcnaf" rules="aacr2" encodinganalog="110" role="creator">Montana Historical Society</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Forrest Anderson Oral History
		  Project</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2011/2014" encodinganalog="245$f">2011-2014</unitdate>
      <physdesc>
        <genreform>Sound Recording</genreform>
      </physdesc>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a"> 6 interviews, with summaries</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">Forrest Anderson Oral History Project
		  includes 6 oral history interview conducted by Brian Shovers as part of a much
		  larger research project related to the administration of Governor Forrest
		  Anderson, and his four year term, 1968-1972, during which state government was
		  reorganized and a new constitution drafted and approved by Montanans. Topics
		  covered in the interview may cover each person's background, their work with
		  Governor Anderson during his years as a Montana Politician, their role in the
		  1971 Executive Reorganization of the state's government offices, and their role
		  in the 1972 Constitutional Convention to re-write the Montana Constitution.
		  Interviewees include Newell Anderson, Tom Mangan, Diana Dowling, Alec Hansen,
		  Rich Bechtel, and George Bousliman.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="5451_">
      <head>Biographical Information</head>
      <p>Forrest H. Anderson was born in Helena, Montana, on January 20, 1913,
		  the son of Oscar Anderson, a Swedish immigrant, and his wife Mary O'Keefe, an
		  Irish immigrant. He attended public schools in Helena, and then studied pre-law
		  at the University of Montana in Missoula. He got his law degree from Columbus
		  University in Washington, D.C.</p>
      <p>Anderson was admitted to practice before the Montana Supreme Court in
		  1938. He was elected to the Montana legislature in 1942, and also served as
		  Lewis and Clark County Attorney. He was elected to the Montana Supreme Court in
		  1952 and served 4 years, before running for Montana Attorney General in 1956.
		  He was re-elected as Attorney General three times. During the 1959 State Prison
		  riot, he personally negotiated with the prisoners in helping to resolve the
		  conflict. In 1968 he defeated incumbent Governor Tim Babcock, largely on an
		  anti-sales tax platform. His slogan was "Pay More, What For?"</p>
      <p>Anderson's one term as Governor was filled with controversy, but made
		  significant accomplishments. The early years of his administration were
		  dominated by conflict with Frank Dunkle, Fish and Game Commissioner, and the
		  Fish and Game Commission, over the direction of the Commission on environmental
		  issues and on fisherman and hunter access issues. In 1971 the Legislature
		  deadlocked over a sales tax. Anderson called two special sessions to deal with
		  the issue, and finally resorted to putting the tax to a public referendum. The
		  sales tax was resoundingly defeated. Anderson actively supported the Montana
		  Constitutional Convention. He later viewed his greatest Gubernatorial
		  accomplishments as the Executive Reorganization, which combined several hundred
		  agencies, boards, commissions, and councils, into 19 Departments; and his
		  establishment of the Board of Investments to remove state funds from low yield
		  bank accounts to place them in higher yield investment accounts. Anderson did
		  not run for re-election due to health problems.</p>
      <p>Anderson was also active in many civic and fraternal organizations. He
		  married Evelyn Samson in 1941. They had three children. Forrest Anderson died
		  in Helena on July 20, 1989, of a self-inflicted gunshot wound.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
      <p>Collection consists of 6 oral histories all in digital format. Oral
		  Histories total approximately five hours in audio recording. All include a
		  summary index of the interview.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <odd>
      <p>Researchers requesting copies of interviews should refer to the OH
		  number and name of interviewee when ordering.</p>
    </odd>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
      <p>Inventory is arranged by item, with each oral history interview listed
		  by the name of the interviewee. An abstract for each interview is provided in
		  the inventory to allow keyword searchability. The abstract includes the number
		  of cassettes, CDs or transcript pages for the interview, as appropriate.
		  Researchers requesting copies of interviews should refer to the OH number,
		  recording number (if it exists) and the name of the interviewee when
		  ordering.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
      <p>The Montana Historical Society is the owner of the materials in the
		  Research Library and makes available reproductions for research, publication,
		  and other uses. Written permission must be obtained from the Research Library
		  before any reproduction use. The Society does not necessarily hold copyright to
		  all of the materials in the collections. In some cases, permission for use may
		  require seeking additional authorization from the copyright owners.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <p>[OH number][Interview title] Montana Historical Society Research
		  Center. Archives. Helena, Montana.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <p>Interviews were conducted by Brian Shovers, Library Manager at the
		  Montana Historical Society Research Center, to aid the research for his article
		  "Forrest Anderson, the 1972 Constitution, and the Reshaping of Montana" which
		  appeared in the Spring 2014 issue of Montana: The Magazine of Western
		  History.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <controlaccess>
      <p> This collection is indexed under the following headings. Researchers
		  desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search under
		  these terms. </p>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh" rules="aacr2">Environmental
			 policy--Montana.</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh" rules="aacr2">Prison
			 riots--Montana</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh" rules="aacr2">Administrative agencies--Reorganization.</subject>
        <subject altrender="nodisplay" source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690">Oral
			 Histories</subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh" rules="aacr2">Montana</geogname>
        <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh" rules="aacr2">Montana.
			 Constitutional Convention (1971-1972)</geogname>
        <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh" rules="aacr2">Montana--Politics and government. </geogname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="lcsh">Oral history</genreform>
        <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="lcsh">Sound
			 recordings</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay">Montana</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay">Oral Histories</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay">Sound Recordings</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay">Politics and
			 Politicians</subject>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc type="in-depth">
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <unitid>OH 2314</unitid>
          <unittitle>NEWELL ANDERSON INTERVIEW</unittitle>
          <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">2 CD(s), Summary </extent>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202">
          <p>In this June 2, 2014 interview Newell Anderson recalls his
				memories of his father, Forrest Anderson, growing up, including what he
				remembers of his father's political career; Executive reorganization. Also
				discusses his father's declining health; his work with seven different
				governors; and a few anecdotes about his father.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>OH 2308</unitid>
          <unittitle>TOM MANGAN INTERVIEW</unittitle>
          <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">1 CD(s), Summary</extent>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
          <p>In this August 15, 2011 interview Tom Mangan discusses his youth
				and how he came to know and work for Forrest Anderson; Tom's role in the
				executive reorganization; crackdown on gambling and prostitution; Forrest's
				failing health, struggle with pain, and suicide. He also discusses his work as
				a private investigator in the 1981 prison riots and reforms to the corrections
				system that followed. </p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <unitid>OH 2308</unitid>
          <unittitle>DIANA DOWLING INTERVIEW</unittitle>
          <physdesc>
            <extent>1 CD(s), Summary</extent>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202">
          <p>In this November 30, 2012 interview Diana Dowling discusses how
				she got involved in the executive reorganization; what occurred during the
				process; its impact. Her role in the 1972 Constitutional Convention, why it
				worked. Also discusses her role in state legislation after the Con Con,
				including the beginning of the state lottery in 1987. </p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <unitid>OH 2308</unitid>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">ALEC HANSEN INTERVIEW</unittitle>
          <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">1 CD(s), Summary</extent>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202">
          <p>In this August 17, 2011 interview Alec Hansen discusses growing up
				in Butte, working as a miner for the Anaconda Copper Mining Company and later
				as a reporter for the Montana Standard; Urban Renewal in butte; executive
				reorganization; sales tax ballot issue; re-writing of the Montana Constitution;
				Anderson's efforts with all three of these; anecdotes from Alec on the type of
				person Forrest Anderson was.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <unitid>OH 2308</unitid>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">RICH BECHTEL INTERVIEW</unittitle>
          <physdesc>
            <extent>1 CD(s), Summary</extent>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202">
          <p>In this December 4, 2012 interview Rich Bechtel discusses how the
				1972 Constitutional Convention came about; his job of staffing the Legislative
				Committee; other involved in the Con Con; the creation of the new constitution
				and its passage and the more open government as a result; his thoughts and
				feelings on Forrest Anderson as governor.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <unitid>OH 2308</unitid>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">GEORGE BOUSLIMAN
				INTERVIEW</unittitle>
          <physdesc>
            <extent>1 CD(s), Summary</extent>
          </physdesc>
        </did>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202">
          <p>In this August 10, 2011 interview George Bousliman discusses the
				executive reorganization staff; reasons behind Forrest Anderson's success as
				governor and his administrative style; the importance of citizen groups; the
				importance of a new constitution on issues of privacy and the environment; the
				economic impact of reorganization. </p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>

