<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601">
    <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="mthi" identifier="80444/xv79425" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv79425" encodinganalog="identifier">
      mtllot025.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title"> Guide to the Paul Eno photograph collection <date encodinganalog="date" type="inclusive" normal="1890/1955">circa 1890-circa 1955</date></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Eno, Paul photograph collection</titleproper>
        <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding aid prepared by Amanda Graham </author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher"> Montana Historical Society</publisher>
        <date encodinganalog="date" normal="2010" calendar="gregorian" era="ce">2010</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation> Finding aid encoded by Amanda Graham <date encodinganalog="date" normal="2010" calendar="gregorian" era="ce">2010</date>. </creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in
        <language encodinganalog="language" langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn"> English.</language>
      </langusage>
      <descrules>Finding aid based on DACS ( <title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content
          Standard</title>)2nd Edition.</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="marc21">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Montana Historical Society<subarea encodinganalog="852$b">Photograph Archives</subarea></corpname>
      </repository>

      <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="us" repositorycode="mthi">Lot 025</unitid>
      <origination>
        <persname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="100" role="collector"> Eno, Paul </persname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Paul Eno photograph collection</unittitle>
      <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" normal="1890/1960" certainty="circa"> circa 1890 - circa 1960</unitdate>
      <unitdate encodinganalog="245$g" type="bulk" normal="1905/1955" certainty="circa">circa 1905-circa 1955</unitdate>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">3 boxes</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">191 b&amp;w photographic prints</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">145 b&amp;w film negatives</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">2 b&amp;w glass plate negatives</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">This collection consists of images acquired from the Mai Wah
        Noodle Parlor and Wai Chong Tai Company buildings in Butte, Montana. Approximately half of
        the images in this collection document the Chinese American presence in Butte, Montana, from
        the early 1900’s through the 1950’s. The bulk of these images are views of Chinese
        businesses and snapshots of groups and individuals. They include views of Huie Pock’s
        mercantile and other Chinese-owned businesses in Butte, portraits of Chinese families, and
        snapshots of other groups and individuals. The other half of the collection consists of film
        negatives of the Rev. Martin D. Hudtloff family in Montana and Washington State, circa
        1915-1925. </abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English </language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="5451_">
      <p>Chinese Americans in Butte</p>
      <p>Chinese immigrants first came to Butte, Montana, in great numbers in the late 1860’s,
        attracted by work in placer gold mines and later by railroad construction projects. By the
        late 1880’s, nearly 2,500 Chinese Americans reportedly resided in Butte, and by the early
        1900’s, Butte’s Chinatown had become well-established. As the gold mining boom ended and the
        railroads were completed, Butte’s Chinese were forced out of their jobs by discriminatory
        laws and ordinances meant to discourage cheap labor. In addition, the 1882 Chinese Exclusion
        Act barred Chinese laborers from immigrating to the United States. By the 1890’s, Butte’s
        Chinese residents were turning to work in the service industry.</p>
      <p>One of the first Chinese districts in Butte arose in the Galena-Mercury neighborhood
        between Colorado and Arizona streets. Here, Dr. Huie Pock practiced Eastern medicine and ran
        a mercantile, while numerous other Chinese Americans operated general stores, laundries,
        noodle parlors, and herb shops. The early Chinese in Butte held onto much of their cultural
        heritage. They built places of worship, and many retained the dress and traditions of their
        homeland. In addition, they embraced some new world institutions, such as the Chinese
        Baptist Mission, established on Mercury Street in 1892. Some Chinese businesses thrived
        during this period despite growing hostile sentiment toward Chinese immigrants. However,
        during the first quarter of the 20th century, the Chinese population in Butte began to
        decline as Chinese Americans sought work in larger cities like San Francisco with
        flourishing Chinatowns.</p>
      <p>By the early 1940’s, the population of Chinese in Butte had dwindled to just a few
        families. One of these families was the Chinn family. Albert (Yu Fong) Chinn had immigrated
        to America by 1912, settling in Butte with his wife, Lou, and daughter, Katherine. Albert
        became a merchant and by 1930 he had fathered nine children. He lived with his family at 21
        West Mercury St. The Chinn family retained ownership of what are today two of the last
        remaining and best-preserved buildings of Butte’s Chinatown: the Wai Chong Tai Company
        building (15 West Mercury) and the Mai Wah Noodle Parlor building (17 West Mercury). William
        Chinn, a son of Albert Chinn, owned the buildings in the 1940’s, and rented the ground floor
        of 17 West Mercury to Paul Eno. Eno ran a lock and repair shop out of the building from late
        1940’s until his death in 1986. His parents were Martha and Edgar Eno.</p>
      <p>Martin D. Hudtloff family</p>
      <p>Martha Eno and her family, the Hudtloff’s, moved to Butte from Wisconsin in the early
        1890’s. Martha married Edgar Eno in 1901, and the couple had five children: Paul, Edward,
        Florentine, William, and Helen. Upon Edgar’s death in 1946, Martha moved to Vancouver, WA,
        to live with her son, Edward.</p>
      <p>Martha’s brother was Martin D. Hudtloff. In 1893, Hudtloff began serving as pastor of the
        new St. Mark German Lutheran Church in Butte, a position he would hold for over 40 years.
        The congregation laid the cornerstone for their present church at the corner of Silver and
        Montana streets in June 1907. Martin was married to Julia Detloff, the daughter of Prussian
        immigrants William and Wilhelmina Detloff. Martin and Julia had five children: Walter W. G.
        (1894-1916), Arthur G. (1895-1968), Esther H. (1898-1950), Dorothy (1900-1908), and Martin
        J. (1902-1969). Dorothy died of spinal meningitis at age seven, and Walter died of a
        lingering illness at 22.</p>
      <p>Arthur G. Hudtloff attended a year at the University of Montana (1914-1915). By 1916, he
        had moved to Seattle to study at the University of Washington, and was residing next to the
        campus at 4339 11th Ave NE. After graduation, Arthur served for some time in the U.S. Navy,
        and rose to at least the rank of Lieutenant, Junior Grade. He later moved to Tacoma,
        Washington, where he became the first superintendent of schools in the Clover Park School
        District in Lakewood, Washington. A middle school in Lakewood, Washington, a suburb of
        Tacoma, now bears his name. </p>
      <p>Esther Hudtloff married Lloyd Sowders and settled in Detroit.</p>
      <p>Martin J. Hudtloff graduated from the University of Montana and moved to Washington, D.C.,
        where he served as Director of the Transportation Service Division for the U.S. Department
        of Agriculture. Martin died in 1969 and is buried at Arlington National Cemetery. </p>
      <p>Julia’s mother, Wilhelmina Detloff, lived with the Hudtloff’s in Butte after her husband
        William died, and later settled in Spokane, Washington, with her nephew, George Detloff, and
        his family.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
      <p>This collection consists of images that Hal Waldrup retrieved from the Mai Wah Noodle
        Parlor and Wai Chong Tai Company buildings in Butte, Montana. The photographs were collected
        by Paul Eno and about half document the Chinese American presence in Butte from the early
        1900’s through the 1950’s. The bulk of these images are views of Chinese businesses and
        snapshots of groups and individuals. They include views of Huie Pock’s mercantile and other
        Chinese-owned businesses in Butte, portraits of Chinese families, including the Chinn
        family, and snapshots of other groups and individuals; most are unidentified. About half of
        these photographs are of an unidentified Chinese American man posed at locations in and
        around Butte, Montana.</p>
      <p>The other half of the collection consists of film negatives of the Rev. Martin D. Hudtloff
        family in Montana and Washington State, circa 1915-1925. These include portraits of the
        family, many views of a family visit to Yellowstone National Park (ca. 1925), Arthur at the
        University of Washington and his service in the Navy, Esther Hudtloff with friends, and the
        George Detloff family in Spokane, Washington. </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
      <p>The photographs are arranged into three subgroups</p>
    </arrangement>
    <altformavail encodinganalog="530">
      <p>Copy prints were made of all the vintage negatives. </p>
    </altformavail>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
      <p>The Montana Historical Society is the owner of the materials in the Photograph Archives
        collections and makes available reproductions for research, publication, and other uses.
        Written permission must be obtained from the Photograph Archives before any reproduction
        use. The Society does not necessarily hold copyright to all of the materials in its
        collections. In some cases, permission for use may require seeking additional authorization
        from the copyright owners.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <p>Paul Eno photograph collection. Lot 025. Box and folder number. Montana Historical
        Society Photograph Archives, Helena, Montana.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <p>Acquisition information available upon request.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo encodinganalog="583">
      <p>Hal Waldrup donated this collection to the MHS Museum where it was accessioned as 86.79 and
        90.57. It was then transferred to the Photograph Archives and received as a single accession
        (PAc 87-13).</p>
    </processinfo>
    <controlaccess>
      <p> This collection is indexed under the following headings. Researchers desiring materials
        about related topics, persons, or places should search under these terms.</p>
      <controlaccess>
        <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Huie, Pock </persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Hudtloff, Martin D.</persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Hudtloff, Julia </persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Hudtloff, Arthur G. </persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Hudtloff, Martin J. </persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Hudtloff, Esther H. </persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Detloff, George </persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="600" source="local">Detloff, Wilhelmina </persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh">University of Washington </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Chinese Americans -- Montana -- Butte </subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Chinese American businesspeople -- Montana -- Butte </subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Navies -- Officers </subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Church buildings -- Montana -- Butte </subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Butte (Mont.) </geogname>     
        <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Chinatown (Butte, Mont.) </geogname>
        <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Puget Sound (Wash.) </geogname>
        <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh">Seattle (Wash.) </geogname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">Thomson's Studio </corpname>
        <corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">Elite Studio </corpname>
        <corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">Angelo (Butte, Mont.) </corpname>
        <corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">Gibson Studio </corpname>
        <corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">Dusseau &amp; Thomson </corpname>
        <corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">Schoettner (Butte, Mont.) </corpname>
        <corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">H. D. Weenink </corpname>
        <corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">W. F. Song (San Francisco, Calif.) </corpname>
        <corpname encodinganalog="710" source="local">Lai Yung </corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject altrender="nodisplay" source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690">Montana</subject>
        <subject altrender="nodisplay" source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690">Chinese Americans</subject>
        <subject altrender="nodisplay" source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690">German Americans</subject>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Detailed Description of the Collection</head>
      <c01 level="subgrp">
        <did>
          <unitid encodinganalog="099">Subgroup I</unitid>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Chinese Americans in Butte </unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 level="series">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series I</unitid>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Huie Pock </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1/1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Portrait of Huie Pock (October 15, 1914, by
                Thomson’s Studio, Butte, Mont.); interior and exterior views of Huie Pock’s medical
                office and mercantile (ca. 1908-1910), two include his son, Quong Pock Huie; large
                group portrait of men and women, including Huie Pock, in front of First Presbyterian
                Church in Butte (by Elite Studio, Butte, Mont.).</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$g" type="bulk">circa 1908-1914</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="item">
            <did>
              <container type="oversized">M1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Huie Pock’s office/mercantile interior, with son
                Quong Pock Huie</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1908</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="item">
            <did>
              <container type="oversized">M2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Sam Huie’s Tailor Shop interior</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1908</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="item">
            <did>
              <container type="oversized">M3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Hum Fay’s Palace Chop House interior</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1910</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="series">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series II</unitid>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Other Chinese Businesses in Butte, Montana
            </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1/1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Exterior of Mai Wah Noodles &amp; Chop Suey
                Building</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1950</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="series">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series III</unitid>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Chinese Individuals and Groups </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">½</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Chinese families and groups - portraits: Albert (Yu
                Fong) and Lou Chinn with children, including Howard, William, Albert, Youngee,
                Kenneth, Edward, Susan, Katherine, and Pearl (family portraits taken ca. 1920 and
                ca. 1927, by Gibson Studio, Butte, Mont.); woman posing with young boy and girl and
                older woman; group portrait of six children in Chinese dress (Angelo, Butte, 1910);
                group portraits of boys and young man, and a mother with children; group of male
                Chinese college students with Stanford and University of California pennants (ca.
                1910); portrait of young women in front of “Woolman House”; portrait of two older
                men (ca. 1960) </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1910 - circa 1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1/3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Chinese boys and men - individual portraits by
                Montana photographers: young boy wearing elaborate hat with tassels and young men in
                western suits and Chinese dress - portraits by Dusseau &amp; Thomson (Butte, Mont.),
                H. D. Weenink (Dillon, Mont.) and Schoettner Studio (Butte, Mont.) </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1/4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Chinese boys and men - individual portraits by W. F.
                Song (San Francisco, CA, Lai Yung (Sappatpo, Canton) and unidentified photographers </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1900 - circa 1950</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1/5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Chinese girls and women – individual portraits (most
                ca. 1940's): Unidentified woman holding a fan by The Palmer Studio (Butte, Mont.),
                hand-colored portrait of girl; young women; young woman in numerous poses; young
                woman seated on couch with baby; and other unidentified women </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$g" type="bulk">circa 1940 - circa 1950</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1/6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Chinese individuals and groups, most unidentified
                (1940's and 1950's): Young women; young men in Air Force uniforms; views of young
                men in China (T. K. Fang, S. F. Chow, and S. H. Lin) with a small folder advertising
                C. H. Wong Photo Studio, Shanghai, China; close-up of snow on pine tree signed by S.
                H. Lin, woman and man seated on couch; young people standing at the base of roller
                coaster possibly at Columbia Gardens in Butte, Montana </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1940 - circa 1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="series">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series IV</unitid>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Unidentified Chinese Man </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Unidentified Chinese man (ca. 1940's and early
                1950's) Portraits and posing with birthday meal; seated on couch and standing next
                to tinsel-laden Christmas tree; standing in front of entrance to Paul Eno’s shop,
                Butte, MT; with car in front of Paul Eno’s shop, 1951 Montana license; posed at the
                base of Marcus Daly’s statue and on the Montana Tech campus in Butte </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$g" type="bulk">circa 1940 - circa 1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Unidentified Chinese man on Montana Tech campus with
                others (early 1950’s) </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Unidentified Chinese man and woman shooting rifles,
                fishing and picnicking with others (1950’s) </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1950 - circa 1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Unidentified Chinese men and woman fishing and
                hunting with others </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Unidentified Chinese man posing with women and
                children (early 1950’s) </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1950 - circa 1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="subgrp">
        <did>
          <unitid encodinganalog="099">Subgroup II</unitid>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Rev. Martin D. Hudtloff Family </unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 level="series">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series I</unitid>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Hudtloff Family </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Hudtloff family groups (Rev. Martin D., Julia,
                Arthur, Martin, J. and Esther Hudtloff and Wilhelmina Detloff); St. Mark’s Lutheran
                Church, Butte, Montana </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1915</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="series">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series II</unitid>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Arthur G. Hudtloff </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Portraits and views taken when Arthur was at the
                University of Washington (ca. 1916-1920): Portraits of Arthur and Rev. Martin D.
                (two taken in front of Seattle, WA, house); Arthur sitting at the old Frosh Pond and
                fountain on the University of Washington campus, Seattle; “Recruits Seattle” -
                unidentified young men in uniform; Arthur and friends in front of house at 4339 11th
                Ave. NE, Seattle, wearing graduation gowns; entrance to the Home Economics building
                (later Raitt Hall) on University of Washington campus; Arthur and woman standing in
                front of “U.S. Naval Aviation Detachment” building (likely at the University of
                Washington) </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1916 - circa 1920</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Arthur Hudtloff in the Navy, onboard ship: Arthur
                wearing Navy officer’s uniform (Lieutenant, Junior Grade); Arthur aboard ship
                wearing a WWI-era ensign’s uniform; posed looking through portholes and in groups
                with fellow officers </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1918</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Navy ships and Puget Sound, Washington: Views of
                Navy ships and other vessels on the water; Arthur Hudtloff on dock; views of
                Bellingham, Washington, from the water; ships and ferries in the Sound </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1920</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="series">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series III</unitid>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Esther H. Hudtloff </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Individual portraits of Esther posing in locations
                outdoors; Esther posing with friends at a water pump; on porch and in snow with an
                unidentified young man</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1920</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="series">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series IV</unitid>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Martin J. Hudtloff </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Martin in suit and bow tie; Martin with others in
                front of car</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1920</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="series">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series V</unitid>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Rev. Martin D. Hudtloff </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/12</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Rev. Hudtloff posed with large group; posed with
                group of girls in white dresses</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1920</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="series">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series VI</unitid>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Yellowstone National Park and family camping
            </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3/1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">The Hudtloff family at Yellowstone National Park,
                camping: Rev. Martin Hudtloff, Julia, Arthur, Esther, and Martin J. at Yellowstone
                National Park; family posed with coach in front of Mammoth Hot Springs Hotel; Old
                Faithful Inn; family at locations around the park including Grotto Geyser, Giant
                Geyser, and Castle Geyser; Martin panning in stream; family standing next to cabin;
                tent cabin; picnicking; and man (possibly Arthur Hudtloff) feeding a bear </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1925</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3/2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Yellowstone National Park: Lake Hotel exterior;
                Riverside Geyser; Old Faithful Geyser; Golden Gate Falls; Lower Falls of the Grand
                Canyon of the Yellowstone, and bears foraging at the garbage dump</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1925</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="series">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series VII</unitid>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Detloff/Dettlaff Family </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3/3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Detloff family (likely in Spokane, Washington):
                family in front of car and home; home exterior; father and sons working in yard and
                with Arthur Hudtloff</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1925</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="series">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series VIII</unitid>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Other </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3/4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Other unidentified individuals and groups:
                Unidentified brothers (possibly Detloff) with two women (possibly their mother and
                grandmother) posing with car; large group; people driving car; young girls and
                women; young women in overalls; women posing under a wooden pergola </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3/5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dettlaff gravestone, church interior: Wilhelmina
                Dettlaff (Detloff) (1837-1924) gravestone in Hudtloff family plot; interior of
                unidentified church (possibly St. Mark’s Lutheran Church, Butte) </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="subgrp">
        <did>
          <unitid encodinganalog="099">Subgroup III</unitid>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">General </unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 level="series">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series I</unitid>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Butte (Mont.) </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3/6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">View of the exterior of the First Baptist Church,
                Butte; unidentified man posing in front of Paul Eno’s store at 15 West Mercury,
                Butte; four men sitting on the steps in front of Eno’s store; men posing with dog
                and car; and man standing in front of a house</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="series">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series II</unitid>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Other </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3/7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Portrait of an unidentified family (circa 1890);
                portrait of a young woman (circa 1890); portrait of unidentified U.S. Navy Chief
                Petty Officer in uniform (physical training instructor specialty mark); girl posing
                with dog; man in waders with woman in striped dress; teepee gas station “Bar – Lodge
                – Cabins – Café” at Corwin Hot Springs; unidentified abandoned mine and mill site;
                interior of dorm room decorated with school pendants, likely at Phillips Academy,
                Andover, Mass.; cigarette card for Richmond Cigarettes with portrait of “Belle
                Archer”</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">circa 1890 - circa 1950</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="item">
            <did>
              <container type="oversized">M4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Class portrait: Company 3005-44, Battalion 5,
                Regiment 14, U.S. Naval training station, Farragut, ID, February 7, 1944 (includes
                list of each man pictured in the portrait)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">1944</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>

