<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601">
    <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="mthi" identifier="80444/xv82803" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv82803" encodinganalog="identifier">MTLRS421.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the Montana Department of Highways, Missoula
          District Office records <date encodinganalog="date" type="inclusive" normal="1927/1988">1927-1988</date></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Montana Department of Highways, Missoula
          District Office</titleproper>
        <author encodinganalog="creator"> Finding aid prepared by Rachel Lilley</author>
        <sponsor encodinganalog="contributor"> Funding for encoding this finding aid was provided
          through a grant awarded by the National Historical Publications and Records Commission
          (NHPRC) </sponsor>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher"> Montana Historical Society Research
          Center</publisher>
        <date encodinganalog="date" normal="2013" calendar="gregorian" era="ce"> 2013</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation> Finding aid encoded by Kathryn Kramer <date encodinganalog="date" normal="2013" calendar="gregorian" era="ce">2013</date></creation>
      <langusage> Finding aid written in <language encodinganalog="language" langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn"> English.</language>
      </langusage>
      <descrules>Finding aid based on DACS (<title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content
        Standard, 2nd Edition</title>).</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="marc21">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Montana Historical Society<subarea encodinganalog="852$b">
            Archives</subarea></corpname>
      </repository>
      <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="us" repositorycode="mthi">RS 421</unitid>
      <origination>
        <corpname encodinganalog="110" role="creator" source="lcnaf">Montana. Department of Highways.</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana Department of Highways, Missoula District Office
        records</unittitle>
      <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" normal="1927/1988">1927-1988</unitdate>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">5.8 linear feet of shelf space</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">Records of the Montana Department of Highways, Missoula
        District Office, consisting primarily of correspondence, both internal and
        inter-departmental, dealing with procedural, personnel, and project-related topics. There
        are also frequent communiqués from the Federal Highway Administration.</abstract>
      <physloc label="Location of Collection: " encodinganalog="852$z">41:3-7 </physloc>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546"> English</language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="5451_">
      <p>The Montana State Highway Commission was created in 1913 by the state Legislative Assembly.
        The original Commission was composed of three members. In 1917 new legislation altered the
        organization of the Commission by authorizing the appointment of twelve members according to
        geographic highway districts. Membership was changed again in 1921 to three members
        appointed by the Governor and in 1941 to five members, also appointed by the Governor. In
        1971 the Commission was renamed the Montana Department of Highways, created by Chapter 7 of
        the Executive Reorganization Act of 1971 and implemented by executive order of the Governor
        on December 16, 1971. The Department of Highways took over all but the advisory functions of
        the State Highway Commission.</p>
      <p>By 1972, the Department consisted of seven divisions: the Legal Division, Personnel
        Division, Centralized Services Division, Engineering Division, Motor Pool Division, Gross
        Vehicle Weight Division, and the Maintenance Division. Each division was headed by an
        administrator. The Centralized Services Division, Engineering Division, Motor Pool Division,
        Gross Vehicle Weight Division, and the Maintenance Division were furthered sub-divided into
        bureaus, headed by Chiefs. In 1991, the Department of Highways became the Department of
        Transportation. </p>
      <p>The Highway Department, the Department of Highways, and Department of Transportation
        maintained regional offices in five districts: Billings, Butte, Glendive, Great Falls, and
        Missoula. The District Engineer (later called the District Administrator) was the chief
        administrative officer in each district office. District office files document the
        activities of the district administrators, engineers, maintenance crew, and other district
        office employees. The district offices addressed administrative, functional, and project
        related issues of their particular area, including: highway needs, current construction
        projects, training for employees, road design, federal and state aid and grants, and reports
        to the Department of Highways/Department of Transportation in Helena. </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
      <p>This collection consists primarily of correspondence documenting district office
        activities, including: notifications of, and judgments on, encroachment of highway right of
        way; training needs and requirements for personnel; departmental policies and procedures;
        signing on Montana highways; plowing, sanding, speed limits, crossing lights/walks, and
        other pedestrian and driver safety measures; testing roadway durability; and scheduling
        roadway projects, such as resurfacing and widening.</p>
      <p>It should be noted that the Archives is only in possession of the Department of Highway,
        Missoula District Office records, and did not receive any accompanying Missoula District
        Office records from the Department of Transportation.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
      <p>This collection is arranged by series. </p>
    </arrangement>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
      <p>The Montana Historical Society is the owner of the materials in the Research Library and
        makes available reproductions for research, publication, and other uses. Written permission
        must be obtained from the Research Library before any reproduction use. The Society does not
        necessarily hold copyright to all of the materials in the collections. In some cases,
        permission for use may require seeking additional authorization from the copyright owners.
      </p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <p>Item description and date. Collection Title. Collection Number. Box and Folder numbers.
        Montana Historical Society Research Center, Archives, Helena, Montana.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <p>Acquisition information available upon request</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <controlaccess>
      <p>This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana Historical Society
        Archives catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places
        should search under these terms.</p>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Roads</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Transportation--Montana</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Highway engineering--Montana</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Roads--Design and construction--Montana</subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
      <subject altrender="nodisplay" source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690">Montana</subject>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Detailed Description of the Collection</head>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Correspondence</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1927 &gt;May–1977 August</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="box">2</container>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1977 September–1982 February</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="box">3</container>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1982 March–1983 December</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="box">4</container>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1983–1985 December</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1986 January–1987 December</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="box">6</container>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1988 January–1988 July</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="box">7</container>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">General Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1988 August–1988 December</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Minutes</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="box">7</container>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">District Staff Meetings</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1984-1986</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>

