<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601">
    <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="mthi" identifier="80444/xv88599" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv88599" encodinganalog="identifier">MTLmc338.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to J. Hugo Aronson papers 
			 <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1924/1968" encodinganalog="date">1924-1968</date></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">J. Hugo Aronson papers
			 papers</titleproper>
        <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding aid prepared by Karen
			 Bjork</author>
        <sponsor encodinganalog="contributor">Funding for encoding this finding
			 aid was provided through a grant awarded by the National Endowment for the
			 Humanities.</sponsor>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Montana Historical Society
			 Research Center</publisher>
        <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2008" encodinganalog="date">2008</date>
        <address>
          <addressline>Helena, MT</addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by Karen Bjork 
		  <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2008">2008</date></creation>
      <langusage>
        <language encodinganalog="language" langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn">Finding aid written in English.</language>
      </langusage>
      <descrules>Finding aid based on APPM ( 
		<title render="italic">Archives, Personal Papers, and Manuscripts : A
		  Cataloging Manual for Archival Repositories, Historical Societies, and
		  Manuscript Libraries </title>)</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="marc21" encodinganalog="341$c">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Montana Historical Society, Research Center Archives</corpname>
        <subarea encodinganalog="852$b">Archives</subarea>
        <address>
          <addressline>225 N. Roberts</addressline>
          <addressline>PO Box 201201</addressline>
          <addressline>Helena MT 59620-1201</addressline>
          <addressline>(406) 444-2681</addressline>
          <addressline>MHSlibrary@mt.gov</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="us" repositorycode="mthi">MC
		  338</unitid>
      <origination>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf" rules="aacr2" role="creator">Aronson, J. Hugo (John Hugo), 1891-1978</persname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">J. Hugo Aronson papers </unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1924/1968" encodinganalog="245$f">1924-1968</unitdate>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">18 linear feet of shelf
		  space</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">J. Hugo Aronson was governor of Montana
		  (1953-1961) and served in Montana House of Representatives (1938-1944) and the
		  Montana State Senate (1944-1952). The bulk of the collection consists of
		  campaign/political materials, correspondence, speeches, press releases, subject
		  files, reports, and scrapbooks concerning his two terms as governor. The
		  collection also contains J. Hugo Aronson’s business and personal papers
		  including financial documents, correspondence and subject material.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>
        <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English and
		Swedish</language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="5450_">
      <head>Biographical Note</head>
      <p>J. Hugo Aronson was born in Gallstad, Sweden on September 1, 1891, a
		  son of Aron Johanson (1856-1927), a tenant farmer, and Rika Ryding Johannsen
		  (1857-1940). The Johannsens had five children: Anna, Karl, Julia, John Hugo,
		  and Erik Johannsen Aronson. Anna Aronson married Karl Skold and the couple had
		  three children: Gunnar, Karin, and Allan. Julia Aronson Joseffson had two sons.
		  Sven Johanson was also a nephew of J. Hugo Aronson.</p>
      <p>J. Hugo Aronson was educated in the public schools of Gallstad,
		  Sweden. He left school at the age of 14 to work. Hugo came to the United States
		  from Sweden in 1911, penniless, except for the $25.00 immigration fee required.
		  His brothers and sisters remained residents of Sweden. After working at various
		  jobs through thirty-eight states, Hugo arrived in Columbus, Montana in 1914.
		  While working for Frank Young in Columbus he got the nickname "The Galloping
		  Swede." In 1915 Hugo filed for a 320-acre homestead in Elk Basin.</p>
      <p>On December 8, 1917, he enlisted in the U.S. Army at Billings and
		  served as a private with the 20th Engineers in France. On June 3, 1919, while
		  in France with the American Expeditionary Forces, Aronson married Matilda
		  Langane, who was in charge of the French-American Red Cross group and had been
		  one of premier Georges Clemenceau’s secretaries. He was honorably discharged on
		  July 17, 1919, as a private first class at Hoboken, New Jersey.</p>
      <p>Aronson returned to Columbus with his wife and rented a farm which he
		  operated while working in the oil fields at Elk Basin, Wyoming. In January
		  1923, Hugo went to Sunburst, Montana where he was a tool dresser, or driller’s
		  helper, for a drilling company. In 1924, another rig-builder, Roy Berrey, and
		  Hugo became partners in the Sunburst Construction Company. It was a profitable
		  business but only after a year Roy decided to sell Hugo out. Hugo then operated
		  his own rig-building outfit under his own name and started advertising as "The
		  Galloping Swede." Matilda was the bookkeeper. He added a trucking business to
		  the rig-building company, and at the time Hugo was the largest rig-builder in
		  Montana. When oil was discovered in Kevin-Sunburst fields in Montana, Hugo
		  built the first building in Oilmont. In 1928 he founded Gallop City near
		  Conrad. It was the largest of the oil-fields camps, a community which boasted
		  500 inhabitants.</p>
      <p>Hugo and Matilda Aronson traveled to Sweden and France to visit family
		  in 1924. That same year, they traveled to Glacier National Park and Waterton.
		  They also visited California, Nevada, and Utah.</p>
      <p>Matilda died in Paris, France in 1936 of cancer.</p>
      <p>On September 25, 1944, J. Hugo Aronson married Rose McClure in
		  Minneapolis, Minnesota. Rose McClure Aronson was born in Mondovi, Washington in
		  1904, the daughter of rancher Evan McClure and Bertha Brink McClure. An
		  educator, she was superintendent of schools in Glacier County at the time of
		  her marriage. The Aronsons had one daughter, Rika Berthevan Aronson, who was
		  born in Cut Bank on December 13, 1945. She married Gary Robert Mogolis and the
		  couple had two children: Joani Michele (born Oct. 1, 1967) and John Robert.</p>
      <p>Aronson's political career began with his election as Cut Bank City
		  Alderman in 1934. A Republican, he served three terms in the Montana House of
		  Representatives as a member from Glacier County (1939-1944), and for the next
		  eight years was a member of the Montana State Senate, also representing Glacier
		  County. Aronson served on the board of directors of the Montana Motor Transport
		  Association for many years. He was also a member of the Veterans of Foreign
		  Wars (V.F.W.) and the American Legion. He was a member of the Algeria Temple,
		  Ancient Arabic Order of Nobles of the Mystic Shrine, Blue Lodge, York Rite, and
		  Scottish Rite Masonic bodies.</p>
      <p>J. Hugo Aronson was elected governor of Montana on November 4, 1952.
		  George Gosman was elected lieutenant governor. Other executive officers
		  included Attorney General Arnold Olsen, Secretary of State Sam W. Mitchell, and
		  Superintendent of Public Instruction Mary M. Condon. Hugh Adair was the Chief
		  Justice of the Supreme Court of Montana; Alex Stephenson, Chief of the Highway
		  Patrol; and Wesley Castles was Aronson's executive secretary.</p>
      <p>Aronson was elected to a second term in 1956. Democrat Paul Cannon was
		  elected lieutenant governor. Edna J. Hinman served as Clerk of the Supreme
		  Court; Forrest H. Anderson as Attorney General; Harriett Miller as
		  Superintendent of Public Instruction; and S.H. Mitchell was the Adjutant
		  General.</p>
      <p>As Governor, Hugo battled over oil and gas leasing that arose out of
		  the discovery of oil in the Williston Basin in 1951; he worked for better
		  schools, for prisoner rehabilitation, for oil conservation, and for highway
		  development. In 1959, a new governors' residence was built and the Aronsons
		  became the first family to reside there. </p>
      <p>Following his second term as governor, the Aronsons retired to
		  Bigfork, Montana. Rose Aronson died February 25, 1968 and J. Hugo Aronson's
		  death came on the tenth anniversary of his wife's, February 25, 1978, at the
		  age of 86.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
      <p>J. Hugo Aronson papers consist of documents relating to the life and
		  career of the former governor.</p>
      <p>Series 1-2: These series contain the personal files of J. Hugo Aronson
		  and his family. These files contain biographical material of J. Hugo Aronson,
		  Matilda Lengagne Aronson, and Rose McClure Aronson; correspondence to and from
		  Rose, Rika, and J. Hugo Aronson including condolence letters to J. Hugo for the
		  death of his first wife, Matilda, reaction towards the articles "What America
		  Means to Me" and "Montana's Galloping Swede," and Christmas letters from 1961.
		  The series also includes financial statements and balance sheets for C. A. F.
		  Oil Co., A. E. Crumley, and Hagerty Oil Co., M. H. O. Co., and legal documents
		  including contracts with the Northern Pacific Railroad for the transportation
		  of livestock, the United States for construction of water storage facility, and
		  oil and gas leases.</p>
      <p>Series 3-4: These small series contains material from J. Hugo's time
		  in the Montana House of Representative and the Senate. The series contain
		  subject files on the sale of State owned lots in Glacier County and
		  conscientious objection and the First Methodist Church during the Korean
		  War.</p>
      <p>Series 5: Campaign materials consist of campaign letters from Aronson
		  for Governor Club, campaign speeches, subject files focusing on campaign issues
		  including oil and gas lease program for schools and Montana highway program.
		  The series also contain John Bonner and Arnold Olsen’s campaign speeches when
		  they ran against J. Hugo.</p>
      <p>Series 6: The bulk of this series documents J. Hugo’s governorship.
		  Much of the correspondences in this series are congratulatory of election and
		  reelection victories with little information on policy and strategy. Speeches
		  include dedications; the Governors message to the Legislature for 1955, 1957,
		  1959; keynote addresses to Montana Republican Convention; and to the Montana
		  AFL-CIO, Montana Press Association, panel on Natural resources, stockgrowers,
		  United States Senate on Interior and Insular Affairs, and the woolgrowers. The
		  series also contains subject files on various state agencies including but not
		  limited to the Highway Commission, Highway Patrol, State Board of Education,
		  State Board of Examiners, and State Board of Land Commissioners. Scrapbooks,
		  which date from 1952-1961 and specifically focus on his governorship.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
      <p>Arranged by subgroup and series</p>
    </arrangement>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <p> Collection is open for research</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
      <p>The Montana Historical Society is the owner of the materials in the
		  Research Library and makes available reproductions for research, publication,
		  and other uses. Written permission must be obtained from the Research Library
		  before any reproduction use. The Society does not necessarily hold copyright to
		  all of the materials in the collections. In some cases, permission for use may
		  require seeking additional authorization from the copyright owners.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <p>[item description and date]. J. Hugo Aronson papers, 1924-1968.
		  Manuscript Collection 338. [box and folder number]. Montana Historical Society
		  Research Center. Archives. Helena, Montana.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <p>Acquisition information available upon request.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo encodinganalog="583">
      <p>Processed in 2007-2008</p>
    </processinfo>
    <separatedmaterial encodinganalog="5440_">
      <p>Artifacts, photographs, and printed materials have been separated to
		  the Museum, Photo Archives, and Library respectively.</p>
    </separatedmaterial>
    <controlaccess>
      <p>This collection is indexed under the following headings in the Montana
		  Historical Society catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related
		  topics, persons, or places should search under these terms. </p>
      <controlaccess>
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh" rules="aacr2">Montana.
			 Office of the Governor.</corpname>
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcsh" rules="aacr2">Republican
			 Party (Mont.)</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh" rules="aacr2">Elections--Montana.</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh" rules="aacr2">Governors--Montana.</subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh" rules="aacr2">Montana--Politics and government.</geogname>
        <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh" rules="aacr2">Montana--Politics and government--20th century.</geogname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject altrender="nodisplay" source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690">Montana.</subject>
        <subject altrender="nodisplay" source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690">Government and Politics.</subject>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <head>Detailed Description of the Collection</head>
      <c01 level="subgrp">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">J. Hugo Aronson</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Biographical Material
				  </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Biographical
					 writings</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Correspondence Incoming
				  </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: Condolences for the
					 Death of Matilda Aronson </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1936</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: Get Well Wishes
					 </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1967</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: Miscellaneous
					 (regarding employee recommendation; Matilda's health; birthday wishes;
					 Republican Convention)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1923-1951, 1961-1964</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: Miscellaneous
					 (Swedish)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1941, 1949-1961</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Correspondence General
				  </unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: re Land owned by
					 Beatrice Sartell and Matilda and J. Hugo Aronson</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1926-1939</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: A-M (correspondents
					 include J. Hugo Aronson; H. B. Burleson; Maxine Kenyon; J. E.
					 Manning)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1942-1943</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Bills and Statements
					 (correspondents include J. Hugo Aronson; H. B. Burleson; Claude Carbis; George
					 Simpson)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1942</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: A-S (correspondents
					 include J. Hugo Aronson; H. B. Burleson; Claude Carbis; George
					 Simpson)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1943-1945</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: 
					 <title render="underline">American Magazine</title> Article,
					 "What America Means to Me"</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956-1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1 / 11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: 
					 <title render="underline">Saturday Evening Post</title>
					 Article, "Montana's Galloping Swede"</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957-1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Financial Documents</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1 / 12</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Balance Sheets (C. A.
					 F. Oil Co.; A. E. Crumley; and Hagerty Oil Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1946-1947, 1951-1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1 / 13</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Bills (Trucking
					 Contractor)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1941-1944</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Financial Summaries
					 for Oil Drilling on Blackfeet Land (A. E. Crumley)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1943-1948</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Financial Summaries
					 for Oil Drilling on Blackfeet Land (Hagerty Oil Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1943-1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Payroll [includes
					 oversize material: see OVBX 6]</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1942</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Statements (C. C.
					 Operating Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1928-1936</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Statements (Land
					 owned by Beatrice Sartell and Matilda and J. Hugo Aronson)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1935-1940</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Statements (M. H. O.
					 Oil Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1941-1945</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 7-8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Statements (Trucking
					 Contractor)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1942-1943</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Statements (Grace
					 Hagerty)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1944-1948</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Statements (M. H. O.
					 Oil Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1946-1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Statements (C. A. F.
					 Oil Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 12</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Statements (Hagerty
					 Oil Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953-1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 13</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: Receipts for Hospital
					 Treatments and the Funeral for Matilda Aronson (French)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1936</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 14</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: Receipts (Swedish and
					 French)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1936, 1941, 1949</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 15</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: Receipts
					 (Sampled)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953-1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2 / 16</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: Statements (Conrad
					 Mercantile Company)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1936</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Legal Documents</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Agreement with H. B.
					 Burleson to transport material from Benbow Mill, Montana to Columbus,
					 Montana</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1942</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Contract with
					 Northern Pacific Railway transportation of Livestock</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1941</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Contract with United
					 States of America for Construction of Water Storage Facility</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1942-1943</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Oil and Gas
					 Leases</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1927-1928</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: United States
					 Immigration and Travel Documents (includes Casper Stahl and Lucien and Renee
					 Lengagne) </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1923, 1929-1930</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Organizational
				  Records</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Hagerty Oil Company
					 Meeting Minutes</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Subject Files</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Construction of Water
					 Storage Facility (including correspondence)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1942-1943</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Elkhorn Metals,
					 Inc.</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1937-1938</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: Swedish Bank
					 (including correspondence) </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1929-1940</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: Westminster Foreign
					 Bank (including correspondence) </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1929-1948</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Miscellany</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Business: Driver's Daily
					 Log</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1942</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 12</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: Awards and
					 Certificates [includes oversize material: see OVBX 6]</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1962, 1964, undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 13</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: Building Permit for
					 Home in Cut Bank, Montana</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1945-1946</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">OVBX / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal: Signed Copy the 
					 <title render="underline">Saturday Evening
						Post</title></unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">December 7, 1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 14</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Personal:
					 Miscellaneous</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1932, 1937, 1940,
					 undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Aronson Family</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Biographical Material</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 15</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Miscellaneous, Matilda Lengagne
					 Aronson (includes French Passport, identity book, travel documents, death
					 notice) </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1919, 1924, 1936,
					 undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 16</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Miscellaneous, Rose McClure
					 Aronson (includes clippings, measurement chart, notes)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959, undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Correspondence
				  Incoming</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 17-18</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Christmas Cards</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1961</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 19</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Miscellaneous</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1949-1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Legal Documents</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 20</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Passports (Hugo, Rika, and
					 Rose)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1919, 1928, 1949</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Miscellany</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 21</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Address Book, Rose
					 Aronson</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="subgrp">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">House of
				Representatives</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Subject Files</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 22</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Sale of State Owned Lots in
					 Glacier County</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1939, 1941</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Senate</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Correspondence
				  Incoming</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 23</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Fred Ward, Meagher County
					 News</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Subject Files</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 24</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Conscientious Objectors and the
					 First Methodist Church</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1950-1951</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Campaign for Governor</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Correspondence
				  General</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3 / 25</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">A (correspondents include Arne
					 Anzjon, Montana Broadcasting; Argus-Farmer Newspaper)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4 / 1-2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Aronson for Governor Club
					 (includes correspondence to and from Frank Connelly, Treasurer; D. E. Hageman,
					 Secretary; Fred Martin, Campaign Manager)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">B (correspondents include Vic
					 Benson, Covered Wagon Ranch; M. W. Blankenship, Missoula County Republican
					 Headquarters; Robert Burroughs, Eisenhower for President Headquarters; Ken
					 Byerly, Byerly Publishing Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">C (correspondents include Ed
					 Craney, Pacific Northwest Broadcasters; William Cherry; Cremer Rodeo Land and
					 Livestock Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">D-G (correspondents include
					 Harry Duntsch, Bozeman Courier; J. G. Edmiston, President Conrad National Bank
					 of Kalispell; Ward Fanning, Jr., Chairman Ballot Battalion Forum; Roswell
					 Goodman, Chairman Lewis and Clark County Young Republicans)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">H (correspondents include Grace
					 Hanson, President Kalispell Business and Professional Women's Club; Hazel
					 Hitchcock, Republican Headquarters; John Hoyt, Toole Co. Attorney)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">I-M (correspondents include
					 Alma Jacobs, Montana State Federation of Colored Women's Clubs; Liberty County
					 Times; Peggy McCormick, Eastern Montana College of Education; Meagher County
					 News; Walter Mecklenburg)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">N-R (correspondents include
					 Bill Neary, Miner's Union Legislative Committee; Northwest Tribune; Don Nutter;
					 Joseph Oien; W. E. Pierce, Chairman Republican County Central Committee; Junior
					 Reinemer, Chairman Aronson Committee; Republican State Central
					 Committee)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">S (correspondents include
					 Frances Sanborn, Chairman Montana Republican Women's Clubs; Lyle Standish,
					 Chairman Teton County Aronson for Governor Club; Sid Stewart, Senator Deer
					 Lodge County; Ruby Swanson, Mountain View Lodge)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">T-Y (correspondents include
					 Frank Trippet, Montana D. A. V. News; Don Valiton, Senator Powell County; T. B.
					 Van Horn, Finance Chairman Republican Central Committee; C. M. Wall, President
					 Montana Chamber of Commerce; Herb Watts, Havre Daily News)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Aronson for Governor Club
					 (includes correspondence to and from Wesley Castles, Secretary; James Felt,
					 Chairman; Ashton Jones, Campaign Manager)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5 / 4-5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Campaign(correspondents include
					 KGHL-Billings; Lions Club; Montana D. A. V. News; Montana Farm Bureau
					 Federation; Montana Legionnaire; Republican Central Committee; Women's
					 Republican Club)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5 / 6-7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Campaign
					 Contributions</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956-1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Ford-Gainan Advertising
					 Agency</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Little People for an Honest
					 Governor</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Financial</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Bills (General
					 Election)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5 / 11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Receipt Log [includes oversize
					 material: see OVBX 6]</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5 / 12</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Basic Budget Plan</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Receipts, Ford-Gainan
					 Advertising Agency</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Press Releases</unittitle>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Reelection Campaign</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Printed Material</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">"They Shall Know the Truth and
					 the Truth Shall Make Them Angry"</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952, 1955-1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Speeches</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Speeches by others (includes
					 two untitled speeches by Albert Krause and Senator Liggetts) </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">"To Every Montana
					 Voter"</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Campaign Speeches (re
					 accomplishments of Governor Aronson's Administration, Cochrane Dam dedication,
					 Farm Program, "How to Smear a Legislator", Montana Employment Service, Montana
					 Oil-Lease Program for Schools, Montana's Economic Outlook, Need for
					 Equalization, Policy Speech, Rebuttal to Arnold Olsen’s Campaign)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Subject Files</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Campaign for Governor (includes
					 campaign song, correspondence, flyers) [includes oversize material: see OVBX
					 6]</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Daily Itinerary</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Radio
					 Advertisements</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Small Trailer Tax</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Campaign Research
					 Material</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955-1956, undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 12</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Itinerary (includes
					 correspondence)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955-1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 13</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana County Republican
					 Chairmen (includes contact list) [includes oversize material: see OVBX
					 6]</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 14</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana Highway
					 Program</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 15</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">
                <title render="underline">Montana Opinion</title>
					 Questionnaire</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 16</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana Press
					 Association</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 17</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Oil and Gas Lease Program for
					 Schools</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955-1956, undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 18</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Arnold Olsen for
					 Governor</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955-1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 19</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Reelection Campaign for
					 Governor (includes correspondence, flyers, clippings)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">6 / 20</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Republican State Central
					 Committee (includes platforms, resolutions, and correspondence)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956, 1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Miscellany</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Mailing Lists</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Voter Registration Lists
					 (includes Garfield County; Lennep, Rock Creek and Ringling
					 Precincts)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">John Bonner: Speeches (includes
					 speeches regarding Utility Rates, Oil, Labor, State Institutions, and Workmen's
					 Compensation)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Arnold Olsen: Speeches
					 (includes speeches regarding Oil and Utility Rates, Oil Leasing, Freight Rates
					 and Oil and Gas Leases)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953-1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Arnold Olsen: Speeches
					 (includes speeches regarding Federal Aid and Education, Right-to-Work Law, Slot
					 Machines and Gambling, and Workmen's Compensation)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="file">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Governor</unittitle>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Correspondence
				  Incoming</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Congratulations on Election:
					 Telegrams</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Albert C. Johnson</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Thure H. Peterson</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953-1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Thank You Letters, Governors'
					 Conference</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Robert Yellowtail
					 Newsletters</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Miscellaneous</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Correspondence
				  General</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 12</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">A (primarily congratulations on
					 election; correspondents include American Legion; L. J. Anders, Broadwater
					 County Representative; Carl Anderson; A. L. (Roy) Atkinson, Lake County
					 Representative; Arlo Axelson, Silver Bow County Republican Planning Committee)
					 </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 13</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Attorney; State
					 Boards and Agencies</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 14</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Board of
					 Education</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 15</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments:
					 Custodian</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 16</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Department of
					 Agriculture</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">7 / 17</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Fish and
					 Game</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Highway
					 Commission</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Highway
					 Department</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Highway
					 Patrol</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Home for the
					 Aged, Lewistown</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Industrial
					 Accident Board</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Industrial
					 School, Miles City</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Livestock
					 Commission</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Motor Vehicle
					 Office</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Public Health
					 Board</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Public
					 Welfare</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Public Welfare,
					 Child Welfare Division</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 12</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Purchasing
					 Department</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 13</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: State Hospital,
					 Warm Springs</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 14</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: State
					 Prison</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 15</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Water
					 Conservation Board</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 16</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">B (primarily congratulations on
					 election; correspondents include O. A. Bergeson; Big Horn County State Bank;
					 Thomas Briggs, President of Welcome Wagon, Inc,; Ken Byerly, President of
					 Byerly Publishing Co.; Ed Byrne; L. W. Busch, Senator Fallon
					 County)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">8 / 17</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">C (primarily congratulations on
					 election; correspondents include Chandler Cohagen, Architect; E. E. Collins,
					 Administrator Rocky Mountain College; Elizabeth Connelly, President of Montana
					 Federation of Business and Professional Women's Clubs; Harry Cooley, Northern
					 School Supply Co.; Ed Cooney, President of Montana Radio Stations, Inc.; W. J.
					 Cooney; Clarence Cunningham, Hold Firm the American Way)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">D (primarily congratulations on
					 election; correspondents include M. S. Danklefsen, Mayor of Jordon, Montana;
					 Tom J. Davis, Attorney; M. D. Dennis, The Texas Company; Wesley D'Ewart,
					 Montana Congressman; G. P. Drowley, President of the First National Bank;
					 Howard R. Dove)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">E (primarily congratulations on
					 election; correspondents include Charles F. Eastabrooks, Manager Monmouth
					 Branch of the United States National Bank; Graydon Edwards; Andrew Eggenberger;
					 Dwight D. Eisenhower; E. P. Ekegren; Lula M. Eschle, Butte City Librarian; Troy
					 Evans, Senator Silver Bow County)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">F (primarily congratulations on
					 election; correspondents include Clyde Flint, Hotel Havre; G. H. Flint,
					 American Insurance Company; Larry Florek, Union Construction Company, Inc.;
					 John Fouse; E. R. Fortin, Agent Great Northern Railway Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">G (primarily congratulations on
					 election; correspondents include Gerard, James, Clerk of Court Glacier County;
					 Gerlough, Wilma; Toole County Republican Central Committee; A. L. Gleason,
					 Great Falls Clinic; Greenlee, Betty; Gribble, Paul)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">H (primarily congratulations on
					 election; correspondents include O. R. Hagen, Vice-President Traders State
					 Bank; Robert Haines, Haines Public Drug; Mack Hamilton, Cascade County
					 Republican Central Committee; B. M. Harris, President Yellowstone Bank; Matt
					 Himsl, Chairman Flathead County Republic Central Committee)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">I-J (primarily congratulations
					 on election; correspondents include Ernest Immel; Elizabeth Ireland; Joseph
					 Iten, Representative Ravalli County; E. L. Johnson, First National Bank of
					 Plains; D. L. Casey Jones, Montana Shannon Mining Co.; O. M. Jorgenson,
					 President Security Trust and Savings Bank)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Inaugural Festival Committee,
					 National </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">K (primarily congratulations on
					 election; correspondents include George Kern, Absaroka Conservation Committee;
					 Glayds E. Knowles; member of Republican National Committee for Montana; Horace
					 Koessler, Intermountain Lumber Co.; Max Kuhr)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">L (primarily congratulations on
					 election; correspondents include Leo J. Lamberson, Supreme Vice President Order
					 of Ahepa; Glenn Larson, Senator Sanders County; Albert Leuthold; E. H.
					 Lindstrom, Montana Medical Association; R. J. Losleben, Valley Drug Co.; G. O.
					 Lowe, Montana Flour Mills Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">M (primarily congratulations on
					 election; correspondents include N. B. Matthews, President Basin State Bank; H.
					 G. Mebust, President First National Bank of Kalispell; Lee Metcalf, Montana
					 Congressman; Earl Moritz, Hi-Way Motor Freight Co.; G. F. Mundy, Gildford
					 Roller Mill; Rod Murchison, Service Plumbing and Heating Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">N (primarily congratulations on
					 election; correspondents include National Safety Council; Matt Newell, Charter
					 Oil Co.; Kenny Newton, Newton Motors; Northern Montana College; Northwest
					 Mining Association;)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 12</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">O-P (primarily congratulations
					 on election; correspondents include Clarence H. Olson, The American Legion; H.
					 E. Olsson, Ronan State Bank; Winfield Page, Missoula County Representative; E.
					 A, Phillips, Secretary Montana Stockgrowers Association, Inc.; W. E. Pierce,
					 Chairman of the Republican County Central Committee)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 13</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">R (primarily congratulations on
					 election; correspondents include A. J. Rasmussen, Rasmussen Farming
					 Corporation; Republican National Committee; Harry C. W. Richter, Livestock
					 Sanitary Board; John Rice, Rice Truck Lines; Thomas Ross, Senator Blaine
					 County)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 14</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">S (primarily congratulations on
					 election; correspondents include Sacred Heart Hospital; T. J. Sillers, First
					 National Bank of Whitefish; Elmer Sorensen, Yellowstone Mercantile Co.; Wynn
					 Sparr, Robertson Petroleum Co.; Ralph L. Starr, Mayor of Missoula)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 15</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">T-Z (primarily congratulations
					 on election; correspondents include Harry Todd, Petroleum County Manager; K. P.
					 Todd, Mountain States Telephone and Telegraph Co.; Toole County Republican
					 Central Committee; John Travis, Havre Daily News; United Press Association; C.
					 M. Wall, President Montana Chamber of Commerce; John Willard, Montana Record
					 Publishing Co.; A. R. Wilson, Texas Co.; W. J. Winters, Senator Ravalli
					 County)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 16</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">A (correspondents include Einar
					 Andersson, Svenska Amerikanaren Tribunen; James Austin, Mayor of Great Falls;
					 L. R. Austin, Big Horn Supply Inc.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 17</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Advisory Board of
					 Pardons and Paroles</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 18</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Board of Barber
					 Examiners</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 19</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Board of
					 Equalization</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953-1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">9 / 20</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Board of
					 Examiners, Accountancy</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Columbia Compact
					 Commission</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Fireman;
					 Veteran's Administration Building</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Hail Insurance
					 Board</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Labor and
					 Industry</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Legislative
					 Council</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Liquor Control
					 Board</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953-1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Milk Control
					 Board</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Oil and Gas
					 Conservation Commission</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953-1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Personnel
					 Commission</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Public Employee
					 Retirement System</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: State Land
					 Office</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 12</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments:
					 Stenographer</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 13</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Teachers
					 Retirement System</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 14</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments: Training School,
					 Boulder</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 15</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments:
					 Treasurer</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953-1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 16</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">B-C (correspondents include D.
					 W. Buckman, Assistant Vice President the First National Bank St. Paul; Ken
					 Byerly, Byerly Publishing Co.; Elizabeth Connelly, President Montana Federation
					 of Business and Professional Women's Clubs; Frank Connelly)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 17</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">D-G (correspondents include
					 Wesley D'Ewart, Montana Congressman; E. L. Dorsett, Superintendent Northwestern
					 Improvement Co.; C. Pat Egan, Manager Hotel Finlen; Dwight D. Eisenhower,
					 President of the United States; S. H. Finger, Vice President National Park
					 Bank; Henry Fowler, Defense Production Administration; Roz Goodman, Chairman
					 Young Republican County central Committee; R. G. Glatz, Winnett
					 Times)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 18</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">H-K (correspondents include
					 Havre Independent; Norman J. Holter; R. E. Huelster, President Gallatin County
					 Women's Republican Club; Millo Jensen, Chairman Lake County Republican Central
					 Committee; G. H. Kern, Absaroka Conservation Committee; J. F.
					 Kumpf)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 19</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">L-N (correspondents include J.
					 Russell Larcombe, Phillips County News; H. L. Lund, President of First National
					 Bank; A. G. Martin, Standard Oil Co.; Paul McCormick, Chairman Yellowstone
					 County Republican Central Committee; Mountain States Telephone and Telegraph
					 Company; Homer Murphy, Flathead Courier; New Rainbow Mining Co.; Donald
					 Nyquist, Court Reporter )</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 20</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">O-S (correspondents include
					 Walter Olson, President Valley Motor Supply Co.; Oliver Powell, President
					 Federal Reserve Bank of Minneapolis; Robert Roush, Secretary Lions Club;
					 Stockgrowers Association)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 21</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">T-Y (correspondents include
					 Herman Talmadge, Governor of Georgia; Stanley Thill, Chairman Pondera County
					 Republican Central Committee; Dan Thornton, Governor of Colorado; C. M. Wall,
					 President Montana Chamber of Commerce; Leonard Young, Board of Railroad and
					 Public Service Commission)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 22</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">A-E (correspondents include
					 Walter Allen, Superintendent of Fisheries; T. L. Blau, Camera Press Limited;
					 Darrell Coover; C. L. Crist, President KOOK; C. J. Doherty, Publisher The
					 Times; K. G. Drew, Rainbow Ranch; Melvin Engles, Chairman Roosevelt County
					 Republican Central Committee)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 23</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">F-L(correspondents include John
					 S. Fine, Governor of Pennsylvania; J. W. Fry, Bice Truck Lines; J. C. Hickman,
					 President Cascade County Taxpayers' League, Inc.; Herbert Hoover; W. J.
					 Jameson; Ed Krebsbach, KGCK; J. Russell Larcombe, Phillips County
					 News)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 24</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">M-Y (correspondents include
					 Joseph W. Martin, Jr., Speaker House of Representatives; Republican National
					 Committee; Allan Shivers, Governor of Texas; Floyd Underwood)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 25</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">A-B (correspondents include
					 Forest Anderson; Victor Anderson, Governor of Nebraska; Erik Bottiger, Grand
					 Secretary, Grand Lodge of Sweden; Norman Brunsdale, Governor of North Dakota;
					 George Buchanan, Husky Oil Co.; Ken Byerly, Byerly Newspapers)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">10 / 26</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">C-E (correspondents include
					 Huntley Childs, Yellowstone Park Company; L. A. Christensen, President Bank of
					 Glacier County; Mary Condon, State Superintendent of Public Instruction;
					 Darrell Coover; Gerald L. Crowley; Bryon Dunn, President National Bank of
					 Commerce; Ellis Cattle Company)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">11 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">F-H (correspondents include
					 James Flaherty, Great Falls Paper Co.; Roy Glover, Vice President and General
					 Counsel Anaconda Copper Mining Co.; G. C. Hoyt)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">11 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">J-M (correspondents include Ben
					 Larson, Publisher Circle Banner; J. H. McCallum, Vice President Harcourt, Brace
					 and Co.; Montana Federation of Women's Republican Clubs)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">11 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">N-S (correspondents include
					 National Broadcasting Company; Melvin Ruder, Hungry Horse News; Bess Reed,
					 Missoula County Representative; R. D. Smith, Union Oil Company; E. B. Stanton,
					 Vice President Northern Pacific Railway Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">11 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">T-Z (correspondents include
					 John F. M. Travis, Havre Daily News; Stewart Varn, Jocelyn-Varn Oil Co.;
					 Western Air Lines, Inc.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">11 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">A (primarily congratulations on
					 reelection; correspondents include Staton Aby, President Kalman and Company,
					 Inc.; I. A. Adams, Chairman Stillwater County Republican Central Committee;
					 Anderson Clothing Company; W. A. Alexander, Shell Oil Company)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">11 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments (includes Montana
					 Highway Engineer and Montana Highway Commission)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">11 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">B (primarily congratulations on
					 reelection; correspondents include Marylou Bowman, Lake County Republican
					 Central Committee; J. S. Brenner, Beaverhead County Senator; Norman Brunsdale,
					 Governor of North Dakota; Ken Byerly, Byerly Publishing Co.;)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">11 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">C (primarily congratulations on
					 reelection; correspondents include Carter Oil Company; Glenn Chaffin, Hamilton
					 Chamber of Commerce; Frank Clement, Governor of Tennessee; George Clevidence,
					 Ravalli County Famers Union; Grover Cochran, U.S. Immigration-Naturalization
					 Officers' Association; Darrell Coover)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">11 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">D-E (primarily congratulations
					 on reelection; correspondents include Wesley D'Ewart, Department of
					 Agriculture; Frank Dougherty, Montana Association of County Commissioners;
					 Robert Dwyer, Anaconda Company; J. G. Edmiston, Conrad National Bank; George
					 Eikhoff, Board of County Commissioners Richland County)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">11 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">F-G (primarily congratulations
					 on reelection; correspondents include Minnie Fink, Glacier County Treasurer; B.
					 A. Fisher, Hi-Ball Contractors, Inc.; Ray German, Oilmont; Leonard Gisvold,
					 Vice President Northwestern National Bank of Minneapolis; James Glover,
					 Jr.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">11 / 11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">H-J (primarily congratulations
					 on reelection; correspondents include Homer Hancock, Yellowstone County
					 Representative; H. Harry Henderson, Ford Motor Co.; Matt Himsl, Chairman
					 Flathead Republican Central Committee; W. H. Hornby Kalispell Lumber Co.; V. C.
					 Hollingsworth, President Citizens State Bank; Larry L. Jones, Jr., Kirby Oil
					 Industries, Inc.; Clark Jorgensen, Miles City Chamber of Commerce)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">12 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">K-L (primarily congratulations
					 on reelection; correspondents include R. F. Kitchingman, Great Falls Chamber of
					 Commerce; Gladys Knowles, Republican National Committee; Carolyn Madden Larsen,
					 Montana Conservation Council, Inc.; Frank Lausche, Governor of Ohio; Little
					 People for an Honest Governor)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">12 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">M (primarily congratulations on
					 reelection; correspondents include Fred Martin, Park County News; Luis
					 Munoz-Marin, Governor of Puerto Rico; K. J. McDonald, President Ravalli County
					 Bank; A. F. McClaine, President Barmac Production Company)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">12 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">N-P (primarily congratulations
					 on reelection; correspondents include Walter C. Nye, dude Ranchers'
					 Association; Lyle Onstad, Hope Lutheran Church; Catherine Pemberton, TA Ranch;
					 J.C. Price; Dan C. Price, Sidney Chamber of Commerce)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">12 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">R (primarily congratulations on
					 reelection; correspondents include Republican National Committee; John W.
					 Rodman, Parade Rest Ranch; Jerry Roe, President of the Young Republican Club;
					 Thomas Ross, Blaine County Senator)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">12 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">S (primarily congratulations on
					 reelection; correspondents include Walter Sagunsky, Madison County Senator; E.
					 J. Scheibe, Superintendent Texaco Petroleum Products; Sherman Smith,
					 Secretary-Manager Helena Chamber of Commerce; Robert Sullivan, Dean School of
					 Law Montana State University; (Rev) Edgar E. Swanson, Evangelical Mission
					 Covenant Church of America)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">12 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">T-V (primarily congratulations
					 on reelection; correspondents include John Tenge, President Midland National
					 Bank; Ernest Thompson, Texas Railroad Commissioner; Union Oil Company of
					 California)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">12 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">W-Z (primarily congratulations
					 on reelection; correspondents include Kay Watson, Cascade County Women's
					 Republican Club; Western Airlines; R. H. Wiedman, Chairman Lake County
					 Republican Central Committee; Robert Wilcox, President Miles City Chamber of
					 Commerce; G. W. Yoder, Yoder Motor Company)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">12 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">A-B (correspondents include Jim
					 Annin, Veteran's Hospital; William Baillie, State Chairman Montana Young
					 Republicans John Ray Bliss, Chairman Republican State Central and Executive
					 Committee; Burke, Chairman Metals Bank and Trust Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">13 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">C-D (correspondents include E.
					 J. Callaghan, Director Veterans' Welfare Commission; Frank Connelly; George N.
					 Craig, Governor of Indiana; John Davis, Governor of North Dakota; Walt Disney,
					 Walt Disney Production)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">13 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">E-G (correspondents include J.
					 W. Emmert, Glacier National Park; F. X. Faust, Chairman Forsyth Chamber of
					 Commerce Hi-Way Commerce; Joe Foss, Governor of South Dakota; Joseph M.
					 Gilmore, Bishop of Helena)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">13 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">H-L (correspondents include Ben
					 Hagerman, Yellowstone County Commissioner; A. W. Heidel, President Powder River
					 County Bank; Rowland Kirks, National Automobile Dealers Association; Horace
					 Koessler, Intermountain Lumber Co.; Herschel Loveless, Governor of
					 Iowa)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">13 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">M (correspondents include W. S.
					 Mather, Chairman Musselshell County Republican Central Committee; Betty Maxey
					 McKean, Sons and Daughters of Montana Pioneers; F. L. McPhail, Western
					 Interstate Commission for Higher Education; Ed Mechem, Governor of New
					 Mexico)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">13 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">N-R (correspondents include
					 Richard Nixon, Vice-President of United States; Northwest Airlines Inc.;
					 Northwestern Life Insurance Co.; Phillips Petroleum Co.; Roland Renne,
					 President Montana State College; Charles Russell, Governor of Nevada
					 )</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">13 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">S-T (correspondents include
					 Milward Simpson, Governor of Wyoming; Robert Smylie, Governor of Idaho; C. H.
					 Steele, Anaconda Company; William Stratton, Governor of Illinois; K. Richard
					 Sturm, Elkhorn Oil Company, Inc.; Ken Todd, Mountain States Telephone and
					 Telegraph Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">13 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">U-Z (correspondents include
					 Union Oil Company of California; Burton K. Wheeler, Montana Senator; Del E.
					 Webb Construction Co.; Bill Zadick, City Editor Great Falls)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">13 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">A-C (correspondents include
					 Arras Tank Co.; Ken Byerly School of Journalism University of North Carolina;
					 Dean Chaffin, National Automobile Dealers Association; J. W. Corwin, Stillwater
					 County Republican Central Committee)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">14 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">D-G (correspondents include
					 Terrell Drinkwater, President Western Airlines; C. J. Doherty, Publisher
					 Missoula Times; J. W. Emmert, Director of Idaho State Parks; Edward Fike,
					 President of Fike Newspapers)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">14 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">H-L (correspondents include
					 Helena Public Schools; Frank Hemingway, Mutual Broadcasting Company; Herbert
					 Waldo Hines, President Rocky Mountain College; George Lund, President First
					 National Bank)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">14 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">M-R (correspondents include
					 Edwin Mechem, Governor of New Mexico; Montana Power Co.; Montana State
					 University; Glenn Nielson, President Husky Oil Co.; Clarence Olson, American
					 Legion; Republican National Committee; Douglas Rigg, Warden Minnesota State
					 Prison)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">14 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">S-Z (correspondents include
					 Fred Seaton, Secretary of the Interior; Robert Stevens; Charles Thronson,
					 President Montana Bank; Ann Wolk, Montana Federation of Women's Clubs; Bill
					 Zadick, Great Falls Tribune)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">14 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">A-Z (correspondents include
					 Price Daniel, Governor of Texas; T. F. Haines, Montana State Food Distributors;
					 Montana Power Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">14 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Duluth Seaway
					 Dedication</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">14 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Governor's Retirement
					 Announcement</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959-1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">14 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">A-E (correspondents include
					 Frank Banes, Chairman Advisory Commission on Intergovernmental Relations; J.
					 Caleb Boggs, Governor of Delaware; Bert Combs, Governor of Kentucky; Richard
					 Cook, Editor Ethyl News; Leo Ellingson, Radio Program
					 Director-KFBB)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">14 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Congratulatory Letters on
					 Governorship</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">14 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">F-L (correspondents include Lee
					 Ford, Chairman of the Board of Great Falls National Bank; Harold Handley,
					 Governor of Indiana; Norbert Hruby, Associate Dean University of Chicago; Joe
					 Joffe, Superintendent Yellowstone National Park; Gladys Knowles, Republican
					 National Committee; J. W. Liddell, Vice President Continental Oil
					 Co.)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">M-Y (correspondents include E.
					 R. McFarland, President, Kainai Chieftainship; Richard Nixon; William Quinn,
					 Governor of Hawaii; Nelson Rockefeller, Governor of New York; Robert Timm,
					 Republican National Committee)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Correspondence
				  Outgoing</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Don Knutson (re Truth or
					 Consequences TV show stunt)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Thank You Letters</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Legal Documents</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Union Contract: State
					 Tuberculosis Sanitarium</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Press Releases</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Editorials re Montana State
					 Prison</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957-1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Miscellaneous (re appointments,
					 legislative bills and agendas, State budget, federal-state
					 relations)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953-1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Reports</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">"Earthquake and Slide at
					 Madison Canyon" by State Highway Dept.</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">State Penal Institutions
					 Survey</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Speeches</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Address to the Montana
					 Federation of Labor (Chadwick H. Smith)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Annual Western Montana Air
					 Show</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Boy Scout Ceremony</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 12</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Boy Scouts</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 13</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Carter County Cattle and Sheep
					 Grower Association</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 14</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Central Montana Highway
					 Association</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957, 1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 15</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Chinook Lincoln Day
					 Talk</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 16</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Christmas Message</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953, 1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 17</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Columbia Basin Inter-Agency
					 Committee</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 18</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Columbia Development
					 Legislation Before Senate Committee on Public Works Subcommittee</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 19</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Commencement Address, "Help
					 Yourself," Rocky Mountain College</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 20</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Community Development
					 Conference</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 21</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Congratulatory Message to KGVO
					 27th Anniversary </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 22</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">County
					 Commissioners</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954-1957, undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 23</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Cut Bank Chamber of
					 Commerce</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 24</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Anaconda Aluminum
					 Company Plant, Columbia Falls</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 25</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Alberta Tourist
					 Information Station, St. Mary's</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 26</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Bannack State
					 Park</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 27</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Canyon Ferry
					 Dam</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 28</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Diamond Match
					 Company, Superior</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 29</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Forsyth
					 Bridge</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 30</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Fred Robinson
					 Bridge</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 31</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Galen
					 Chapel</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 32</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Glendive
					 Bridge</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 33</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Lewis and Clark
					 Cavern State Park</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 34</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Livingston Memorial
					 Hospital</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 35</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Miles City
					 Bridge</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 36</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Montana-Dakota
					 Utilities Plant, Sidney</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 37</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Montana School of
					 Mines Building</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 38</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Montana State
					 College Fieldhouse</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 39</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Noxon Dam, Thompson
					 Falls</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 40</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Noxon Rapids
					 Dam</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">15 / 41</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Senator Bill
					 Cowan</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Terry
					 Bridge</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, United States Army
					 Reserve Training Center</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, Van-Evan Company,
					 Plentywood Plant</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, "Whoop-Up
					 Trail"</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Dedication, William Wylie Galt
					 Hall, Great Falls</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Delegates at the Republican
					 National Convention</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">DeMolays Attending State
					 Conclave of DeMolay</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Excerpt from Governor's Message
					 to Legislative Assembly</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Farmers Day of Greater Moorhead
					 Days</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Feeder Airline Service for
					 Eastern Montana and North Dakota</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Fellow Governors</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 12</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Fellow Republicans Regarding
					 Voting for President Eisenhower (incomplete)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 13</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Fiftieth Anniversary of Sanders
					 County</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 14</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Forestry Meeting</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 15</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Girls State Graduation, Willson
					 Junior High School</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 16</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Governor's Day at National
					 Guard Camp</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 17</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Governor's Greeting, Opening
					 Business Session</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 18-20</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Governor's Message to the
					 Montana Legislative Assembly</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955, 1957, 1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 21</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Governor's, Omaha
					 Nebraska</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 22</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Governor's Reelection
					 Campaign</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 23</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Ground-Breaking Ceremony,
					 Carroll College</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957, 1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 24</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Hamilton Chamber of
					 Commerce</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 25</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Harlem, Montana (regarding
					 Governor Aronson's campaign reelection promises to Harlem)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 26</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Highway Department
					 Revenue</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 27</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Highway Notes for Governor's
					 Conference, Chicago, Illinois</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 28</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Ike Night</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 29</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Industrial Development Clinic,
					 Billings</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 30</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Intermountain States, Regarding
					 Tourist Travel</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 31</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Interstate Oil Compact
					 Commission, New Orleans</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 32</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Keynote, Bismarck, North
					 Dakota</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 33</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Keynote, Montana Republican
					 Convention, Helena</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954, undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 34</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Members of Boys State,
					 Dillon</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 35</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Members of Girls
					 State</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954-1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 36</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Missouri Basin Inter-Agency
					 Meeting, Sidney</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 37</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Missouri River States
					 Committee, Topeka, Kansas</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 38</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana AFL-CIO</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 39</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana Automobile Dealers
					 Association</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 40</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana Business and
					 Labor</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 41</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana Legislative Assembly
					 regarding Oil Lease Law</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 42</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana Press
					 Association</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 43</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana Reclamation
					 Association, Butte</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 44</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana School Board
					 Association</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953, undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 45</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana State Grange
					 Convention</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 47</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana Thespians</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">16 / 48</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana's Natural
					 Resources</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">"Montana's Relation With Other
					 States," Montana Legislative Assembly</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montanans regarding the 1956
					 Election</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">National Bison
					 Range</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">National Resource
					 Conference</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">New Mexico Oil and Gas
					 Association</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">New Year's Message</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Northwest Monopoly State
					 Enforcement Conference</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Opening Remarks, Governor's
					 Traffic Safety Conference</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Panel on Interstate
					 Institutions</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Panel on Natural Resources,
					 Western Governor's Conference</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Paradise Dam</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 12</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Pilot Education Conference on
					 Education</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 13</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">"Problems of Effective State
					 Government," Republican Western Conference</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 14</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Public Meeting, Education
					 Beyond the High School</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 15</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Radio Speech to Boy
					 Scouts</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954, 1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 16</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Rally, Bozeman</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 17</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Rally, Deer Lodge</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 18</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Rally, Dillon</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 19</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Rally, Petroleum County
					 Republican Party</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 20</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Rally, Plentywood</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 21</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Rally, Sanders
					 County</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 22</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Republican Women's
					 Club</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959, undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 23</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Resource Development, Fargo,
					 North Dakota</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 24</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Rural
					 Electrification</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954, undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 25</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Safety Finance
					 Meeting</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 26</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Salute to KVCK, Wolf
					 Point</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 27</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Search and Rescue Seminar,
					 Malmstrom Air Force Base</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 28</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Silver Anniversary Banquet of
					 Montana Hospital Association, Great Falls</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 29</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Silver Bow County Republican
					 Meeting, Butte </unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 30</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Soil Conservation</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 31</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">State Chamber of Commerce
					 Banquet</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 32</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">State Industrial
					 School</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 33</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">State Water Conservation
					 Board</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 34</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Statement Before Brooks
					 Subcommittee of House Committee on Armed Services</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 35</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Stockgrowers</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953, 1955, 1956,
					 undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 36</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Supporting Wes D'Ewart for
					 United States Senate</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 38</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Swedish Day, 20th Annual
					 Minneapolis-St. Paul (includes correspondence)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 39</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Swedish Societies' Old People's
					 Home Association, Evanston, Illinois (includes correspondence)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 40</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Tax Conference
					 Meeting</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 41</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Texas Mid-Continent Oil and Gas
					 Association, Texas</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 42</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Traffic Safety
					 Problems</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 43</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Tri-State Hereford Futurity,
					 Miles City</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 44</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Twenty-fifth Anniversary,
					 Waterton-Glacier International Peace Park</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 45</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">United States Senate on
					 Interior and Insular Affairs, Missoula</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 46</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Voting Republicans in
					 Office</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">17 / 47</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Welcome, Agricultural
					 Teachers</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Welcome, Montana Association
					 for Rehabilitation Meeting</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Welcome, State-Wide Meeting of
					 Fire Chiefs</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Western Association of State
					 Highway Officials, Billings</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Western Interstate Committee on
					 Highway Policy Problems, Billings</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">"What America Means to
					 Me"</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Women's Republican Club,
					 Billings</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Woolgrowers</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Young Montanans, Members of the
					 Governor's Committee</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Subject Files</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Forest Anderson, Attorney
					 General (includes correspondence)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958-1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Application for Beer and Liquor
					 Licenses</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 11</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Appointments</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953, 1957</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 12</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Architects and Architectural
					 Contracts</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954-1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 13</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Biographical Sketches for
					 Speeches</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 14</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Capital Complex and Governor's
					 Mansion</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 15</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Depository Board</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 16</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Clyde Downey, Montana State
					 Prisoner (includes correspondence)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 17</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Federal Land Exchange for State
					 Land</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953, 1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 18</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Governors'
					 Conference</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955, 1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 19</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Governor's Premiere "John Paul
					 Jones" (includes correspondence)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 20</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Highway Commission</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953-1954, 1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 21</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Highway Department</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955, 1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 22</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Highway Patrol</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 23</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Missouri Basin Inter-Agency
					 Committee</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 24</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana Republican
					 Party</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954-1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 25</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Montana Supreme
					 Court</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958, 1960, undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 26</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Frank Murray, Secretary of
					 State (includes correspondence)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958-1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 27</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Proclamations</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 28</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Production and Cost of Farm
					 Operations of State Prison</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 29</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Property and Equalization for
					 Tax Purposes</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 30</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Salaries, State and City
					 Employees</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959, undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 31</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Shipping of Daughter's
					 Autocycle (includes correspondence, financial and legal documents)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">18 / 32</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">South American Visit of
					 Governors (includes correspondence)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 1</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">State Board of Education
					 [includes oversize material: see OVBX 6]</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">State Board of Examiners
					 (includes correspondence)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954-1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">State Board of Land
					 Commissioners</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955-1960</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 4</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">State Expenses</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1956-1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">State Prison (includes
					 correspondence)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955, 1958</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 6</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Swedish Trip (includes
					 correspondence)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1958-1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 7</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">"The Life We Prize",
					 Biographical Radio Broadcast (includes correspondence)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 8</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Tri-State TV Repeater
					 Association</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Miscellany</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 9</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Awards and Certificates
					 [includes oversize material: see OVBX 6]</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1955, 1960-1961</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 10</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Favorite Recipes at Governor's
					 Mansion</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 11-13</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Guest Registers</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1953-1955</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 14</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Jamestown Festival
					 Booklet</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 15</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Song, "Trastland"</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 16</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Transcript, Telephone
					 Conversation between Governor Aronson, Wes D'Ewart, and Fred Martin regarding
					 Bricker Amendment</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1954</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">19 / 17</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Unidentified Notes</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Clippings</unittitle>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">OVBX / 1-5</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Scrapbooks (re
					 Governorship)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1952-1961</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">20 / 1-2</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Scrapbooks, Swedish
					 Trip</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">20 / 3</container>
              <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Miscellaneous
					 (Swedish)</unittitle>
              <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1949-1959</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>

