<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<!--Template updated 20150-04-24 by J. Allison-Bunnell in accordance with changes that resulted in Best Practices version 3.8-->
<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
<!--                              EADHEADER BEGINS HERE                           -->
<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
<!--Remember to name and save documents using the OCLC code + local filename. Documents that are revised/updated after initial submission much be submitted with precisely the same filename. Do NOT use the MARC code in your filename!-->

<ead> 
<!--The following section is header information that describes the finding aid-->
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601"> 
  	<eadid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="identifier" mainagencycode="mtu" identifier="80444/xv81710" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv81710">MTGRg002</eadid> 
	 <filedesc> 
		<titlestmt> 
		  <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the University of Montana (Missoula, Mont.) Mansfield Library Records
			 <date encodinganalog="date" normal="1903/2003">1903-2003</date></titleproper>
		  
			<titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">University of Montana (Missoula, Mont.) Mansfield Library records</titleproper>
		  
		  <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding aid prepared by Archives Staff</author>
		</titlestmt> 
	 	<publicationstmt>
	 		<publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Maureen and Mike Mansfield
	 			Library, The University of Montana--Missoula<extptr actuate="onload" show="embed" href="http://www.lib.umt.edu/images/Lib_logo.gif"/></publisher>
	 		<date encodinganalog="date"/>
	 		<address>
          <addressline>Missoula, MT 59812</addressline>
          <addressline>406-243-2053</addressline>
          <addressline>http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc</addressline>
          <addressline>library.archives@umontana.edu</addressline>
        </address>
	 	</publicationstmt>
	 </filedesc> 
	 <profiledesc> 
		<creation>Finding aid encoded by Kellyn Younggren
			<date normal="2015">2015</date></creation>
		
		<langusage>Finding aid written in 
		  <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.</langusage> <descrules>Finding aid based
		on DACS ( 
		<title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content
		  Standard</title>) 1st Edition.</descrules> 
	 </profiledesc> 
  </eadheader> 
	
	<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
	<!--                         COLLECTION-LEVEL DESCRIPTION BEGINS HERE             -->
	<!-- oooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooooo -->
	
  <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="marc21"> 
	 <did> 
	 	<repository>
	 		<corpname encodinganalog="852$a">University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections</corpname>
	 		<address>
          <addressline>The University of Montana—Missoula </addressline>
          <addressline>Missoula, MT 59812</addressline>
          <addressline>406-243-2053</addressline>
          <addressline>http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc</addressline>
          <addressline>library.archives@umontana.edu</addressline>
        </address>
	 	</repository>
		<unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="us" repositorycode="mtu">RG 002</unitid>
		
		<origination> 
		  <corpname encodinganalog="100" role="creator" source="lcnaf">Mansfield Library</corpname> </origination> 
		<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">University of Montana (Missoula, Mont.) Mansfield Library Records</unittitle>
		
		<unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" normal="1903/2003">1903-2003</unitdate>
		
		<physdesc> <extent encodinganalog="300$a">82.4 linear feet</extent>
		</physdesc>
		<abstract encodinganalog="5203_">This collection consists of materials created by the operation of the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library of the University of Montana in Missoula. Materials include annual reports, correspondence, meeting materials, contracts, holdings information,
		grants, budgets, and information about the library buildings from 1903 to 2003.</abstract> 
		<langmaterial>Materials are in <language encodinganalog="546">English.</language></langmaterial>
	
	 </did>
 
  	<bioghist encodinganalog="5451"><head>Historical Note</head><!--Enter ENCODINGANALOG value of 5450_ for biog. or 5451_ for historical note, or use <head> element-->
		
  		<p>The library at the University of Montana in Missoula began with University President Oscar Craig’s daughter, Mary, presiding over 817 volumes at the university’s first campus, the old Willard School building. By the end of the first academic year, the collection had grown to 1,369 books, 19 periodicals, and 20 newspaper subscriptions. The library later moved to University Hall.</p>
  		<p>Librarian and Professor Gertrude Buckhous served from 1902 to 1931 and built the first comprehensive library program. She received advanced study at Columbia University in New York City and was active in national and international library associations. A Missoula, Montana native and University of Montana graduate, she also administered the library economy program. Highlights of her administration include the construction and occupation of the first library building (now Jeannette Rankin Hall) in 1908 and construction and occupation of a second library building (now the Social Sciences Building) in 1922. Miss Buckhous died in 1931.</p>
  		<p>Librarian and Professor Philip Keeney served from 1931 to 1940, though he was absent during the lawsuit over his employment from 1937 to 1940. He was a graduate of the University of California School of Librarianship (certificate 1927) and the University of Michigan Graduate School (MA in history and library science 1930). He was active in the Pacific Northwest Library Association. His administration was marked by conflict and strife; the Board of Regents ordered removal of certain materials from library in 1935 and he refused to comply with their move to censor materials. The Board requested Keeney’s resignation in April 1937. After a lengthy lawsuit with the university, he resigned in 1940 for a position at the Library of Congress.</p>
  		<p>Executive Librarian and Professor Kathleen Campbell served from the fall of 1939 to the spring of 1966. She arrived on temporary assignment during Keeney’s absence, but was officially appointed to the position following his resignation in 1940. A graduate of the University of Denver School of Librarianship, she was active in the Pacific Northwest Library Association, the Montana Library Association, and the American Library Association. She also served as professor in the UM’s Library Economy department. Highlights of her administration include renovation of the second library building to accommodate growth, planning for the third library building, and the beginnings of the Archives program.</p>
  		<p>Dean of Library Services Earl Thompson served from 1964 to 1982, replacing Campbell the last two years of her administration. He earned a MA in history from Duke University (1951), a MLn (Master of Librarianship) from Emory University (1951) and did graduate work in history at Louisiana State University. Before he moved to Montana, he was Associate Dean of Libraries at Louisiana State University. Thompson was active in the Pacific Northwest Library Association, the American Library Association, and the Montana Library Association. His administration planned the construction and move to the library’s present location, laid groundwork for automation, extended participation in interlibrary loan efforts, hired additional faculty, and merged with the Forestry Library. The library building was named for Maureen and Mike Mansfield in 1979. </p>
  		<p>Dean of Library Services Ruth Patrick served from 1983 to 1990. She came from Wayne State University and held a PhD in Library Science from the University of California, Berkeley. Highlights of her administration included planning for automation and a major reorganization of staff and faculty.</p>
  		<p>Dean of Library Services Karen Hatcher served from 1991 to 2000. She was active in the Montana Library Association and Pacific Northwest Library Association. Highlights of her administration included automation, planning for future automation systems, and the inclusion of other Montana campuses under the library’s administration.</p>
  	</bioghist> 
	 <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_"> 
	 	<p>The records consist of the paper files from the library administration, library directors, staff association, and Archives. Organization, order, and completeness vary widely by administration. There are no records that predate the Buckhous administration.
	 	</p><p>Materials include contracts, annual reports, meeting materials, holdings records, orders, budgets, grants, and building information.</p> 
	 	
	 </scopecontent> 
	
	 <arrangement encodinganalog="351"> 
	 	<p>Materials are mostly arranged chronologically by administration, then largely as they were arranged and used by the originating office. Alphabetical and subject arrangements vary widely.</p>
	 </arrangement>  
  	<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506" id="a14"> 
  		<p>Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of
  			Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and
  			The University of Montana-Missoula. These materials are restricted, please contact Archives and Special Collections for details.</p>
  		
  	</accessrestrict> 
  	<userestrict encodinganalog="540" id="a15"> 
  		<p>Researchers are responsible for using in accordance with 17 U.S.C. and
  			any other applicable statutes. Copyright held by the University of Montana.</p>
  		
  	</userestrict> 
  	<prefercite encodinganalog="524" id="a18"> 
  		<p>University of Montana (Missoula, Mont.). Mansfield Library Records,
  			Archives and Special Collections, Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The
  			University of Montana-Missoula.</p> 
  	</prefercite> 
	 <custodhist encodinganalog="561"> 
		<p>Materials were in possession of the Mansfield Library's administration until their transfer to Archives and Special Collections in many different accessions.</p> 
	 </custodhist>  
	 <accruals encodinganalog="584"> 
		<p>Additions to this collection are expected.</p> 
	 </accruals> 
	 <processinfo encodinganalog="583"> 
		<p>The actions of the original processor(s) are unknown. The original order of these materials was largely maintained, materials are arranged intellectually by library administration and then, to varying degrees, alphabetically and by subject. Materials received after 1998 are unprocessed and may have an inventory. Please contact Archives and Special Collections for details.</p>
		
	 </processinfo> 
 
  	<!-- ooooooooooooooooooo     ACCESS POINTS     oooooooooooooooooooo -->
  	
	 <controlaccess> 
		<p>This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online
		  catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or
		  places should search the catalog using these headings.</p> 

		<controlaccess> 
			<corpname role="subject" encodinganalog="610">Mansfield Library--Archives</corpname>		  
			<corpname role="subject" encodinganalog="610">University of Montana--Missoula--Libraries</corpname>
		  
		</controlaccess> 

		<controlaccess> 
			<subject encodinganalog="650">Libraries--Montana--Missoula</subject>
		  
		</controlaccess> 
		<controlaccess> 
		  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Colleges and Universities</subject> 
		  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Montana</subject>
		  
		</controlaccess> 

	 </controlaccess> 
  	<!--A finding aid without a series or container list may end here.-->
  	
  	<!-- ooooooooooooooooooooooooo BEGIN CONTAINER LIST (Optional) oooooooooooooooo -->
   	<!--Be sure to choose the appropriate TYPE attribute for this collection-->

  </archdesc> </ead>

