<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="dc" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv07278" identifier="80444/xv07278" mainagencycode="mtbc" encodinganalog="identifier">MZF2395.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the Manhattan Malting Company Records 1895-1914<date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1895/1914" type="inclusive"/></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Manhattan Malting Company Records</titleproper>
        <author encodinganalog="creator">Kim Allen Scott</author>
        <sponsor encodinganalog="contributor">Funding for encoding this finding aid was provided by a grant from the National Endowment for the Humanities</sponsor>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections</publisher>
        <date encodinganalog="date" calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2009">2009</date>
        <address>
          <addressline>P.O. Box 173320, Centennial Mall</addressline>
          <addressline>Montana State University</addressline>
          <addressline>Bozeman, MT 59717</addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-11-16</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn" encodinganalog="language">Finding aid written in English</language>
      </langusage>
      <descrules>Finding aid based on DACS (Describing Archives: A Content Standard), 2nd Edition.</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="marc21" type="inventory">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Montana State University Library, Archives and Special Collections, Manuscript Collections</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Manhattan Malting Company records</unittitle>
      <origination>
        <corpname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="110">Manhattan Malting Company (Manhattan, Mont.)</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unitid countrycode="US" repositorycode="mtbc" encodinganalog="099">2395</unitid>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">2 volumes</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1895/1914" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1895-1914</unitdate>
      <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">The Manhattan Malting Company Records include two volumes. The volumes chronicle the company's transactions and expenses from the malt house and elevator, farm, townsite and freight.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>Collection materials are in English</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="5451_">
      <p>In the late 1880s, a group of wealthy New York and Brooklyn maltster became interested in the farming opportunities in Gallatin County. By 1891 they bought 13,000 acres of land next to Manhattan and planted barley. The newly created Manhattan Malting Company was ran by an elite force from back east. Henry Altenbrand, Sr., a wealthy maltster from New York, was named president; Jacob Rupert, vice-president, owned the largest brewery in the world; and George Kinkel, Jr., son of the owner of the New York Yankees, was manager. These men were so influential that in 1891 they had the name of the town changed from Moreland to Manhattan after the Democratic Manhattan Club in New York where most of the stockholders were members. The company quickly grew. By 1892 the first elevator was completed which had a holding capacity of 275,000 bushels of barley. The malting plant was finished a year later and could hold an additional 250,000 bushels. The company purchased a Jacob Price Field Locomotive steam plow in order to farm its vast lands. This plow was the first of its type used in Montana and could plow forty acres a day. The company was building worldwide? fame as well when its first brewmaster, Louis DeKregnasis's product was famed across the country and was especially liked in Germany. In 1905 the Manhattan Malting Company sold its land to the Manhattan (Ranching) Company. The malting company continued to grow and in 1914 won the award for best malted barley by the Pabst Brewing Company in Milwaukee. The company could not, however, overcome prohibition. The plant closed early in 1915 when Idaho, Oregon and Washington became dry states. The company was forced out of business in 1919 when Montana passed prohibition on 1 January 1919. The malt house was condemned after the earthquake of 1925, but the farm houses of the company are still standing today and are occupied. Many of the older citizens of Manhattan still refer to the buildings as Number One and Number Two, as the malting company designated them. Harry Altenbrand, Jr. was the Manhattan Malting Company manager from 1905 until it closed. His house is now the Masonic Temple in Manhattan.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
      <p>The Manhattan Malting Company records include two volumes. The first book is a monthly journal from December 1895 to January 1908, recording transactions from the malt house and elevator, farm, townsite, and freight. The second book is a cash book from February 1909 to October 1914. It is a record of expenses from the malt house and elevator, farm, and townsite.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <p>This collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <p>The business ledgers of the Manhattan Malting Company from 1895-1914 were donated to Special Collections by the Gallatin County Justice Center in the fall of 1979 and separated from accession 2083.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <processinfo>
      <p>This collection was processed 2009 February 20</p>
    </processinfo>
    <controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <geogname source="lcsh" encodinganalog="651">Montana</geogname>
        <geogname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="651">Manhattan (Mont.)</geogname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="650">Malt industry-Montana-Manhattan</subject>
        <subject authfilenumber="sh 85002415" source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Agriculture</subject>
        <subject authfilenumber="sh 85080195" source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Malt industry</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Business enterprises --Montana</subject>
        <subject authfilenumber="sh 85018285" source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Business enterprises </subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Montana</subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <genreform source="lcsh" encodinganalog="655">Business records--Montana--Manhattan (Mont.)</genreform>
        <genreform authfilenumber="300141693" source="aat" encodinganalog="655">Business records</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc type="in-depth">
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Manhattan Malting Company Journal ledger book</unittitle>
          <unitid encodinganalog="099">Volume 1</unitid>
          <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1895 December - 1908 January</unitdate>
          <container type="volume">1</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="item">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Manhattan Malting Company Cash book</unittitle>
          <unitid encodinganalog="099">Volume 2</unitid>
          <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1909 February - 1914 October</unitdate>
          <container type="volume">2</container>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>

