<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="publish" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-DSI-AAA" url="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9d259c7ef-2930-40f2-93ee-63583644234b">AAA.phelw</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper type="filing">Phelps (William Preston) papers</titleproper>
        <titleproper>A Finding Aid to the William Preston Phelps and Ina Phelps Hayward papers, 1849-2001, bulk 1890s-1920s  </titleproper>
        <author>Stephanie Ashley</author>
        <sponsor>Glass plate negatives in this collection were digitized in 2019 with funding provided by the Smithsonian Women's Committee.</sponsor>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Archives of American Art</publisher>
        <p>
          <date>2018/11/13</date>
        </p>
        <address>
          <addressline>750 9th Street, NW</addressline>
          <addressline>Victor Building, Suite 2200</addressline>
          <addressline>Washington, D.C. 20001</addressline>
          <addressline>Business Number: Phone: 202-633-7950</addressline>
          <addressline>https://www.aaa.si.edu/services/questions</addressline>
          <addressline>
            <extptr xlink:href="https://www.aaa.si.edu/" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://www.aaa.si.edu/" xlink:type="simple"/>
          </addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-08-24 12:58:07 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did id="refIDd1e67">
      <repository>
        <corpname>Archives of American Art</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>William Preston Phelps and Ina Phelps Hayward papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname authfilenumber="no2010061678" rules="aacr" source="naf">Phelps, W. P. (William Preston), 1848-1923</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>AAA.phelw</unitid>
      <unitid type="ark">
        <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9d259c7ef-2930-40f2-93ee-63583644234b" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
      </unitid>
      <physdesc id="refIDd1e91" altrender="whole">
        <extent type="Linear feet">1.1 Linear feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1849/2001" type="inclusive">1849-2001</unitdate>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1890/1929" type="bulk">bulk 1890s-1920s</unitdate>
      <abstract id="aspace_197cf1e8ccd5a6f8878b45e38e480087">The papers of New Hampshire landscape painter William Preston Phelps and his daughter, artist Ina Phelps Hayward, measure 1.1 linear feet and date from 1849-2001, with the bulk of the material dating from the 1890s to the 1920s. Papers include letters from Phelps, and correspondence regarding Ina Phelps Hayward's involvement in her father's 1917 estate sale; sales and legal records related to the Phelps estate; a scrapbook and printed material about William Preston Phelps; a sketchbook of sketches attributed to Phelps; sketches by Ina Phelps Hayward and her husband Roger Hayward; photographs of Phelps, his home and studio in Chesham, New Hampshire, and his artwork; and glass plate negatives, including two of Phelps and thirty-six of his artwork.</abstract>
      <langmaterial id="refIDd1e106"><language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <arrangement id="aspace_b23418c69b207c0f4797c789364a0f4b">
      <head>Arrangement</head>
      <p>The collection is arranged as one series.</p>
      <list type="ordered">
        <item>Series 1: William Preston and Ina Phelps Hayward Papers, 1849-2001 (1.3 linear feet; Box 1, OV 2, Boxes 3-4)</item>
      </list>
    </arrangement>
    <bioghist id="aspace_617ec41f515f905a51eefeacd4331bfb">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>William Preston Phelps (1843-1923) was known as "the painter of Monadnock," for his paintings of his native New Hampshire and the state's most prominent peak.</p>
      <p>Phelps grew up working on his family's farm in Chesham, New Hampshire, and by his early twenties owned his own sign business in the neighborhood. Meanwhile, his first exhibition of paintings in Lowell, Massachusetts, attracted the attention of some local businessmen who funded an education for Phelps in Europe. During the late-1870s to the mid-1880s, Phelps studied in Munich and Paris with William Merritt Chase and others. Upon returning to the United States via England and Scotland, Phelps set up a studio in Lowell and then traveled west in 1886 where he painted a notable series of western landscapes, with subjects including the Grand Canyon. Following his father's death, Phelps took over and settled on the family farm, and painted the New Hampshire landscapes for which he is best known. </p>
      <p>Following his son's death in an accident in 1901, and his wife's death six months later, Phelps's financial situation began to unravel and his health entered a steady decline. In 1914 he turned over his estate to an auctioneering firm, J. E. Conant &amp; Co., from which he had borrowed money for a number of years. Phelps's daughter, Ina Phelps Hayward, herself an artist, attempted to ensure that her father's property was handled fairly in the estate sale, but much of his property and paintings, including some of his best known pictures, were sold for very little or disappeared with no record of provenance. Phelps, who was in the Concord State Hospital at the time, died five years later and his daughter's attempts to pursue J. E. Conant &amp; Co. through the courts, were unsuccessful. </p>
      <p>Phelps's paintings can be found in the collections of the William Benton Museum of Art, the New Hampshire Historical Society, the Shelburne Museum, and others.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_36c8e7e813f8430e69606a14c5d617c7">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C., Research Center.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <userestrict id="aspace_66ff5302d0d64cad2dfe0e41822508cb">
      <head>Terms of Use</head>
      <p>The Archives of American Art makes its archival collections available for non-commercial, educational and personal use unless restricted by copyright and/or donor restrictions, including but not limited to access and publication restrictions. AAA makes no representations concerning such rights and restrictions and it is the user's responsibility to determine whether rights or restrictions exist and to obtain any necessary permission to access, use, reproduce and publish the collections. Please refer to the <extref xlink:href="https://www.si.edu/termsofuse" xlink:title="Smithsonian Terms of Use">Smithsonian's Terms of Use</extref> for additional information.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <altformavail id="aspace_6f1bf5750001bad2c3e9ed2646cb4543">
      <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
      <p>Portions of the collection and material lent for microfilming are available on 35mm microfilm reels 79, 370 and 647 at Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of material described in the container inventory does not reflect the arrangement of the collection on microfilm.</p>
    </altformavail>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_522465489ab26bfb482a011d43afbdee">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>Peter Hayward, grandson of Phelps, donated the collection to the Archives of American Art in 1969. Hilda Hayward Parker, Phelps' granddaughter, lent a notebook for microfilming in 1973. Karl Gabosh, an art dealer who purchased the papers from the estate, donated additional material in 2009.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <prefercite id="aspace_c84b471406bc1767e80475816368c92a">
      <head>Preferred Citation</head>
      <p>William Preston and Ina Phelps Hayward papers, 1849-2001, bulk 1890s-1920s. Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo id="aspace_451abcfac93ef745c532069c83041dff">
      <head>Processing Information</head>
      <p>Portions of the collection were microfilmed on reels 79 and 370 at some point after receipt. The glass plate negatives were re-housed in 2015 with a grant provided by the Smithsonian Collections Care and Preservation Fund. The entire collection was merged and processed and a finding aid written by Stephanie Ashley in 2018.</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_037726f335b3e13d7bc856763bb6ab0b">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>The papers of New Hampshire landscape painter William Preston Phelps and his daughter, artist Ina Phelps Hayward, measure 1.1 linear feet and date from 1849-2001, with the bulk of the material dating from the 1890s to the 1920s. Papers include letters from Phelps, and correspondence regarding Ina Phelps Hayward's involvement in her father's 1917 estate sale; sales and legal records related to the Phelps estate; a scrapbook and printed material about William Preston Phelps; a sketchbook of sketches attributed to Phelps; sketches by Ina Phelps Hayward and her husband Roger Hayward; photographs of Phelps, his home and studio in Chesham, New Hampshire, and his artwork; and glass plate negatives, including two of Phelps and thirty-six of his artwork.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <separatedmaterial id="aspace_81db7e5d216885ac541b5fec9eb69c31">
      <head>Separated Materials</head>
      <p>The Archives of American Art also holds material lent for microfilming (reel 647) including a notebook kept by Ina Hayward containing notes on her father, William Preston Phelps, in preparation for a book on Phelps (never written). The notebook includes biographical information, data on a few of his paintings, and notes about his study in Munich, Germany. Her daughter, Hilda Hayward Parker, later added additional biographical data, and a description of the Phelps' homestead and family life in Chesham, New Hampshire. Lent materials were returned to the lender and are not described in the collection container inventory.</p>
    </separatedmaterial>
    <controlaccess id="refIDd1e199">
      <occupation altrender="occupation" source="lcsh">Painters -- New Hampshire</occupation>
      <genreform altrender="genre_form" authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300027354" source="aat">Sketchbooks</genreform>
      <genreform altrender="genre_form" authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300015617" source="aat">Sketches</genreform>
      <genreform altrender="genre_form" authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300046300" source="aat">Photographs</genreform>
      <genreform altrender="genre_form" authfilenumber="http://vocab.getty.edu/aat/300027341" source="aat">Scrapbooks</genreform>
      <persname authfilenumber="n89606689" source="naf">Hayward, Roger</persname>
      <persname authfilenumber="no2010138650" rules="aacr" source="naf">Hayward, Ina Phelps, 1871-1944</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc id="refIDd1e224">
      <c level="series" id="ref57">
        <did id="refIDd1e228">
          <unittitle>William Preston Phelps and Ina Phelps Hayward Papers</unittitle>
          <unitid>Series 1</unitid>
          <unitid type="ark">
            <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw95d8d4fae-61df-4a1d-8f41-df15e8da284f" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
          </unitid>
          <physdesc id="refIDd1e240" altrender="whole">
            <extent type="Linear feet">1.1 Linear feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">Box 1, OV 2, Boxes 3-4</extent>
          </physdesc>
          <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1849/2000" type="inclusive">1849-2000</unitdate>
        </did>
        <scopecontent id="aspace_2e682017cb0665093984640854f3ad5e">
          <head>Scope and Contents</head>
          <p>Correspondence includes letters from William Preston Phelps to John I. Coggeshall, posthumous letters to Ina Phelps Hayward from various people and institutions regarding Phelps exhibitions, and Karl Gabosh's correspondence relating to his interest in, and research on, Phelps. One letter written in reply to Gabosh encloses a photograph taken by Phelps of Mount Monadnock.</p>
          <p>Correspondence and legal records related to the Phelps estate include correspondence with auctioneers J. E. Conant and Co., and with Phelps's attorney; payments and receipts kept by Ina Phelps Hayward documenting her work done on behalf of her father's estate and payments she made to him such as allowances and expenses; legal documentation of Phelps Hayward being appointed her father's guardian; and records of her attempts to protect the integrity of his estate prior to, and after, the 1917 estate sale. Phelps Hayward's notes for the estate sale catalog provide biographical information about her father and lists of his paintings and exhibitions.</p>
          <p>A scrapbook contains news clippings primarily about Phelps, two family letters, an invitation to Phelps's studio, an announcement for the exhibition of Phelps's Grand Canyon painting, a catalog of his paintings for sale in 1878, and a loose copy of "A Painter of Monadnock" by Charles E. Hurd, reprinted from <emph render="italic">The New England Magazine</emph>. </p>
          <p>A sketchbook, labeled "W. P. Munchen" is attributed to William Phelps and contains figure sketches and sketches of rural and city scenes in pencil. Twelve sketches in pencil and watercolor are by Ina Phelps Hayward and her son, Roger Hayward.
Printed material consists primarily of photocopies of articles about Phelps, and scattered exhibition invitations. Of note are a copy of a 1900 exhibition catalog of Phelps's work with prices, and a copy of the estate sale catalog. Later news clippings document posthumous interest in Phelps's work up to 2001. </p>
          <p>Photographs include two studio portraits of Phelps and a photograph of him reclining in his orchard. Also found are photos of an unidentified woman and a baby; a print made from a negative of the Phelps estate sale; photos of Phelps's Chesham home, studio, and surrounding landscape; and photos of his paintings.</p>
          <p>Glass plate negatives include two portraits of Phelps and thirty-six negatives of his paintings.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <altformavail id="aspace_d6cea846cfc80aa2144eefc6ed4d3377">
          <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
          <p>Glass plate negatives have been scanned.</p>
        </altformavail>
        <c level="file" id="ref58">
          <did id="refIDd1e284">
            <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9ae746a15-e346-4177-a112-8ae76f3ad4ca" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1872/1888" type="inclusive">1872-1888</unitdate>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1891/1899" type="inclusive">1891-1899</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_091f5221e224b6542b958fcc4142355c" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844932]">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_091f5221e224b6542b958fcc4142355c" type="Folder">1</container>
            <dao id="refIDd1e307" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://edan.si.edu/slideshow/slideshowViewer.htm?eadrefid=AAA.phelw_ref58" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Correspondence" xlink:type="simple">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Correspondence</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref59">
          <did id="refIDd1e319">
            <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw926a51614-0d9d-482a-9dc5-c77aaf61c7e0" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1900/1908" type="inclusive">1900-1908</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_9003183d490e0277bc034b5a51010c66" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844932]">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_9003183d490e0277bc034b5a51010c66" type="Folder">2</container>
            <dao id="refIDd1e339" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://edan.si.edu/slideshow/slideshowViewer.htm?eadrefid=AAA.phelw_ref59" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Correspondence" xlink:type="simple">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Correspondence</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref60">
          <did id="refIDd1e352">
            <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw99ecbf3b3-4c13-45bc-b344-d93dba35027e" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1905/1931" type="inclusive">circa 1910-1931</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e4b17ce75e8608c6c5f23384774e4abc" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844932]">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_e4b17ce75e8608c6c5f23384774e4abc" type="Folder">3</container>
            <dao id="refIDd1e372" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://edan.si.edu/slideshow/slideshowViewer.htm?eadrefid=AAA.phelw_ref60" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Correspondence" xlink:type="simple">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Correspondence</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref61">
          <did id="refIDd1e384">
            <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw90389e004-ab9a-4fe0-bc7c-64aec062d150" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/2000" type="inclusive">1981-2000</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_c9333a2ab40b90968a61422c133d970d" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844932]">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_c9333a2ab40b90968a61422c133d970d" type="Folder">4</container>
            <dao id="refIDd1e404" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://edan.si.edu/slideshow/slideshowViewer.htm?eadrefid=AAA.phelw_ref61" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Correspondence" xlink:type="simple">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Correspondence</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref62">
          <did id="refIDd1e416">
            <unittitle>Correspondence Regarding Estate</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw95377965a-618e-4479-bab9-d0e7ba5eaa1c" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1911/1915" type="inclusive">1911-1915</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_1ed8e51dfef006ebd47f012dd4fd360f" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844932]">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_1ed8e51dfef006ebd47f012dd4fd360f" type="Folder">5</container>
            <dao id="refIDd1e436" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://edan.si.edu/slideshow/slideshowViewer.htm?eadrefid=AAA.phelw_ref62" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Correspondence Regarding Estate" xlink:type="simple">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Correspondence Regarding Estate</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref63">
          <did id="refIDd1e448">
            <unittitle>Correspondence Regarding Estate</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw98b88b1ea-ce3d-4747-9527-28cda8ff303e" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1916/1923" type="inclusive">1916-1923</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_8f4296fdc7aa45eaf6729c9fcf22b969" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844932]">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_8f4296fdc7aa45eaf6729c9fcf22b969" type="Folder">6</container>
            <dao id="refIDd1e468" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://edan.si.edu/slideshow/slideshowViewer.htm?eadrefid=AAA.phelw_ref63" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Correspondence Regarding Estate" xlink:type="simple">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Correspondence Regarding Estate</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref64">
          <did id="refIDd1e480">
            <unittitle>Estate Records, Legal Documents</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw979d18837-8d3f-419c-933f-5ce12205ef84" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1849/1923" type="inclusive">1849-1923</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_9d4f972418855f11ee0db254048ba8e9" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844932]">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_9d4f972418855f11ee0db254048ba8e9" type="Folder">7</container>
            <dao id="refIDd1e500" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://edan.si.edu/slideshow/slideshowViewer.htm?eadrefid=AAA.phelw_ref64" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Estate Records, Legal Documents" xlink:type="simple">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Estate Records, Legal Documents</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref65">
          <did id="refIDd1e512">
            <unittitle>Estate Records, Notes for Estate Sale Catalog</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw99747ea82-9c3b-4caa-9cfb-73208c8b13a7" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1912/1922" type="inclusive">circa 1917</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_9244446b1f3d4d044f819086376f47a7" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844932]">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_9244446b1f3d4d044f819086376f47a7" type="Folder">8</container>
            <dao id="refIDd1e532" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://edan.si.edu/slideshow/slideshowViewer.htm?eadrefid=AAA.phelw_ref65" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Estate Records, Notes for Estate Sale Catalog" xlink:type="simple">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Estate Records, Notes for Estate Sale Catalog</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref66">
          <did id="refIDd1e545">
            <unittitle>Estate Records, Payments and Receipts</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9009dc89c-5b1a-433d-960d-7f7c32bcffc5" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1915/1922" type="inclusive">1915-1922</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_eeb703336f755852ec9609b226f4e3d3" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844932]">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_eeb703336f755852ec9609b226f4e3d3" type="Folder">9</container>
            <dao id="refIDd1e565" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://edan.si.edu/slideshow/slideshowViewer.htm?eadrefid=AAA.phelw_ref66" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Estate Records, Payments and Receipts" xlink:type="simple">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Estate Records, Payments and Receipts</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref67">
          <did id="refIDd1e577">
            <unittitle>Estate Records, Payments and Receipts</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw90ef59239-86bd-463a-b13e-f81bbf215a6f" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1917/1922" type="inclusive">1917-1922</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_7125b3e40c0815dd604bc86a210bd3b1" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844932]">1</container>
            <container parent="aspace_7125b3e40c0815dd604bc86a210bd3b1" type="Folder">10</container>
            <dao id="refIDd1e597" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://edan.si.edu/slideshow/slideshowViewer.htm?eadrefid=AAA.phelw_ref67" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Estate Records, Payments and Receipts" xlink:type="simple">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Estate Records, Payments and Receipts</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref68">
          <did id="refIDd1e609">
            <unittitle>Scrapbook, Sketchbooks, and Sketches</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9e2815264-0b6e-4d37-bcdf-3da0ccc7c6f2" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1871/1934" type="inclusive">circa 1875-circa 1929</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_afc5f67c7dc03178e1870582e5ca26e2" type="Oversize" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844221]">2</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref72">
          <did id="refIDd1e629">
            <unittitle>Clippings</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9e02f6585-7b09-4375-96c3-72936e54294b" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1905/1950" type="inclusive">circa 1910-1950</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_6881662eb99d3337c57be2a8cad2d97c" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844940]">3</container>
            <container parent="aspace_6881662eb99d3337c57be2a8cad2d97c" type="Folder">1</container>
            <dao id="refIDd1e649" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://edan.si.edu/slideshow/slideshowViewer.htm?eadrefid=AAA.phelw_ref72" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Clippings" xlink:type="simple">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Clippings</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref73">
          <did id="refIDd1e661">
            <unittitle>Photocopied Research Material</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9350ca568-b534-4b68-adc2-306c1faf7800" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1970/1989" type="inclusive">1970s-1980s</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_031a6dbaeeb919d64433342a48b34827" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844940]">3</container>
            <container parent="aspace_031a6dbaeeb919d64433342a48b34827" type="Folder">2</container>
            <dao id="refIDd1e681" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://edan.si.edu/slideshow/slideshowViewer.htm?eadrefid=AAA.phelw_ref73" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Photocopied Research Material" xlink:type="simple">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Photocopied Research Material</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref90">
          <did id="refIDd1e693">
            <unittitle>Duplicates of Research Material</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw96c514a58-586e-48b9-aca7-29908e56f12e" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1970/1989" type="inclusive">1970s-1980s</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e8e05454ef02d95d6f5956404a8f28fe" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844940]">3</container>
            <container parent="aspace_e8e05454ef02d95d6f5956404a8f28fe" type="Folder">3</container>
          </did>
          <altformavail id="aspace_6d029553595bcd99eeec61b56d3672a5">
            <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
            <p>(not scanned)</p>
          </altformavail>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref91">
          <did id="refIDd1e724">
            <unittitle>Clippings and Exhibition/Auction Announcements</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9d94c3615-53f7-4121-8398-75c1e2eed5c7" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1982/2001" type="inclusive">1982-2001</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_cfc5b4c9b8e050313ade157b5f2f868f" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844940]">3</container>
            <container parent="aspace_cfc5b4c9b8e050313ade157b5f2f868f" type="Folder">4</container>
            <dao id="refIDd1e744" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://edan.si.edu/slideshow/slideshowViewer.htm?eadrefid=AAA.phelw_ref91" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Clippings and Exhibition/Auction Announcements" xlink:type="simple">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Clippings and Exhibition/Auction Announcements</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref74">
          <did id="refIDd1e756">
            <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9bc346034-6b28-4e7c-a482-ce4d873fb2d3" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
          </did>
          <c level="file" id="ref75">
            <did id="refIDd1e769">
              <unittitle>Of Phelps and Others</unittitle>
              <unitid type="ark">
                <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9a0c35d0b-10db-448f-b35b-68c29482569a" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
              </unitid>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1900/1910" type="inclusive">circa 1905</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_715b84d48366d65801989f61c64859eb" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844940]">3</container>
              <container parent="aspace_715b84d48366d65801989f61c64859eb" type="Folder">5</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c level="file" id="ref76">
            <did id="refIDd1e792">
              <unittitle>Of Estate Sale</unittitle>
              <unitid type="ark">
                <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9a6696b29-3f4f-4021-a243-f0e242582231" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
              </unitid>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1917/1995" type="inclusive">1917, circa 1980s</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_b8fd2dcf3b4deeb3e23b865bf17b7dc9" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844940]">3</container>
              <container parent="aspace_b8fd2dcf3b4deeb3e23b865bf17b7dc9" type="Folder">6</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c level="file" id="ref77">
            <did id="refIDd1e815">
              <unittitle>Of Home, Chesham, NH</unittitle>
              <unitid type="ark">
                <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9de1a127c-1e18-4f03-9fa9-6183fd81abad" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
              </unitid>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1885/1905" type="inclusive">circa 1890s</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_cf43146fa9788c82a3a5e2058c4bb8c2" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844940]">3</container>
              <container parent="aspace_cf43146fa9788c82a3a5e2058c4bb8c2" type="Folder">7</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c level="file" id="ref78">
            <did id="refIDd1e838">
              <unittitle>Of Home, Chesham, NH, by K. Gabosh</unittitle>
              <unitid type="ark">
                <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw92320dca8-4a9f-4bde-b56d-c7fdc07c9e64" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
              </unitid>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1982/1982" type="inclusive">1982</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_2c0ea190e7d26ba8006cae8dea97a0ca" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844940]">3</container>
              <container parent="aspace_2c0ea190e7d26ba8006cae8dea97a0ca" type="Folder">8</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c level="file" id="ref79">
            <did id="refIDd1e862">
              <unittitle>Of Studio, Chesham, NH</unittitle>
              <unitid type="ark">
                <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw983d36d3d-cd1b-4b75-b15b-f1ab58a87576" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
              </unitid>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1886/1896" type="inclusive">circa 1891</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_3e5bc9be8ff2a76f81462e93392ad4cb" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844940]">3</container>
              <container parent="aspace_3e5bc9be8ff2a76f81462e93392ad4cb" type="Folder">9</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c level="file" id="ref80">
            <did id="refIDd1e885">
              <unittitle>Of Artwork by Phelps</unittitle>
              <unitid type="ark">
                <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw903e3af49-09ad-4b7e-a564-484cb619c58d" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
              </unitid>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1849/2000" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_d18b1162e3c7a95b0d49b9ac34382e10" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844940]">3</container>
              <container parent="aspace_d18b1162e3c7a95b0d49b9ac34382e10" type="Folder">10</container>
            </did>
          </c>
          <c level="file" id="ref81">
            <did id="refIDd1e908">
              <unittitle>Of Artwork by Phelps</unittitle>
              <unitid type="ark">
                <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9f9b21fe9-040d-4da5-919d-e01f5334794e" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
              </unitid>
              <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1915/1935" type="inclusive">circa 1920s</unitdate>
              <container id="aspace_7c76b1ac2d316ae0e8ada4f9d22a61a3" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844940]">3</container>
              <container parent="aspace_7c76b1ac2d316ae0e8ada4f9d22a61a3" type="Folder">11-14</container>
            </did>
          </c>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref82">
          <did id="refIDd1e932">
            <unittitle>List of Glass Plate Negatives</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw98dc4e201-9dcd-4e4c-897a-410f07f107cf" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1914/1935" type="inclusive">circa 1919-circa 1920s</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_59ace97f5cba37d19ccba91c17642888" type="Box" label="Mixed Materials [31027000844940]">3</container>
            <container parent="aspace_59ace97f5cba37d19ccba91c17642888" type="Folder">15</container>
          </did>
        </c>
        <c level="file" id="ref83">
          <did id="refIDd1e955">
            <unittitle>Glass Plate Negatives, of Phelps and Artwork by Phelps</unittitle>
            <unitid type="ark">
              <extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9bbd184ce-b1b9-46f3-b894-a1d0d9bf32f8" xlink:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
            </unitid>
            <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1914/1935" type="inclusive">circa 1919-circa 1920s</unitdate>
            <container id="aspace_e1c964672561199d730db4c7235c171d" type="Box" label="Negatives [31027000771028]">4</container>
            <dao id="refIDd1e971" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="https://edan.si.edu/slideshow/slideshowViewer.htm?eadrefid=AAA.phelw_ref83" xlink:role="image-service" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="Glass Plate Negatives, of Phelps and Artwork by Phelps" xlink:type="simple">
              <daodesc>
                <p>Glass Plate Negatives, of Phelps and Artwork by Phelps</p>
              </daodesc>
            </dao>
          </did>
        </c>
      </c>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>