<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="publish" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-DSI-AAA" url="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw961270f3b-b894-4152-920d-1b67a6fa9c74">AAA.bendwill</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>William H. Bender papers </titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Archives of American Art</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>750 9th Street, NW</addressline>
          <addressline>Victor Building, Suite 2200</addressline>
          <addressline>Washington, D.C. 20001</addressline>
          <addressline>https://www.aaa.si.edu/services/questions</addressline>
          <addressline>
            <extptr ns2:href="https://www.aaa.si.edu/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="https://www.aaa.si.edu/" ns2:type="simple"/>
          </addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-04-06 15:29:28 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did id="refIDd1e54">
      <repository>
        <corpname>Archives of American Art</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>William H. Bender papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname source="ingest">Bender, William H., 1894-</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>AAA.bendwill</unitid>
      <unitid type="ark">
        <extref ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw961270f3b-b894-4152-920d-1b67a6fa9c74" ns2:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
      </unitid>
      <physdesc id="refIDd1e78" altrender="part">
        <extent type="Linear feet">6 Linear feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1940/1972" type="inclusive">[ca. 1940]- 1972</unitdate>
      <langmaterial id="refIDd1e87"><language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_hzc208733n506as34840620045068">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C., Research Center. Contact Reference Services for more information.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_hzc208733n520as40633153245722">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>Correspondence, photographs, clippings, catalogues, business records, and files on his collection of works of art. These files include clippings, photographs, biographical information about the artists, research summaries on the subjects of the works of art, and correspondence with relatives, agents, or the artists themselves, about the works of art.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_hzc208733n520as49361860097411">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>Artists' files include: Edwin A. Abbey, Harold Altman, Thomas Anshutz, George Ault, Mordechi Avniel, John Avery, Milton Avery, Peggy Bacon, Charles Bargue, John Noble Barlow, Paul W. Bartlett, Gifford Beal, George Bellows, Ben Benn, Thomas H. Benton, Saul Berman, James H. Beard, Albert Bierstadt, Sarah Bernhardt (contains a photograph of Bernhardt taken by Napoleon Sarony, 1891), Ralph Blakelock, Oscar Bluemner, Frank M. Boggs, Louis Bouché, Charles Burchfield, Arthur B. Carles, Guiseppe Castiglione, Thomas Chambers, J. Wells Champney, Christine (Brush) Chaplin, William M. Chase, Alson Clark, Samuel Clarkson, Timothy Cole, Thomas Cole, Vincent Colyer, Bruce Crane, Jasper Cropsey, Charles C. Curran, J. Frank Currier,</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_hzc208733n520as57176826742434">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>Elliot Daingerfield, F.O.C. Darley, Randall Davey, Andrew Dasburg, Arthur B. Davies, Charles Deas, Carl de'Albert, Charles Demuth, Edwin Deming, Thomas Dewing, N. Diaz, Edwin Dickinson, Preston Dickinson, Francis Dixon, Thomas Doughty, Arthur G. Dove, Guy Pène du Bois, Frank Duveneck, "The Eight," Louis M. Eilshemius, Albert Looking Elk (Albert Martinez), William Etty, Abel Faivre, John M. Falconer, Lyonel Feininger, Alvan Fisher, Gilbert Gaul, Samuel W. Gaylor, Wood Gaylor, Q. T. Galwey, Lillian Genth, William Glackens, Arthur C. Goodwin, Florence Wolf Gotthold, Samuel Halpert, James Hamilton,</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_hzc208733n520as77029706880388">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>William Harnett, George W. Harris, George O. Hart, James &amp; William Hart, Marsden Hartley, Childe Hassam, Charles Hawthorne, Martin J. Heade, Robert Henri, E. L. Henry, Eugene Higgins, Winslow Homer, Peter Hopkins, Edward Hopper, William M. Hunt, William F. Hulk, George Inness, LeRoy Ireland, David Johnson, Eastman Johnson, Bernard Karfiol, John Kensett, Walt Kuhn, F. S. Kurz, Harry Lachman, John La Farge, Ernest Lawson, Hayley Lever, Ossip Linde,Louis Lozowick, George Luks, Elmer MacRae, Norwood MacGilvary, Dodge Macknight, John Marin, Reginald Marsh, Homer D. Martin, Jan Matulka, A. H. Maurer,Henry Lee McFee, Richard Emil Miller, William R. Miller, Thomas Moran, Louis Moeller, Gabriel Morcillo, James H. Moser, William S. Mount, J. Francis Murphy,</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_hzc208733n520as31251008312850">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>Jerome Myers, Robert L. Newman, John Noble, George Of, Georgia O'Keeffe, Majorie Organ, Jules Pascin, Louis M. Potter, Edward Potthast, Charles Prendergast, Maurice Prendergast, Levi W. Prentice, James Preston, F. Newlin Price, William Prior, Henry W. Ranger, Odilon Redon, T. Addison Richards, Theo Robinson, Orlando Rouland, A. P. Ryder, John S. Sargent, Charles Sarka, Charles Sheeler, Everett Shinn (includes a typescript of a play by Shinn), Florence S. Shinn, Walter Shirlaw, John Sloan, Edith Smith (Hertz), William L. Sonntag, Raphael Soyer, Eugene Speicher, Niles Spencer, Carl Sprinchorn, John Wells Stancliff, Joseph Stella, Maurice Sterne, Thomas Stevens, Thomas Sully,</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_hzc208733n520as43094913400359">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>Arthur F. Tait, John H. Twachtman, Allen Tucker, Alfred W. Thompson, Henry O. Tanner, Wilhelm Trubner, Elihu Vedder, Antoine Vollon, Horatio Walker, William Aiken Walker, Abraham Walkowitz, Max Weber, J. Alden Weir, Robert Weir, Benjamin West, Irving R. Wiles, James M. Whistler, Stanford White, Worthington Whittredge, Charles S. Woodbury, Robert S. Woodward, Carl Wuermer, Alexander H. Wyant, Mahonri Young, Marguerite Zorach, and William Zorach.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <bioghist id="aspace_hzc208733n545as21699407018396">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>William H. Bender, Jr. was an insurance businessman and American art collector; New York, N.Y. Among his early interests were "The Eight" group of painters: Robert Henri, George Luks, Everett Shinn, Arthur B. Davies, Ernest Lawson, John Sloan, William Glackens, and Maurice Prendergast. He later became an avid collector of Lillian Genth, and was designated her executor.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_hzc208733n561as97205671911059">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>Donated 1976 by Mrs. William H. Bender, widow of Bender.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <controlaccess id="refIDd1e157">
      <subject altrender="topical" source="lcsh">Art, American -- Collectors and collecting</subject>
      <subject altrender="topical" authfilenumber="https://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85007472" source="lcsh">Art -- Collectors and collecting</subject>
      <persname source="ingest">Bender, William H., 1894- -- Art collections</persname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc id="refIDd1e170">
      
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>