<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><ead xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:ns2="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="publish" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511">
    <eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-DSI-AAA" url="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9e652c3ae-3b75-450e-add1-f873c1f5df4e">AAA.burdhora</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Horace Robbins Burdick papers </titleproper>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Archives of American Art</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>750 9th Street, NW</addressline>
          <addressline>Victor Building, Suite 2200</addressline>
          <addressline>Washington, D.C. 20001</addressline>
          <addressline>https://www.aaa.si.edu/services/questions</addressline>
          <addressline>
            <extptr ns2:href="https://www.aaa.si.edu/" ns2:show="new" ns2:title="https://www.aaa.si.edu/" ns2:type="simple"/>
          </addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-04-06 15:51:36 -0400</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in English.</langusage>
      <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did id="refIDd1e54">
      <repository>
        <corpname>Archives of American Art</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle>Horace Robbins Burdick papers</unittitle>
      <origination label="Creator">
        <persname authfilenumber="nr2005023135" source="naf">Burdick, Horace Robbins, 1844-1942</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid>AAA.burdhora</unitid>
      <unitid type="ark">
        <extref ns2:actuate="onLoad" ns2:href="https://n2t.net/ark:/65665/mw9e652c3ae-3b75-450e-add1-f873c1f5df4e" ns2:show="new">Archival Resource Key</extref>
      </unitid>
      <physdesc id="refIDd1e78" altrender="part">
        <extent type="Items">3 Items</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1866/1942" type="inclusive">1914-1932</unitdate>
      <langmaterial id="refIDd1e87"><language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict id="aspace_hzc209416n506as33091993510131">
      <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
      <p>Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C., Research Center. Microfilmed materials must be consulted on microfilm. Contact Reference Services for more information.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <scopecontent id="aspace_hzc209416n520as93807961924592">
      <head>Scope and Contents</head>
      <p>A diary, Jan. 1, 1931-Jan. 1, 1932, containing daily, detailed entries regarding art and personal activities; a vol., "Constitution and By-Laws of the Boston Art Club," June 1, 1914; and a sketch identified as "Cow Boy Pool, Boston Art Club," by an unidentified artist, depicting men playing billiards at the Boston Art Club.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <altformavail id="aspace_hzc209416n530as59384924878752">
      <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
      <p>The diary and Boston Art Club v. are available on 35mm microfilm reel 3960; the papers lent for microfilming on reel 2523. Both reels are available at Archives of American Art offices and through interlibrary loan.</p>
    </altformavail>
    <originalsloc id="aspace_hzc209416n535as16361279106671">
      <head>Existence and Location of Originals</head>
      <p>Reel 2523: Originals, with the exception of one sketch, returned to the lender, art dealer Robert A. Goldberg, after microfilming.</p>
    </originalsloc>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_hzc209416n544as14178605193016">
      <head>Related Materials</head>
      <p>Also in the Archives are Horace Burdick papers, 1866-1942, lent for microfilming (reel 2523), including biographical information; writings and notes; photographs of Burdick and his family; clippings and sketches and drawings by Burdick, and many other artists, among them Hammett Billings, Edward Burrill, Carelton, Ed Champney, Augustus D. Chapin, Aldebert P. Close, J. Frank Currier, Horace P. Giles, H.R. Heaton, Augustus Hoppin, John N. Hyde, Wilhelm Leibl, Frank T. Merrill, John C. Miles, George Munzig, William E. Norton, Richard Pauli, W.C. Schouher, William Titcomb, Frank H. Tompkins, Frank C. Tompkins, and Paul S. Yendell.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <relatedmaterial id="aspace_hzc209416n544as62950701922390">
      <head>Related Materials</head>
      <p>Additional Horace Robbins Burdick papers, including a daybook (1869-1885); diaries, 5 v., 1914-1934; and a notebook containing painting instructions; two original sketches; and photographs of some of Burdick's work, are located in Winterthur Library, Joseph Downs Collection of Manuscripts and Related Ephemera, Winterthur, Del.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <bioghist id="aspace_hzc209416n545as18678450438530">
      <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
      <p>Portrait painter, teacher, conservator, photographer, and writer. Burdick was born in East Killingly, Conn. and studied at the Lowell Institute and the School of the Museum of Fine Arts, Boston. After working in Providence, R.I., he moved to Boston in 1864 where he set up a studio and became a member of the Boston Art Club. He is best known for his portraits in crayon and oil.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <acqinfo id="aspace_hzc209416n561as57937136854994">
      <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
      <p>The 1931 diary and Boston Art Club Constitution and By-laws were donated in 1985 by William Dromgoole, occupant of Burdick's former residence. Dromgoole acquired the papers from Burdick's daughter, Doris Burdick. The papers on microfilm reel 2523 were lent for microfilming 1982 by Robert Goldberg, an art and antique dealer from Conway, New Hampshire. Goldberg donated one of the many sketches that were lent; it is unclear how or where the remainder of the loan was dispersed. (Goldberg died in 1997; his art collection was bequethed to the Hood Museum at Dartmouth).</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <controlaccess id="refIDd1e150">
      <subject altrender="topical" source="lcsh">Painting, American -- Massachusetts -- Boston</subject>
      <occupation altrender="occupation" source="aat">Portrait painters -- Massachusetts -- Boston</occupation>
      <corpname authfilenumber="n91119218" source="naf">Boston Art Club</corpname>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc id="refIDd1e162">
      
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>