<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd" xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="completed" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-txhr">urn:taro:rice.wrc.00219</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Guide to the Men's League for Woman Suffrage of the State of New York letters, 1915
 <num>MS 144</num></titleproper><author>Laura Pike</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas</publisher><p><date>2005</date></p><address><addressline>Fondren Library MS-44, Rice University</addressline><addressline>6100 Main St. </addressline><addressline>Houston, Texas 77005</addressline><addressline>woodson@rice.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://woodson.rice.edu/woodson" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="http://woodson.rice.edu/woodson" xlink:type="simple" /></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p>Stored onsite at the Woodson Research Center.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2022-04-01 17:24:25 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>English</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <head>Collection Summary</head><repository encodinganalog="852$a">
      <corpname>Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas</corpname>
    <extref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:type="simple" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:href="http://www.w3.org/xlink">https://library.rice.edu/woodson</extref></repository>
    <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Men's League for Woman Suffrage of the State of New York letters</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname rules="local" source="local" encodinganalog="100">Hotchkiss, Thomas W.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid repositorycode="US-txhr" countrycode="US" encodinganalog="099">MS 144</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole" encodinganalog="300$a">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.1 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier"> (1 folder)</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate normal="1915/1915" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" type="inclusive">1915</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_58f1e04533fa2f3532c087c5dae2f0fa" encodinganalog="520$a">This collection consists of replies to a survey on suffrage for women conducted by the Men's League for Woman Suffrage of the State of New York, and signed by Thomas W. Hotchkiss, member of the League's Campaign Committee. The League was campaigning for the passage of an amendment to the N.Y. State Constitution on Nov. 2, 1915. Hotchkiss' letter was sent to governors and other officials of states, mostly western, which had already adopted women's suffrage, and was intended to solicit responses which would refute the objections raised by anti-suffragist opponents of the amendment in New York.</abstract>
    <langmaterial encodinganalog="546$a">
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist id="aspace_37e3bd9c4d311c2d27c527c8c79c5d72" encodinganalog="545$a">
    <head>Biographical Notes</head>
<p>Thomas W. Hotchkiss, a lawyer, editor, magazine writer, and professional researcher, was a member of the Campaign Committee of the Men's League for Woman Suffrage of the State of New York, which was active in promoting the passage of a women's suffrage amendment to the state constitution. In November of 1915, referenda for women's suffrage were on the ballot in four eastern states, including New York, but the opposition was strong. Many claimed that if given the right to vote, women would neglect their homes, and the fabric of society would be destroyed. The opposition also argued that undesirable women would flood the polls, and that a woman should not be allowed to vote if she wasn't willing to fight for her country. To help organize a response to the arguments against women's suffrage, Hotchkiss sent a form letter, dated September 27, 1915, to public officials in the states that had already adopted women's suffrage. While the response from the public officials was favorable, suffrage for women was again denied in the November 2, 1915 election. The New York Men's League for Woman Suffrage continued to campaign until New York passed the measure in 1917, three years before a national Constitutional Amendment granted suffrage to all American women.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_88a3126081acd0dab056a6f51d00b6f1" encodinganalog="520$b">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The collection consists of the form letter sent from Thomas W. Hotchkiss regarding the effects of women's suffrage, as well as the responses from public officials in states that had previously adopted the measure. The form letter, dated September 27, 1915, was sent to public officials in hopes of soliciting responses to the opposition to suffrage. Hotchkiss' letter asked if women began to neglect their homes, if the social fabric had been damaged, if undesirable women are active, and how one should respond to the argument that voting women should be expected to defend her country. </p><p>Twenty-seven public officials responded, including the Governor of Alaska, the Executive Secretary of California, the Governor of Illinois, the Attorney General of Utah, the Governor and Lieutenant Governor of Colorado, the Secretary of State and the Chief Justice of Washington, and the Governor, Chief Justice, and Secretary of State of Kansas. From Montana, the Governor, Chief Justice, Secretary of the Department of the Attorney General, and the Secretary of State all responded. In Nevada, the Governor, Chief Justice, Attorney General, and Secretary of State also sent responses, as did the Governor, Chief Justice, Secretary of State, and State Librarian of Oregon. The Governor, Secretary of State, Attorney General, and Deputy Secretary of State of Wyoming also wrote in response to the survey. The responses, which were of varying length and enthusiasm, were all in support of women's suffrage. </p>  </scopecontent>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_acc0dedde57d421518099a8ce3fa4100" encodinganalog="506">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This material is open for research.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_a6127243a611286229243fbc11793a6e" encodinganalog="541">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>This collection was purchased in 1960.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_f005ac20b9d5d51100bc9b736366832d" encodinganalog="524">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Men's League for Woman Suffrage of the State of New York letters, 1915, MS 144, Woodson Research Center, Fondren Library, Rice University</p>  </prefercite>
  <userestrict id="aspace_f335d01898898d71b1cdd127bc6d45b3" encodinganalog="540">
    <head>Restrictions on Use</head>
<p>Permission to publish material from the Men's League for Woman Suffrage letters must be obtained from the Woodson Research Center, Fondren Library.</p>  </userestrict>
  <controlaccess><head>Index Terms</head><controlaccess><head>Subjects</head><subject authfilenumber="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/1176568/" source="FAST" encodinganalog="650">Women</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Women -- Suffrage</subject>
    <subject source="local" encodinganalog="650">Political campaigns</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="http://id.worldcat.org/fast/1919741/" source="FAST" encodinganalog="650">Politics and government</subject>
    </controlaccess><controlaccess><head>Document Types</head><genreform source="aat" encodinganalog="655">corrrespondence</genreform>
    </controlaccess><controlaccess><head>Subjects (Persons)</head><persname rules="local" source="local" encodinganalog="600">Hotchkiss, Thomas W.</persname>
  </controlaccess><controlaccess><head>Subjects (Corporations)</head><corpname source="naf" encodinganalog="610">Men's League for Woman Suffrage (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
    </controlaccess></controlaccess><dsc type="combined"><c01 id="aspace_ref14_nyt" level="series"><did><unittitle>Series I: Correspondence, 1915</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="8459" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">8459</unitid></did><c02 id="aspace_ref15_0kn" level="item"><did><unittitle>Form letter by Hotchkiss, 1915</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="8461" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">8461</unitid><container id="aspace_a78cf694701cf51a440b3ce4f43da8ba" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ref16_lox" level="file"><did><unittitle>Response letters arranged in order alphabetically by state of origin.</unittitle><unitid audience="internal" identifier="8460" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT">8460</unitid><container id="aspace_105abfed40417c108af67990269176e9" label="Mixed Materials" type="Folder">1</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>