<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="dc" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="US" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv71939" identifier="80444/xv71939" mainagencycode="orhi" encodinganalog="identifier">ohy_coll482.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the World War I letters from Bertrand St. Marie and George St. Marie<date calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1917/1919" type="inclusive"/></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">St. Marie (Bertrand and George) World War I letters</titleproper>
        <author encodinganalog="creator">Alecia Giombolini</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Oregon Historical Society Research Library</publisher>
        <date encodinganalog="date" calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2015/2023">2015; revised 2023</date>
        <address>
          <addressline>1200 SW Park Ave.</addressline>
          <addressline>Portland, OR 97205</addressline>
          <addressline>Business Number: 5033065204</addressline>
          <addressline>Business Number: 5033065240</addressline>
          <addressline>libreference@ohs.org</addressline>
          <addressline>https://www.ohs.org/research-and-library/</addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-07-21</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>
        <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="latn" encodinganalog="language">Finding aid is written in English.</language>
      </langusage>
      <descrules>Finding aid based on DACS (Describing Archives: A Content Standard), 2nd Edition.</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="marc21" type="inventory">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Oregon Historical Society Research Library</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">World War I letters from Bertrand St. Marie and George St. Marie</unittitle>
      <origination>
        <persname rules="rda" source="local" role="corespondent" encodinganalog="100">St. Marie, Bertrand, 1896-1986</persname>
        <persname rules="rda" source="local" role="corespondent" encodinganalog="700">St. Marie, George, 1894-1983</persname>
      </origination>
      <unitid countrycode="US" repositorycode="orhi" encodinganalog="099">Coll 482</unitid>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">0.2 cubic feet</extent>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">1 slim document case</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate calendar="gregorian" certainty="approximate" era="ce" normal="1917/1919" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1917-1919</unitdate>
      <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">Letters written by brothers George St. Marie and Bertrand (Bert) St. Marie during World War I, while they were serving in the United States Army. The letters were written to their mother, Blanche St. Marie, and sister, Dorothy St. Marie, who were living in Portland, Oregon.</abstract>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>
</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <p>Gift of George Stahl, via Andrea Noorts, May 2015 (Lib. Acc. 28573).</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="5450_">
      <p>Brothers Bertrand St. Marie (also known as Bert, 1896-1986) and George St. Marie (1894-1983) were born in Pocatello, Idaho, where their father had significant land holdings, including the St. Marie Hotel, now the historic Whitman Hotel. Several years before the outbreak of World War I, the two brothers, with their sister, Dorothy, and their mother, Blanche, moved to Portland, Oregon, while their father remained in Idaho.</p>
      <p>When the United States entered into World War I, Bert St. Marie seems to have been living in Portland, while George St. Marie had moved to Los Angeles, California. During the war, Bert St. Marie served in France with the 148th Field Artillery regiment, 66th Artillery Brigade, 41st Infantry. After the war, he lived in Portland until the 1940s, later moving to Southern California, where he married. He died in Santa Monica in 1986. </p>
      <p>George St. Marie served in the 316th Field Signal Battalion, 91st Infantry Division, known as the "Wild West Division." After training at Camp Lewis near Tacoma, Washington, he fought in the St. Mihiel offensive and the Meuse-Argonne offensive. He subsequently joined the military police and was stationed in Laval and Le Flèche, France. After the war, he initially returned to Portland, but later moved to Pocatello, Idaho, where he married and spent the remainder of his life.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <p>World War I letters from Bertrand St. Marie and George St. Marie, Coll 482, Oregon Historical Society Davies Family Research Library.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <processinfo>
      <p>Revised in July 2023 to conform to current standard. Collection was previously titled "St. Marie family papers."</p>
    </processinfo>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
      <p>This collection consists of of letters written by brothers George St. Marie and Bertrand (Bert) St. Marie during World War I, while they were serving in the United States Army. The letters were written to their mother, Blanche St. Marie, and sister, Dorothy St. Marie, who were living in Portland, Oregon. The letters begin in 1917, while Bert St. Marie was in training and George St. Marie was preparing to enlist. These early letters describe their experiences in training and preparations to be sent overseas. Letters from 1918 document the brothers' arrival in France, Bert St. Marie's first experiences in combat, the final months of the war, the armistice, and the months immediately after. The final letters were written while the brothers were part of the occupying forces in France and Germany. The letters end in mid-1919, when Bert St. Marie had returned to the United States and while George St. Marie was still serving with the military police in France. The collection also includes empty envelopes that did not have corresponding letters, and fragments of correspondence that could not be matched to other letters.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
      <p>The Oregon Historical Society owns the materials in the Research Library and makes available reproductions for research, publication, and other uses. The Society does not necessarily hold copyright to all materials in the collections. In some cases, permission for use may require seeking additional authorization from copyright owners.</p>
    </userestrict>
    <controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <persname rules="rda" source="local" encodinganalog="600">St. Marie, Bertrand, 1896-1986--Correspondence</persname>
        <persname rules="rda" source="local" encodinganalog="600">St. Marie, George, 1894-1983--Correspondence</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <corpname authfilenumber="no2014069122" source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">United States. Army. Field Artillery Regiment, 148th</corpname>
        <corpname authfilenumber="n2017004677" source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="610">United States. Army. Field Signal Battalion, 316th</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject authfilenumber="sh2008112029" source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Soldiers--United States--Correspondence</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">World War, 1914-1918--France</subject>
        <subject authfilenumber="sh2008113789" source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">World War, 1914-1918--Personal narratives, American</subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Oregon</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Military</subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <genreform authfilenumber="300026877" source="aat" encodinganalog="655">correspondence</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>

