<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Li-VAE4249</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Kock mss., May 1868</titleproper><titleproper>Kock mss., May 1868 <num>LMC 2979</num></titleproper><subtitle>Papers of Charles Paul de Kock, May 1868, at the Lilly Library, Indiana University</subtitle><author>Ava Dickerson</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Lilly Library</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/lilly.png" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>11/8/2022</date></p><address><addressline>1200 E. Seventh St.</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-5500</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-2452</addressline><addressline>liblilly@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-18 22:37:34 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Lilly Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Kock mss.</unittitle>
    <unitid>LMC 2979</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 bound</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1868-05/1868-05">May 1868</unitdate>
    <abstract audience="internal" id="aspace_cf8e0bba498f5bdc5f22becb47491060">The Kock mss., May 1868, consists of a bound manuscript draft of French novelist Charles Paul de Kock's <title render="italic">Madame Tapin.</title></abstract>
    <physloc audience="internal" id="aspace_f09e43effb7372f646fa047e323007ef">Lilly - Stacks</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="fre">French</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict audience="internal" id="aspace_e0060becb875a6d8e3843fb6cc66a816">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p>Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/ask">make an appointment</extref> a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict audience="internal" id="aspace_e9630d22f01cdfa79c7e8a919d91a8ca">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Photography and digitization may be restricted for some collections. Copyright restrictions may apply. Before publishing, researchers are responsible for securing permission from all applicable rights holders, then filling out the <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/permission-to-publish" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest">Permission to Publish form.</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo audience="internal" id="aspace_a4ae644e97fd544f795a72b0dd51f322">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Purchase: 2022</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist audience="internal" id="aspace_aa6b8d659fc2c5bc0bdcf6adabf2a960">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>"Kock, Charles Paul de (1793-1871), French novelist, was born at Passy on the 21st of May 1793. He was a posthumous cild, his father, abanker of Dutch extraction, having been a victim of the Terror. Paul de Kock began life as a banker's clerk. For the most part he resided on the Boulevard St Martin, and was one of the most inveterate of Parisians. He died in Paris on the 27th of April 1871. He began to write for the stage very early, and composed many operatic libretti. His first novel, <title render="italic">L'Enfant de ma Femme</title> (1811), was published at his own expense. In 1820 he began his long and sucessful series of novels dealing with Parisian life with <title render="italic">Georgette, ou La Mere de Tabellion.</title> His period of greatest and most successful activity was the Restoration and the early days of Louis Philippe. He was relatively less popular in France itself than abroad, where he was considered as the special painter of life in Paris. Major Pendenis's remark that he had read nothing of the novel kind for thirty years except Paul de Kock, who certainly made him laugh, is likely to remain one of the most durable of his testimonials, and may be classed with the legendary question of a foreign sovereign to a Frenchman who was paying his respects, "Vous venez de Paris et vous deves savoir des nouvelles. Comment se porte Paul de Kock?" The disappearance of the grisette and of the cheap dissipation described by Henri Murger practically made Paul de Kock obsolete. But to the student of manners his portraiture of low and middle class life in the first half of the 19th century at Paris still has its value." - 11th Edition of the Encyclopaedia Brittanica [1911]</p><p>"[Kock was] the prolific and immensely popular author of rollicking, risky, and more often frankly coarse frequently sentimental, and fundamentally good-natured novels. Written with an untiring comic vigour which made up for their complete lack of style, they were good pictures of the life and amusements of the people of Paris and the country c. 1825-45. They were read and enjoyed in England (by Macaulay and Elizabeth Barrett Browning among others..." - Harvey &amp; Heseltine, Oxford Companion to French Literature</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent audience="internal" id="aspace_9857ea97ca56082c28e1d5e6b743ed35">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>"The original manuscript of one of Charles de Kock's later novels, a closely written manuscript comprised of 19 chapters, with copious corrections, additions and deletions throughout, with occasional long notes in the margins. Written in May 1868, it was published by Ferdinand Sartorious as a 272-page book the same year. It reached a third edition by 1870. Kock appeared in Thackeray's <title render="italic">History of Pendennis</title> and James Joyce's <title render="italic">Ulysses.</title> A good natured story partly about a street violinist and singer, theatre, vaudeville, love, all of which includes a long chapter about preparing and eating a sumptuous meal, "Nouvelle omelette soufflee." Written near the end of Kock's long literary career, the romance was reprinted a number of times into the 20th century, as well as being translated into Polish in 1878. It's interesting that Kock would gravitate towards "Madame Tapin" as a fictional character 55 years after she appeared in his first book, <title render="italic">L'enfant de ma femme [the Child of My Wife]</title> (1813)." - Bookseller's description, Howard S. Mott, Inc.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement audience="internal" id="aspace_0a61b459bd2d84f70d9c014eeb9c6373">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged following original order, in a single volume.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite audience="internal" id="aspace_fd26095e6bf36453997e851f8f10da08">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Kock mss., Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </prefercite>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ed360e5d182f14e96348c9a7ae59078c" level="file"><did><unittitle><title render="italic">Madame Tapin</title></unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1868-05/1868-05">May 1868</unitdate></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
