<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="originaldraft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Li-VAE1188</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>American Song Sheets,<date normal="1850/1870" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1850-1870</date> <num>M1628.2.A5</num></titleproper><author>Electronic finding aid encoded by Indiana University Libraries.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Lilly Library</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/lilly.png" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2020</date></p><address><addressline>1200 E. Seventh St.</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-5500</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-2452</addressline><addressline>liblilly@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2020">© 2020</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-18 22:30:21 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English. </langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>27 April 2020</date><item>Encoded finding aid created by Mary McSparran.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Lilly Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>American Song Sheets</unittitle>
    <unitid>M1628.2.A5</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">459 Items</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1850/1870" type="inclusive">1850-1870</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1999/1999">1999</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_63c8b7d27ec7ac1ba48f4628ae5dcb15">This collection consists of American song sheets without music from the mid-19th century.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_f8a866840904b16a3b0bbb40af95808e">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_dc272c5960748bf7389c8167d974463b">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p>Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/ask">make an appointment</extref> a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_2ec0309acc0de8a7b702c5ba314661e5">
    <head>Historical Note</head>
<p>Most of the song sheets were published or printed by J. Andrews and H. De Marsan of New York and J. H. Johnson of Philadelphia. Some have the ink stamp of T. C. Boyd, 228 Montgomery, San Francisco. The list was compiled by the Zamboni &amp; Huntington, booksellers.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_2b7fd06104f54aca76d0b4880c1a1c1c">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged alphabetically by song title.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_26d431bb32fa41abf4491e946cd0f703">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection consists of American song sheets without music from the mid-19th century. Included are ballads, patriotic songs, Irish songs, love songs, etc. Most of the items have illustrated borders, some of which are colored. The entry for each item includes a caption title; any composer, performer or author information from the piece; the first line of the text, number of verses and chorus if present; name of melody; place and publisher or printer; date if given; printing details, such as border design; and a reference to Edwin Wolf's <title render="italic">American song sheets, slip ballads, and poetical broadsides 1850-1870: a catalogue of the collection of the Library Company of Philadelphia.</title></p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_1bab126062f6e188c1756b932919b4dd">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Purchase: <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate></p>  </acqinfo>
  <prefercite id="aspace_fb6b954128bfdf0f023a3c8e7078f256">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], American Song Sheets, Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="ingest">American Song Sheets</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_4c54b4d91484206e152a54d35ffbd07c" level="file"><did><unittitle>1. Acrostic. Mary, Wilt Thou Have Me? - Mary, tho' I'm doomed to languish (5 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_6a5115cdfee387020e29a87f3ce7bb47" level="file"><did><unittitle>2. Adolpheus Snow. - White folks, listen to me now (5 verses.) Air. - "Blow, ye Winds, I, O." New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper. See Wolf 16.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2b32d774dd0bbb4e864077d7e3b2f797" level="file"><did><unittitle>3. Agnes May. - I kissed her lip and left her side (3 verses.) New York: H. Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4ab9aa239a67c6c64010df02b96d6660" level="file"><did><unittitle>4. Aileen Astore - Oh! blessings for ever on Aileen Astore! (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. See Wolf 24.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0b42fad5425d347049a8a636038896bc" level="file"><did><unittitle>5. All among the Hay. - Though I am what is called a "swell" (5 verses, chorus, spoken part.) Written by Wallace Markham. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with battle scenes in lower comers. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_af59859df16c62bd3ca55e62279abf35" level="file"><did><unittitle>6. All Round My Hat. - All round my hat I vears a green villow (6 verses, spoken part.) No. 331. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley Pat and Mike. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_6a26e86e5a19a615b47e0e3d5fe85d40" level="file"><did><unittitle>7. All's for the Best. - All 's for the best! be sanguine and cheerful (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. See Wolf 32.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f3fa193eadd6d0d837f37f3147368615" level="file"><did><unittitle>8. The American Boy. - "Father look up and see the flag (8 verses.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Wavy-line with ornamental corners. Wolf 35b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_009ebd7a80b1ffcfa8edb31db1d64a3f" level="file"><did><unittitle>9. American Drinks. - The other night I'd been indulging -which I own is very silly (4 verses and chorus.) Sung by W. F. Sinclair, the Greatest Serio-Comic Singer in the United States. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower corners. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_7be84eb5232338073f4a3c5bb372dad3" level="file"><did><unittitle>10. An Angel Form. - An Angel Form, in dreams beheld (2 verses.) Second song: "Care Flies the Brain." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 42.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_05bdb214a192e9720707c34d8407b9b4" level="file"><did><unittitle>11. Annie I Have Missed You. - Dear Annie, it is you there, safe and well alone (3 verses.) Air... "Willie we have missed you." By Frederick S. English. New York: J. Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 44.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_acc98876ab531c228f840854a3fd1efb" level="file"><did><unittitle>12. Annie of the Vale. - The young stars are glowing (2 verses and chorus.) Words by G. P. Morris; music by J. R. Thomas. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. See Wolf 47.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ef87988b29f3ec42d35a1fa1da97d93e" level="file"><did><unittitle>13. Annie of the Vale. - The young stars are glowing (2 verses and chorus.) Words by G. P. Morris; music by J. R. Thomas. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. See Wolf 47.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_724d1943a65ccc7d51a9747df993aa0f" level="file"><did><unittitle>14. Answer to a Thousand a Year. - Have you heard the strange news just came down, Gaffer Green (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 53.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_404c65452c96b3eb855258726365d24b" level="file"><did><unittitle>15. Aunt Dinah. - I knew an old nigger Aunty once (3 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_93359489972bf7acf026cade3f0c3d28" level="file"><did><unittitle>16. Banks of Allan Water. - On the banks of Allan Water (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0cb3324095f99b869062f7607ae9434c" level="file"><did><unittitle>17. Banks of Claudy. - It was on a summer 's morning all in the month of May (7 verses.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Wavy lines top and bottom of text. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_24edbc17091f3747a226a9d3c6a2c0a1" level="file"><did><unittitle>18. Banks of Claudy. -It was on a summers morning all in the month of May (7 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Dc Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d14eb2dc3eea68bbb3620e138cb17f72" level="file"><did><unittitle>19. The Banks of Sweet Dundee. - It is of a farmer's daughter, so beautiful I'm told (10 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4f9cc71a84ff828aa5dcf04fc615e660" level="file"><did><unittitle>20. Banks of the Old Mohawk. - On the banks of the Old Mohawk (3 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c201dabc9c1aa0b9517250181a308e45" level="file"><did><unittitle>21. The Bard's Legacy. - When in death I shall calm recline (3 verses.) Second song: "The Lover's Wish." New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 85a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_74d974135899d935c9e5167a5b08cfbc" level="file"><did><unittitle>22. Bashful Young Man. - They say I shall get over it, but no, I never can (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Wolf 87b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_682deaabedf98ac5e6cb1fac709f5477" level="file"><did><unittitle>23. The Batchellor. - The batchelor sits in is dreary room (7 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Yankee pedlar, colored. Wolf 75a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_63aebf8893c346194853f189929d74d4" level="file"><did><unittitle>24. Battle of Bull-Run. - Our gallant soldiers they are gone and left their friends to mourn (8 verses.) Dedicated to the 69th Regiment, N.Y.S.M. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower corners. See Wolf 95.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9d4c3bf42293c7e396256b4e226bff59" level="file"><did><unittitle>25. Beautiful Nell. - Don't talk to me of pretty girls! (6 verses and chorus.) Published with music by C. W. A. Trumpler. Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Lines at top and bottom of text, one dotted. See Wolf 119.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c0571169359d4335b69317f138dd8053" level="file"><did><unittitle>26. The Belles of the 'Bus. - T'other day I indulged in an omnibus ride (6 verses.) Air: "The Mistletoe Bough. (The Old Oak Chest." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 129.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1bd378df6b58d1659ff1e9ff5f11774a" level="file"><did><unittitle>27. Be Quiet, Do, I'll Call My Mother. - As Kate was sitting in a wood (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. See Wolf 116.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f53199e3d7139b8073553132c24728f5" level="file"><did><unittitle>28. Billy Barlow. - Oh, good evening, gentlemen. how do you do? (10 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 142.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_610d22cfd4774a624914325ae9da2138" level="file"><did><unittitle>29. Black Ey'd Susan. - All in the Downs the fleet was moor'd (7 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 153.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_43cca7892894efacd55f721cb0cd13f4" level="file"><did><unittitle>30. Black Eyed Susan. - All in the Downs the fleet was moor'd (8 verses.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 153.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c170b4c5642ee485436efa574048d2ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>31. Blue Violets. - Blue violets, blue violets, beautiful blue violets (2 verses.) As sung by Charles Melville, the celebrated Balladist and Tenor vocalist. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 163a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e2b07ef6f0f0fba1a4e2a85362e2c577" level="file"><did><unittitle>32. Bonaparte's Farewell. - Farewell to the land, where the gloom of my glory (3 verses.) Air.: "Captain O'Kean." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower corners. Wolf 174.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_cfc30e3274a52d22e0b4e49cc924ae29" level="file"><did><unittitle>33. Bonnie Jamie. - The twilight hour is stealing (5 verses.) By James Robinson. Respectfully dedicated to my friend, Sergeant Wheeler, U.S.A.... New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 176.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_57386cd23c945046d5602b42186704ef" level="file"><did><unittitle>34. Brave Boys. - Heavily falls the rain (4 verses and chorus.) Words and Music by Henry C. Work. Published by H. M. Higgins.... Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 196h.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d06dff14d2cb20a7c399ae13787c2e41" level="file"><did><unittitle>35. Brooks's Canada Song. - To Canada Brooks was asked to go (6 verses.) Air - "The Cork Leg. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 211.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ae5fa1bdcde9ae3d146bec601a4c2f6a" level="file"><did><unittitle>36. Bruce's Address to His Army. - Scots, wha hae wi' Wallace bled! (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship, colored. See Wolf 215.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0101d13dfab33c4cd5b75ad8b0dd8f05" level="file"><did><unittitle>37. Bucanier's Bride. - Away, away o'er the boundless deep (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan trapper. Wolf 216.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e572b5e70c735a5900111df31a3c327f" level="file"><did><unittitle>38. Bummers, Come and Meet Us. -McClellan is our leader now, we've had our last retreat(7 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 225 a or b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4aae0d363dd2a3fae9516c7ff9287181" level="file"><did><unittitle>39. Burial of Sir John Moore. - Not a drum was heard nor a funeral note (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. Wolf 227.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_22c34545dbd15126a8ae8a6ca8fa65f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>40. By the Margin of Fair Zurich's Waters. - By the margin of fair Zurich's waters (2 verses.) New York: H. Dc Marsan, © 1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1b4f1474e77c34255ce154b21ca40424" level="file"><did><unittitle>41. By the Sad Sea-Waves. - By the sad sea-waves (2 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. See Wolf 232.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_829637f953e9a74cf59bf7b093b13751" level="file"><did><unittitle>42. The Carrier Dove. - Fly away to my native land, sweet Dove (3 verses.) N.p.: Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrew's ivy. Wolf 255a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_82c3ad3b4357e19465163937b479fb97" level="file"><did><unittitle>43. Carry the News to Mary. -Oh! Martha wept and Mary cried (3 verses and chorus.) Words by Charley Howard - Music by Walter Bray. Arranged by Eddie Fox. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 275.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_607a209d63a5aa3f94c25fea7d8ffc0b" level="file"><did><unittitle>44. Charming Jane Louisa. - It was in the merry month of June, when woods and fields were flowery (8 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. See Wolf 285.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d4e07aaf1f1b9b06a48e64fbeca24c0d" level="file"><did><unittitle>45. Cheer for the Pilots. - The sturdy Pilots put to sea (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship, with war scenes in lower comers, colored. See Wolf 293.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a6b01e3594a27d50125a370f9e504cdd" level="file"><did><unittitle>46. Christmas Carol. - The cold wind sweeps the branches bare (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_623b37ea98f95a718bdaedc71270019a" level="file"><did><unittitle>47. Come Home, Father. - Father, dear father, come home with me now (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Wolf 353.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f77cf68a3753ef5ced0de043b5307d4c" level="file"><did><unittitle>48. Come to de Old Gum Tree. - Come to de old Gum Tree (6 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c1de04d95e56fbe9013135f8f1b8d474" level="file"><did><unittitle>49. Come Wake Up, My Lady Love. - Come lend an ear, my lub, to me (4 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 362.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e901eec5ea95b0a779650eb33bf8e6ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>50. The Constitution! - Oh God, preserve the Union (3 verses and chorus.) National Anthem written, composed and respectfully dedicated to the President and people of the United States, by F. Widdows. Sung by James Dunn. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship, colored. Wolf 380.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_dac9fcad563ca93aeb0b653047f16fd9" level="file"><did><unittitle>51. The Crow Family. - I went from here to Washington a short time ago (7 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Wolf 408.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_785150c3e878c206670a524fdb40227f" level="file"><did><unittitle>52. Cruelty to Johnny! - Cruel wos de Captain vot took my Shon vrom me (4 verses and chorus.) [Philadelphia]: Johnson, n.d. See Wolf 409.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4596d6d16998eb6b87476ccb3b8516c8" level="file"><did><unittitle>53. Cum Plung Gum. - I wish I was a turtle dove (4 verses and chorus.) Original Song and dance by Joe Murphy, of San Francisco, Cal. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b21eeecc2f8eade39bfc3271593bf3f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>54. Daylight Is on the Sea. - Daylight is on the sea! (2 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Wolf 441.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_6e2e0a19aca6c085b15f64ba273ab8c0" level="file"><did><unittitle>55. The Dearest Spot on Earth to Me Is Home, Sweet Home. - The dearest spot of earth to me (2 verses.) Second song: "Welcome, Welcome Home." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Wolf 452a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_8f6f97302f2a4fc2de0b4727b6d6293c" level="file"><did><unittitle>56. Dearest, Then I'll Love Thee More. - Yes, I love thee, and how dearly (3 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Auner and Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_433aa145c9f21135021898cfdd94495e" level="file"><did><unittitle>57. Dear Mother I've Come Home to Die. - Dear mother, I remember well (3 verses and chorus.) No.855. Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1467r (under "Mother, I've Come Home to Die")</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_fcf3c48cee252ddb6586ca8d791bcdfe" level="file"><did><unittitle>58. Dear Old Hag! - See the Flag! the dear old Flag (4 verses and chorus.) Composed and dedicated to the Soldiers of the Unit. Stat. By Wm. B. Bradbury. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan eagle. Wolf 449c.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_5bd7530ac28ee676b669f546253eb3c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>59. The Declaration. - We come, we come, a little band (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan eagle. Wolf 465a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3633e583b33b9cbbb3f3bf3fad97f1bc" level="file"><did><unittitle>60. Dina's Wedding. - Hurrah! hurrah! the day is come (3? verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: G. S. Harris, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 479.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_df6310a23d1694f663e0ed4fd5632a46" level="file"><did><unittitle>61. A Dollar or Two. - With cautious steps, we tread on our way through (3 verses and chorus.) As sung nightly, with tremendous applause, by Mrs. W. Jones in the drama of "Fast women" at the New Bowery Theatre.... New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Wolf 503.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_07c2560f9d352f45748cc22e102bd9a0" level="file"><did><unittitle>62. Donnelly &amp; Cooper, That Fought on Kildare. - Come all you true bred Irishmen, I hope you will draw near (8 verses.) [Philadelphia]: Johnson, n.d. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_bcb6bc9e9d3fada25981a31b9ae1f1bc" level="file"><did><unittitle>63. Don't You Go, Tommy. - You'll miss it, my boy, now mind what I say (3 verses and chorus.) Words and Music by C. T. Lockwood. Copied from the "Pulling hard against the Sream [sic] Songster,".... New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 511.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ea0264cd7ef81cc0cdab3f804662e9b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>64. Donybrook Fair. - Once I went to Donybrook, that good old Irish fair, sirs (8 verses and chorus.) Air - "Limerick Races." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. See Wolf 512.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_21bcccf42519be2347d61801d061af0f" level="file"><did><unittitle>65. Do You Ask Me if I Love You! - Do you ask me: if I love you? (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 496a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_dc6e1199dc4ec94bf9098710758c9575" level="file"><did><unittitle>66. The Dream of Bonaparte. - One night, sad and languid, I went to my bed (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. See Wolf 523.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_28cdfcb0b8a354bed2bb39c4478136d6" level="file"><did><unittitle>67. Drover Boy. - I'm a merry heart'd mountain drover boy (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Wolf 527.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e55d907c20710501b6a6cb16c7bdb62b" level="file"><did><unittitle>68. Drunkard's Lone Child. - Out in the gloomy night sadly I roam (3 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. See Wolf 534.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_04a1b37bde502a3b9a6a9d30619858bc" level="file"><did><unittitle>69. The Dumb Scold. -There lived an English blade, who loved a pretty maid (6 verses.) Air -"Cowskeen Lawn." New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 538.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_081a3eebd17e1240d965f94c482dcab5" level="file"><did><unittitle>70. Ellsworth's Avengers! - Down where the patriot army (5 verses and chorus.) Air: "Annie Lisle." By A. L. Hudson. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 562.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d21331c95ac1a3c90c1d19add46ecd08" level="file"><did><unittitle>71. The Englishman. - There's a land that bears a well known name (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Wolf 569.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_dfc40b18848352ed97f33158d360c378" level="file"><did><unittitle>72. Erin's Green Shore. - One evening so late as I rambled (4 verses.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_26d80fcb3ea3bed92ee5c1a4317a875c" level="file"><did><unittitle>73. The Escape of Stephens, the Fenian Chief. New Version of Shan Van Vocht. - Perhaps you'd like to know (9 verses.) With narrative preceding text, beginning: "The only exciting topic...." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 576.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ae0c4049ea56856290028d4ccda3bfa6" level="file"><did><unittitle>74. Ever of Thee. - Ever of thee I am fondly dreaming (2 verses.) As Sung by John Hasset. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 581.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1786c2fe4cef6261b0016e293062e751" level="file"><did><unittitle>75. Every Bullet Has Its Billet - I'm a tough true hearted sailor (3 verses.) A song by Mr. Charles Swain, at Jenkins' Concert Saloon Seventh &amp; Chestnut Streets. [Philadelphia: Harris, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 582a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a4e19c3dedae27af127ce87016f35411" level="file"><did><unittitle>76. Fairy Dell! - Wilt thou meet me in the fairy dell, love (3 verses and chorus.) A Companion to "Hazel Dell." Philadelphia: J. J. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 595.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3c4b62a1859c0cc7932458b6c1c67682" level="file"><did><unittitle>77. False One I Love Thee Still. - Still so gently o'er me stealing (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments. See Wolf 1012.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a9d8d8f8809d4145b73128d9611769ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>78. Fanny Gray. - Well, well, sir, so you've come at last, I thought you'd come no more (8 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 604.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_db1b13ddd0a0f30a17761838c73cb81e" level="file"><did><unittitle>79. Fare Thee Well Kitty Dear. - I saw the smile of evening die (3 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 607.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_33592559dd9eed5b96d1feef0355573b" level="file"><did><unittitle>80. Farewell! Dearest Maiden. - Farewell! dearest maiden (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_bff1b14e7a0f8adcd203286e0b3483b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>81. Farewell to the Home of My Childhood. - Farewell to the home of my childhood (2 verses.) With second song: "Saucy Kate." Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_714725a4ab938f876b2b078424450075" level="file"><did><unittitle>82. The Farmer Sat in His Easy Chair. - The farmer sat in his easy chair (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. See Wolf 613.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3be0ea31c93932c1168910085306b31e" level="file"><did><unittitle>83. The Farmer's Boy. - The sun had gone down behind yon hill (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Wolf 612b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c63af0731a0a5ef5646bea44a98924f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>84. The Farmer's Daughter. - It is of a rich farmer, I dare not tell his name (10 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3a47b71cbaab91187747d96fe84105ea" level="file"><did><unittitle>85. Father Macshane. - Old father Macshane hed was holy and fat (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Wolf 618a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_bde3f94d018b804b10ecbc543570a840" level="file"><did><unittitle>86. The Father of All Songs. - And come all, you lads and lasses, wherever you may be (5 verses.) Composed by Wm. Dunne. Air - "The Glorious Sixty-Ninth." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 619a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_68fd9d4e4fce920e3255468b67e5e4bd" level="file"><did><unittitle>87. The Father of All Songs. - And come all, you lads and lasses, wherever you may be (5 verses.) Air - "The Glorious 69th." Number 902. [Boston?]: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 619.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_df51a609e3b29805c0b48d189b208c44" level="file"><did><unittitle>88. The Fenian Brigade. - 0 ye, Sons of Green Erin, assemble (3 verses and chorus.) Air - "Red, White and Blue." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_dbde38eb84d3ac00fe9d99ce9c068f8a" level="file"><did><unittitle>89. The Fenian Men. - See who come over the red-blossomed heather! (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Wolf 627.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b52c3a7942265bc1b6482762d589852f" level="file"><did><unittitle>90. Few Days No.2. - This world is coming to an end, few days-few days (5 verses and chorus.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 629a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a8b8d7fc8ceb939b4730bd223ae6b0f6" level="file"><did><unittitle>91. The Fireman's Boy. - Mother, look out and see that light (22 verses.) Air - "The American Boy." N.p., n.d. See Wolf 642.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_52900a5db84836f41a9f89b26bd467f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>92. The Fireman's Death. - He slept, and o'er his dauntless brow (3 verses and choruses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 643b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_07caa6b2b3f3dd22f88a255ddf4eca56" level="file"><did><unittitle>93. The Flag with the Thirty-four Stars. - The Rebels sing the "Bonnie Blue Flag, " (5 verses and chorus.) New York: Charles Magnus, n.d. Letter paper, blue ink. Headpiece: Magnus 109A?, colored. Wolf 654g(?).</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f81e1ae4f9139bd8bfdb73c38a8c9669" level="file"><did><unittitle>94. The Flower of the Land. -The Sun-burst has dawned over all the glad mountains (3 verses and chorus.) Air - "Jessie, the Flower of Dumblane." - Sung by G. W. Gill. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 662.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a3ae6905f7f771f044ddddf01cd8e9d8" level="file"><did><unittitle>95. How Gently Sweet Afton. - Flow gently sweet Afton among thy green braes (2 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 661.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_bad7277df5b1925caa91ba9586859ec2" level="file"><did><unittitle>96. Folks that Put on Airs. - Oh White Folks listen will you now this darkey's going to sing (6 verses and chorus.) No 45. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley Ethiopian, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_36373d1f85aaee3dae5708797a69b666" level="file"><did><unittitle>97. Fond Hearts at Home. - When I left the dear home of my father's (3 verses.) No.1.66. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley kissing cupids. See Wolf 666.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d86d382ed94a5fed792e0b49ca919599" level="file"><did><unittitle>98. The Four Leaved Shamrock. - I'll seek a four leaved shamrock (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Wolf 670a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2c5e07533123b710ced2808831f48d9e" level="file"><did><unittitle>99. Fourth of July Song. - We hail, once again, the glad day that gave (3 verses.) Air: "Star-Spangled Banner." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan eagle. Wolf 672a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0d7f77a7578f196a367f802f18228944" level="file"><did><unittitle>100. Free and Easy Still. - I'm the lad that '5 free and easy (7 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. See Wolf 679.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ed31464c796750f83b6763c275bcbb0d" level="file"><did><unittitle>101. Friendship and Love. - Of every sensation true joy can impart (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 692.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2afaa7c421d79e6991627907d46850ce" level="file"><did><unittitle>102. Gal from the South. - My Massa had a colored gal (3 verses and chorus.) [New York?]: Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. Wolf 698.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_22ac6daa9575c2c2d2d1f47e0a385e1a" level="file"><did><unittitle>103. Gentle Jenny Gray. - My heart is sad, I'll tell you why (3 verses and chorus.) As sung by Mr. Joseph Murphy, of Wood &amp; Christy's Minstrels. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Wolf 731.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0fc02101bda54e4e898ca7855608c779" level="file"><did><unittitle>104. Gentle Maggie. - On an Island in the old Mohawk (3 verses and chorus.) Words by John Miller. Music composed and Arranged by Frank Mosier. As sung by the Mohawk Chorals of Cohoes, N.Y. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. See Wolf 732.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9f168b143b345eedc5225950e7fed82a" level="file"><did><unittitle>105. Gipsey Davy. - There was a lord, a high born lord (5 verses and chorus.) With second song: "Going Round the Horn." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_7b42ee24622d90223b5a2b8ba9f43944" level="file"><did><unittitle>106. The Gipsey Girl. - My father was king of the gipsies you know (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_86db6d1154d0f82210495a730724fc79" level="file"><did><unittitle>107. Give Me a Cot in the Valley I Love. - Give me a cot in the valley I love (2 verses.) Second song: "The Cot Where I Was Born." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 751c.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1eb1f90a014b8e0144d8d43052ea177e" level="file"><did><unittitle>108. God Will Care for Mother Now. - Weep no more, 0 nobly fallen! (3 verses and chorus.) Air - "Who will care for Mother now?" By Louise Barrows. No.901. [Boston?]: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 775.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9282172a7ad1b811119f487b8ad61239" level="file"><did><unittitle>109. The Good-Bye at the Door. - Of all the mem'ries of the past (2 verses.) Second song: "'Twas Rank and Fame." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. See Wolf 791.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b8dd1b370db333e9f9e9ec4007be8335" level="file"><did><unittitle>110. Good News from Home. - Good news from home - good news for me (3 verses and chorus.) No.154. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley kissing cupids. See Wolf 784.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_01f60021de8ad4e9c4e08aa8e06684a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>111. Good News from Home. - Good news from home - good news for me (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. See Wolf 784.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_7a1f823f346c3063dbf7fcba2bea4a69" level="file"><did><unittitle>112. The Grave of Bonaparte. -On a lone barren isle, where the wild roaring billow (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. See Wolf 805.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_98014795fed1f097a57478c254d72b57" level="file"><did><unittitle>113. The Great Prize Fight. - Sullivan made a match to fight (8 verses and chorus.) Air -"Camptown Races." Following title: "Which took place at Boston Corners, Oct. 12th, 1853." [New York: Andrews], n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 817a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c75db773fa64b4f9a8ee6eafc9d2fafa" level="file"><did><unittitle>114. The Grecian Bend [Nos. 1 and 21. - The ladies want something new (4 verses and chorus) and The world is taken all aback (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_dbc679867ba0c22b2307024a8da305a2" level="file"><did><unittitle>115. The Grecian Bend. No.3. - There was a young lady who in Gotham did dwell (8 verses and choruses, moral.) Air - "Vilikins and his Dinah." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2ac0150de5d08484e87d07f57909fd2e" level="file"><did><unittitle>116. The Green above the Red. - I am an Irish hero, that the English ne'er can frighten (3 verses and chorus.) Air: "There's Whiskey in the Jar." Composed and sung by Wm. H. Lindsey. Dedicated to St. Lawrence Circle of F.B. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower comers. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_7029654a5690dfe0b82134da365098f9" level="file"><did><unittitle>117. The Green Bushes. - I'll buy you new bavers and fine silken gowns (4 verses.) Second song: "Blow, Gentle, Gales." New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 822.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3337483dcc119fdea9364f919f5c5ec1" level="file"><did><unittitle>118. The Handsome Cabin Boy. - It is of a pretty female, as you shall understand (8 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 836.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_236ad8fda5722c0dc6a67cbadddb3ea9" level="file"><did><unittitle>119. Hans Dunder Has Gone for a Solger. - I'd traveled dis Countree there und here (5 verses and chorus.) Composed and sung by P. Bradel Jr. better known as Brudder Bones, Comic Singer of Avenue B. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Wolf 840.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ac0b27697ead5c5fb623735cc99faffb" level="file"><did><unittitle>120. Happy Haidee. - Gentle, gentle is the beam (2 verses and chorus.) As sung by Bryants' Minstrels. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 843a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_8124fba297ca3e7af61a2d318ec02d88" level="file"><did><unittitle>121. Happy Land of Canaan. - You may talk about de times (4 verses and chorus.) No.537. Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 848.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_83bed4d7c4da8344cac95f06af7476c2" level="file"><did><unittitle>122. Happy Land of Canaan. No.2 - Now kind folks, I'm going to sing a song (5 verses and chorus.) As sung by Toney Pastor. New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan clown, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_905215bbf7c276c5ea3c6ddbabe39a64" level="file"><did><unittitle>123. The Harp. - Magic harp of Erin! what stills thy sweet cadence (5 verses.) By Charles Conroy. N.p., n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0e0e7b309e1f207570c46f5129312612" level="file"><did><unittitle>124. The Harp of Old Erin and Banner of Stars. - The war trump has sounded, our rights are in danger (4 verses.) Air - "St. Patrick's Day." Dedicated to Charles J. Murphy, 1st Lieut., Scott Life-Guard, N.Y., by his sincere friend, Thomas Kean. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship. Wolf 854.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e996d26eef5c486fa9bc19759241bf49" level="file"><did><unittitle>125. Have You Seen My Sister. A Highly Popular Comic Song. - Say, my lovely friends, have you any pity (6 verses.) Tune. - "Bob and John." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_38b3fc3040c12e389d216f1e514cfad5" level="file"><did><unittitle>126. Heather Dale. - The peaceful little valley (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan clown, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d005be34832c5a12225c0a668f16e335" level="file"><did><unittitle>127. Heenan the Champion of the World. - Who was it crossed the raging ocean (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan harp, colored. Wolf 869.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_fd7b57e9c84243e8380d6bda6a999706" level="file"><did><unittitle>128. He Led Her to the Altar. - He led her to the altar (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_dfafbd2f1d696410f2f1e6f572298c3a" level="file"><did><unittitle>129. Her Heart Is the Prize I Will Gain. - To the Ball, to the Ball, I'll pursue her (3 verses.) Composed by F. W. N. Bayley. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Wolf 872.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a5571c7fbb299ca9481a6175b0b08b0c" level="file"><did><unittitle>130. Hicks the Pirate. - A mournful tale heart rending (5 verses.) Air: "The Rose Tree." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp, colored. See Wolf 881.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_203ec629bc1b271bc7646d303f0b7ea1" level="file"><did><unittitle>131. The Hod Carrier's Song. - l am a bold Hodman, I live by my trade (6 verses and chorus.) Air.- "Villikens and His Dinah." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Wolf 887a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_094b9416fb6f525dbdaa4fc94461b057" level="file"><did><unittitle>132. Hoist Up the Flag. - Away down in Dixie, the war first begun (7 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower comers. Wolf 888d.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_36a7bfe1544317bc66035a49704f7a00" level="file"><did><unittitle>133. Hoist Up the Flag Long May It Wave. - The Rebels thought they had us when the war first begun (11 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Auner-Johnson. Wolf 889e.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2f5635e502c7d84cb279db2d3ba70226" level="file"><did><unittitle>134. Hold Your Horses. - Now hold your horses, will you' and do not drive so fast ( 3 verses and chorus.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 163 la.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_83edc004968d6411ed54a28eac54e673" level="file"><did><unittitle>135. Holy Friar. A Humorous Song. - I am a Friar of orders Gray (2 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: George S. Harris, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_cb4ae1501ff9c683aa55de715a593d55" level="file"><did><unittitle>136. Home Again. - Home again, home again (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. See Wolf 891.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0a5fbb3ba04c1dda51ec33ec3ba521c9" level="file"><did><unittitle>137. The Home Where Roses Grew. - Oh! how often, when at eve I'm sitting (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Wolf 897.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_78e32efa8d9416d9d51353478c687d6d" level="file"><did><unittitle>138. Hoops, No.2. What a Ridiculous Fashion? - Now Crinoline is all the rage with ladies of whatever age (6 verses and chorus.) Air: "King of the Cannibal Islands." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Wolf 904b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_52df3f9a698627532302ed6a678b8f7b" level="file"><did><unittitle>139. How Sheridan Whipped Longstreet. - It was just before the day break, that this famous fight began (5 verses.) Air - "Jeannette and Jeannot." By John Ross Dix, October 19th, 1864. New York: Charles Magnus, ©1864. Letter paper, blue ink. Headpiece: Magnus 159, colored. Wolf 920g.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_8bbe5ee6281360d31ee98282d9a034ab" level="file"><did><unittitle>140. How Sweet Are the Roses. - How sweet, how sweet are the roses (3 verses.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f581f6dbd6bac2302f0af31eafb56cb1" level="file"><did><unittitle>141. How the Gates Came Ajar. - 'Twas whispered one morning in Heaven (4 verses and chorus.) Words by H. L. Bostwick. Music by Eastburn. Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_37027229946ac685cc26774cc1d579fe" level="file"><did><unittitle>142. Hurdy-Gurdy Man. - I am not so very happy, nor am I so very sad (4 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_7669727c312bb0c952641bc779496272" level="file"><did><unittitle>143. Hurrah for the Land We Love! - Harrah for the land we love! (2 verses.) Air: "A Life on the Ocean Wave." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border De Marsan eagle, colored. See Wolf 938.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a5add587f1d5f19ec9ff1b4c482c546f" level="file"><did><unittitle>144. The Husband's Dream. - Why Dermot you look healthy, now your dress is neat and clean (8 verses.) A Companion to the "Wife's Dream." Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Auner-Johnson. See Wolf 946.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_bcdd24bd7e5bd9db528f10603bf7b24a" level="file"><did><unittitle>145. The Husband's Dream. - Why Dermot you look healthy now, your dress is neat and clean (8 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 946b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f796e0e5192d19480990d50b9a1559c8" level="file"><did><unittitle>146. I'Am not Myself at All. - Oh! I'm not myself at all, Molly dear, Molly dear (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. See Wolf 954.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_5c8745101d269ccbb1c502e7c4518875" level="file"><did><unittitle>147. I'd Be a Gipsy. - I'd be a gipsy merry and free (2 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 997.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e4d80066095dadb9003da1f5ba012169" level="file"><did><unittitle>148. I'd Choose to Be a Baby. - I'd choose to be a baby (4 verses and chorus.) Original version and Tony Pastor's version. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan's comic heads. See Wolf 998.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e262e596269360fb31e59f2165a5b95f" level="file"><did><unittitle>149. I'd Mourn the Hopes that Leave Me. - I'd mourn the hopes that leave me (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 1000.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b891d211a0177dd522060baa09982447" level="file"><did><unittitle>150. I Dream of Home. - I dream of my home, happy home of my childhood (3 verses and chorus.) Sung by G. C. Glendale, at Bryants' Minstrels, Mechanics' Hall, 472 Broadway. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 960.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_dccef53c502b8053bba0e6280f429e0e" level="file"><did><unittitle>151. I Had a Dream. - I had a dream, a happy dream (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper. Wolf 963.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3c028cd1930cc9c4f0bae741ca4ebb6e" level="file"><did><unittitle>152. I Know not if She Loves Me. - I know not if she loves me (2 verses.) Second song: "When We Dwell on the Lips." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 970.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d468a0e752cba3276c8724aa9c9a0440" level="file"><did><unittitle>153. I'll Hang My Harp on a Willow Tree. - I'll hang my harp on a willow tree (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 1008.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a05b6fa77ae0e9de19e6f09f3690b51c" level="file"><did><unittitle>154. I'll Never Forget Thee. - "Forget thee?" - If to dream by night (3 verses.) [New York?: Andrews?], n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. See Wolf 1009.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_6b6dbdc3087a3f23429fa82eddce6624" level="file"><did><unittitle>155. I'll Never Forget Thee, Dear Mary. - My heart wanders back, o'er the waters (3 verses.) Words by George Cooper. Music by T. B. Bishop. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f9a690a758a400e530a4874eacf85b09" level="file"><did><unittitle>156. I'll Throw Myself Away. - Now, ladies, your attention! (4 verses and chorus.) N.p., n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 101la.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3f275aefc5baca297a6376bb02ed0507" level="file"><did><unittitle>157. I'll Touch My Harp. - Oft in that calm and gentle hour (2 verses.) Sung nightly with Shouts of Applause by W. Vincent. at his new and beautiful opera house, No.49 Bowery. Directly opposite the Bowery Theatre. Second song: "False One, I Love Thee Still." New York: J. Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1012a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a68377bae234e943c8fefbd8f6edd169" level="file"><did><unittitle>158. I'll Woo Thee in the Summer Time. - I'll woo thee in the summer time (3 verses.) Words by R. Scott Cowenlock. - Music. by Chas. J. Hargitt. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. See Wolf 1013.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_83d59b02e737a8d71f6bf1ad2bd05147" level="file"><did><unittitle>159. I Loved That Dear Old Flag the Best. - Look within my knapsack (4 verses and chorus.) Words by Ednor Rossiter. Music by B. Frank Walters. Rev. M. P. Gaddis relates...[narrative of a dying soldier]. Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Wolf 974b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_73167ed5558f2c800504dd46a0f6a7dc" level="file"><did><unittitle>160. I Miss Thee So. - I miss thee so in our cottage home (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. See Wolf 975.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_5cb35cc8b43d2468f68ea2c6425725b0" level="file"><did><unittitle>161. I'm Lonely Since My Mother Died. - I'm lonely since my mother died (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 1018.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f752a5e7a754b0023f6f0995d228cada" level="file"><did><unittitle>162. I'm Off for Nicaragua. - One day, while walking down Broadway (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f7de6d11429296f8c303a239a9049fa2" level="file"><did><unittitle>163. I'm Turning Gray, Dear Kate. - Time's hand is even there, sweet Kate (2 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. See Wolf 1025.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2c11ef52b6c2172c5411bc7071407bd8" level="file"><did><unittitle>164. Independence Day. - Squeak the fife and beat the drum (6 verses.) As sung by Mrs. Barney Williams and Mrs. Florence, throughout the States. Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Auner-Johnson. Wolf 1039c.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_df15a0802775ac1c223f1fd759bf7bbc" level="file"><did><unittitle>165. The Indian Warrior's Grave. - Green is the grave by the wild dashing river (3 verses.) Second song: "Indian Hunter." New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1047a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ca663a7e64c6876de895b07b3ff014d0" level="file"><did><unittitle>166. Indian Warrior's Grave. - Green is the grave by the wild dashing river (3 verses.) Second song: "No.2. Indian Hunter." Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1044.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4188822bdc6c86b784553a2709f12b3b" level="file"><did><unittitle>167. Innocent Mike. - I am a wandering Irishman, they call me Innocent Mike (5 verses.) Air - "Low Backed Car." Words by G. W. Anderson. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1049a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c8185818c6bdbb9e254d68e38d942fc9" level="file"><did><unittitle>168. In the Days When We Went Gipsying. - In the days when we went gipsying (3 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1036.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0e7700e3172a6a2f60914b580fd94caf" level="file"><did><unittitle>169. I Promised I Would Never Leave Her. - Now, look on this warrior bold (6 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 977</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_fc5f3cf7e3cc6d06c2d949bb4aef6c79" level="file"><did><unittitle>170. The Irish Brigade. - When brave hearts shall be a reproach to a nation (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Wolf 1053.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_82348ae960939f66e367223a175df839" level="file"><did><unittitle>171. The Irishman. - The savage loves his native shore (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_80e1b7f5e51912af410e0496ca62a392" level="file"><did><unittitle>172. Irishman's Shanty. - Did ye 's ever go intil an Irishman's shanty? (8 verses.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_63803dab1c571719d0a583feee35ba5b" level="file"><did><unittitle>173. The Irish Refugee, or Poor Pat Must Emigrate. - Fare you well, poor Erin's Isle! (6 verses.) Air - "Podgee and Rhu." Sung by J. S. Berry. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 1060.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1783536c1f8252ac40164f02ed5c0868" level="file"><did><unittitle>174. The Irish Stranger. - Oh, pity, the fate of a poor Irish stranger (6 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2176a5123fe33b4756886a43693e8eba" level="file"><did><unittitle>175. The Irish Wide-Awake. - As I walked out one evening (4 verses and chorus.) Air: "Billy O. Rourke." - By Harry M. Palmer. New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Wolf 1067.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a160cd8d6d12e7f44fb8d795f622fb74" level="file"><did><unittitle>176. Isle of Beauty, Fare Thee Well. - Shades of ev'ning close not o'er us (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_eeb90295a5edee93db48214ebe9d1342" level="file"><did><unittitle>177. Isn't It a Wonder? - Sister Norf and Sister Souff(4 verses.) Written by Henry Wood, Esq. and sung by Wood's Minstrels, with most enthusiastic applause. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. See Wolf 1071a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_dbb45700c139831aee02372be9017129" level="file"><did><unittitle>178. Is that Mother Bending O'er Me? - Is that mother? Is that mother bending o'er me (2 verses and chorus.) No.821. Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1069b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f3e0a62abdd0215e5dcb0792a8fae2c0" level="file"><did><unittitle>179. I Stood Amid the Glittering Throng. - I stood amid the glittering throng (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. See Wolf 982.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_5273f83ac5b6fac47db6b2f6252c5194" level="file"><did><unittitle>180. I Think of Old Ireland Wherever I Go. - I'm a wanderer, now, from the land of my birth (8 verses and chorus.) Air - "My Heart's in the Highlands." Written by J. H. Howard. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_bff07ffe4a5393b73f0c0df2e8a69206" level="file"><did><unittitle>181. It's Wonderful How We Do It, but We Do. - Napoleon used to say: There's no such word as Fail (5 verses.) Sung by Tony Pastor at his Opera-House, 201 Bowery. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 1077</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0efde35182853fbc3339263f031671e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>182. I've Wandered by the Hut Side. - I've wandered by the hut side (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Wolf 1078b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c1c864ba39ba3c0767f15e104b95b711" level="file"><did><unittitle>183. I Vish I Vas de Mayor. - Last night I vent me oud, und I dolt you all aboud (2 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Wavy line above and below verses. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_db00a84a69d4745c28c760dc68513c0a" level="file"><did><unittitle>184. The Ivy Green. - Oh! a dainty plant is the ivy green (3 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1079.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9dcb0537aae329284a07ef0bdc9fc1af" level="file"><did><unittitle>185. Jack Muggins, or The Donkey-Balancer. - Of all the strange tales about asses (9 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. See Wolf 1081.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e0a3953cb814755b84ba6e6d513bf71e" level="file"><did><unittitle>186. Jamie's on the Stormy Sea. - E'eer the twilight bat was fletting (4 verses.) As sung by John Hassett. A four-line verse, "Constancy," follows the song. New York: H. Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_096835fc48a0d05c2f6af0e9ade19b2c" level="file"><did><unittitle>187. Jamie's on the Stormy Sea. - E'eer the twilight bat was fletting (4 verses.) As sung by John Hassett. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_8d689f38fb0e10200f52bf83954c6e4d" level="file"><did><unittitle>188. Jenny Lane. - When I was young and in my prime (2 verses and chorus.) Sung by Wm. A. Wray, the Celebrated Banjoist with great applause. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. See Wolf 1106.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_910ef68888ce127832cb82afa17e608a" level="file"><did><unittitle>189. Jersey Calves. - I am a jolly roving blade, and in Jersey I was bred (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Wolf 1112.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_558e3ccc5138c6c4f4b29d5096e0e990" level="file"><did><unittitle>190. The Jersey Lovers. - Of a heart-rending tragidy (6 verses.) A Pathetic Ballad. As sung by Bryant's, Wood's and Campbell's Minstrels. Words and Music by Eugene T. Johnson.... No. 1264. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley Ethiopian. See Wolf 1114.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3f0067cdf0997817222f821994788a71" level="file"><did><unittitle>191. Jimmy Riddle. - Now, I'll tell you, if I can, of a pretty girl named Nan (5 verses and chorus.) As sung by Harry Richmond. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 1119.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4cae25d7ab7e1cadc354fb3da990d2a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>192. The Jockey Hat and Feather. - As I was walking out, one day (3 verses and chorus.) Sung by W. N. Smith, the great bone-player, of Bailey's Circus. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan trapper. Wolf 1 120a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_91c60c253dd966a5b876673ff98e639d" level="file"><did><unittitle>193. Joe Hardy. - Yes, I know that you once were my lover (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Wolf 1 123a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9521d1d25619cb5d1f57f420a53a75f0" level="file"><did><unittitle>194. John Bull. - John Bull don't you remember (6 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ad338e4337adf62e9ba87af3c366bae0" level="file"><did><unittitle>195. Johnny Doyle! - l am a fair maiden, all tangled in love (11 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. See Wolf 1 138a (with De Marsan comic heads border).</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_207d7d9e566941567ec9c2a17dc3c461" level="file"><did><unittitle>196. Johnny, Fill Up the Bowl. - Abram Lincoln, what yer 'bout? (4 verses.) Free-and-Easy Song. By Saul Sertrew. Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1139.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c5fabc25c828cbe3e7278c9f3210da5c" level="file"><did><unittitle>197. Johnny Is Gone for a Soldier. - I'll trace these gardens o'er and o'er (5 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower comers. See Wolf 1143.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2c84f83eff27ab598599f3bcfdc1e2a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>198. Johnny's So Bashful! - They tell me the roses are leaving my cheek (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Wolf 1147a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ce900a642981949280e2d703cb466bdc" level="file"><did><unittitle>199. The Jolly Old Crow. - On the limb of an oak sat a jolly old crow (3 verses and chorus.) Sung nightly with shouts of applause, by Charley White at his Opera House, 49 Bowery, N.Y. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1150.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4795dc6bc7fc8bf4f836647cbf8a2458" level="file"><did><unittitle>200. Jolly Spree. - My song relates about the time (8 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Wolf 1153a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2bce3f2f05726eb7c452ee227001f4fc" level="file"><did><unittitle>201. The Jolly Young Waterman. - And did you ne 'er hear of a jolly young waterman (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, © 1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. See Wolf 1154.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b310e55264d237913e6bbf033f1a7f86" level="file"><did><unittitle>202. Jordan Is a Hard Road to Travel. No.4. - Of all the banjo songs that have been sung of late (7 verses and chorus.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1157a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_10342e7943ba47accfc277922604cc7e" level="file"><did><unittitle>203. Juliana, Phebiana, Constantina Brown. - Oh! I'm going to sing a song to you Juliana Brown (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan trapper. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0f6a6d3ec519b24b1aa92d9253257862" level="file"><did><unittitle>204. The Lads Who Live in Ireland, or Where Apple Praties Grow. - My name is Ned O'Manney, I was born in sweet Killarney (7 verses.) Composed and Sung by Jas. Seymour, at Niblo's, in the "Duke's Motto." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower comers. Wolf 1206.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_8f9eeda4d5d1c5f6c254ccf671e18157" level="file"><did><unittitle>205. Lamentation for J. P. Donnelly. - All you, who 're tender hearted, come and listen to my song (7 verses.) Words by H. J. Howard. - Gaelic air. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan homed imp, colored. Wolf 1211.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_8f0dbac978bbe0d98771286f8d53c76f" level="file"><did><unittitle>206. Lament of the Irish Emigrant. - I'm sitting on the stile, Mary (6 verses.) No.433. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley homed imp. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_75ce62f40a0fbf5e687ed0c31b49a731" level="file"><did><unittitle>207. The Land of Shillelah! - I was just on my way starting home from Sligo (5 verses.) Sung by Wm. H. Lindsey. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan trapper. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_5abe0c4bd4cb166cdbf588a3a7f23963" level="file"><did><unittitle>208. Larboard Watch. Duett. - At dreary midnight's cheerless hour (2 verses and chorus.) Second song: "The Gondolier." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_31aa141c6eb5e0a4394aa1a27ad14451" level="file"><did><unittitle>209. Larry O'Gaff. - Near a bog in sweet Ire land. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. See Wolf 2220.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1ea862db8c085741926b06ac82e19d67" level="file"><did><unittitle>210. The Lass of Gowrie. - 'Twas on a simmer's afternoon (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 1221.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c230211cc3979069d1536dedd55af295" level="file"><did><unittitle>211. The Last Link Is Broken. - The last link is broken that bound me to thee (3 verses and chorus.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1224a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_65b3b6651186088b3ba13128e29c5503" level="file"><did><unittitle>212. The Last Potato. - 'Tis my last, last potato! (3 verses.) Parody on: "'Tis the Last Rose of Summer." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 1226a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c5a4c95f16e2614be211e357e84276fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>213. Laughing Song. - My story, yes, c'est amoureuse (3 verses.) From Auber's "Manon Lescaut." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 1230.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_6baf597ad1e7c64a14743edb3d539562" level="file"><did><unittitle>214. Lazy Club. - My wife is such a lazy Turk (7 verses and chorus.) Air - "Green Grow the Rushes, Oh!". New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 1232a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3075895d620fb840d05198f3447f9c0c" level="file"><did><unittitle>215. Liberty Tree. - In a chariot of light, from the regions of day (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan eagle, colored. See Wolf 1248.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_8043227e1bd1a2056c222f89cb158d37" level="file"><did><unittitle>216. Life Let Us Cherish. - Life let us cherish, while yet the taper glows (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_039e134efd9db28d6665cbbad4f75103" level="file"><did><unittitle>217. A Life on the Ocean Wave. - A life on the ocean wave! (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 1250.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_953de961b1faa3476981d5076604ae65" level="file"><did><unittitle>218. Linda Has Departed. - Death with his cold hand, hath robb'd me of evry hope (2 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 1265.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ef603e291eafe930386edc0be26cee8d" level="file"><did><unittitle>219. Linger Not, Darling. Serenade. - Linger not, darling, awake from they sleep (2 verses and chorus.) Words by George Cooper. Music by J. R. Thomas. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 1275a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_89cb40eed62a6a92b93b85203fe178b2" level="file"><did><unittitle>220. Little Alice. - Oh! I knew you little Alice (3 verses and chorus.) Words by George Cooper. Music by Henry Hyatt. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 1278</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_8ca2279ac55166c160451782a06440ed" level="file"><did><unittitle>221. Little Bare-Foot. - Standing where the bleak winds whistled (3 verses and chorus.) Words and Music by Frank Howard. Sung by Miss Maggie Mitchell in the popular Drama of that name. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Wolf 1279.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c297cd2c0f5511f96487e4c68cc746e7" level="file"><did><unittitle>222. The Little Blacksmith. - We heard his hammer all day long (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan clown, colored. See Wolf 1280.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_6c3a6ae485223ac53b18e1535e549f16" level="file"><did><unittitle>223. Little Eva. To Her Papa. - When your daughter's ta'en away, and your heart is filled with care (3 verses.) As sung by Little Cordelia Howard, in the successful Drama of "Uncle Tom's Cabin," at the National Theatre, N.Y. Second song: "Little Eva in Heaven." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. See Wolf 1283.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1e5359924e69a18bc4381164719ecd27" level="file"><did><unittitle>224. Little Major. - At his post the little major (4 verses and chorus.) No.968. N.p., n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1288.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_72fa3a2421a5f4eaf91c4a7b06a7bafb" level="file"><did><unittitle>225. Little Nell. The Heroine of "The Old Curiosity Shop." - They told him gently she was dead (3 verses and chorus.) Words by Casserly. - Music by T. Bissell. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 1290.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_310e6ff3eeccf7ea2d379de36be3a685" level="file"><did><unittitle>226. Little Sally's Wooden Ware. - Come, buy poor Sall'ys wooden ware (2 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_60a4ef6252388adc896317402f0a6346" level="file"><did><unittitle>227. Little Topsy's Song. - Topsy neber was born, neber had a moder (3 verses and 3 choruses.) Words by Eliza Cook - Music by Hutchinson. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp, colored. Wolf 1294b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c695cdd5ca4fcce52b90c97187084060" level="file"><did><unittitle>228. Lora Vale. - Calmly fell the silver Moon-light (3 verses and 3 choruses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_6cad73b5f591745450579a21b88830d0" level="file"><did><unittitle>229. Lottie in the Lane. - The Sun was going down to rest (3 verses and chorus.) As sung by Bryants' Minstrels. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Wolf 1314a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_5db847337dfc8dcc8eb6df2aef10ac82" level="file"><did><unittitle>230. Lovely Dolly Day. - I've told you 'bout de banjo (4 verses and chorus.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. Wolf 1320.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2dee40607d475de931fa42f147d1519b" level="file"><did><unittitle>231. Lovely Mary. - I'll taste no more of the poison'd cup (4 verses.) Air - "Highland Mary". New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. See Wolf 1322.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f3ad5e4f626cda0901eb42581eba0e2b" level="file"><did><unittitle>232. Mc'Donald's Return to Glenco. - As I went a walking one evening of late (11 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. See Wolf 1354.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1c8712579c4c7c02d32c3cfa71b4da79" level="file"><did><unittitle>233. Major Andre's Arrest and Execution. - Come all you gallant heroes, I pray you, lend an ear (11 verses.) Air - "Dog and Gun". New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan Yankee pedlar, colored. Wolf 1363.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3ebd6767bf03c6ad6168e3179a7f95da" level="file"><did><unittitle>234. Man the Life Boat. - Man the life boat! man the life boat (4 verses.) By Henry Russall. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. See Wolf 1268.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_50b78c51475ce1846586ae1a756c76b1" level="file"><did><unittitle>235. The Man Who Lost His Breeches. - On a night both dark and thick, while asleep in the forecastle (6 verses.) Air - "Courting in the Kitchen". New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c4061f565d6ad180eae5cd18f693afd8" level="file"><did><unittitle>236. Maria, the Dustman's Wife. - Oh! once, there lived, in Bowling-Green (6 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 1382.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a681c42002f6abc1fca61196df167266" level="file"><did><unittitle>237. Mariner's Grave. - I remember the night was stormy and wet (6 verses.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Auner-Johnson. See Wolf 1383.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_bfcc0d3bd6525293bbe176ba7cc69ffe" level="file"><did><unittitle>238. Marseilles Hymn. - Ye sons of freedom, wake to glory! (4 verses and chorus.) Revised and Printed expressly for the Public Schools. N.p., n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1385.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_8743255928ab415fbcc3af4f65b37944" level="file"><did><unittitle>239. The Marseilles Hymn. - Ye sons of Freedom, wake to glory! (4 verses and chorus.) No. 152. Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1385.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3a2244030ca581b3cd7b7e437fc810a7" level="file"><did><unittitle>240. Mary Blane. - Oh! once I loved a yellow gal (4 verses and chorus.) Headline: "New Song." [New York]: Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. See Wolf 1389a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_adf91b8f1aa21e9206dd2129aba6c2e9" level="file"><did><unittitle>241. Maud Adair and I. - One year ago were we sixteen (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a98d4cf49d5a5a72ee98094c2a4c84cc" level="file"><did><unittitle>242. Meeting of the Waters. - There is not in the wide world a valley so sweet (4 verses.) Second song: "Remember Thee!". New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. See Wolf 1415.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_dc3eddb8d35c07cf2b59ddc77c84077e" level="file"><did><unittitle>243. Meet Me by Moonlight Alone. - Meet me by moonlight alone (2 verses.) Second song: "How Dear to Me the Hour!" New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 141 lb.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_5d6b670c1ad2808af797b426549b1bf6" level="file"><did><unittitle>244. Minnie Dear. - Minnie dear has left us (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Wolf 1437a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_841bd977e0f1cf0781eefff31cdbd39a" level="file"><did><unittitle>245. Misfortunes of Barney O'Neil. - Oh, listen now, Ladies and Gentlemen (4 verses and chorus.) Air - "Broth of a Boy". New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 1442a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_89ec1e566176646d5d077f6e196fa2eb" level="file"><did><unittitle>246. Mississippi Boat Song. - Some boats are fast and others slow (3 verses and chorus.) Sung by Jerry Bryant, at Bryant's Minstrels, 472 Broadway, N.Y. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. See Wolf 1446.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3bf2c837965ac264a47f19946f767e04" level="file"><did><unittitle>247. Mister Finagan. - I'm a dacent laboring youth (8 verses and chorus.) No.652. N.p., n.d. Border: Moon. See Wolf 1483.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4d7498057d9326e145c6fd8a69ee2c89" level="file"><did><unittitle>248. The Monitor and Merrimac. - I'm going to sing a song, I won't detain you long (7 verses and chorus.) By Chas. A Clarke. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 1453.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_66a35adc2c9d14517be91c6f8480f474" level="file"><did><unittitle>249. Monitor and the Merrimac. - I'm going to sing a song, I won't detain you long (7 verses and chorus.) Air.- "Yankee Doodle Dandy." Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Wolf 1453e.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_538ec6929cdafcd926216d954b972971" level="file"><did><unittitle>250. Moonlight on the Lake. - Come away, come away (3 verses.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_514065c3ebaea7129e817ecc93c1ef62" level="file"><did><unittitle>251. Mother Dear, I'll Come Home. - Oh! mother dear, I sigh in vain (2 verses and chorus.) Sung by T. B. Prendergast, at Bryant's Minstrels, 472 Broadway, N.Y. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Wolf 1462b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_68b685ca6e094ff5256ef1061fa29e90" level="file"><did><unittitle>252. Mother, Is the Battle Over? - Mother, is the battle over? (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 1466.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4377ab34b346e7d751f4d54bea58d309" level="file"><did><unittitle>253. Mother Kissed Me in My Dream. - Lying on my dying bed (3 verses and chorus.) No. 893. With a preceding narrative text, beginning: "A young soldier who was severely wounded at the battle of Antietam..." Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1468.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e0d8006655a6d5b3c9434c7be5c74243" level="file"><did><unittitle>254. Mother Would Comfort Me. - Wounded and sorrowful, far from my home (3 verses and chorus.) No.1171. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley military cupid. See Wolf 1472.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9e936efbc70ac5e5d24c570fffb3a7db" level="file"><did><unittitle>255. My Boyhood's Happy Home. - My boyhood's happy, happy home (2 verses and chorus.) Words and Music by Our Ned. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments. See Wolf 1495b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d1f3df784e5e1a941f472d7f82935fb1" level="file"><did><unittitle>256 My Good Old Irish Home. - Och my heart still yearns for my good ould Irish Home (3 verses and chorus.) Air - "My Old Kentucky Home." New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1505.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a5106e74e980e170510c2b7b67f4f789" level="file"><did><unittitle>257. My Good Ould Irish Home. - Och my heart still yearns for my good ould Irish Home (3 verses and chorus.) Air - "My Old Kentucky Home." Words written by John L. Zieber, expressly for Mr. J. P. Gannon, the young Irish Comedian and Vocalist, and sung by him only. [Philadelphia]: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1505c.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_564eb63d8f4c0f6e369aff4ff38a4f38" level="file"><did><unittitle>258. My Gum a Rubber Boots. - Go it rubber boots and save my pantalets (3 verses and chorus.) Air.: "Jordan Is a Hard Road to Travel." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. See Wolf 1507.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a2076628b6c6c005b1d3d83621883ef7" level="file"><did><unittitle>259. My Highland Home. - My Highland home, where tempests blow (2 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 151 la.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_535ba8cf113055271ead9be3b85dba33" level="file"><did><unittitle>260. My Johnny Was a Shoemaker. - My Johnny was a shoemaker (4 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. See Wolf 1514.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_8c34f342cb1d4cdb7738ac288135dcd2" level="file"><did><unittitle>261. My Love He Is a Sailleur Boy 19 Y'rs Old. - My love, he is a sailleur boy, so gallant and bold (4 verses and chorus.) A sung with unbounded applause, by that Inimitable delineator of Ethiopian Characteristics, Dan Bryant. New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border De Marsan fountain, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_7bbcd39cbc17d6760de8430cc925e0f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>262. My Love She Vas a Radish Girl Only 16 Years Old. - Mine love, she vas a radeesh gal, shust sixdeen years old (7 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b9c4893f881e16f77086c85383550dbb" level="file"><did><unittitle>263. My Own Dear Home. - In foreign lands I longed to roam (4 verses and chorus.) Second song: "Orphan Boy's Song of Home". New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_11097cd1fa3a54c836f1c14ff8c0faa9" level="file"><did><unittitle>264. My Own Native Land. - I've roamed over mountains, I've crossed over floods (3 verses.) Second song: "Happy Land". New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1530.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_82c02116ca530e6d3a29b46b75b6955b" level="file"><did><unittitle>265. My Poor Dog Tray. - On the green banks of Shannon, when Shelah was nigh (6 verses.) [New York]: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1531.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_baf76690e3d903c537122af8cc58dbe4" level="file"><did><unittitle>266. My True Love Is a Butcher Boy. - My true love is a Butcher Boy, I would have you all to know (6 verses.) Air - "The Sailleur Boy". Composed by J. J. Allen. New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: Dc Marsan clown, colored. Wolf 1534.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_389353be9f1d5c338731ab83b963e2da" level="file"><did><unittitle>267. Nancy Bell or Old Pine Tree. - Oh darkies, now I'm going to sing (3 verses and 2 choruses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. Wolf 1536a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ea41591a8ac680a57214adc46f7743cb" level="file"><did><unittitle>268. Nancy Hill. - I've traveled over mountains (4 verses and chorus.) Air - "Home o'er the Mountains". By John Cross. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_261fc47894bf2accdbeb565dba6f7d8f" level="file"><did><unittitle>269. National Song. Clime Beneath Whose genial Sun. - Clime, beneath whose genial sun (3 verses.) Air: "Scots Wha Hae Wi' Wallace Bled." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a7d3e9baa37272eee082dde32d74ce4c" level="file"><did><unittitle>270. Nellie of the North. - The watch-fires are gleaming-the bright stars so beaming (2 verses and 2 choruses.) Air - "Annie of the Vale". By John Ross Dix. New York: Charles Magnus, n.d. Letter paper, blue ink. Headpiece: Magnus 234a, colored. Wolf 1567b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4bfacbfe8ec7e15f57e99ac555954522" level="file"><did><unittitle>271. Nelly Bray. - In a silent little corner of the old church-yard (3 verses and chorus.) Air -"Nettie Moore". By Thomas Sloan Jr., author of the popular song "Kitty Wells". New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1ed49954de1fb9185a93fb52a2faba3a" level="file"><did><unittitle>272. Nettie Is No More. - In a little loney cottage by the shady mountain side (3 verses and chorus.) Air - "Nettie Moore". Composed by John Benjamin and sung by H. Greenwood, at the Chatham Theatre. New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Wolf 1573a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2c1ab3dc05e1a1dabc33895bf476c9cc" level="file"><did><unittitle>273. Nettie Moore. - In a little white cottage where the trees are ever green (5 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 1574.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_755143a75dc32961063a355d501d3a9a" level="file"><did><unittitle>274. New England. - New England, I love thee, thou land of the free! (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3ee380bb2c9783fc5efdf907a55b06f6" level="file"><did><unittitle>275. New Red, White, and Blue. - For Freedom, the soul of our nation (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 1983b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_16e828166bde733b0385cd4381603c8c" level="file"><did><unittitle>276. The New Sebastopol. - Sebastopol will soon he taken/The French are now advancing, and to the walls are near (6 verses and 6 choruses.) Tune - "Hop de dooden do". Philadelphia: G. S. Harris, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_003f4cb0b907a9cb2c0cf4f345f07fe6" level="file"><did><unittitle>277. De Nigger on de Fence. - Now, listen to me, white folks, de truth I'm going to tell you (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 1600b or c.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_fabd317ea5834a99d957c54d90e371e8" level="file"><did><unittitle>278. No One to Love. No one to love, none to caress (3 verses and chorus.) As sung by Abecco. Second song: "The Melodies of Many Lands." San Francisco: T. C. Boyd, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1611.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_6bfa9a20a7a592d19bf86b0650e30885" level="file"><did><unittitle>279. Ode on Shanghai Mary Engine Co. 6. - I hope you'll pay attention (8 verses.) By a Runner. New York: J. Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1648.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2794004dbbd395f3fb66368a6ae26060" level="file"><did><unittitle>280. Oh! and He Loved Me Dearly! - There was a nice young man came a courting of me (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, 0c1860. Border: De Marsan trapper. Wolf 1652a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_42f0781c5700ce90f4f43e24611e7143" level="file"><did><unittitle>281. Oh! Boys, Carry Me 'Long. - Oh! carry me 'long (3 verses and chorus.) [New York?: Andrews?], n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1654a?</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_7c634b60445ebe41754c4ccaaad6ea06" level="file"><did><unittitle>282. Oh, Breathe not Her Name. - Oh, breathe not her name! for it steals to my heart (2 verses.) Words by L. A Jones - Music by Frederick Buckley. Second song: "Choice of a Wife." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1655.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_6518f77183a99ad3c0bf62991228b5a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>283. Oh, Let Me Dream of Former Years! - Oh! let me dream of former years (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1670a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_7cf5d40d87b994c17ae3209cbc8e20d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>284. Oh, Let Me Go to My Home Again. - Oh, let me go to my home again (3 verses.) Second song: "Oh! for Wings to Soar." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. See Wolf 1671.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_30c324921907753d5576850ef45f5eb4" level="file"><did><unittitle>285. Oh! Silber Shining Moon. - Last night de moon was beaming (3 verses and chorus.) New York: J. Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. Wolf 1680a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_5a88cbd00d72de79aabc440367a92610" level="file"><did><unittitle>286. Oh! Write Me a Song of My Father. - Oh! write me a song of my Father (3 verses and chorus.) Song and Chorus written and composed by C. Henry. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 1686.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e0b8bbfa011cd7979aa7f9b1d7c2e92c" level="file"><did><unittitle>287. The Old Bog-Hole. - The pig is in the mire, and the cow is on the grass (4 verses and 2 choruses.) Air - "Old Zip Coon". New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. See Wolf 1694.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_da5242a5ec06df8ba2e593fbd84109ea" level="file"><did><unittitle>288. The Old Brown Cot. - Among the scenes to memory dear (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Wolf 1695.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_fc03487135ebfe69bfa6d8ce0ecd1d5c" level="file"><did><unittitle>289. The Old Country Party. - Say, did ye iver go till an ould country party (8 verses.) Air - "Irishman's Shanty". By Harry M. Palmer. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Wolf 1700a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b0d06b54669add962a76831a5f7ee3a4" level="file"><did><unittitle>290. The Old Folks Are Gone. - Far, far in many lands I've wander'd (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Wolf 1706a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9b02b35712634ff905db876823d43e86" level="file"><did><unittitle>291. The Old Folks Down on the Farm. - Oh, darkies, all draw near to me (3 verses and chorus.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_867a6e10e4069f47ffe41136b9abb921" level="file"><did><unittitle>292. Old K. Y. KY. - De snow am in de cloud (6 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 1715a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2ffee25e26432035b73c573666ab9ad2" level="file"><did><unittitle>293. Old Parson Brown. - Not long ago, in our town (6 verses and prose dialogue.) Air.: "The Rakes of Mallow." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Wolf 1725.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a573e4ae4c5835d2c1fda9443a854fdd" level="file"><did><unittitle>294. The Old Play Ground. - I'm sitting to-day in the old play ground (2 verses and 2 choruses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 1727c.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_df3400939a688afec3830376aa9a877c" level="file"><did><unittitle>295. Old Rosin the Beau. - I have travelled this wide world over (7 verses and chorus.) New York: J. Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. Wolf 1728a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a369141a1242390ae8f321e4798f3064" level="file"><did><unittitle>296. One Foot in the Stirrup. - "One foot in the stirrup, one hand in the rein" (7 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Wolf 1750.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b6be578184bd617ff8b706d8aa09e6fa" level="file"><did><unittitle>297. One Good Turn Deserves Another. - The light of wisdom dimly burns (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. See Wolf 1751.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2678e2b4275eba033e657e4b79ee885c" level="file"><did><unittitle>298. O'Toole &amp; McFinnigan on the War. - Two Irishman out of employ (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. See Wolf 1764.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_61f642732e3af895d700dec78cb16447" level="file"><did><unittitle>299. Our Battle-Flag. - 0, never mind, boys! raise me up once again (3 verses and chorus.) Written by Edward Willett. Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Auner-Johnson. Wolf 1768b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_629654b9940d41d1beb7a6210003b43b" level="file"><did><unittitle>300. Our Fifer-Boy. - While the battle was raging (8 verses.) Composed by C. G. Wright, on board the U.S. Steam-Ship Mississippi, (New-Orleans.) Air: "James Bird; or Dying Californian." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship. Wolf 1778b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ae4079a18912f9de4fbd8dcac8e904ed" level="file"><did><unittitle>301. Our Grand-Father's Days. - A song for to please all my kind friends before me (5 verses.) Written by John F. Poole. - Sung by Tony Pastor. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 1791c.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4d44fd41c7c0725660c2325337d60ebc" level="file"><did><unittitle>302. Our Own Flag of Green. - Soon, soon shall our Green Flag wave 0'er us (4 verses and chorus.) Air - "Red, White, and Blue". New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Wolf 1796a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f5b294e9cbb0c1b57b3b85093529711d" level="file"><did><unittitle>303. Paddy Murphy's Auction. - Now, Gintlemin, we'll soon begin: there's seats for those that walk in (7 verses?) Air: "Whack row de dow!" Sung by Tony Pastor. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0c44c61e4cb71723ee609da499185857" level="file"><did><unittitle>304. Paddy O'Neil. - Ye sons of Hibernia, who snug on dry land (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_728fbfa13753506143e17a42c2b58dc9" level="file"><did><unittitle>305. Paddy's Land. - Oh, I've lately come to town, and for Ireland l am bound (4 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Not in Wolf. 2 copies</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0e2336fe82359a3d9ee3bc21c9dbd5ec" level="file"><did><unittitle>306. Paddy Whack. - Oh, here lam and that is flat (5 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Wolf 1822.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_cc816122f09cd4308970b01d1d98f6d6" level="file"><did><unittitle>307. Pat of Mullingar. - They may talk of Flying Children (6 verses and chorus.) As sung by Joe English. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower corners. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9346b8a41f0d9751b4e8467f0c76c280" level="file"><did><unittitle>308. Petticoat Lane. - When to Dublin I came from the sweet County Down (8 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Wolf 1871.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f8d560cbd008c252a0eb0a197cf28bf5" level="file"><did><unittitle>309. Phelim Mavourneen. - Oh, Phelim, dear Phelim! tho' lonely you wait (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. See Wolf 1872.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f0e579118a6895a625e35b5f4ed12a1a" level="file"><did><unittitle>310. Phoebe Dearest. - Phoebe, dearest, tell, oh! tell me (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 1876b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b67e178d21b40daa28911402e9d01d5c" level="file"><did><unittitle>311. The Pilot. - When lightnings pierce the pitchy sky (4 verses.) Second song: "Ever of Thee. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship, colored. Wolf 1886.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4049c437dcc8aad201ee020a41308ec9" level="file"><did><unittitle>312. Pirate of the Isles. - A hearty band I do command (4 verses and 2 choruses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_6f6ce73003eeab1dd7a9ed59d859c8ea" level="file"><did><unittitle>313. Pity the Sorrows of a Poor Old Man. - Pity the sorrows of a poor old man! (10 verses.) By the Rev. Thomas Ross. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1889a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9b223caf289f58139fd937c5d7902896" level="file"><did><unittitle>314. Played Out. - New By-words come up every year (9 verses and chorus.) As sung by Tony Pastor. Air: "King and Countryman." New York: H. De Marsan, 0c1860. Border: De Marsan trapper. See Wolf 1891.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1ee3feb8320b246052b8feeaf704022b" level="file"><did><unittitle>315. Pocahontas. - Upon the barren sand (3 verses and four line narrative.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 1894a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4e96ed8a1bc5c0fe7a9d7c3563c7f49c" level="file"><did><unittitle>316. Poor Billy Vail. - 'Twas a cold raw night (4 verses and chorus.) A Parody on "Lilly Dale." New York: J. Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. Wolf 1898a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f3da409913e15449662542a4987b153d" level="file"><did><unittitle>317. The Poor Little Soldier's Boy. - The snow was fast a falling (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Wolf 1901b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ddf68888147846915dd1f4ab86ede650" level="file"><did><unittitle>318. Poor Old Mike. - I was reared in Doncaster, some forty years ago (6 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan comic heads. See Wolf 1904.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f20642b07150a853ad9af7c2d58ff78a" level="file"><did><unittitle>319. The Poor Soldier Boy. - Gather a round me, one and all, short and tall, great and small (6 verses.) Words by Patrick Hayes. Air - "Bold Soldier Boy." New York: J. Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 1906.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_515fca9ebc0cbb7f886e53b502275cce" level="file"><did><unittitle>320. Poor Tom the Greek. - It was on the twenty-second of June, from New York we set sail (9 verses.) Air - "Flowers of Edinburg." By Capt. Jack Ratling. N.p., n.d. Border: Double line with typographical ornament in comers. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_56e0ab64f8e27a04e6dda9db5a0560f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>321. Pop Goes the Question! - Matrimony is a nut (10 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. See Wolf 1909.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_46ca2abbb976559c7f1a020b3fdb1a7d" level="file"><did><unittitle>322. The Post-Boy's Song. - The night is dark, and the way is long (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_8a8b09ed7133a93cc7f12c0c5e825860" level="file"><did><unittitle>323. Pretty Sally. - 'Tis o'er the mountains far away (3 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 1927a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_7ad695ec0c012798c7feb161d942035f" level="file"><did><unittitle>324. The Quill of the Concert Saloon. - I'll sing to you of a poor little quill, d[sic] I guess you've all seen him about (8 verses.) Air - "Sally of the Sewing Machine". New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. See Wolf 1947.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_69e4e6be5251f042b144c47ce8597f1e" level="file"><did><unittitle>325. Red Petticoats. - Down Broadway, ere the sun was low (7 verses.) By Willie E. Pabor. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship, colored. Wolf 1979.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2ad3ea1b65a52740057a75ca3ee44134" level="file"><did><unittitle>326. Rockaway. - On old Long Island's sea girt shore (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 2021.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2d7c52eb040006dd9b5fc5d1e6720736" level="file"><did><unittitle>327. The Rock Beside the Sea. - Oh, tell me not the woods are fair (2 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. See Wolf 2018.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_09a6492785b8bd80f341aa170514b7ba" level="file"><did><unittitle>328. The Rock Beside the Sea. - Oh, tell me not the woods are fair (2 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown, colored. See Wolf 2018.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_8051a859abd0f6e3c00d7c3581bce110" level="file"><did><unittitle>329. Rock Beside the Sea. - Oh, tell me not the woods are fair (2 verses.) Second song: "Laurie's Cottage." Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2018.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_fbd00c4c1a572d54dd3ac4ab212b356d" level="file"><did><unittitle>330. Rock Me to Sleep, Mother. - Backward, turn backward, 0 time, in your flight! (3 verses and chorus.) Words by Florence Percy. Music by Ernest Leslie. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 2019.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_597f657c288fd998c44eb8749bbfeac2" level="file"><did><unittitle>331. The Rocky Road to Dublin. - In the merry month of June (7 verses and chorus.) Sung by William Carleton. Air - Irish jig. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship with war scenes in lower corners. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2e96128c57d50e1a3260acf8d687a60a" level="file"><did><unittitle>332. Roll on Silver Moon. - As I strayed from my cot at the close of day (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. See Wolf 2023.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_98cf2705c8c26e4ed9ecc07576353f9c" level="file"><did><unittitle>333. Root Hog or Die. - I'll tell you of a story that happened long ago (7 verses.) Sung with shouts of Applause all over the country in Madigan &amp; Co's National Travelling Circus. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Wolf 2025a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ba27cf547bf2b10cf1a101d31a01efa4" level="file"><did><unittitle>334. Root Hog or Die! No 2. - The greatest old Nigger that I ever did see (4 verses and chorus.) Composed and Sung with Unbounded Applause by Richard J. McGowan, the World Renowned Champion Banjoist. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2026a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_01b7b8c35e5f8d9a900de714e74d9838" level="file"><did><unittitle>335. Root Hog or Die! No.3. - I am a jolly nigger as ever you did see (5 verses and chorus.) Composed and Sung by C. Morrell, Banjoist. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament, colored. See Wolf 2027.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_af92ba10c1f4722f2352863105640fae" level="file"><did><unittitle>336. Root Hog or Die! No.3. - I am a jolly nigger as ever you did see (5 verses and chorus.) Composed and Sung by C. Morrell, Banjoist. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2027.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_17a184780bca6b8cff2a62d778087731" level="file"><did><unittitle>337. Root Hog or Die. No.4. - I am de greatest little darkey on de top ob de earth (4 verses and chorus.) Composed and sung by Wm. H. Core, the Young Banjoist. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament, colored. See Wolf 2028a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_69a2bcf9a6f746f1276ab237df423932" level="file"><did><unittitle>338. Root Hog or Die. No. 4. - I am de greatest little darkey on de top ob de earth (4 verses and chorus.) Composed and sung by Wm. H. Core, the Young Banjoist. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2028a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e687cd6c0c7974e724ee827e5941f4c7" level="file"><did><unittitle>339. Root Hog or Die. No. 5. - Come, listen to my story, and a good one I'll relate (6 verses). Written on board U.S. Gunboat Com. Barneyey, after the Battle at Newbern, N.C. - By a Blue-Jacket. New York: D. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Wolf 2029a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2c45ab55a541869c03c311a0073a803a" level="file"><did><unittitle>340. Rory O'More. - Young Rory O'More courted Kathleen Bawn (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 2030.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_5d2312c67e195e0fcc9979e7ba47ec41" level="file"><did><unittitle>340a. Rory O'More. - Young Rory O'More courted Kathleen Bawn (3 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2030a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_5d8ac9c3ae9af87767c326060eaef29d" level="file"><did><unittitle>341. Rosalie the Prairie Flower. - On the distant prairie, where the heather wild (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. Wolf 2032a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0fa8840512c182b9d6bea57d58e19efa" level="file"><did><unittitle>342. Rosa's Wedding Day. -0, name de spot, and tell me where (4 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1e18df723e9d777a251d1d29e0d63914" level="file"><did><unittitle>343. The Rose and the Lily. - In the gay month of June, a fair blushing rose (5 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Wolf 2033 a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_60d96815e3d72c7ed92392e47ae1cc84" level="file"><did><unittitle>344. Rose Atherton. - The summer days are coming (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Wolf 2034.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b9c03af2ea7e6e8b6983105b4abebae4" level="file"><did><unittitle>345. The Rose of Alabama. - Away from Mississippi's vale (7 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Wolf 2035.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_5f5da3faaa6894ea927b09f4b74cba67" level="file"><did><unittitle>346. Rose of Tennessee. - 'Twas on a summer morning all in de month of June (3 verses and chorus.) Composed by Dan Eletcher. Philadelphia: Harris, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b4f9aefc07a8760295af4bdd969988e4" level="file"><did><unittitle>347. Roy's Wife of Aldivalloch. - Roy's wife ofAldi valloch (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Wolf 2044.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_869f7435c4dad7b81d2dc2d7cb527e74" level="file"><did><unittitle>348. Sad News from Home. - Sad news from home for me (3 verses and chorus.) [New York?: Andrews?], n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2049?</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_28e7aa8dcd245f3fefb98c7364e614c0" level="file"><did><unittitle>349. Saint Patrick's Day. No.2. - You, Sons of the Gael, wherever you kneel (12 verses.) No. 1058. Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4580664e955be2fde119cdcb1cc62fef" level="file"><did><unittitle>350. Sairy Sykes. - To me said mother, t'other day (3? verses of uneven length.) As sung by Master George. [Philadelphia]: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2055.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f55f05faf57fda10d0b7deeb40197d18" level="file"><did><unittitle>351. Sairy Sykes. - To me said mother t'other day (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. See Wolf 2055.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_6dd6b653e5202dedfb3e97f9cbb6dfdb" level="file"><did><unittitle>352. Sambo, I Have Missed You. - Oh, Sambo, it is you, dear, come down to see me now (3 verses.) By John Allen. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2061.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_36021070d653d3f376aaa32c34825105" level="file"><did><unittitle>353. Sandy and Jenny. - "Come, come, bonny lassie," cried Sandy, "a wa (6 verses.) New York: . De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Wolf 2064.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2b2218fe1a9fd5fb384406910176549d" level="file"><did><unittitle>354. Savoureen Deelish Eileen Oge. - Ah! the moment was sad, when my Love and I parted (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Wolf 2070.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_6a8d401267c1c83cee253a4ffe40d786" level="file"><did><unittitle>355. Scenes That Are Brightest. - Scenes that are brightest may charm awhile (2 verses.) From Maritana. Second song: "Nature's Woodland Call." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1ce88c39544055d0476309fc7b575cf8" level="file"><did><unittitle>356. She Danced Like a Fairy. - I'll relate to you, Public, the source of my woes (5 verses and chorus.) Sung by the celebrated Charles Vivian. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b3f3b8df9ed73a0d978b5d895ed16f22" level="file"><did><unittitle>357. Sheepskin, Beeswax. - Now I'm gwine to sing a song (5 verses and chorus.) As sung nightly with thunders of Applause, by Dan Emmit, at White's Melodeon, 53 Bowery, N.Y. New York: J. Andrews, n.d. Border: Andrews ivy. Wolf 2093a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3170906d4841046babb6b2c9b4cdcdd7" level="file"><did><unittitle>358. Shelling Green Peas. - I sing you a ditty of a damsel so pretty (5 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1cbdf0324dedb1acdfb34a020175fc93" level="file"><did><unittitle>359. She Never Blam'd Him, Never. - She never blam'd him, never (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Wolf 2088.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b76fe0a7dd2e63bcbe3d53a1d183911e" level="file"><did><unittitle>360. She's Handsome as a Rose. Or She Was Such a Charmer. - I'll sing to you a song (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_62e787e2ff8f14614b4f27e573681afa" level="file"><did><unittitle>361. She Was Such a Nice Young Gal. - Blow on, ye winds, and crack your cheeks (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan harp, colored. See Wolf 2090.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b105a06fff09a3a4f163011776310050" level="file"><did><unittitle>362. She Wore a Wreath of Roses. - She wore a wreath of roses (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Wolf 2091a</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9ff9ac57dab125b9c87ff47f46cf884f" level="file"><did><unittitle>363. Sing Me to Sleep My Mother. - Sing me to sleep, my mother (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2117.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_01f6e9efccdd455c6cb0076b7971c4ae" level="file"><did><unittitle>364. Sleeping I Dream, Love. - Sleeping I dream 'd, love, dream 'd, love, of thee (2 verses.) Second song: "Oh, Whisper What Thou Feelest!" New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. See Wolf 2129.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2f8c95b264d90ac4e8a9baceac45f339" level="file"><did><unittitle>365. Sleigh Bell Song. - Jingle, jingle, jingle, jingle, clear the way (4 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4820a399185122ad51409bb4e43644c0" level="file"><did><unittitle>366. Smiggy McGuirrel. - I had a son, he came from the war (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 2130a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9c0a545ccd0dbccbd141f31b1e84e8b2" level="file"><did><unittitle>367. Soda-Water Man. - Now all American citizens just listen to me (3 verses and chorus.) As sung by Dick McGowan the Celebrated Banjoist. New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan clown, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_7ec7e975b1b478cb242bae844a3689af" level="file"><did><unittitle>368. The Soldier's Child. - A mother sat by her open door (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 2142.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4e7cd5e5a544e2fd5260eeb475e95d0a" level="file"><did><unittitle>369. The Soldier's Dream. - Our bugles sang truce-for the night-cloud had lour'd (6 verses.) Second song: "The Soldier's Tear." New York: J. Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2145.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ac22c7188268b8301f5cbd341c1de642" level="file"><did><unittitle>370. The Soldier's Welcome Home. - From the camp and filed returning (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 2162.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_34342e3ce18c8955b286f699a4afab19" level="file"><did><unittitle>371. Some One to Love. - Some one to love in this wide world of sorrow (2 verses and choruses.) New York: De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. See Wolf 2165.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_cb9b5f4e099c19774a304a89272a92ed" level="file"><did><unittitle>372. The Song of All Songs. No.2. - You've heard of many songs, but of one thing I'm sure(5 verses.) Air - "The Captain with His Whiskers." No.877. Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2182.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_6f6ec8c4aa26fcbf69ba8753406aa15b" level="file"><did><unittitle>373. Sprig of Shillelah. - Och, love is the soul of a neat Irishman (4 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_02833e8ee7573b7beb2071a6c0392bef" level="file"><did><unittitle>374. Squire Jone's Daughter. - Sweet is the gush of waterfalls (4 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, 0c1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Wolf 2223a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4d2504bab3bef07086ffa624263fdb25" level="file"><did><unittitle>375. The Stage Driver. On the Knickerbocker Line. - Now white folks pay attention, Ise gwane to sing a song (3 verses.) Composed and sung by Unsworth. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e8d31b0f66d6b88efea4054e47969507" level="file"><did><unittitle>376. The Standard Bearer. - Upon the tented field a Minstrel Knight (3 verses and choruses.) New York: Andrew 5, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2235a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c6593993d38d63b06071811f25570a9d" level="file"><did><unittitle>377. The Standard Bearer. - Upon the tented field a Minstrel Knight (3 verses and choruses.) As sung by Mr. J. Spellman. Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2235b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_6e88170f652659e4222da66cd287e4f2" level="file"><did><unittitle>378. The Standard of the Free. National Song and Chorus. - Fling out that Banner, the Standard of the free (3 verses and chorus.) Dedicated to Col. Lefferts, and officers and men of the Gallant New-York Seventh Regiment.---Sung with great Applause at the Tammany Celebration, 4th July 1861. Words and Music by John Mahon. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship. Wolf 2236b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3c7cc69561db93bae619898a5b50e90e" level="file"><did><unittitle>379. Stand by the Flag. - Stand by the flag ye gallant sons (4 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2229b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ff4497afa519d68670956acf34ae226b" level="file"><did><unittitle>380. Stand to Your Guns! - Stand to your guns, my hearts of oak (2 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship. Wolf 2232a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c2675be64feddee744a3c337b6521d3b" level="file"><did><unittitle>381. The Star of Love. - The star of love now shines above (2 verses and chorus.) Sung by N. W. Gould, at Bryants' Minstrels. New York: H. De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_55cb0d2878139a3251af8eeb4d81610c" level="file"><did><unittitle>382. Star of the Twilight! Beautiful Star! - Star of the twilight! Beautiful Star! (2 verses.) Second song: "To the Highlands." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. See Wolf 2239.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3dec7ffe49bc4b4bd37b9ff55868c3a9" level="file"><did><unittitle>383. The Steam Arm. - Oh, wonders sure, will never cease (12 verses and chorus.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2248.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_dfda845431d315163dc0a889462ad369" level="file"><did><unittitle>384. Steph. A. Douglas and H. V. Johnson. - We'll raise our glorious banner high (3 verses.) Air: "Dandy Jim of Caroline." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan ship. See Wolf 2249.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_4ffeb2e4eb052a3863dd0bb9bf6749eb" level="file"><did><unittitle>385. The Strawberry Girl. - With this humble stock to store (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9fee0f84ae872fb0411e37c2505ef1b4" level="file"><did><unittitle>386. Sunlight on the Sea. - Sunshine on the wave is lying (2 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 2260.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9c468fe740a598e1775b78bde747a2ef" level="file"><did><unittitle>387. The Sunny Hours of Childhood. - The sunny, sunny hours of childhood (2 verses.) Second song: "Land of the Brave and Free." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_7a2a8927522ad1c6c802acccfd3f3f03" level="file"><did><unittitle>388. Sweep O! - I come from old Louisiana (4 verses.) Sung by the Original Virginia Serenaders. Air - "Buy a Broom." Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2265.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2d5986d6309390937c4b0cc26ec5744d" level="file"><did><unittitle>389. Sweet Bolt Ben Allis. - 0 don't you remember, Sweet Bolt Ben Allis (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b60c96880574f9f112a899635b51b1d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>390. Sweet Evelina. - Way down in the meadow where the lily first blows (4 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan trapper. See Wolf 2267.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_27de711fcdde1c0ace9aa89bc552f5b4" level="file"><did><unittitle>391. A Sweet Face at the Window. - A sweet face at the window (3 verses and chorus.) Words by W. C. Baker. Music by H.P. Danks. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 2268.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3c7446ed5051346a17b259844ecf99d7" level="file"><did><unittitle>392. Sweet Jenny of the Moor. - One morn, for recreation, as I strayed by the sea-side (8 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan horned imp. See Wolf 2271.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d2353c3b44ca2ae6c50487849943fe3b" level="file"><did><unittitle>393. Sweet Lilies of the Valley. - O'er barren hills and flowery dales (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_620ec9416877393575c6f8455b808f02" level="file"><did><unittitle>394. Taken in and Done For. - One day, I strolled out West, round every street went dodging (7 verses.) Air - "Down in Piccadilly." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Wolf 2283.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_36cced87cf43f1a5bcdd93844d69a7a9" level="file"><did><unittitle>395. That's Where the Laugh Comes In. - Augustus Don Pedro, a handsome young man (4 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 2310.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f34e041539a93d7344da37c1f12d1805" level="file"><did><unittitle>396. There Is Light Beyond the River. - There is light beyond the river (5 verses and chorus.) No.945. N.p., n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e25b9babe4f7dbd2bd96877e7fa653da" level="file"><did><unittitle>397. There's a Light in the Window for Thee. - There's a light in the window for thee, brother (4 verses and chorus.) With narrative preceding text, beginning: "When a boy but twelve years old...." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_10fb4c3421ce1198b75797fb85763be0" level="file"><did><unittitle>398. There's a Queer Time Coming, Boys. - There's a queer time coming boys-a queer time coming (6 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_b28d44f697762acd8443a1cd2e06f7d6" level="file"><did><unittitle>399. A Thousand a Year. Robin Ruff and Gaffer Green. - If I had a thousand a year, Gaffer Green (6 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_675a5a45f7671cc26e605a4b2e0d7640" level="file"><did><unittitle>400. Three Bells. - Come swell the strain, the proud refrain (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_85cebf48345226d1e77478dc2bd07802" level="file"><did><unittitle>401. Thy Voice Hath a Charm. - Thy voice hath a charm, Thy smile hath a spell (2 verses.) Words and Music by Lucas Brinley. Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2332.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2106678f198b7194af71db78dcc6878d" level="file"><did><unittitle>402. 'Tis Home Where the Heart Is. - "Tis home where e'er the heart is (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 2341 a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_341efd53d770183e4ee392b349a1ceff" level="file"><did><unittitle>403. 'Tis Midnight Hour. - 'Tis midnight hour, the moon shines bright (2 verses.) Second song: "Oft in the Stilly Night." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments. See Wolf 2342.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_83681056214deb81fb74f509a937c58b" level="file"><did><unittitle>404. 'Tis Said that Absence Conquers Love. - 'Tis said that absence conquers love (4 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2343 a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e15404dfea8b7dbed4f047e15a482170" level="file"><did><unittitle>405. To the West. - To the West! to the West! to the land of the free (3 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Border: Auner-Johnson. See Wolf 2354.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a3d17227c5a0aa0f073da5250d8de731" level="file"><did><unittitle>406. A Tough Yarn. - Ladies and gents, if you will list a little while to me (8 verses.) Air -"Wonderful Crocodile." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads, colored. See Wolf 2360.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1c535f0954ce1e6e948fd5854d129f4d" level="file"><did><unittitle>407. 'Twas Within a Mile of Edonburg Town. - 'Twas within a mile of Edinburgh town (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. See Wolf 2377.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_42787698f6deef90c918f83d5b7ea2b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>408. The Two Lovers. - There was and old woman who somewhere did dwell (10 verses.) A highly romantic Song, to the tune of Vilikins and his Dinah. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2382a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a0f393dc95d38c4b150e920b9969bec6" level="file"><did><unittitle>409. Uncle Sam's Farm. - Of all the mighty Nations, in the East or in the West (5 verses and chorus.) Tune - "Walk in de Parlor and Hear de Banjo Play. '9 New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2394a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_204ac5332385393ffa8f71be4ac16ca5" level="file"><did><unittitle>410. Under the Gaslight. Or Poor Little Laura. - Under the gas-light, while the snow falls (3 verses.) Words by Geo. Cooper. Music by Henry Tucker. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Wolf 2399.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_3d1d8625d6e667547172a1b65368aa4b" level="file"><did><unittitle>411. Vengeons la Patrie. - Debout, Fils de l'Union (4 verses.) Hymne patriotique par Gustave Dime, ouvrier-estampeur. Air - "Gloire aux martyrs victorieux!" New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan eagle, colored. Wolf 2450.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_38f05c8c679eb2c33912cd8a37a4c0a3" level="file"><did><unittitle>412. Victory at Last. - For many years we've waited (3 verses and chorus.) Words by Mrs. M. A. Kidder. Music by Wm. B. Bradley. New York: Chas. Magnus, n.d. Letter paper, blue ink. Headpiece: Magnus 62a?, colored. Wolf 2460h?.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_724c907bb85443f2accf2cc4628eb20a" level="file"><did><unittitle>413. The Village-Born Beauty. - See the star-breasted villain to yonder cot bound (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ff8a56a37dc5da891507aefdf277a272" level="file"><did><unittitle>414. Viva l'America. - Noble Republic! happiest of lands (3 verses and chorus.) Words and music by H. Millard. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan eagle. See Wolf 2465.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_06752fa634a09b91ff8f067307f08ea2" level="file"><did><unittitle>415. Vive la Compagnie. - Let Bacchus to Venus libations pour forth (5 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan trapper. See Wolf 2466.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_7998f3dff77d42b7c9e4eb7fef52413c" level="file"><did><unittitle>416. The Vorkhouse Boy. - The cloth vos laid in the vorkhouse hall (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_fb30d8ca1ebb85c33990e56839968655" level="file"><did><unittitle>417. Walk in the Parlor. - I'm right from old Virginny, with my head so full of knarledge (4 verses and chorus.) Second song: "Walkey in de Parlor." New York: J. Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f42e4fd7de5808130fef327e55c3f6fb" level="file"><did><unittitle>418. The Wanderer's Farewell. - Farewell, dear friends, once more farewe11(2 verses and chorus.) As Sung by Dick McGowan, Banjoist and Comedian. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 2484a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2e7a05a55bb2b9a08f017d7a4247a209" level="file"><did><unittitle>419. The Watchman. No.2. - The snow was falling fast and deep, and cold the North-wind swept (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 2502.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_64742b694b79034e646d629f98e35c33" level="file"><did><unittitle>420. The Waterford Boys. - Well, boys, for divarsion, we've all met together (6 verses and chorus.) Sung by Wm. Carleton. Air - "The Flaming O'Hannigans." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_01ed144de78118922da63044d4cc25d6" level="file"><did><unittitle>421. The Watery Grave. - The sun had set in its crimson bed (3 verses.) Composed by A.B.E. Second song: "Nellie, Wilt Thou Be My Bride." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2505.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_359f7d2545eb6247f551f7076cd00fe7" level="file"><did><unittitle>422. We Are All So Fond of Kissing. - Oh, kiss me quick and let me go (3 verses and chorus.) As sung by John Dudley of Perham's Opera Troupe. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2e44a2311c1838ce09b298c654522255" level="file"><did><unittitle>423. The Wearing of the Green. - They've trampled on poor ould Ireland (5 verses.) Sung by J. H. Glenny, the celebrated Irish Comedian and Vocalist in the drama of "Arra na Pogue" at Niblo's Garden, New-York. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 2526.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d00afa0b34c792f75377aec151e3f077" level="file"><did><unittitle>424. Weep not, Comrades, for Me. Weep not, oh, weep not! Comrades for me (3 verses and chorus.) And extract from soldier's diary. Words and Music by Geo. Reed Cromwell. New York: Charles Magnus, n.d. Letter paper, blue ink. Headpiece: Magnus 192, colored. Wolf 2529b.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_f228e78c6766e198d4430a8a2cf65042" level="file"><did><unittitle>425. Welcome Mother. - Welcome, mother! now I greet thee (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids, colored. Wolf 2535a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_dedaa4001b9fb374b25c27ff13e1c002" level="file"><did><unittitle>426. A Welcome to James Stephens. - All hail to Jimmy Stephens (8 verses.) By Michael O'Donnell. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. Wolf 2539.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c1b4595a41aeb925329b926b7fccb5db" level="file"><did><unittitle>427. We Shall See Her No More. - Oh, the bright sunny South where the sugar cane grows (2 verses and chorus.) Words by C. Hart, music by F. Buckley. Sung with Tremendous Applause by Buckley's celebrated Band of Minstrels. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2521.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_45411224034f47a7028265f64058ced2" level="file"><did><unittitle>428. What Norah Said. A Reply to Norah O'Neal. - Is it lonely ye are then without me? (3 verses and 2 choruses.) Words by Arthur Matthison. Music by W. F. Wellman, Jr. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 2562a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_71b704237eb5cbccdda838b972e6e70a" level="file"><did><unittitle>429. What Other Name than Thine, Mother. - What other name than thine, mother (4 verses and 2 choruses.) New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. Wolf 2563.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_594ac7dd821575273130a699b792a126" level="file"><did><unittitle>430. When I Am on a Distant Shore. - When l am on a distant shore (4 verses.) No.1119. Air - "The Harp That Once through Tara's Hall," by M. J. Million. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley Ethiopian. Wolf 256.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_50ec64ec99884ce4408fa711ca553dd6" level="file"><did><unittitle>431. When I Dream that You Love Me. - When I dream that I love you, you 'ii surely forgive (3 verses.) Second song: "Angel of Light." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. See Wolf 2569.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1f24447c03d4d52138b380083615cc45" level="file"><did><unittitle>432. When I Saw Sweet Nellie Home. - In the sky the bright stars glittered (3 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. See Wolf 2570.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_61c0e285896ed3c00b6c550fabeca500" level="file"><did><unittitle>433. When the Boys Come Home. - The boys are coming home again (3 verses and chorus.) Words and Music by Charles Carroll Sawyer. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 2577.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d0a380a245f0ac53c11d133f9d0e5ee3" level="file"><did><unittitle>434. When the Twilight Dews Are Failing. - When the twilight dews are falling soft (2 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan harp, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_eb0761cdf2f00d70e62408f10f77c438" level="file"><did><unittitle>435. Where Is My Lover? - Where is my lover? can any one tell? (3 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2594.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_1c8c0c0be889aac14430129ce7b412a8" level="file"><did><unittitle>436. Where's That Back Pay? - Boys, our back pay is a coming (4 verses.) By J. Ward Childs, 53d. Massachusett's Reg. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. Wolf 2599.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_94211a27d37d830122b096f92cd6185a" level="file"><did><unittitle>437. Where There's a Will, There's a Way. - This life is a difficult riddle (4 verses and chorus.) Sung by the celebrated Charles Vivian, at Butler's American Theatre.... New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_5a525ec79ee16923c4017b2f905b2cb8" level="file"><did><unittitle>438. While There's Life, There's Hope. - Never lose heart, where 'er thou art (2 verses and 2 choruses.) As sung by Mr. John Collins, the celebrated Irish Comedian and Vocalist, in Brougham's play of the: Duke's Motto, at Niblo's Garden, N.Y. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. Wolf 2601a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_c36ccadbfcf5071c0d8566fa965a46f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>439. Whispering Hope. - Soft as the voice of an angel (2 verses and chorus.) Philadelphia: J. H. Johnson, n.d. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_86e70779abc6f16dce04868b13caa239" level="file"><did><unittitle>440. The Whistling Thief. - When Pat came o'er the hills his colleen fair to see (5 verses and moral.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan clown. See Wolf 2603.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_16c60f25fa7dcb0687ee65f2ca56500d" level="file"><did><unittitle>441. The White Pilgrim. - I came to the spot where the white pilgrim lay (14 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_43edb20c64adf0509682e1a99ca5f7b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>442. Who Stole the Ham? - We had a ham, 'twas in the bunkroom hanging (2 verses, solo and chorus.) Air - "Virginia Rosebud." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian. Wolf 2613a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e15120e4cfce0b0a852d6154cb12b2ce" level="file"><did><unittitle>443. Who Will care for Mother Now. - Why am I weak and weary? (3 verses and chorus.) Words by Chas. Carroll Sawyer, Music by Chas. F. Thompson. With narrative preceding text, beginning: "During one of our late battles...." N.p., n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2616.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ca1d42c60be895519883d7820a63fc39" level="file"><did><unittitle>444. Why Awa' So Lang at Night. - John, Anderson, my Jo, John (4 verses.) Air.- "John, Anderson, My Jo." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid, colored. Wolf 2625.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d7ea66c8a48ef3423ce3c1ba09aaa2a5" level="file"><did><unittitle>445. Why Don't They Do So Now? - When I was a little boy, the ladies all would say (4 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_211584ab64f7efb4c8e1b5a0a6e17032" level="file"><did><unittitle>446. Widow Widdle. Or a Thousand Pounds a Year. - I once was dressy, volatile, and rich as any Jew (10 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2637a.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_71ff01b138107fd8fb2271b7cfd2beb7" level="file"><did><unittitle>447. The Widow's Last Prayer. - Oh! Mother dear, leave off crying (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan fountain. Wolf 2638.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ea959eeec098275e911046d0862f2d22" level="file"><did><unittitle>448. The Wife's Lament. A New Temperance Song. - My Connor was loving, gentle and kind (5 verses and 2 choruses.) By Archibald Scott. Air - "Dear Irish Boy." New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan musical instruments, colored. Wolf 2641.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_ad9566f275b18806b13ced6aad3b6efa" level="file"><did><unittitle>449. Will Friendship Buy Us Bread. - Mother! she spoke of friendship; what did the lady mean? (4 verses.) By Wm. Shires. With a three-line narrative. New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2645.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_134d6cb03438498f857e618a92dcc9f7" level="file"><did><unittitle>450. William of the Ferry. - Near Clyde's gay stream there liv'd a maid (4 verses.) New York: Andrews, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. See Wolf 2651.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_75298b613bfe00402fb859b8c2cfcea1" level="file"><did><unittitle>451. Willie Gray. Or Answer to Kitty Clyde. - Oh! who has not see Willie Gray (4 verses and chorus.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan comic heads. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_53ef6ef1cd85ae2309427b5b5e44ef93" level="file"><did><unittitle>452. Willie's Welcome Home. Answer to Willie, We Have Missed You. - Yes, Annie dear, my lov'd one (3 verses.) Words by A. Fleetwood. Music by A. Von Smit. New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan kissing cupids. See Wolf 2656.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_bd5bbed66459ece5836f36c4121e6164" level="file"><did><unittitle>453. Will They Weep for Me at Home. - Will they weep for me at home (3 verses.) Air - "Do They Think of Me at Home" - by Walter Warren. No.850. Boston: Horace Partridge, n.d. Border: Typographical ornament. Wolf 2647d.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_2856ee659bb09ae81968b6270af7e667" level="file"><did><unittitle>454. Woodman, Spare That Tree. - Woodman, spare that tree! (4 verses.) No.213. New York: J. Wrigley, n.d. Border: Wrigley kissing cupids. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d88abef265b3c45b4fc80887ddf7c6b2" level="file"><did><unittitle>455. Woodman, Spare That Tree. - Woodman, spare that tree! (4 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan trapper. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_34577a5c5e233e1b1e47dc6a3e95e829" level="file"><did><unittitle>456. Yankee Doodle Uncle Sam. - I'm Yankee-doodle Uncle Sam (8 verses and chorus.) As sung by Tony Pastor, also by D. McConhay. Tune.- "Bag of Nails." Philadelphia: Johnson, n.d. Wolf 2688.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_9009f79006ed98d974b8accb39dbae0f" level="file"><did><unittitle>457. The Yellow-Hair'd Laddie. - In April, when the primroses paint the sweet plain (5 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan Ethiopian, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_7d9840aa9c48a8a50f089c160e32cec4" level="file"><did><unittitle>458. Ye Winged Winds. - Tell me, ye winged winds, that round my pathway roar (4 verses and 2 choruses.) Sung by T. B. Prendergast, at Bryants' Minstrels. New York: H. De Marsan, ©1860. Border: De Marsan fountain, colored. Not in Wolf.</unittitle></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_a36edad7db74e9c83b1bed91f303d4c8" level="file"><did><unittitle>459. You Would Not Leave Your Norah! - "You would not leave your Norah! (3 verses.) New York: H. De Marsan, n.d. Border: De Marsan military cupid. See Wolf 2707.</unittitle></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
