<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Li-VAD6120</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Bowen mss., 1932-1938</titleproper><titleproper>Bowen mss., 1932-1938 <num>LMC 1111</num></titleproper><subtitle>Papers of Kathleen Bowen, 1932-1938, at the Lilly Library, Indiana University</subtitle><author>Mary McSparran</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Lilly Library</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/lilly.png" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>12/12/2020</date></p><address><addressline>1200 E. Seventh St.</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-5500</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-2452</addressline><addressline>liblilly@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-18 21:53:03 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>March 10, 2017</date><item>Encoded finding aid created.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>December 08, 2017</date><item>Edits and rearrangement of content into requisite Lilly EAD structure, including addition of abstract, bioghist, scopecontent, controlaccess, relatedmaterial, and c01 levels of container list. Haley Suby.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>April 27, 2018</date><item>Batch update to change subject links.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Lilly Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Bowen mss.</unittitle>
    <unitid>LMC 1111</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folio</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1932/1938" type="inclusive">1932-1938</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_b40a58fd988407ba9631df2ed0f11297">The Bowen mss., 1932-1938, consists of the correspondence of research worker Kathleen Bowen with businessman George Alexander Ball, 1862-1955, and naval historian Sir Geoffrey Arthur Romaine Callender, 1875-1946.</abstract>
    <physloc audience="internal" id="aspace_ebc75fe3bb2841e425f9cacd9f0d0ed1">Lilly - Folio</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_58d01cf7cc5f51d952a12c542f07c9cf">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p>Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/ask">make an appointment</extref> a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_08a31aeb84bab6851c21e0e8690bc913">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Photography and digitization may be restricted for some collections. Copyright restrictions may apply. Before publishing, researchers are responsible for securing permission from all applicable rights holders, then filling out the <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/permission-to-publish" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest">Permission to Publish form.</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_aeeed2db0fab680a67f17796eecacde6">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Gift: 1989</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_eb9fdc6144ec7fa88be75d47918dea78">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Kathleen Bowen was born on 9 May 1876 and died in April 1946. She worked as a legal and literary research worker and cared for her brother, Walter Bowen (born 9 April 1874), who was disabled in World War I. They lived at 8 Netley Terrace, Portsmouth, Hampshire, England.</p><p>Sir Geoffrey Arthur Romaine Callender (b. November 25, 1875 at Didsbury, Manchester, England; d. November 6, 1946 in Greenwich, London, England) was a naval historian. He studied modern history at Oxford University's Merton College and became a professor at the Royal Naval College, Osborne, in 1905. While at Osborne, Callender produced the three-volume naval history textbook Sea Kings of Britain (1907-1911), and in January 1913, he was promoted to the head of the history and English department. In 1920, Callender became both the secretary and treasurer of the Society for Nautical Research, positions he held until his death. He left Osborne in 1921 to head the history department of the Royal Naval College, Dartmouth, and in 1922, Callender was appointed chair of history at the Royal Naval College, Greenwich. Two years later, he published The Naval Side of British History. In the early 1920s, Callender was also heavily involved in the Society for Nautical Research's successful campaign to preserve the HMS Victory. After helping to save the HMS Victory from utter destruction, Callender set his sights on a naval museum to preserve and display Britain's naval history. Following the passage of the National Maritime Museum Act in 1934, Callender became the institution's first director. </p><p>George Alexander Ball (b. November 5, 1862 in Greensburg, OH; d. October 22, 1955 in Muncie, IN) was an industrialist and philanthropist who worked for the Ball Brothers Company. Educated at the Canandaigua Academy in New York, Ball joined his older brothers' glass manufacturing business in 1883; Ball moved with the company in the late 1880s from upstate New York to Muncie, Indiana, to take advantage of the region's abundant natural gas resources to manufacture glass jars. George A. Ball held various positions in the family business, including bookkeeper, secretary, treasurer, vice president, president, and board chairman. In the 1930s, he became the owner of an extensive railroad empire. The youngest Ball brother was also involved in politics as Republican national committeeman from Indiana. He served on the boards of the Borg-Warner Corporation, the Nickel Plate Railroad, Indiana University, Ball State University, Ball Memorial Hospital, and various banks. </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d1c638d494c9e52ba890a70f66e479ab">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The Bowen mss., 1932-1938, consists primarily of the correspondence of research worker Kathleen Bowen of Southsea, Portsmouth, England, with George Alexander Ball of Muncie, Indiana and with naval historian, Sir Geoffrey Arthur Romaine Callender. </p><p>With her letter of October 21-23, 1937, Bowen sent George Ball a copy of <emph>The Story of H.M.S. Victory by Callender</emph> (London, Philip Allen &amp; Co., 2nd edition, Nautilus Library, 1929: Lilly VA458 .V6 C15 1929) inscribed by the author to Bowen with the message: "England has nothing to fear in the present disturbed state of the political world if only she can remember her own history." Inscribed on the second flyleaf, October 6, 1937, are the autographs of the crew of the yacht Endeavour I which had participated in the America's Cup Race and of the officials of the town of Gosport from which the ship had sailed. An ink sketch of the Endeavour I by A. Smith completes the collection. </p><p>Correspondents in the collection are George Alexander Ball, Kathleen Ball, Sir Thomas Walker Hobart Inskip, 1st viscount Caldecott, Sir Geoffrey Arthur Romaine Callender, Louis Brian Caple, Lucy France-Hayhurst, and T.K. Parr.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement audience="internal" id="aspace_85e65563da04d88afa54564bdd3bf32a">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is arranged following original order.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_ac1575eb5c2c70e868cbd153b50b0385">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Bowen mss., Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_4a65c6ee29b9e24bcd11edef92235b6c">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p><emph>The Story of H.M.S. Victory by Callender</emph> (London, Philip Allen &amp; Co., 2nd ed., Nautilus Library, 1929: Lilly VA458 .V6 C15 1929), also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <persname rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Bowen, Kathleen A.</persname>
    <corpname source="lcnaf">Ball, George A. (George Alexander), 1862-1955</corpname>
    <corpname source="lcnaf">Callender, Geoffrey, 1875-1946</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAD6120-00001" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><container id="aspace_0f40ef48bfeafc1a356f9bb643e9e3a2" label="Mixed Materials" type="foliobox">2</container></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
