<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAE3664</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Willkie Residence Center scrapbooks and other materials, 1962-2007</titleproper><titleproper>Willkie Residence Center scrapbooks and other materials, 1962-2007 <num>C680</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2022</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-1127</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/university-archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/university-archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-03-03 21:44:50 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English</langusage><descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Willkie Residence Center scrapbooks and other materials</unittitle>
    <unitid>C680</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 cubic foot</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">4 scrapbooks, 3 legal folders and 1 oversize folder</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/2007" type="inclusive">1962-2007</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1981" type="bulk">1968-1981</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_55e9bb701d13b092f14315e8db476944">The Wendell L. Willkie Quadrangle opened in the fall of 1964 as a residence hall for men and women, and was rededicated as the Willkie Residence Center in 2000. This collection contains four scrapbooks that were compiled by staff of the Willkie Quadrangle residence hall between 1968 and 1981. The scrapbooks contain photographs, newspaper clippings, event pamphlets, and other materials that document staff and resident events during their respective time periods. In addition, the collection contains loose photographs of Willkie staff and leadership teams from 2004-2007, as well as loose newspaper clippings and other materials documenting Willkie residents and staff from the late 1960s to the early 1980s.</abstract>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_86dd831caecbc2d5053619ebd342e418">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_deb331e72d7f35bab226b4bfe8fd8ef5">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Accession 2012/088</p>  </acqinfo>
  <arrangement id="aspace_4150a1d3f53c28af7a998c3a3b35e5e4">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection consists of four scrapbooks, as well as other assorted documents that are arranged into folders according to format.</p>  </arrangement>
  <bioghist id="aspace_b8dfdf386a5eb3c9b2a4f1be3670672e">
    <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
<p>Willkie Quadrangle, named after Wendell L. Willkie, opened in the fall of 1964 as a residence hall for men and women. Born in Elwood, Indiana, Wendell Willkie became an accomplished attorney, businessman, and statesman. He completed his bachelor's and law degrees at Indiana University. </p><p>Construction of the Willkie Quadrangle buildings began in July 1963 and was completed in February 1965, but the first students were able to move in for the fall semester of 1964. At its opening, the Willkie Quadrangle residence hall was the tallest residence hall on campus, with two eleven-story buildings and accommodations for 589 men and 577 women. Each building had utility and laundry rooms, a student lounge, recreation and TV areas, and single and double bedrooms and a smaller lounge on each of the 11 floors. The service building had kitchen, dining and library facilities. </p><p>Willkie Quadrangle had an organized student government, with governors representing each of the units to formulate dress codes, approve budgets, and create an election code. Willkie Quadrangle had its own newspaper staff, glee club, and at least two magazines: a literary magazine called The Thistle, and a general interest magazine called Willkie Life.</p><p>There were two cooperative living units in the center building of the quadrangle, which housed 57 men and 57 women. Students who lived in these cooperative living units did their own housekeeping and performed dining hall duties, and in exchange they received housing at a cost lower than that of the regular residence halls on campus.</p><p>In 1997, the board of trustees approved a $28 million renovation plan to convert Willkie Quadrangle from a traditional dormitory to a complex of suites and apartments. The renovation was completed in 1999, and in September 2000 the building was rededicated as the Willkie Residence Center.</p>  </bioghist>
  <custodhist id="aspace_33ac66dfd8e045a8e84642527877260d">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>The materials in this collection were transferred to the University Archives from the Willkie Residence Center in July 2012.</p>  </custodhist>
  <prefercite id="aspace_c9ffa7dd944204ad8fe9a36f078fcb2c">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Willkie Residence Center scrapbooks and other materials, Collection C680, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_d15873c3d8aa60ee724c8b7eaa87f582">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Tyler Davis. Finding aid completed August 2017.</p>  </processinfo>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_41034c179c34eaa6bd326508e391eaac">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>Archived web sites for this residence center may be included in <extref xlink:href="http://www.archive-it.org/collections/219"> Archive-It</extref>.</p><p>Related photographs may be available in the <extref xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesphotos/">Archives Photograph Collection</extref>.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_57f473cc4dc2ed7658eca3197c4624ee">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>This collection contains four scrapbooks compiled by staff of the Willkie Quadrangle between 1968 and 1981, documenting staff and resident events and news. One scrapbook, which was completed in 1981, contains documents related to Willkie events from as early as 1962. The collection also contains loose newspaper clippings, photographs, informational documents, and a promotional poster, all of which are related to Willkie resident and staff events and news from the late 1960s to the early 1980s. Additionally, the collection contains a folder of loose photographs of Willkie staff and leadership teams from 2004-2007.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <userestrict id="aspace_9c8de3596f5102c4fa46d8cc1375a8ab">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Copyrights for records originating with Indiana University administrative units, departments, and other offices are held by the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p>The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p>Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p>  </userestrict>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_f6d3c8a7c8adb9c048822c5617dc1658" level="file"><did><unittitle>Fliers and event programs
</unittitle><unitdate certainty="circa" datechar="creation" normal="1973/1980" type="inclusive">1973-1980</unitdate><container id="aspace_0b237d79ccd61fe98a45945e4a489cbf" label="box">SC 16</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_dee3ff546b71e950d0a5a49cd3797035" level="file"><did><unittitle>Newspaper clippings
</unittitle><unitdate certainty="circa" datechar="creation" normal="1968/1979" type="inclusive">1968-1979 and circa 1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b699365f7b4617952aeef0069ca8afa" label="box">SC 16</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_e79ac61453f976ccc98bd5657191484a" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs, loose
</unittitle><unitdate certainty="circa" datechar="creation" normal="1967/1979" type="inclusive">1967-1970 and circa 1970s</unitdate><container id="aspace_119fb846d8fa4f2feafd302f27ac279c" label="box">SC 16</container></did><separatedmaterial audience="internal" id="aspace_995ad959e0a2419fa246a37dc97e1223"><head>Separated Materials</head><p>Original photographs have been transferred to the Archives Photograph Collection</p></separatedmaterial></c01><c01 id="aspace_5cb41023575870da879e61275b4c6bc0" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs, Willkie staff and team leadership
</unittitle><unitdate certainty="circa" datechar="creation" normal="2004/2007" type="inclusive">2004-2007</unitdate><container id="aspace_67d043839c36c79da86d58cd0bf8e750" label="box">SC 16</container></did><separatedmaterial audience="internal" id="aspace_55c37140b3674378a9b2287e857799b1"><head>Separated Materials</head><p>Original photographs have been transferred to the Archives Photograph Collection</p></separatedmaterial></c01><c01 id="aspace_e159065d7250f27f66826e8d454511a1" level="file"><did><unittitle>Promotional poster for "Company" presented by Willkie Theatre
</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_b6cbead9094c918ecd42d66f80ada318" label="box">OS 3</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_835b1f10191c625c35a8006be92fda6b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Willkie Quadrangle Scrapbook 1
</unittitle><unitdate certainty="circa" datechar="creation" normal="1962/1981" type="inclusive">1962-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_12befaca016e75e5c1ddfcdf1a15249b" label="box">Box 1</container></did><odd id="aspace_9d9de98ac9f9e48cb78d959e601d48d3"><head>General</head><p>Brown boards with gold border and string binding</p></odd></c01><c01 id="aspace_53c23582959038b0cf3271ff385b21d3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Willkie Quadrangle Scrapbook 2
</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1980/1981" type="inclusive">1980-1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_1dd88a48fd96ce57879584242cfd713c" label="box">Box 1</container></did><odd id="aspace_85940b0ef93354c7b35d8a6ca4e69568"><head>General</head><p>Brown boards with gold frontal design and string binding</p></odd></c01><c01 id="aspace_4cebec2e2c4e55273f5f732a5076661e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Willkie Quadrangle Scrapbook 3
</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1978" type="inclusive">1977-1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_84badad79c5c6fc770dc82cd986aa3c3" label="box">Box 1</container></did><odd id="aspace_d5d6a63c5feca5a69b64cde249a31056"><head>General</head><p>Red boards with gold border and string binding</p></odd></c01><c01 id="aspace_2a01ca9315b2a8a13fb9c8719c6e9474" level="file"><did><unittitle>Willkie Quadrangle Scrapbook 4
</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1969" type="inclusive">1968-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_695501c630e82a0392cc1df95538ae65" label="box">Box 1</container></did><odd id="aspace_5e8a39af8677e79ab3996c6494524de2"><head>General</head><p>Yellow boards with gold border</p></odd></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
