<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="original" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Li-VAE1176</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>The Carleton Hodge collection: books from the library of Carleton Hodge <num>Z7770 .H6</num></titleproper></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Lilly Library</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/lilly.png" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2020</date></p><address><addressline>1200 E. Seventh St.</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-5500</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-2452</addressline><addressline>liblilly@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2019">© 2020</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-18 22:30:09 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>April 13, 2020</date><item>Encoded finding aid started.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Lilly Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>The Carleton Hodge collection: books from the library of Carleton Hodge</unittitle>
    <unitid>Z7770 .H6</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">56 Boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1805/1995" type="inclusive">1805-1995</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_769ea0c3ff1e3a4b499e22b709cfc0a3">Consists of personal collection of Professor Carleton Hodge, including many 19th and 20th century Bibles and works about the Bible.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_110d371eb81ac9e3163f52c514973db3">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e8c3c8407dd5edcbdfcaed9e078f101f">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p>Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/ask">make an appointment</extref> a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_34be9d08f37f5abf0fbe309a55959fd1">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Carleton T. Hodge, Professor Emeritus of Linguistics and Anthropology at Indiana University, was born in Springfield, Illinois on November 27, 1917 and died on September 8, 1998. After receiving his B.A. in 1939 from DePauw University, he began graduate work in linguistics, Near Eastern studies, and Ancient Egyptian at the University of Pennsylvania. He completed his Ph.D. dissertation, a descriptive grammar of Hausa, in 1943. From 1943 to 1963, Hodge worked for the Foreign Service Institute, supervising courses in foreign language training and publishing pedagogical language materials such as <title render="italic">Some Aspects of Persian Style</title> (1957) and <title render="italic">Serbo-Croatian Stress and Pitch</title> (1958).</p><p> In 1964, Hodge took a tenured position at Indiana University where he remained until his retirement in 1983. Hodge taught linguistics and was a founding member of both the Department of Linguistics and the African Studies Program, where he served on various committees throughout his career. He was the director of the Intensive Language Training Center, where he negotiated contracts with the Peace Corps and the Office of Education, until 1968. From 1969-1972, Hodge served as Associate Chairman of the Research Center for the Language Sciences and was Editor-in-Chief of the <title render="italic">African Series,</title> a role he continued after leaving the RCLS. Hodge then went on to teach linguistics full time and to hold a joint appointment in Linguistics and Anthropology.</p><p> After his retirement from Indiana University in 1983, Hodge continued to publish articles and book reviews. A full bibliography of his writings lists over 150 publications. Hodge also continued to attend meetings of the Linguistic Society of America, the American Oriental Society, and the Linguistic Society of India. Throughout his career, Hodge made both practical teaching and research contributions on the grammar and historical relationships among the languages of Africa, Europe, and Asia.</p><p> Carleton T. Hodge died in Bloomington, Indiana on September 8, 1998. He was survived by his wife, Pat (Sutcliffe) Hodge; four children: daughter Nina, and sons Philip, Nicholas, and Charles; and two grandchildren.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_c2f94428fec72feb7611ee63a40007f5">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Books are arranged alphabetically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_9b74431c998421ca4239d25eaa20907e">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection consists of personal collection of Professor Carleton Hodge, including many 19th and 20th century Bibles and works about the Bible.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <prefercite id="aspace_4d38fd39b22b6f846497aaafb6b54714">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], The Carleton Hodge collection: books from the library of Carleton Hodge, Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_a32e977357e84e60f2ddbff841ea8497">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>See the Carleton T. Hodge papers at the Indiana University Archives, Indiana University, Bloomington.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Hodge, C. T. (Carleton Taylor), 1917-1998--Library.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Bible.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Bible--Harmonies.</subject>
    <persname authfilenumber="n82156837" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Hodge, C. T. (Carleton Taylor), 1917-1998</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_ffed658ee50eff06ab62a1f3e0a4a29a" level="file"><did><unittitle>A</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_1afae36c651c9f8bb83438f8e4ada4bd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Allis, Oswald T. Five books of Moses a reexamination of the modern theory that the Pentateuch is a late compilation from diverse and conflicting sources by authors and editors whose identity is completely unknown. Philadelphia: Presbyterian and Reformed Publishing Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_3fe4548ce08d636cc76cd8a52b38f8c8" label="box" type="box">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_489e8c243b503f2628134c8a0839ab90" level="item"><did><unittitle>Allis, Oswald T. God spake by Moses an exposition of the Pentateuch. [Sticker of the distributer over publisher information] Grand Rapids, MI: Baker Book House</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_43bfcef6398e395709cd4233d8096cd5" label="box" type="box">28</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_cd178fae2c75687fc9cabf6eb4205b9f" level="file"><did><unittitle>B</unittitle><container id="aspace_6982d85acd51bb723d3cd7990789ccb5" label="box" type="box">28</container></did><c02 id="aspace_9bf6a7dbbae637c9cafb3ccacf49f165" level="item"><did><unittitle>Beauclerk, Henry. Jesus his life in the very words of the four Gospels a diatessaron. London: Burns and Oates, Limited</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1896/1896">1896</unitdate><container id="aspace_1c25cf712c0d2954e79e05e5bcf84fee" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_83ce289654b9804cb380f486dc291ec5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. (t.p. for O.T. is missing using N.T.) New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by His Majesty's special command. Appointed to be read in churches. London: Eyre &amp; Spottiswoode, [1800s?].</unittitle><container id="aspace_1979bc176ec1319a58970e1d1884c4d6" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1327023e38ff12d4bde4cb976a6bdcd7" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Biblia, das ist die ganze heilige schrift des alten und neuen testaments, nach der deutschen uebersetzung D. Martin Luthers; mit eines jeden capitels kurzen Summarien, auch... Erste Auflage. Reading: Gottlob Jungmnn</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1805/1805">1805</unitdate><container id="aspace_e35cf818010f0bfab5273fa0e40c8006" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2db6853ce059b2d06c2070a375e091f0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible: containing the old and new testaments: together with the Apocrypha: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by the special command of his Majesty King James I of England. With marginal notes and references... Philadelphia: Printed and Published by Mathew Carey</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1806/1806">1806</unitdate><container id="aspace_9c09ade65d02ece1543de7fa3e9c8434" label="box" type="box">19</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_47d91481adec0722c6121bd99ac4d472" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible: containing the old and new testaments: together with the Apocrypha: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with marginal notes and references, and the explanatory notes of Osterv Ald... embellished with maps, and a number of elegant historical engravings. New York: Printed and sold by Collins, Perkins, and Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1806/1807" type="inclusive">1806-1807 (N.T. t.p. has date of 1806)</unitdate><container id="aspace_89d6200d73bf7be6475f02a16a1191ed" label="box" type="box">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d1850d3d191d0219a1c3eb8dba50960d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible: containing the old and new testaments, together with the Apocrypha at large; and illustrated with notes and annotations, theological, practical and divine: the whole forming a neat family bible, embellished with thirty beautiful engravings. By the Rev. Mr. Ostervald, ... Stourbridge: printed and published by J. Heming</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1808/1808">1808</unitdate><container id="aspace_539cb677d9bb76ce800528bdcd2cd541" label="box" type="box">26</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3e0aea4a766a50b1304d525e984481f1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, ... (center of page has a hole) with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Boston: Printed by Greenough and Stebbins</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1809/1809">1809</unitdate><container id="aspace_b583589b6e17e059dff070322cab3b31" label="box" type="box">14</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_41c913caa56b1ff0247bcba6ca9890e3" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Scripture expositor; a new commentary critical and practical, on the Holy Bible; in which difficult passages are explained, mistranslations corrected, and apparent contradictions reconciled, by reference to the labors of the most celebrated critics and commentators, ancient and modern; particularly to the treasures of eastern literature. ... by the Rev. Samuel Burder, A.M. ... In Two Volumes. London: Albion Press printed for J. and J. Cundee</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1811/1811">[1811?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_135c49d698a32e9ea3779779f881dd3e" label="box" type="box">34</container></did><c03 id="aspace_b1978eddf09873709348e244d26465d5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. I, pt. I. Genesis to end of Samuel 2</unittitle><container id="aspace_bf3a59c69d298ebe866bb16df8843e3b" label="box" type="box">34</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_f3c390d484c4ece8ceec9155d06ee40c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. I, pt. II. 1 Kings to end of Psalms</unittitle><container id="aspace_7bd9cf009fe6fb7cb4c3d6be7258a988" label="box" type="box">34</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_42ee6309460b7835834a746b846c8ea6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. II, pt. I. Proverb to end of Malachi</unittitle><container id="aspace_6328b4c6af655b697de4a5b3ed6394f8" label="box" type="box">34</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_cf1bed7a1e1aa8cbb05bbc109fecb3e1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. II, pt. II. Matthew to end of Revelations</unittitle><container id="aspace_b2efec33542faa0f8e47c6584218cb58" label="box" type="box">34</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_785e1bd5131eb13734837ddf8fa63310" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New family bible, containing the old and new testaments, with notes, illustrations, and practical improvements, selected from the exposition of the Rev. Matthew Henry. By the Rev. E. Bloomfield. Embellished with fifty beautiful engravings. Bungay: printed and published by C. Brightly and Co., published also by T. Kinnersley</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1811/1811">1811</unitdate><container id="aspace_97bbdb2da98e060b04d03875e3181805" label="box" type="box">26</container></did><c03 id="aspace_cf25eb28e52b0ea50a391752513e9ab1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 1</unittitle><container id="aspace_4dc8c0cbaffdb1c7123dc1164bdcc273" label="box" type="box">26</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_507cf0bf9fccce39f1001852091efdd7" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 2</unittitle><container id="aspace_c93e90962c824c82d19f7a67c0a664f6" label="box" type="box">26</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_a54b1f9096aa1a56314a4644cc07b244" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. (O.T. title page missing. Using information from N.T. t.p.) Heilige Schrift neuen testaments unser herrr Jesu Christi, ferdeeutschet von Doktor Martin Luther; mit jeden capitels kurzen summarien und richtigen schriftstellen auf das duetlichste fersehen. Minden: Georg Wilhelm E?smann</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1811/1811">1811</unitdate><container id="aspace_01d000cd5dceb02dfa5576dd147bcf25" label="box" type="box">38</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_28827bcc1b86a81b15bb2f667bba5eed" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. London: Stereotyped for the Bible Society at Philadelphia, by T. Rutt</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1812/1812">1812</unitdate><container id="aspace_ef268f5425225a8c53fd5112b857b64e" label="box" type="box">14</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e389345ec01f6e66fd03b080e362e92a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. London: Stereotyped for the Bible Society at Philadelphia, by T. Rutt(No covers)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1812/1812">1812</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1aea8c046e987971e4a1a05e93fc3b3" label="box" type="box">38</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c70e6917870721c827b01994cc97c376" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Boston: Printed for Thomas and Andrews, West and Richardson, and West and Blake by W. Greenough</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1814/1814">1814</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8f51d8eb66f70b3320694fec5edc386" label="box" type="box">14</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fa07e4073e2121b4683971c1a6c40a99" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible: containing the old and new testaments, together with the Apocrypha: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by the special command of his majesty King James I of England. With marginal notes and references. To which are added... Philadelphia: Printed and Published by M. Carey</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1815/1815">1815</unitdate><container id="aspace_58ccb2f0d7328c2eae90d32b50686787" label="box" type="box">19</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_556924bd40d24e610b04f1e7012d7ee1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Biblia, das ist die ganze heilige schrift des alten und neuen testaments, nach der deutschen uebersetzung D. Martin Luthers. Die CXX auflage. Halle: Cansteinischen Bibel – Anstalt</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1816/1816">1816</unitdate><container id="aspace_adab7cf88ec44a9958d0c77d069b9bb6" label="box" type="box">7</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6503bf542249018ce25f18cc594cc078" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Old testament translated out of the original Hebrew, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Together with the Apocrypha: done by the special command of King James I of England. Philadelphia: Printed and Published by M. Carey(T.p. for whole Bible missing; N.T. t.p. has same imprint information)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1816/1816">1816</unitdate><container id="aspace_08c0c35ca2e79a517d246385d67042f4" label="box" type="box">19</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e2148e079305f95caa0ae17352f8929c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible: containing the old &amp; new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. With marginal notes and references. Together with the Apocrypha. ... Brattleborough, Vt.: J. Hollbrook's Stereotype Copy seventh edition</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1816/1817" type="inclusive">1816-1817 (N.T. t.p. imprint 1816)</unitdate><container id="aspace_aa6b495891800db33274f4d67274bf45" label="box" type="box">50</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c405476bec72549a5e548cd99a4d17e2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible: containing the old and new testaments, together with Apocrypha: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by the special command of his Majesty King James I of England. With marginal notes and references. ... Philadelphia: Printed and Published by M. Carey</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1816/1817" type="inclusive">1816-1817 (N.T. t.p. imprint 1817)</unitdate><container id="aspace_271c0086dd871f2bf59d4a4c75ce0c90" label="box" type="box">18</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_36d3b5e076fa714a9f3e49ff3e5f2b9a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Boston: Hudson and Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1817/1817">1817</unitdate><container id="aspace_f16ced945821b0ff043e3a3275ffb321" label="box" type="box">14</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_13bf7beac144eea012e3caf5e821f437" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. (O.T. t.p. is missing) Das Neue testament unsers HCrrn und Heilandes Jesu Christi, verdeutsch fon D. Martin Luther. Dreizehente Auflage. Stututtgart: mit ?ebenden Schriften dedrucht, und zu finden ben der privilegirten Bible = An?alt</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1821/1821">1821</unitdate><container id="aspace_3c127cbada1cb63050670fcc6f344ca4" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1926fa33753cca1c2eae15435002fa0d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. [Holbrook &amp; Fessenden's stereotype hot-press edition.] The holy bible: containing the old &amp; new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, with marginal notes and references. ... Brattleborough, Vt.: Holbrook &amp; Fessenden</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1821/1821">1821</unitdate><container id="aspace_a2e63988e33474f8048605ad8a7fe575" label="box" type="box">49</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b3364255ccf22b98d02cf7ef028f33bf" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments. Translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: Stereotyped by D. &amp; G. Bruce</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1821/1823" type="inclusive">1821-1823 (N.T. imprint date 1821)</unitdate><container id="aspace_5aa9a0ab100ddce460e1865d7063b780" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_400ae869d187f7e68fe513dac2614f78" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: H.C. Carey &amp; I. Lea</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1823/1823">1823</unitdate><container id="aspace_574185c292490c6a90b51d301c3ccc61" label="box" type="box">16</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4f6e8f880ec9bed7334a9956ec13bd77" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Kimber and Sharpless' Stereotype edition. The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: together with the Apocrypha: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. With Canne's marginal notes and references. ... Stereotyped by E. White, New-York. Philadelphia: Kimber and Sharpless</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1823/1844" type="inclusive">[1823-1844?] (Date range from a note by Hodge)</unitdate><container id="aspace_99d7e26264f09f4dc8f98ff4151ce4b5" label="box" type="box">52</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_65ce4a655da7c4468223b8847e684f0d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: stereotyped for the American Bible Society by D. &amp; G. Bruce</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1824/1824">1824</unitdate><container id="aspace_19fd7f2c6d3aab99670ece98c60dc80a" label="box" type="box">14</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_884efe3c83ded55323d58790f37c22d2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, translated from the Latin vulagt: diligently compared with the Hebrew, Greek, and other editions, in divers languages. The Old Testament, first published by the English College at Doway, A.D. 1609. and New Testament, first published by the English College at Rhemes, A.D. 1582. ... First stereotype, from the fifth Dublin edition. ... Philadelphia: Eugene Cummiskey</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1824/1824">1824</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f99867e1e0efb1485bdee69a63521bb" label="box" type="box">38</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_431838282a34b3d5bb2def313d1ede96" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, translated from the Latin vulagt: diligently compared with the Hebrew, Greek, and other editions, in divers languages. The Old Testament, first published by the English College at Doway, A.D. 1609. and New Testament, first published by the English College at Rhemes, A.D. 1582. ... First stereotype, from the fifth Dublin edition. ... Philadelphia: Eugene Cummiskey</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1824/1831" type="inclusive">1824-1831 (date on N.T. t.p. 1831)</unitdate><container id="aspace_5975755bda316fdf0f46e12412dcbf17" label="box" type="box">38</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2c1d6b4711109d53d525d5b7643f2dfb" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible: containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. With Canne's marginal notes and references. To which are added an index: and an alphabetical table of all the names in the old and new testaments with their significations. ... Stereotyped for Collins and Co. by B. &amp; J. Collins. Boston: Published by C. Ewer and T. Bedlington</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1825/1825">1825</unitdate><container id="aspace_ec37533e15839412cdcb35c19deb964d" label="box" type="box">42</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_996350d6e0dc4f690cd28f0f71b6d53c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments; translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: Published by George W. Mentz</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1826/1826">1826</unitdate><container id="aspace_b644ae3d85da0fef3bd828240f32b652" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ded4d24e6896f6d9f092b0a81dc375be" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible: containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. With Canne's marginal notes and references together with the apocrypha. ... Boston: Published by C. Ewer and T. Bedlington, printed by J.H.A. Frost</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1827/1827">1827</unitdate><container id="aspace_fa8e2cc353b55e512d8d39538c77f482" label="box" type="box">13</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cd87009aca97dfb37b1e50a2adf669be" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Stereotype edition. The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: together with the Apocrypha: translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised with copious marginal notes and references. To which are added, an index; an alphabetical table... [imprint information missing from O.T. t.p. information missing from O.T. t.p. information taken from N.T. t.p.] [Cooperstown: Printed by H. &amp; E. Phinney for S. Thompson, York, (U.C.)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1827/1827">1827]</unitdate><container id="aspace_1a143ba0e51a707490f8e10f8c45cdf3" label="box" type="box">40</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6c25f6b7c2ca8722f7ba5eeb04dd2a6a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments; translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: Published by George W. Mentz</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1827/1827">1827</unitdate><container id="aspace_9793ed9f03b3f6827e241ad828da6ca9" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5b41b9de91974e4588fdc73e2e5b58ee" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Biblia, das ist die ganze heilige schrift des alten und neuen testaments, nach der deutschen uebersetzung D. Martin Luthers; mit eines jeden capitels kurzen Summarien, … Philadelphia : Kimber und Scharlpes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1828/1828">1828</unitdate><container id="aspace_172251ad4d58fb22d590ad90130cf4d3" label="box" type="box">7</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_09bb9d903912bbe1c7b38dc0a5bf38ee" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: Stereotyped for the American Bible Society by D. &amp; G. Bruce</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1828/1828">1828</unitdate><container id="aspace_07e31a53a93a8f2d053eb0ba171ccda8" label="box" type="box">13</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8a2e31812c459e5af34a78af935e4781" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: together with the Apocrypha: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. With Canne's marginal notes and references. ... New York: Daniel D. Smith</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1828/1828">1828</unitdate><container id="aspace_b9fd6b3a7f531114301970bcd17b0b28" label="box" type="box">13</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_74b47baa0c8f3206856895759a1a581a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Biblia, das ist: die ganze heilige schrift des alten und neuen testaments, nach der deutschen uebersetzung D. Martin Luthers; mit eines jeden capitels kurzen Summarien, ... Philadelphia : In Stereotypen versertigt, von J. Howe, Kimber und Scharlpes Buchhandler</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1828/1828">1828</unitdate><container id="aspace_4699f8753392ae391dee13b3349607cd" label="box" type="box">21</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cc91cac2d44b0132d17b8660565a87b2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. H. &amp; E. Phinney's Stereotype edition The Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised with Canne's marginal notes and references. To which are added ... Cooperstown, N.Y.: Stereotyped, Printed and Published by H. &amp; E. Phinney(No covers).</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1829/1829">1829</unitdate><container id="aspace_98ce3fed2564ced8e1f1ddbeb893a968" label="box" type="box">21</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2077c6415a567e894995b616b9388029" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: Stereotyped by James Conner, for the American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1830/1830">1830</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe1891910d7ee89ad82b92100d01c49f" label="box" type="box">13</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_77b81c820d7708f8e5ee844fd1a8b16c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Biblia, das ist die ganze heilige schrift des alten und neuen testaments, nach der deutschen uebersetzung D. Martin Luthers; mit eines jeden capitels kurzen Summarien, ... Philadelphia : Kimber und Scharlpes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1830/1830">1830</unitdate><container id="aspace_34e5f52f7cc5cc3fcc0a9ce3cc7d9fd2" label="box" type="box">7</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5517863678108d64f61296c13cc2e153" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: Printed by D. Fanshaw, for the American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1830/1830">1830</unitdate><container id="aspace_d8a276e3e98d2356a1eb24b29f1caec5" label="box" type="box">13</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f5696fd7f07d94224d3fde2a9966769a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by His Majesty's Special Command. Appointed to be read in churches. Cambridge: Printed by J. Smith, Printer to the University. For the British and Foreign Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1830/1830">1830</unitdate><container id="aspace_ae179475039b84661174ab542fdc8a84" label="box" type="box">40</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9511bfccf3dd133f8571c72a4f59d112" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. English version of the Pollyglott Bible; containing the old and new testaments: with a copious and original selection of references to parallel and illustrative passages, exhibited in a manner hitherto unattempted. London: Printed for Samuel Bagster(In English and Hebrew) (Only the old Testament is present).</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1831/1831">1831</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b21b34c5c65829b19916eff8c1bd9fa" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_114cae4321120ecea8e162aa8f870b9f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible: containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. With Canne's marginal notes and references... Stereotyped by B. &amp; J. Collins. Boston: Langdon Coffin</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1831/1831">1831</unitdate><container id="aspace_f0316609bb1c929b91f26243a1b77d9c" label="box" type="box">48</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4b5e051c961a88a86460164390ed2060" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Daniel D. Smith's stereotype edition. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised with Canne's marginal notes and references: ... stereotyped by J. Howe, Philadelphia. New York: Daniel D. Smith</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1832/1832">1832</unitdate><container id="aspace_ea70924e7eb9eb2dc4b948c58a72cbab" label="box" type="box">37</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_99834032fec77c66b4100a466e05d722" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. H. &amp; E. Phinney's stereotype edition the Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised with Canne's marginal notes and references. ... Cooperstown, (N.Y.): Stereotyped, printed and published by H. &amp; E. Phinney</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1834/1834">1834</unitdate><container id="aspace_56fa5810dfc65cdcd2e69b3c601ca3ba" label="box" type="box">40</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cfc2b4eb4b32313fc8155bd376282b53" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Fessendon &amp; Co's edition. The English version of the polyglot bible, containing the old and new testaments, with the marginal readings, and a full and original selection of references to parallel and illustrative passages, ... Brattleboro: Fessendon &amp; Co. and Peck &amp; Wood, and Boston: sold by Lincoln, Edmands &amp; Co. and William Peirce</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1834/1834">1834</unitdate><container id="aspace_8abdb2acfaca985c88f09b8ddf5a1ecd" label="box" type="box">42</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_77d454b5c8e3c5d167c6050210d5e628" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Hartford, CT: Andrus &amp; Judd</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1835/1835">1835</unitdate><container id="aspace_95885f32953187ce6201d2cd901fbbe4" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1590b167da7cbaa9dd2d2c5ff6018712" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible: containing the old and new testaments: together with the Apocrypha: translated out of the original tongues. and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with Canne's marginal notes and references. To which are added, an index; ... Woodstock, VT: N. Haskell</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1836/1836">1836</unitdate><container id="aspace_27f25339fa5e784d3ec55192558aa3d3" label="box" type="box">52</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_36d577b46e2a45d4dc29b7e36ef230e1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. English version of the polyglot bible, containing the old and new testaments; with the marginal readings: together with a copious and original selection of references to parallel and illustrative passages. Exhibited in a manner hitherto unattempted. Philadelphia: stereotyped by L. Johnson Published by Desilver, Thomas &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1837/1837">1837</unitdate><container id="aspace_4a7059d433b2d6fc08b2d7e38c37514a" label="box" type="box">20</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_879f921c5134fff40ae3365b36c78dab" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Claremont, N.H.: Claremont Manufacturing Company's Power Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1838/1838">1838</unitdate><container id="aspace_b01e7cc1c24d03eb76ed1f25f221ca32" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_de82b3eea47f2ba10eaf84a0a7aed877" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible; containing the old and new testaments, according to the authorized version; with the references and marginal readings of the polyglot bible, with numerous additions from Bagster's comprehensive bible. First edition. Hartford, Con.: Andrus, Judd, &amp; Franklin</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1838/1838">1838</unitdate><container id="aspace_ec4302cbe0645963a58f961b80223a04" label="box" type="box">52</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4cd897bd85e7b6f387ee5efc2576150e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised: with references and various readings. Illustrated with engravings. In two volumes (2 in 1) Baltimore: Joseph N. Lewis. John D. Toy, printer</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1838/1838">[1838?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_370f45842b4c2010ac886803a72e5095" label="box" type="box">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2a9ba9171213dbaa29506f146945103e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. English version of the polyglot bible, containing the old and new testaments; with the marginal readings: together with a copious and original selection of references to parallel and illustrative passages. Philadelphia: Thomas, Cowperthwait, &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1839/1839">1839</unitdate><container id="aspace_f029e1337ffa2042dbdabc6ab2bb597d" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a4c0b09c916e2b6ab83c7ce542563cbb" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, translated from the Latin Vulgat: diligently compared with the Hebrew, Greek and other editions in divers languages the Old Testament, first published by the English College at Doway, A.D. 1609. and the New Testament, first published by the English College at Rhemes, A.D. 1582. with... first stereotype, from the fifth Dublin edition... Philadelphia: Eugene Cumminsky</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1839/1839">1839</unitdate><container id="aspace_17751f0cfbb20c02022d11681d001ebb" label="box" type="box">36</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5003093b22487f209f123632bd9fd0fd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Baltimore: Armstrong and Berry</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1839/1839">1839</unitdate><container id="aspace_06b4c3371f1f2a5e78218d7bf4dad508" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1735184684993aac990cdcc107a5dd95" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Die Bibel, oder die ganze heilige schrift des alten und neuen testaments. Nach Dr. Martin Luther's uebersetzung. Zwolfte Auflage. Stereotypirt von J. Howe, Philadelphia. New York : Amerikanischen Bible=Gesllschaft</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1839/1839">1839</unitdate><container id="aspace_5d849dc1ca4f9fd3e24e61ebc84beaa4" label="box" type="box">50</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_97477dca0c78fc36753fbd278279b56d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Alexander's stereotype edition the Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated from the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised: with Canne's marginal notes and references to which are added and index: and alphabetical table... Philadelphia: Stereotyped and published by C. Alexander &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1839/1839">1839 (N.T. t.p. date 183?)</unitdate><container id="aspace_b9ee4f5e0eed69f7886e71c025dd2cc5" label="box" type="box">24</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c446d06bbe88f1e001efb7776502e77a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible &amp;c. &amp;c. &amp;c. with notes by Rev. Henry Stebbing A.M. M.R.S.L. London: Allan Bell and Co. and Francis Orr &amp; Sons, GlasgowNew Testament dated 1839.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1830/1840" type="inclusive">1830-1840</unitdate><container id="aspace_b031d3301b5e64077511bb4f67bb0952" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4474e6a2bd14cf917b006a81da07ee96" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his Majesty's special command. Appointed to be read in churches. Oxford: Printed at the University Press by Samuel Collingwood and co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1840/1840">1840</unitdate><container id="aspace_cb00373e014564c205a2cbcc133b4fe5" label="box" type="box">36</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_defabc64f9691621eac8ddeefa52f116" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Stereotyped by L. Johnson, Philadelphia. Philadelphia: Ed. Barrington and Geo. D. Haswell</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1840/1840">[1840?] (Date from a note by Hodge)</unitdate><container id="aspace_c2c264d3bd319692088d41102296e7fd" label="box" type="box">53</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_065088c57f4a9cf2105a6afb81229533" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: Printed by D. Fanshaw for the American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1841/1841">1841</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a2372c27bff1b6b38de4440d831af2c" label="box" type="box">13</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_07deeb667be18630d8f709240fe7cbde" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: Printed by Daniel Fanshaw for the American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1842/1842">1842</unitdate><container id="aspace_e623e35f9483812fff4ee81590417a67" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4f1d47b5288dc416d8d8bb14785d0e38" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: Printed by D. Fanshaw for the American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1843/1843">1843</unitdate><container id="aspace_f2d62a78fa5129e4021bac6b9b6379df" label="box" type="box">20</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_76d26980e6039d54deeb6a451cb810f8" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Pictorial bible, being the old and new testaments according to the authorized version: illustrated with more than one thousand engravings, representing the historical events, after celebrated pictures; ... New York: J.S. Redfield and Philadelphia: Thomas, Cowperthwait, &amp; Co., and Boston: Saxton, Pierce, &amp; Co.(Pt. Of St. Matthew missing at beg. of N.T.)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1843/1843">1843</unitdate><container id="aspace_7e5a8abbdb5599097a9547ccb84ebd45" label="box" type="box">36</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9937585be03509a49d898f96413fc563" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. English version of the Polyglott bible, containing the old and new testaments; with the marginal readings; together with a copious and original selection of references to parallel and illustrative passages, exhibited in a manner hitherto unattempted. With Psalms in metre. Philadelphia: Wm. Rutter &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1843/1843">[1843?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_896cd7122d273c6f0d04e20f9a505ddc" label="box" type="box">36</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3c70aa8f02dbb491fddf5fbf7db38f5b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments; translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Stereotype edition. Philadelphia: Bible Association of Friends in America</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1844/1844">1844</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6e4e768821cb1887c55fa4d5386f1d4" label="box" type="box">53</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_14b252b9b19a5df1de2d56e3ce274146" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Devotional family Bible: with practical and experimental reflections on each verse of the Old and New Testaments, and rich marginal references. By the Rev. Alexander Fletcher D. D. London and New York: Virtue, Emmins &amp; Roberts2 volumes.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1844/1845" type="inclusive">[1844 or 1845?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_f9b2e5d125c86196c229c002eeee75f3" label="box" type="box">15</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1bd5c6488e3d68f0057b7fa41a40c433" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Der Bibel, oder die ganze Heilige Schrift des alten und neuen Testaments. Mit Tsugabe des dritten buchs der Maccabaer und des dritten und vierten buchs Efra, ... Philadelphia : Mentz und Roboudt</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1845/1845">1845</unitdate><container id="aspace_d6749f961dc8048ffe07b1dc8cecfaef" label="box" type="box">40</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a5dedc5979c3a1ccf90180c20a760064" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1845/1845">1845</unitdate><container id="aspace_75bae731e7a5b01f605476ae2e848361" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4e7f349e66e5f53701c9df4493479eca" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments; translated out of the original tongue and with the former translations compared and revised. Stereotype edition. Philadelphia: Bible Association of Friends in America</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1845/1845">1845</unitdate><container id="aspace_60a513d5ae2348ab4ad743fe9b4eaa73" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8446b1dd188073be583a854a2b026f20" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1846/1846">1846</unitdate><container id="aspace_20e43c4d15ad06afe46852fd4b637ab7" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7ad5c1420346cebe1fc06126772a1a4b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Illuminated bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues. and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. With marginal readings, references and chronological dates. ... New York: Harper &amp; Brothers, Publishers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1846/1846">1846</unitdate><container id="aspace_a2f446a77b09b31beed86b3d11760ad4" label="box" type="box">49</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ec08c08fdca993d039cd7017ba8e872c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. English version of the Polyglott Bible: containing the old and new testaments, with the marginal readings: together with a copious and original selection of references to parallel and illustrative passages. Exhibited in a manner hitherto unattempted. New York: American and Foreign Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1847/1847">1847</unitdate><container id="aspace_919d0a331087fce03247047dc95d3d4e" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a32ab55569f4a2c45c57ad868abaa6d6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. (old testament t.p. missing starts w/chap V,VI signature a2 or page 5 information from new testament t.p.) New testament of our lord and saviour Jesus Christ, the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Hartford: S. Andrus &amp; Son</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1847/1847">1847</unitdate><container id="aspace_613ea33745cfadadeb7a40a72a084ca8" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_03faddbef2dee3668f508a5466c2f25f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1848/1848">1848</unitdate><container id="aspace_373f843cb3a2a8f1d31db1a9d3b5c987" label="box" type="box">16</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c9e7235cd8b64f65157f5a6bcaac19fc" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1848/1849" type="inclusive">1848-1849 (N.T. has date of 1849)</unitdate><container id="aspace_83f63734a160e38c667fd8e4aad01060" label="box" type="box">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3fa157b46ebc0b8ae7ffaef101966283" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. With Canne's marginal references. Together with the Apocrypha and Concordance. To which are added, an index, a table of texts, and what has never before been added, an account of the lives and martyrdoms of the apostles and evangelists. ... stereotyped by James Conner, New York. Hartford: S. Andrus and Son.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1849/1849">1849</unitdate><container id="aspace_599f8727d3388cf4b0bf9f6f5aa72c78" label="box" type="box">54</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ff37cdc8532de323f6fef2838ff6514e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments together with the Apocrypha translated from the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with Canne's marginal notes and references. ... Concordance, and the Psalms of David in metre. Philadelphia: Edward W. Miller</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1849/1849">1849</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a797d00d9aa446378c23a16b075b267" label="box" type="box">54</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_46adbb65115a7e62552d3e749ece4eb3" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old testament and the new: according to the commonly received version. New York: American and Foreign Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1849/1850" type="inclusive">1849-1850. (New Testament dated 1850)</unitdate><container id="aspace_995ee332ebcb914e67de8c4e33a5e961" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5ee31df2b75db5fe594b2ff14cf13e5d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1850/1850">1850</unitdate><container id="aspace_0e53e969e1031e679f6854459ae250f8" label="box" type="box">15</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a7df1a226c490ae750805681573c0a5d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible; containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. With marginal readings, references, and chronological dates. New York: George Lane &amp; Levi Scott</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1850/1850">1850</unitdate><container id="aspace_b58048f5ea457d2ce3dafcf2221a2194" label="box" type="box">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_14488063d42eca71b663782e35f853c0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: together with the Apocrypha: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. With Canne's marginal notes and references. ... Buffalo: Phinney &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1850/1851" type="inclusive">1850-1851. (N.T. t.p. imprint 1851)</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a5d85007d2df1a6b2d086fa64bc44cd" label="box" type="box">18</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5e649f7cb44e3c01288d6be83272920a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, together with the Apocrypha: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. To which is appended, a concordance, the Psalms of David in metre, ... The text conformable to that of the American Bible Society. Philadelphia: I. Kohler</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1850/1889" type="inclusive">[1850-188?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8c98eb4bb0599960a6152a04ce58c3a" label="box" type="box">51</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_73c7f40574b064d53a403b86a2d7279e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society(2 copies same size and same cover).</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1851/1851">1851</unitdate><container id="aspace_c1f97ae4b39edfc0d5b5e36a8608734e" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3d6a73a330f03a41efc7dd0aaa932688" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1851/1851">1851</unitdate><container id="aspace_a6e434382a650c4ca16aecb7690e0743" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e67f1ada3532bd3a52568a7380831f22" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Kimber &amp; Sharpless' Edition. The holy bible, containing the old and new testaments, together with the Apocrypha: translated from the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with Canne's marginal notes and references; to which are added an index, ... Philadelphia: Jesper Harding</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1851/1851">1851</unitdate><container id="aspace_12864a4bf4948cfca758568e7e012753" label="box" type="box">48</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_26c127fbd88befa5cd6c83c038b785c9" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Kimber &amp; Sharpless' Edition. The holy bible, containing the old and new testaments, together with the Apocrypha: translated from the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with Canne's marginal notes and references; to which are added an index, ... Philadelphia: Jesper Harding</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1851/1851">1851</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b07fedd01000565e6b1c36d34d0ce68" label="box" type="box">48</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a63bd10a51a870ae8bcfd64c085aba87" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his majesty's special command. London: G.E. Eyre and W. Spottiswoode</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1853/1854" type="inclusive">1853-1854 (New Testament has date of 1854)</unitdate><container id="aspace_2ea3879d761805291bcdf1d81e839e4d" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_07f4a703ec8df081e28ed2bf47822d09" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments; translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1853/1854" type="inclusive">1853-1854</unitdate><container id="aspace_7f561a63ad49b5688f6f7999c87fa2ac" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e1057efe81f498d01b7b371381db8291" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his majesty's special command. London: G.F. Eyre and W. Spottiswoode</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1854/1854">1854</unitdate><container id="aspace_89e0d93bcce730bef5884214a7dbf386" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_27d7430f567035241346ba13675978d4" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1854/1854">1854</unitdate><container id="aspace_89143f9fa7a25e623789382773cbde40" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_69e82af12ca000fcf45533b09c7ae8ee" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1854/1854">1854</unitdate><container id="aspace_9e49679e1f6aef3eca6acce667815464" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_def9653e4eace066320b335a4e2e31f7" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, together with the Apocrypha: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. To which is appended, a Concordance, the Psalms of David in Metre, ... Cincinnati: Published by J.A. &amp; U.P. James; stereotyped by A.C. James</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1854/1854">1854</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4ede38841b62aeba557b1704eb799c4" label="box" type="box">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_93680419adca7b074c64b2087ff70909" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1855/1855">1855</unitdate><container id="aspace_0ad7ce85905ef234054bc183e07c1b24" label="box" type="box">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_73a5b97b11349c0f089be7104d307f49" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1855/1855">1855</unitdate><container id="aspace_ced9d3d6c4fbca8722fab85827244105" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d9ccc3bce4c1689be8ae4c422ac269d9" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, together with Apocrypha: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. ... Philadelphia: John B. Perry</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1855/1855">1855</unitdate><container id="aspace_2a7b5952fdc03e4ea70b285a901d5c0a" label="box" type="box">21</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2f86e10483854d717bc98f5707ef4db3" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Comprehensive Bible: containing the old and new testaments, according to the authorized version, with the various readings and marginal notes usually printed therewith a general introduction, containing disquisitions... Philological and explanatory notes: ... Philadelphia: Lippincott, Grambo &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1855/1855">1855</unitdate><container id="aspace_04a7bb93e30985ff7a85e78b5f13bcf6" label="box" type="box">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fd08b3fc80aa9610837e921dc81f014c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. English version of the polyglot bible, containing the old and new testaments; with the marginal readings; together with a copious and original selection of references to parallel and illustrative passages, exhibited in a manner hitherto unattempted. Philadelphia: Lippincott, Grambo &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1855/1855">1855</unitdate><container id="aspace_4b8c55fcd1e791429186e3bcc026417a" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4739f49d21ab58878554fc52327f9f8e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1856/1856">1856</unitdate><container id="aspace_98cef0e4ee153734b86850df0cab13f7" label="box" type="box">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3edde4754370865faa23da23718b003b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Pictorial bible, being the old and new testaments according to the authorized version: illustrated with more than one thousand engravings, representing the historical events, after celebrated pictures; the landscape scenes, from original drawings, or from authentic engravings; and the subjects of natural history, costume, and antiquities, from the best sources. New York: Robert Sears</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1856/1856">1856</unitdate><container id="aspace_f61ad6d8b3ae80de4a3c55ee412c7157" label="box" type="box">54</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_44c6273d4bde8f5e1b070dc5aaf4671a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. (O.T. t.p. is missing. And p.7-10 of Genesis missing information from N.T. t.p.) New Testament, according to the authorized version; with the marginal references, and the usual various readings. Also notes; reflections; questions; improved readings; ... by the Rev. Ingram Cobbin, M.A. illustrated with numerous descriptive engravings. [S.l.: s.n.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1856/1856">1856] (Date from a note by Hodge)</unitdate><container id="aspace_2f0d87a853bed1668e8a81efb7c38ed1" label="box" type="box">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1485a5639561c5cacfbf6b96872386cd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. (No t.p. in front of O.T. using info from N.T.) New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. With marginal readings, references, and chronological dates. New York: T. Carlton &amp; J. Porter</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1857/1857">1857</unitdate><container id="aspace_c0e65c477504b5f318f5de19402fd2b2" label="box" type="box">14</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_579cba0c4730f3bec66670db3b76dcf5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments; translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1857/1857">1857</unitdate><container id="aspace_d2d3b0f43f55f2628cf7e0a43b8bc914" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_eadde41fa669cf9f103a4bf65f9e69e3" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments; translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1857/1857">1857</unitdate><container id="aspace_4cd6e979e2ff2bf5af0b95295c5b45f4" label="box" type="box">36</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a2706db49c89c957e7030d543768c917" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments; translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society(Bottom half of N.T. page missing)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1857/1857">1857</unitdate><container id="aspace_c282bd415ad60bd11a9b84dad9427cc1" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d738f24298023c96b272b363ca911d6c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1858/1858">1858</unitdate><container id="aspace_8f8e7c0e783b42d6fcc7e54c10c3b780" label="box" type="box">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_bb1cb14d03e733f81ca894981868ed15" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. (No t.p. in front of O.T. using info from N.T.) New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1858/1858">1858</unitdate><container id="aspace_049389d62f832cb8556a748c0a87e285" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d808def6a7249004caa4c264ccb9f355" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, together with the Apocrypha: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. To which is appended, a Concordance, the Psalms of David in metere, ... Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott &amp; Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1858/1858">1858</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b4ada3acf4fb5ee142338e2edf2e2cf" label="box" type="box">14</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_76f53048a33cc03f39e3d60632d07296" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments; translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1859/1859">1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_c393a63ebc4eef3e9925e20a15adb7b0" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_84bfb6340a41c47a14ff487de7a83a17" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Hardings' fine edition. The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, together with the Apocrypha, Concordance, and Psalms, and with the former translations... conformable to the original edition of the year of our Lord 1610, and the American Bible Society's Original Standard edition of 1816. Philadelphia: William W. Harding</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1862/1862">1862</unitdate><container id="aspace_fb2fea70752ec864bbecf9ca7fa2d87e" label="box" type="box">14</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d7015cace45f680dd63e7621162f0cac" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1862/1862">1862</unitdate><container id="aspace_a22e3bb622b2557cad5666f51abf24c0" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_dc9a651bec2633b5ca71cb73fbf6de24" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1863/1863">1863</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b1d0a4319cb2ae1a6bb59e8b9f1b7a2" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_66f4a557f74d77da304205b6ffb18f64" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his majesty's special command. Oxford: University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1864/1864">1864</unitdate><container id="aspace_bc087cc4a5ed389949c45ac09afdbe0a" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_be60bca70729ce4c2b39877e6a5a0b93" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Cottage Bible, and family expositor; containing the old and new testaments, with practical expositions and explanatory notes. By Thomas Williams ... to which are added, the references and marginal readings of the Polyglott Bible, together with ... embellished with maps and engravings. Edited by Rev. William Patton, D. D. Complete in two volumes. Hartford: Printed and Published by Case, Lockwood and Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1864/1864">1864</unitdate><container id="aspace_6b5284881c6ff5d99b36656ac6bd2049" label="box" type="box">30</container></did><c03 id="aspace_a09a0daa04ba9866d888928f5d2736b4" level="item"><did><unittitle>v.1</unittitle><container id="aspace_c17bd82a569680ce75629f068e6aecfb" label="box" type="box">30</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_c54c64abd02bbd8036b66a52997b12c7" level="item"><did><unittitle>v.2</unittitle><container id="aspace_253936250bdf1e8b258aa96fdda2441b" label="box" type="box">30</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_5c41997713e6bb08aab36625b9880e91" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1864/1864">1864</unitdate><container id="aspace_147acdaab63ed95026019e5074f79be6" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9775c08cd9b1c5fb72ac1dfd092a4d0e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues: and with former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1864/1864">1864</unitdate><container id="aspace_0215e525ce0aa64ef9d762d3816f5044" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_dd28c6025b30347ae8b5b6a8da392b92" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his majesty's special command. Oxford, University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1865/1866" type="inclusive">1865-1866. (New Testament with date of 1866)</unitdate><container id="aspace_e7f901d5da7025d611cef5cabe3ad8f3" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b14653da9f053ff8335b82d6e886328b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the new and old testaments; translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1865/1865">1865</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d7ef7225c556abe42be521f8c8a42a8" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2e830483465820788d876b792e852f12" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible. Containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1866/1866">1866</unitdate><container id="aspace_0fb6b1bc587a628ebf5074b1d4b6ea7f" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_626507930d043eefdff007b8050a537a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1867/1867">1867</unitdate><container id="aspace_aa9a6729317175194e97102740215a00" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fee8ed9f161e71b94f0f251e4eb2a8dd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1867/1867">1867</unitdate><container id="aspace_590bb10d1a9d102743686cb1f7e9fd5f" label="box" type="box">30</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c02fc30314e2f6fed8392949b6aacbde" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, together with the Apocrypha, Concordance and Psalms, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Text conformable to the original edition of the year of our Lord 1610, ... Philadelphia: William W. Harding</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1867/1867">1867</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c24d8609d2b0bd92446e9fecb2beeae" label="box" type="box">30</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9557854df5281b07d6edf938c671b6b9" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, according to the authorized version; with the marginal references, and the usual various readings. Also notes, reflections... by Rev. Ingram Cobbin. M.A. illustrated with numerous descriptive engravings. Hartford: Case, Lockwood and Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1867/1867">1867</unitdate><container id="aspace_e8b604f95a4c7114aff59f347f257cfa" label="box" type="box">47</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c27b904f70d01716a93483c32bfe1919" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1868/1868">1868</unitdate><container id="aspace_5362ced5d2124229c01cf0076d1b3eb4" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_33f7585ff9279dbaf4af1b5cefebee5d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Pronouncing bible. The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments; translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; ... according to the orthoepy of John Walker. By Israel Alger, Jun. A. M. Pittsburgh: United Presbyterian Board of Publication</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1868/1868">1868</unitdate><container id="aspace_e96a4ae1f609b8be599a98189a8c118a" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_33de12dfa600cf35eac30ddccdee6b5c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Comprehensive Bible; containing the old and new testaments, according to the authorized version with the various readings and marginal notes usually printed therewith. A general introduction, containing disquisitions... philological and explanatory notes: a table of contents... an index to the notes, introductions, and concluding remarks. Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott &amp; Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1869/1869">1869</unitdate><container id="aspace_1c09584b99705242af31cb8f709c0528" label="box" type="box">20</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_738da5c7795bc1b65174fdfc7ec250f7" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1869/1869">1869</unitdate><container id="aspace_d8d188e976aca7068a29122f4d029908" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b2cb10d5805ccf89a19b0ea4be38b52e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1869/1869">1869</unitdate><container id="aspace_a80be73b3c41ed4e4062292aedac1327" label="box" type="box">13</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5cf72cc870e1fbf2d5879e0bb5157801" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Complete analysis of the Holy Bible: or, how to comprehend holy writ from its own interpretation, containing the whole of the old and new testaments, collected systematically arranged in thirty books; together with an introduction, ... So elaborated and arranged in alphabetical order as to direct at one to any subject required. By Rev. Nathaniel West, D.D. ... New York: A.J. Johnson, Publisher</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1869/1869">1869</unitdate><container id="aspace_1c02ac35aa77dc1b1a2851e914cc2db9" label="box" type="box">33</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d2403b1b28edb0776ed283b5319e6484" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments; translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1870/1870">1870</unitdate><container id="aspace_76ab3b015515e70f70aa1b90b1fbc7e0" label="box" type="box">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f36dd70f9792255674571d4c08cd235f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1870/1870">1870</unitdate><container id="aspace_6ee4020b89aa0fef8c114696aaf9ffd2" label="box" type="box">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1bd81ad09dd38346e2c759c8a36a85b8" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Devotional and practical polyglot family bible, containing the old and new testaments, with the marginal readings, and a full and original selection of references to parallel and illustrative passages, arranged in a manner hitherto unattempted. Together with a concordance, a careful index to the bible, ... Cincinnati, OH: National Publishing Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1870/1870">1870</unitdate><container id="aspace_565c97e82cb071f95d2131ee7bc14f7b" label="box" type="box">16</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8dfaa5ce4030d5e67162217354d9a3b6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Devotional family bible containing the old and new testaments according to the most approved copies of the authorized version with practical and experimental reflections on each verse and rich marginal references and readings. By the Rev. Alexander Fletcher, D.D. New York: Virtue and Yorston</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1870/1870">[1870?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_46607f6e4c3e53a4221aa6ce1f0453ec" label="box" type="box">53</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_058707aa74621cd2791369936d2b9812" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1871/1871">1871</unitdate><container id="aspace_bdd095ab51a93d439707f6bff20a1789" label="box" type="box">16</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0d6a9caabfea78ed9da7fa55c48b0a4c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1872/1872">1872</unitdate><container id="aspace_23595d49927b9cc9d8ec019cf23d1918" label="box" type="box">16</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ef4e0c64cd978e495789bfa2d67dfc68" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Die Bibel oder die ganze Heilige Schrift des alten and neuen testaments nach der deutschen uebersetzung D. Martin Luther's. Berlin : Ferlad der Königlikhen Gehrimen Oder Hofbuchbrudere (R. f. Deder)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1872/1872">1872</unitdate><container id="aspace_5b1cf53ec1a61ea472c532ffea665843" label="box" type="box">19</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fde822ba06aecfb99f5897c878200006" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Die Bibel oder die ganze Heilige Schrift des alten and neuen testaments. New York : Amerikanishe Bible Gesllschaft</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1872/1872">1872</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf67e75ec098461376d4b39115825502" label="box" type="box">40</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_045e4d56e75d973d21a181b10f98d41e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Hitchcock's new and complete analysis of the holy bible: or, the whole of the old and new testaments arranged according to subjects in twenty-seven books. On the basis of Matthew Talbot, as improved with indexes, tables, and other valuable matter by Nathaniel West, D.D. ... Word of God. Revised and edited by Rev. Roswell D. Hitchcock, D.D. ... New York: A.J. Johnson</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1872/1872">1872</unitdate><container id="aspace_37ea5b34f40dc158c83586e6ebf0ec20" label="box" type="box">33</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_bb60bb542447c2630cf522af6c68b991" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Latest illustrated polyglot family bible containing the old and new testaments, together with the Apocrypha: translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. To which are appended... New York and Cincinnati: C.F. Vent, (4 other publ. Locations and publs. Also listed)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1872/1872">1872</unitdate><container id="aspace_fffcfe88aacd24b92ecb0fce4ea3cc11" label="box" type="box">47</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_763745bb73b1f1d7f54915d27abf57a6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, authorized version, carefully revised with Bagster's references in full. Pittsburgh: United Presbyterian Board of Publication</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1873/1873">1873</unitdate><container id="aspace_8ffade8e6ba313f967d816a08f362818" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f64ed80841d87848319eb92ede7f16c6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1873/1874" type="inclusive">1873-1874 (N.T. has imprint 1873)</unitdate><container id="aspace_ed99f4f70e3326742b001bc08c6f37a6" label="box" type="box">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5eb7fbc8fb7225baa623e77554bd45e0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1874/1874">1874</unitdate><container id="aspace_6f123a7fe4c1d9052690947b41820bb2" label="box" type="box">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_78d938debe0073122d6383eed117801d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Pictorial home bible, devotional and explanatory: containing the old and new testaments, with the apocrypha, concordance, and marginal references. The text conformable to the standard of the American Bible Society: ... Philadelphia, Cincinnati, Springfield: William Flint and Syracuse, N.T.: Watson Gill and Thompsonville, Conn., Horace King</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1874/1874">1874</unitdate><container id="aspace_a8544659ff96230a1dd8db77ded56fbb" label="box" type="box">40</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c36994f267b4b125f9377290be1e7fec" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Approved holy Catholic Bible. The Holy bible: containing the entire canonical scriptures, according to the decree of the council of Trent; translated from the Latin Vulgate: diligently compared with the Hebrew, Greek and other editions in divers languages. ... with annotations by the Rev. Dr. Challoner; to which is added the history of the Holy Catholic Bible, ... London and Ontario: Schuyler Smith and Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1875/1875">[1875?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_b6ad576066db08a8e582b98ef8a3a166" label="box" type="box">41</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1570de11e460c31894012e88eb91b2f6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1878/1878">1878</unitdate><container id="aspace_09ea2a2a0f12c778d3e417123d2fe016" label="box" type="box">16</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_926643125653a44afc18b7bc12f07296" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Hitchcock's new and complete analysis of the holy bible: or, the whole of the old and new testaments arranged according to subjects in twenty-seven books. On the basis of Matthew Talbot, as improved with indexes, tables, and other valuable matter by Nathaniel West, D.D. ... Word of God. Revised and edited by Rev. Roswell D. Hitchcock, D.D., LL.D., ... New York: Alvin J. Johnson Son, and Pittsburg: W.D. Cummings, and Chicago: E.P. Kingsley</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1878/1878">1878</unitdate><container id="aspace_fd267679822656d62044ab1430782da0" label="box" type="box">33</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_bec56444f2ddc5266ebefe8821037d34" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holman's edition. The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with complete concordance. Embracing every passage of scripture in the largest editions. Apocrypha and Psalms. Philadelphia: A.J. Holman &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1879/1879">1879</unitdate><container id="aspace_e2e5080bacec6dcec083826ccad3788e" label="box" type="box">20</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_62aee23e19382e7402cd227e7f9c798f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Neue Illustrirte familien bibel, für häusliche erbauung und belehrung. Nthaltend das alte und neue testaments, mit den … mit einer einleitung von Rev. A. Martin … Cincinnati : F.? M.? Dillie &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1870/1879" type="inclusive">187? (Date from verso of t.p. when it was entered according to an Act of Congress, but I can't read the last number of the date)</unitdate><container id="aspace_575d9d367a73143801953bd66afb2b0c" label="box" type="box">43</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9736b198c337ffd7efbf6c82b32ae763" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Standard edition. The Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with concordance and psalms of David in meter. The text conformable to the Oxford and the American Bible Society's standard editions. Chicago: David C. Cook</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1879/1882" type="inclusive">[1879-1882] (Dates are from the verso of t.p. when they were entered according to an act of congress, n.t. has 1882)</unitdate><container id="aspace_8828d1b796563b9f70e79bb26481ea04" label="box" type="box">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_18bab1c2681c94cff78a9341400929ea" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holman's edition. The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with complete concordance. Embracing every passage of scripture in the largest editions. Apocrypha and Psalms. Philadelphia: A.J. Holman &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1880/1880">1880</unitdate><container id="aspace_a52897148f94618c27700dbf34f867fd" label="box" type="box">20</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_388aecaf54e43dd28ff55d07e23436a7" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, By his Majesty's special command. Appointed to be read in churches. London; New York: Eyre and Spottiswoode</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1880/1889" type="inclusive">[1880-1889?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b61feb31fb0118bcab2d8d053b182d4" label="box" type="box">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_34f83ff577f9bd171d0177f6bcaf01d5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. A practical and explanatory commentary on the old testament. By the Rev. Robert Jamieson D.D., London: Virtue &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1881/1881">1881? [Imprint information from N.T. t.p., O.T. t.p. is loose; imprint date from Hodge note]</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a10138d38c729f2623036245855a584" label="box" type="box">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ac882f975c9e041da4799cd47275c490" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holman's edition. The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with the Concordance &amp; Psalms of David in metre. The text conformable to the Oxford and the American Bible Society's standard editions. Philadelphia: A.J. Holman &amp; Col</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1882/1882">1882</unitdate><container id="aspace_06d5557ee6ba7c1add8c40b989e3674d" label="box" type="box">18</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0a3c17823e76ed4969715ce1cb14a98e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Die neue illustrirte familien bibel für häusliche erbauung und belehrung, enthaltend ds alte und neue testament mit den Apokruphen, der Concordanz, randparallelen, ... Indianapolis, IN and Troy, OH : Union Publishing Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1882/1882">1882</unitdate><container id="aspace_39c6b31179a29ae959928a7c94151f0f" label="box" type="box">37</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_57e00692048a53ccd006de67b7c851cd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Die Bibel oder die ganze Heilige Schrift des alten and neuen testaments, nach der deutschen uebersetzung D. Martin Luthers. Refidirte ausgabe. Milvaukee : Berlad von Geo. Brumder</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1884/1887" type="inclusive">1884-1887 (N.T. t.p. has imprint of 1884)</unitdate><container id="aspace_d208386bf8216470eb9d1ba153d5ed24" label="box" type="box">19</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_236c49c052995565a31ddd3f58294965" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible: containing the entire canonical scriptures, according to the decree of the council of Trent; translated from the Latin vulgate: diligently compared with the Hebrew, Greek, and other editions in divers languages the old testament, first published by the English college at Douay, A.D. 1609. The New testament, by the English college at Eheims, A.D. 1582. ... Boston: George V. Jones</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1884/1884">1884. (Date from verso of t.p. date entered according to Act of Congress)</unitdate><container id="aspace_36759d2c0b47d4ef54ebe82d11d05c39" label="box" type="box">43</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c7b2956694e1080e84541451975f7b70" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the authorized edition of the new testament, A.D. 1611, and the revised version of A.D. 1881 arranged in parallel columns; with complete concordance, ... Philadelphia: A.J. Holman &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1885/1885">1885</unitdate><container id="aspace_c4b3562118736bdda48b9912762521f3" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_42905e69ff5eba0e4e85cc7934b8453c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Approved holy catholic bible. The holy bible: containing the entire canonical scriptures, according to the decree of the council of Trent; translating from the Latin vulgate: diligently compared with the Hebrew, ... annotations by the Rev. Dr. Challoner; to which is added the history of the holy catholic bible, ... Philadelphia: John E. Potter and Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1885/1885">[1885?] (Date from note by Hodge)</unitdate><container id="aspace_0c104f0a3450bc1b68723685dd906a8d" label="box" type="box">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d19dd1902f460fff4459d1f466900b43" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Parallel bible. Authorized edition. The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues: being the King James version arranged in parallel columns with the revised version. Portland, Maine: H. Hallett &amp; Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1885/1885">[1885?] (Date from note by Hodge)</unitdate><container id="aspace_7d03b870d966a5525e7add554b7d6902" label="box" type="box">35</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8fe8e83ab809bb4712670dc790ce2f76" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Parallel bible. Authorized edition. The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues: being the King James version arranged in parallel columns with the revised version. Portland, Maine: H. Hallett &amp; Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1885/1885">[1885?] (Date from note by Hodge)</unitdate><container id="aspace_07f74c254c4ef58b67a28a452700283c" label="box" type="box">35</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_276e62d6657cafc6d70c3f7ed397ac85" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible: containing the authorized and revised versions of the old and new testaments arranged in parallel columns; the text conformable to that of the universities of Oxford and Cambridge: complete concordance, marginal references, chronological tables, a history of ancient biblical manuscripts with fac-similes of the same, the earliest printed editions of the Bible, a history of the revision of the Bible, etc. Philadelphia: A.J. Holman &amp; Co.(Missing t.p.)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1887/1887">1887</unitdate><container id="aspace_a22c1209e695871cec58fc8a55cbf838" label="box" type="box">51</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_32817cd8519b9559337c6e142a13e8fc" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Neue Illustrirte Familien Bibel für Häushliche Erbauung und Belehrung, enthaltend das Alte und Neue Testament mit den Apokrnphen, der Concordanz, Randparallelen, ... Philadelphia : A.J. Holman &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1888/1888">1888</unitdate><container id="aspace_7895d636f1188a1ec828a2a643c97181" label="box" type="box">10</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e690465a9e78a64a2fa6652ac7475b3d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Altemus' Edition The Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with complete concordance, embracing every passage of scripture in the largest editions. Apocrypha and Psalms. Philadelphia: Henry Altemus</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1888/1888">1888</unitdate><container id="aspace_e614419a8dc5106417162250f19cc01c" label="box" type="box">35</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_865d90d1d3e5bab69d846aa5a07dd14d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Die neue illustrirte heilige schrift für häusliche erbauung und belehrung, enthaltend ds alte und neue testament mit den Apokruphen, der Concordanz, randparallelen, …Pittsburg, PA : W. J. Giffith, 18??. (Can't read date on back of t.p.)</unittitle><container id="aspace_1127b42c93c84462d00c7203673e5c91" label="box" type="box">37</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_88fee8782b9ffbeb49fc72839d8df34f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, translated from the Latin vulgate: diligently compared with the Hebrew, Greek, and other editions in various languages. ... with annotations by the Rev. Dr. Challoner; ... New York: D. &amp; J. Sadlier &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1880/1889" type="inclusive">188? (Date from a note by Hodge)</unitdate><container id="aspace_59f1d10b905970c0eb85c7b1a02af95c" label="box" type="box">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0e998130510dd420eaa2fd1932f5a0e0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible or the old and new testaments containing the authorized and revised versions in parallel columns family pronouncing edition with pictorial illustrations and aids for readers and students. Cincinnati: Jones Brothers Publishing Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1880/1889" type="inclusive">[188?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_ed7ded81300669af0479d7908b6a3238" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_949f409afedb82c2ea2f26f602e963d5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1890/1890">1890</unitdate><container id="aspace_5052921bc7d2151f0e36e8d2ea272c62" label="box" type="box">16</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_441b34a34fbf4adf9b9bfc66087c28ca" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; with a history and facsimile of the ancient manuscripts. The text conformable to the Oxford and the American Bible Society's standard editions. Chicago: R.S. Peale &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1890/1890">1890</unitdate><container id="aspace_2018950c10d995c5bb2fe56c890554c6" label="box" type="box">51</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c1e831f75ea89b97ccf0ae3e2c869779" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Pronouncing edition of the Holy Bible. Containing the authorized and revised versions of the old and new testaments, arranged in parallel columns, giving the correct pronunciation of every scripture proper name contained in the bible, by Prof. S.W. Williams. Complete concordance: ... Indianapolis: Union Publishing Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1890/1890">1890</unitdate><container id="aspace_83cedf96767d71187d52784a9a70b9ca" label="box" type="box">5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c494b1c56ce9e78efd86aa00d998805c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Altemus' edition the Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised; embracing every passage of the scripture in the largest editions. With complete Concordance, and Psalms. Philadelphia: Henry Altemus</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1891/1891">1891</unitdate><container id="aspace_7a467d9fc762fe97b2102d92cd121692" label="box" type="box">28</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5ea53cebb81a28d8581cad176babc7eb" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Self-Pronouncing edition. In which all the proper names are divided, accented, and marked with the vowel sounds, showing how they should be pronounced. Holy Bible containing the King James and the revised versions of the old and new testaments arranged in parallel columns. The text conformable to that of the universities of Oxford and Cambridge. ... Chicago: Chicago Publication &amp; Lithograph Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1892/1892">1892</unitdate><container id="aspace_2f57267ea1b5a4b19d4070dca4c5f343" label="box" type="box">5</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6a73012bbc00b1fe65423951c5a611e0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Self-Pronouncing edition. In which all the proper names are divided, accented, and marked with the vowel sounds, showing how they should be pronounced. Holy Bible containing the King James and the revised versions of the old and new testaments arranged in parallel columns. ... [S.l.: s.n.(part of the title page is missing)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1892/1892">1892?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_378278c7056956519aaad11fdfca794d" label="box" type="box">34</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_dc4dfe977f29f723bf348d7345df3e08" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. 1492 the jubilee year, in commemoration of the discovery of America. 1892 the pronouncing edition of the Holy Bible. Containing the authorized and revised versions of the old and new testaments, arranged in parallel columns, giving the correct pronunciation of every proper name... by Prof. S.W. Williams. ... Cincinnati: A.J. Conroy &amp; Co., and St. Louis: Conroy Bros.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1892/1892">[1892] (according to Hodge note)</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1dad80905a7f6ce92645832511cccbf" label="box" type="box">28</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_901498aa92e8bdc85b2806e0ea2606a5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1893/1893">1893</unitdate><container id="aspace_08aeb702fb81dcf1ed46e9c16d24fb4f" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_91ea51902cd35236d131e49f03c2c36f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible: containing the old and new testaments, translated out of the original tongues. with a complete concordance, embracing every passage of scripture in the largest editions. 100,000 marginal references and readings, ... with revised new testament, the old (King James') version and the revised version arranged in parallel columns for convenience... Philadelphia: National Publishing Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1893/1893">[1893?] (date from Hodge note in bible)</unitdate><container id="aspace_6ccd6bed9e53515e60f5da5cc6bf7dc6" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_abf13e0bc7540af2e94a50f62b919ff1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Self-pronouncing edition in which all the proper names are divided, accented, and marked with the vowel sounds, ... trade combination mark. Holy Bible showing in simple form all changes, additions and omissions that appear in the revised version, enabling all bible readers to see at a glance... containing the old and new testaments. Translated out of the original tongues, ... test conformable to that of the Oxford Bible, ... Philadelphia: Gately &amp; Fitzgerald</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1895/1895">1895</unitdate><container id="aspace_ec6b6c4a02c4c6fb1abe4b86616907e6" label="box" type="box">10</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cb051626718dda43fddb98dec2f71752" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues being the version set forth A.D. 1611 compared with the most ancient authorities and revised A.D. 1881-1885 newly edited by the American revision committee A.D. 1901 standard edition. New York: Thomas Nelson &amp; Sons2 copies.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1900/1901" type="inclusive">1900-1901 (New Testament dated 1900)</unitdate><container id="aspace_6b5273da2e3e3a1748417f62bf9530b8" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cb322dd359c3367475aa3d1f6b99ad25" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues being the version set forth A.D. 1611 compared with the most ancient authorities and revised A.D. 1881-1885. Newly edited by the American Revision Committee A.D. 1901 standard edition. New York: Thomas Nelson &amp; Sons</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1901/1901">1901</unitdate><container id="aspace_84e794278b6ca3765fa0453fc42f6471" label="box" type="box">50</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0ffda5f3e98f6367aba2838d88b6eae2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. With marginal notes and analytical references. New York: Henry F. Giere(Spine title: Wilmore's new analytical reference bible).</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1902/1902">[1902?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_120fb92bb4ac52a357e63b20bd432bec" label="box" type="box">38</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_bc8c3cea31b4889bc1474aadcccbf67e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by His Majesty's special command. Appointed to be read in churches London: Samuel Bagster &amp; Sons, Limited; New York: James Pott and Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1902/1902">[1902?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_632c8a98b8f48ecba4f7850d8e80e1a0" label="box" type="box">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_62359b7afa9074767cb7ca44f281d713" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments and the apocrypha. Boston: R.H. Hinkley Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1904/1904">[1904?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_9428f449e85a59de7eef8929215fa70c" label="box" type="box">32</container></did><c03 id="aspace_6ed2585e6bd2f0b18ff8c42d144a6d07" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 1 Genesis and Exodus no. 569 of 1000</unittitle><container id="aspace_61b1deda3141721a0a2cc0694cc39255" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_d071e8fc1e86b65acda0970d46e9acdf" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 2 Leviticus, Numbers and Deuteronomy no. 569 of 1000</unittitle><container id="aspace_ae41405816a5ea96ef598b59b4cab9a1" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_6c59137c985e4d37826223e8d588a55f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 3 Joshua, Judges, Ruth and the first book of Samuel no. 569 of 1000</unittitle><container id="aspace_5268bf5c0a889a5288ae2350f610474d" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_1375b30978a3228ab9b9c9e5389655b0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 4 Second Book of Samuel and the Books of the Kings no. 569 of 1000</unittitle><container id="aspace_d9681561f4ee6d26320243ce63f1fee1" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_ebbfe14e50a9feb21c61442000d1c17b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 5 Books of the Chronicles Ezra, Nehemiah and Esther no. 569 of 1000</unittitle><container id="aspace_ea0700dc78980fff20d0d9369953059a" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_8829cde2c39ffa3558f563ad4e65cc2d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 6 Book of Job and the book of Psalms no. 569 of 1000</unittitle><container id="aspace_ea5fd4a73b8312cdce0e165e12ed3566" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_89d10061a87ba7aa86907d74b7fbb6c2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 7 Proverbs, Ecclesiastes, the Song of Solomon and Isaiah no. 569 of 1000</unittitle><container id="aspace_2591591a2fdbb2f1c2ad52a37fad5a12" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_dab61650fc065a1af7a569b2e44042ce" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 8 Jeremiah, Lamentations and a portion of the Prophecy of Ezekiel no. 569 of 1000</unittitle><container id="aspace_9d3d0c44a67ca65349e1a985d99dd65c" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_c9751f0c04624e1fb4677972fa8752c9" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 9 Conclusion of Ezekiel, the book of Daniel and the Minor Prophets no. 569 of 1000</unittitle><container id="aspace_595eb115553501e182edc2f59199baca" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_6132cce1abc126451eea9cc543e303a6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 10 The Apocrypha, The First book of Esdras to Chapter XXI of Ecclesiasticus no. 569 of 1000</unittitle><container id="aspace_eba4df27c32211327679021197f84dab" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_8b454bc036e7c087f7fcb8881a8b4c66" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 11 The Apocrypha, Conclusion of Ecclesiasticus to end of the second book of the Maccabees no. 569 of 1000</unittitle><container id="aspace_517b5b37385965d7d3151808c82f3fa7" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_af4583fb57a36386c252b01d6f6f6807" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 12 The Gospels according to Saint Mark and Saint Luke no. 569 of 1000</unittitle><container id="aspace_e33c607f66805632c2cc31cb54d2dfe0" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_fc71a1711f54fac70a03aa89662ef5c9" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 13 The Gospel of Saint John, The Acts Epistle to Romans First Epistle to Corinthians no. 569 of 1000</unittitle><container id="aspace_0cb0cd455698fa8941896d092b052b5f" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_1393d085d31cb717ffe467d639e17e19" level="item"><did><unittitle>Lacking vol. 14</unittitle><container id="aspace_658373639018e897da5e6ed33ef6a002" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_1959642306a3c5583f9892caf98d4331" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments translated into the Telugu language under the auspices of the British and Foreign Bible Society. [S.l.]: Madras auxiliary to the British and Foreign Bible Society S.P.C.K. Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1904/1904">1904</unitdate><container id="aspace_92cebf21001df2707e1f83a0df2e41c3" label="box" type="box">35</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3fa30a38a93d2069f426d7bdd3abbee8" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Bible for home reading edited with comments and reflections for the use of Jewish parents and children by C.G. Montefiore. London: Macmillan and Co., Limited and New York: Macmillan Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1907/1907">1907</unitdate><container id="aspace_44eda7287504cb32eb4d5612d392942e" label="box" type="box">46</container></did><c03 id="aspace_600710790afcd83c8613265a1dbbf10c" level="item"><did><unittitle>First Part</unittitle><container id="aspace_eba59a67dacba2eb75b8ce8349ca247b" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_86f26d68ca60d1ba488ce3659ff8d266" level="item"><did><unittitle>Second Part</unittitle><container id="aspace_dcaf42f6cd4045377b0b0a6bce1a084b" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_6e4a77a86eabb672b5b1f7bf02e5e09f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Biblia sacra vulgatæ editionis sixti v. pontificis maximi jussu recognita et Clementis VIII. Auctoritate edita nunc novissime ad exemplar vaticanum epressa cura Augustini Arndt S.J. … editio Quarta. Ratisbonæ, Romæ, Neo Eboraci et Cincinnati : Sumptibus et typis Friderici Pustet(There is also a t.p. in German; text is in two columns, one in Latin and the other in German).</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1907/1907">1907</unitdate><container id="aspace_c6a07ad6dd1c766407e074ed0f2e954e" label="box" type="box">19</container></did><c03 id="aspace_f3a54ec99e2155e105ebaaec3a3dd113" level="item"><did><unittitle>Tomus Primus</unittitle><container id="aspace_031d4fbc69152047a104cdbc827d2cbd" label="box" type="box">19</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_cf10983ca6ed387ae561792be248ba41" level="item"><did><unittitle>Tomus Secundus</unittitle><container id="aspace_21bbfe6cfde4209b399f193f6e0decc2" label="box" type="box">19</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_755c907fa32e105d520ed98d10492182" level="item"><did><unittitle>Tomus Tertius</unittitle><container id="aspace_c0183b7b2c941e80cfb65b8b6c8b62fe" label="box" type="box">49</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_f720c0002d92cbe2b11ef223afdbd082" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Die Bibel oder die ganze heilige schrift des alten und neuen testaments, nach der deutschen uebersetzung Dr. Martin Luthers. Saint Louis : Concordia Publishing House</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1907/1907">1907</unitdate><container id="aspace_1aae0cdb089b5eed10e69502240e537c" label="box" type="box">50</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_700b5791067e83af50fa7a0d5fdec876" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Sainte Bible, qui contient le vieux et le nouveau testament; revue sur les originaux, par David Martin, … New York : Société Bibliqué Americaine</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1908/1908">1908</unitdate><container id="aspace_3cf80c657232bee837bc951a8dec08bc" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8843dbe22b42417ffec05c39f9b36404" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible, containing the old and new testaments: translated out of the original tongues; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1913/1913">1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_8e0fa8e2f85119510b56483a0dd45954" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8e7bbac1d83b3de28d05f21e0bc7e753" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible translated from the Latin vulgate diligently compared with Hebrew, Greek and other editions in divers languages The old testament first published by the English College at Douay, A.D. 1609. and the new testament first published by the English College at Rhemis, A.D. 1582. ... Published with the approbation of his eminence James Cardinal Gibbons Archbiship of Baltimore. Baltimore, New York: John Murphy</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1914/1914">[1914?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_1afc09dcc081787ef08c6b3b11a61806" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b4b228cb57ae8518405b4df4063c4c43" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Modern reader's bible the books of the bible with three books of the Apocrypha presented in modern literary form edited with introductions and notes by Richard G. Moulton... New York: The MacMillan Company and London: MacMillan &amp; Co., Ltd.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1924/1924">1924</unitdate><container id="aspace_90f5ea380496aa9214e5bcfc9d0932cf" label="box" type="box">52</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_460aec9c1e6c867eab66b13da47f6863" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Concordia bilingual edition of the Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments in the English translation according to the authorized version and in the German translation according to the original Luther text. St. Louis: Concordia Publishing House</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1925/1925">1925</unitdate><container id="aspace_85051e7e01fc42d5c4089942e74018d4" label="box" type="box">18</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_077e5685e447a36951d38529b332871f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Living bible being the whole bible in its fewest words. Edited from the King James version by Bolton Hall. New York: Alfred A. Knopf</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928/1928">1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_e716d2e042f65001b49c64a82ee9581d" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ffe46fa13e8928e819f4d250d648f0a0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Bible an American translation + the old testament translated by a group of scholars under the editorship of J.M. Powis Smith The new testament translated by Edgar J. Goodspeed. Chicago: University of Chicago Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1931/1931">1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_9e0111eccba1154c4e0cab57830bd65d" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_51643c8e108a51dd62ecbcc4b63bbe1a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. English. 1932. Numberical bible; being a revised translation of the Holy Scriptures with expository notes: arranged, divided, and briefly characterized according to the principles of their numerical structure. New York: Loizeaux Bros.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1932/1956" type="inclusive">[1932-56]</unitdate><container id="aspace_2ead0c0c808657612325428eb6d1bbdf" label="box" type="box">7</container></did><c03 id="aspace_0ee160aff705702939fd86d1ea9732fd" level="item"><did><unittitle>[1] The Pentateuch. [1956] c1903</unittitle><container id="aspace_e600908cdd9f74d3a13f941895458f8e" label="box" type="box">7</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_054313cd62c6f15db128f3f77cbe7192" level="item"><did><unittitle>[2] The covenant history -- Joshua to (2) Samuel, 5th ed. [c1932]</unittitle><container id="aspace_623c6f477362598d41172239f99ce1a2" label="box" type="box">7</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_83ff0f4935903720b9a52b87d4b4f716" level="item"><did><unittitle>[6] Acts to (2) Corinthians. [n.d.]</unittitle><container id="aspace_f48b8f5a4e11985f72d419057667ac4e" label="box" type="box">7</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_f2a8d80d2b4ad5d0f3f9b31544620af6" level="item"><did><unittitle>[7] Hebrews to Revelation. 5th ed. [c1932]</unittitle><container id="aspace_7e82ca665d486c2c81a9aabbe7e2286a" label="box" type="box">7</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_3f53bfdc494142bfc11310fbc8dd7c3d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Bible designed to be read as living literature the Old and New Testaments in the King James version 1936 this edition arranged and edited by Ernest Sutherland Bates. New York: Simon and Schuster</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_58ec049f6f75d0bfb45687f849e2133e" label="box" type="box">39</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6b4e64a1dd81c4a399dae583a9a56987" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New analytical bible and dictionary of the bible authorized version with the addition in many instances, in brackets, of the more correct renderings of the American revised version, copyright 1929 by the international council of religious education, and used by permission. A system of helps comprising textual revision, ... Chicago: John A. Dickson Publishing Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_7216bc3a0c50662545bf3d26671324ff" label="box" type="box">33</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a9fd9c5fd1b80a6f6e80b78506f68bcd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Digest of the bible the authorized version condensed for easy reading. By Peter V. Ross. New York: Prentice-Hall, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_ff42abbd8309bd06ff66e618e392246c" label="box" type="box">42</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d2dcfd4dd765dd191e203845d4f579b6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. College Bible -- a selection made by the School of Letters... The School of Religion at the State University of Iowa. New York: Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_8d6a4fd630d368c236782b5bb4a6ea9d" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f720734dcaac277ce12008d15b55a4ae" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Complete Bible an American translation the Old Testament translated by J.M. Powis Smith and a group of scholars the Apocrypha and the New Testament translated by Edgar J. Goodspeed. Chicago: University of Chicago Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_9d4a2b28bed89244490e568c1a93f317" label="box" type="box">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fb826d415bb2c14e4a1dc247b1e5ea5f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holman edition The Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised The text conformable to that of the 1611, ... Philadelphia: A.J. Holman Company (Imprint date from Hodge note and History and facts concerning the order of the Eastern Star with scriptural quotations and references... revised in 1941 at beg. of bible).</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">[1941]</unitdate><container id="aspace_ba5c6517b8f947cc7b7265a74d8dbe62" label="box" type="box">17</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_97e99069c46957e6e5a169c7f706029a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible translated from the Latin vulgate and diligently compared with the Hebrew, Greek and other editions in divers languages... With notes by Bishop Challoner and also the encyclical letter "On the Study of Scriptures." by Pope Leo XIII... Table of references, maps and other helpful matter. New York: Douay Bible House</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e62ac6cf997e9d259c194733877b0c5" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3d2b3ef73eabe9aaf439fdc752f8aaea" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Quotable bible edited by Louis M. Notkin with a forward by Ralph W. Sockman. The old and new testaments in the King James version. New York: Samuel Curl, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_1feb9585e8e08e027eb0bcb30e9add70" label="box" type="box">43</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_92a8c4d7c8d0b2e0fd6c9cbf458f1a54" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Short Bible and American translation. Edited by Edgar J. Goodspeed and J.M. Powis Smith. Chicago: University of Chicago Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1944/1944">1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_0e95627e943242b4662f9ac698b71e76" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_20402fa7ff97ae5c59f03ceff91d9cf1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible revised standard version containing the old and new testaments translated from the original tongues being the version set for A.D. 1611 revised A.D. 1881-1885 and A.D. 1901 compared with the most ancient authorities and revised A.D. 1952. Toronto, New York and Edinburgh: Thomas Nelson &amp; Sons</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1952" type="inclusive">1946-1952 (Old testament t.p. has date 1952; New testament t.p. has date 1946)</unitdate><container id="aspace_e059e2e4fda526b57d26e618ed6d2db8" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9e25a13a887fac7e9b198c5eceb6637a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible authorized King James version published as the good leader bible. Easy-to-use references, complete indexes and charts, colorful illustrations, and other features... Chicago: John A. Dickson Publishing Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_4e41259ccc33bdd8cbca9e69336f8106" label="box" type="box">47</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e1b5a13b6112170748d0df37fc1eeab0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New standard alphabetical indexed bible Holy Bible (authorized King James version) school and library reference edition -- containing the old and new testaments ... red letter edition pictorial pronouncing dictionary and other interesting instructive features ... family bible beautifully illustrated with colored paintings. Chicago: John A. Hertel Co.(on front cover Blue Ribbon Edition)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1948">1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_25eba4622208cc90a6b0da164456b545" label="box" type="box">41</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_63a4af2a4dbe5c2e69b25d423213139a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New translation of the bible containing the old and new testaments James Moffatt Hon. D.D. (St. Andrews; Oxford), D. Litt. New York and London: Harper &amp; Brothers Publishers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_e95487646a15fefd051f5b41a73e936e" label="box" type="box">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_673fd6c612eed2d66eb71bab5e62d99b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Home bible arranged for family reading from the King James version by Ruth Hornblower Greenough with illustrations from designs by William Blake Decorations by Rudolph Ruzicka. New York: Harper &amp; Brothers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_55310838ac03a3a2ec3b4798c55c7eaa" label="box" type="box">42</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_34688ec2b06ff45e5927796b11902157" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Bible in pictures edited by the Rev. Ralph Kirby editorial consultants the Rev. Professor E.O. James, ... the Rev. C.C. Martindale, ... Professor S.H. Hooke, ... New York: Greystone Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_61a42cd82630547ea9f97f6b5d3f9c80" label="box" type="box">33</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5e1f607d15f5145b94460e9a42244e83" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible in brief the King James text edited and arranged by James Reeves... New York: Mentor Book published by the New American Library</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_d71de873ab257922f45d77687ac2ff2d" label="box" type="box">42</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_97e34c49ea7b0920751e78c9224b3fbe" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible a translation from the Latin vulgate in the light of the Hebrew and Greek originals authorized by the hierarchy of England and Wales and Hierarchy of Scotland. New York: Sheed &amp; Ward, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_f61d102739f9e5e46abf1a08e79fc3c8" label="box" type="box">20</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_de052da997e3d20bfe3665d9d1c885bf" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues and with the former translations diligently compared &amp; revised set forth in 1611 and commonly known as the King James Version. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">[1956] (date from note by Hodge in front of book)</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4f7b9aa8fb2d58fbfad6c52c3abdf8c" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_53d240c38ffb973b7ba8407175a5991d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible from ancient eastern manuscripts containing the old and new testaments translated from Peshitta, the authorized Bible of the Church of the East by George M. Lamsa. Philadelphia: A.J. Holman Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_e08f8400499cb127b8b6d1d05f292587" label="box" type="box">24</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5cb855b9abc6903a4f5fb769dee48aa5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Pamphlet bible series; a commentary and complete text of the old and new testaments. New York: Paulist PressLibrary has: v.2-v.12; v.25-v.36</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">1960-</unitdate><container id="aspace_50817faa146f3a8492d9fd6796f55f73" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6fb4b9b836f463c4444ce580453daab4" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New world translation of the holy scriptures rendered from the original languages by the New World Bible Translation Committee -- revised A.D. 1961 -- New York: Watchtower Bible and Tract Society of New York Inc., and Brooklyn: International Bible Students Association</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_0c84a46b117e35848afffe1ab1e89668" label="box" type="box">24</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3638906636abffc72276f96ec3e90a09" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Saint Joseph "New Catholic Edition" of the Holy Bible The Old Testament confraternity -- douay version ... and the New Testament confraternity edition ... New York: Catholic Book Publishing Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962 (copyright on verso of N.T. 1948)</unitdate><container id="aspace_99ec3bda7ec5a6baea32f1f8124715af" label="box" type="box">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_69200c22a42504e879c4f66c2a08123f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New world translation of the Hebrew scriptures rendered from the original languages by the New World Bible Translation Committee -- A.D. 1953-1960 -- New York: Watchtower Bible and Tract Society of New York Inc., and Brooklyn: International Bible Students Association</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_ae207ef86787aba7ec864be2f0681d9b" label="box" type="box">24</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_40b0f2024dc9d60ff3e5a611591f671b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New Saint Joseph simplified bible "The Heart of the Bible" -- the most important texts of each book of the holy bible in the official confraternity version, modern format and with short helpful notes edited by Rt. Rev. John E. Steinmueller, ... and Mother Kathryn Sullivan, ... New York: Catholic Book Publishing Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_af44bdc32a5836af9ee6d3e9cd666249" label="box" type="box">43</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ee211f8c069a4e48cbdb44e649da4917" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Shortened arrangement of the holy bible revised standard version edited by Robert O. Ballou. Philadelphia: Published by A.J. Holman Company for J.B. Lippioncott Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1964">1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_a09f70fc937e3ef25e30d3a21675cd2f" label="box" type="box">43</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_de5c78fa118e78aeaf9189d8f5cc9f6b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Anchor Bible. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday &amp; Company, Inc.(Mixed Set incomplete; 39 volumes 2 copies of v.15)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1978" type="inclusive">1964-1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_e8606a4208f4db095b6f61e1267a3b89" label="box" type="box">44</container></did><c03 id="aspace_036cbde783e3c7528ab5f98b7ebbb99f" level="item"><did><unittitle>[1, 5-9, 12-17]</unittitle><container id="aspace_7d060d30376cf16b41c90e3cd737f6d3" label="box" type="box">44</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_081f30e9226eac4f8b8bb0625b3ae4e0" level="item"><did><unittitle>[17a-18, 20-21, 23-24a, 26, 29-29a, 31-32, 34-34a, 36-38, 40-41a]</unittitle><container id="aspace_67f4677dd4b6b9997bfea1964d71f12d" label="box" type="box">45</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_7f5706604a46c79855c9856b42ed525c" level="item"><did><unittitle>[42-44]</unittitle><container id="aspace_190464d1853d0a434a7b1c9ab5cfe389" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_67995c4eceb11c8efc11f9951e9f6b8d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Amplified bible containing the amplified old testament and the amplified new testament. Grand Rapids, MI: Zondervan Publishing House</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_9b2d2033bd68b7923076f1f6a2c91dff" label="box" type="box">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_db793548dcaef86db36fd967de70116f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Oxford annotated bible with the apocrypha revised standard version with an introductory article the number, order, and names of the books of the bible. Herbert G. May and Bruce M. Metzger, editors. New York: Oxford University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_c8635ae90f36deec63bf2e73b8877c7b" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5de2f8f6acc54eb6ba4c5943e7891515" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Westminster study bible the Holy Bible revised standard version containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues being the version set forth A.D. 1611 revised A.D. 1881-1885 and A.D. 1901 compared with the most ancient authorities and revised A.D. 1952... New York and Glasgow: Collins' Clear-Type Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_a762adcd4984d27ac5f4d9fbbe48db12" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_58a94645f1d6dc18865ea11a4fe8388d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Jerusalem bible. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday &amp; Company, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4b0f04aced5d909d1f89b9ca7d40e95" label="box" type="box">50</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_505cc416faeb056c8eb61122296dd4c0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New English bible. S.l.: Oxford University Press and Cambridge University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970 (on verso of t.p. printed in the United States of America)</unitdate><container id="aspace_3fbc784272af044da49f209b06c7a415" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a854e59372c8482582ac0b0189252dc2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Restoration of original sacred name bible containing the old and new testaments the restoration of Original Sacred Name Bible is designed to restore to the scriptures the sacred name of the MOST HIGH and his son from the sacred original on the basis of the Rotherham version revised by Missionary Dispensar Bible Research. Buena Park, CA and Winfield, AL</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_84a1f341aba52a6fc5b82a6ad4f39a1b" label="box" type="box">33</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_71dc321c0b783a035085ee33fef5c599" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New world translation of the holy scriptures rendered from the original languages by the New World Bible Translation Committee -- revised 1970 c.e. -- New York: Watchover Bible and Tract Society of New York Inc., and Brooklyn: International Bible Students Association</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_010103d3b2106835b23ce68e11d27ee1" label="box" type="box">24</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_47bcf30f45a161e8a3855e2c4e88a4ab" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Jerusalem bible illustrations by Salvadore Dali. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday &amp; Company, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_d757e578a11415359425d7729f156564" label="box" type="box">47</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7117ff7e4214429f2dd9c6eaf9ef28fd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Saint Joseph edition of the new American bible translated from the original languages with critical use of all the ancient sources by Members of the Catholic Biblical Association of America. ... New York: Catholic Book Publishing Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_807ab8825add90584f7deeea9596e8cc" label="box" type="box">49</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2c8f26f146590d1636b64613b2e69931" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible revised standard version containing the old and new testaments with the Apocrypha/Deuterocanonical books and ecumenical edition. New York, Glasgow, London, Toronto, Sydney, Auckland: Collins</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1973" type="inclusive">1971-1973 (Old Testament t.p. has date 1973; New testament t.p. dated 1971 second edition)</unitdate><container id="aspace_7ffa59154feea14181328c7de578befe" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_aae3112b8b3d1fbebda5038834b061e6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible illustrated containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues and with the former translations diligently compared and revised King James version 1611. Pleasantville, New York: Reader's Digest Association, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_584c0d631628e5efac6792ace8079dea" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b8f7fce061aa900eeaae1d5baa46e1f8" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New world translation of the holy scriptures rendered from the original languages by the new world bible translation committee -- revised 1971 c.e. -- New York?: Watchtower Bible and Tract Society of New York, Inc., and Brooklyn: International Bible Students Association</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b5647d1dc81228e1f477c98d9decb17" label="box" type="box">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8d8542d3c5a90a52c5df75f4347fd105" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. King James II version of the bible. Grand Rapids, MI: Associated Publishers and Authos Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971 (on verso of t.p. second edition)</unitdate><container id="aspace_1838ac850101246f43eb5a579b05e255" label="box" type="box">26</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8edb79d538ddfe87780579316b303128" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. American standard bible text edition. Carol Stream, Ill.: Creation House, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_0602f62cddca3f200e845e130806cdfb" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a771c6ac53b1001691c77138f28f8aaf" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible old and new testaments in the King James version translated out of the original tongues and with previous translations diligently compared and revised self-pronouncing. Nashville: Camden: New York: Thomas Nelson, Publishers.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_ff1f78a1b7e8e589b4d8583987535627" label="box" type="box">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_66951fb5f7ec85a4243a140055d10e96" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible in four translations. King James version -- New American standard bible -- New English bible -- The Jerusalem bible. New York: Iversen-Norman Associates</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972 (also on Front of t.p. World-Wide Publications)</unitdate><container id="aspace_443507bd6d0162cefc3047fcf54cf6f1" label="box" type="box">41</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_babf1474753561698a2b230adb78ca3d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Living Bible Holman illustrated edition paraphrased with 550 full color illustrations including 53 maps and charts. Philadelphia: New York: A.J. Holman Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973">1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_ff4cf607c9a82a3b45fd2de3d340628c" label="box" type="box">24</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0a6c57aa591f13504bceb3561a47e40c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New American standard bible. Carol Stream, IL: Creation House, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973">1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_d4504dccc84e00380cfa186938868701" label="box" type="box">26</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_43a0d7ee56122a37b3de575d7820d1d9" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Special English-German edition The Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments and English text -- The Authorized King James Version German translation of Dr. Martin Luther with references and maps. Aylmer, Ontario and LaGrange, IN: Pathway Publishers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_503c8d788ccefe445b3fe9a57e8ad65a" label="box" type="box">18</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d11dc801e309d379cef5907ac0ea1390" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Bible in order all the writings which make up the bible, arranged in their chronological order according to the dates at which they were written, or edited into the form in which we know them; seen against the history of the times, as the bible provides it. With introductions and notes Edited by Joseph Rhymer Jerusalem bible version. London: Darton, Longman &amp; Todd</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_27bd457f7b31719b87960047b20737f1" label="box" type="box">52</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3e0a35de76c6d0957afa0e9d50e2f925" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Interlinear bible Hebrew/English. Jay P. Green, Sr. ed. Grand Rapids, MI: Baker Book House</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1983" type="inclusive">1976-1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_5dd5e8b4896f1e0d4688338c519d5109" label="box" type="box">22</container></did><c03 id="aspace_e53decedbe6b7842e8a4af80b2813a99" level="item"><did><unittitle>v. I Genesis - Ruth</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976">1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_2348b3b92fbdecee7c6ead2229d39a72" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_53ff259415ba9dde6378ae7fe99dd8b9" level="item"><did><unittitle>v. II Samuel - Psalm 55</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976">1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_4adef7a8cf31d309a2f3f103f8a3b6b5" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_1460ddca000c04959d34f7033d6fbf85" level="item"><did><unittitle>v. III Psalm 56 - Malachi</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1978">1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_05c270b8aa2cda356b7e7ebcefe94221" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_0b162c99ba793f36bda1c51a0e8b56cb" level="item"><did><unittitle>v. III Psalm 56 - Malachi</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_c5515744397a32a69f1488e51233dd57" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_21a68ab7310d0672d6487e8651a05a4b" level="item"><did><unittitle>v. IV New Testament</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_21a127539cdf3c4092713c3217e872ce" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_c5439ddab48213c8de1d61084d41d862" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New English bible with the Apocrypha Oxford study edition. Samuel Sandmel general editor... New York: Oxford University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976">1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_70eeff10c9f548d3ce1f597b91018540" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2cabd48cb3900eeabdd3141211961ad3" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New American bible translated from the original languages with critical use of all the ancient sources by members of the Catholic Biblical Association of America Sponsored by the Bishops' committee of the Confraternity of Christian Doctrine. Nashville, TN: Memorial Bibles International, Inc.Bible in cedar box.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976">1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_01b4bedb92400bfc3a32886c2a52e6d0" label="box" type="box">54</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c6454b231cba5c2e31a6fb4265ce80d0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments with the apocryphal/Deutercanonical books new revised standard edition. New York and Oxford: Oxford University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1977">1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_db7b275c6b9a5dfdf992f3ce7e560032" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3cdb16954a8ec13fc2b284c7a51a7c93" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Andrew's Holy Bible for the layman -- Dallas: B and B Foundations, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1977">1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_e3419a91d6746025db7b198da3469af6" label="box" type="box">37</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_112d480897ab5cbb85cf97f1d7409a34" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible new international version containing the old and new testaments. Grand Rapids, MI: Zondervan Bible Publishers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1978">1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_1012f50ea1e403f48a661a1d37360160" label="box" type="box">18</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f8f8e97e9039ddc8d39cb0dbd2501d67" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible the new King James version containing the old and new testaments. Carmel, N.Y.: Guideposts</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1982/1982">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_7b679833182ba3430948d9bea354eee0" label="box" type="box">26</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d0030fff21438d6d0b700098b05709b6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Reader's digest bible condensed from the revised standard version old and new testaments General editor Bruce M. Metzger... Pleasentville, N.Y., London, Montreal, Sydney, Cape Town, Hong Kong: Reader Digest Association</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1982/1982">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_83b4acf1a666a0ec1709368ecfa7f739" label="box" type="box">43</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_05a8c39df6fd194a85c8dc07f5fc5202" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. King James version The Reese chronological bible the authorized edition of the original work by Edward Reese. Minneapolis, MN: Bethany House Publishers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1982/1982">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_738ee97469c5d4c5b1ea12e16081c075" label="box" type="box">50</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_396b222dac0109ff7a8162665b8d47a2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Possibility thinkers bible. The new King James version positive verses for possibility thinking highlighted in blue. Nashville, Camden, New York: Thomas Nelson Publishers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_77a0a10ddad9e7386a0086a2228d48ef" label="box" type="box">48</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b1b9882c8109fad315e70d57c6d736c6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New world translation of the holy scriptures with references rendered from the original languages by the New World Bible Translation Committee -- revised 1984 -- Brooklyn, N.Y.: Watchtower Bible and Tract Society of New York Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1984/1984">1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_ca346e52d1f6ba511ce0e9c7d6c84bf3" label="box" type="box">48</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_574dab0be30cd636c0b7fb7231ac78f1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. St. Jerome edition the catholic study bible today's English version with Deutercanonicals/Apocrypha. Nashville: Camden: New York: Catholic Bible Press a division of Thomas Nelson Publishers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1985/1985">1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_b5beb41c0777c585284c21929c6cf668" label="box" type="box">26</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_bfe7b5bfa362dc523259acda1aef0fda" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New Jerusalem Bible. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday &amp; Company, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1985/1985">1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_eef01fb6bc6a26e1e564fdc777e868a7" label="box" type="box">52</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9925563bcca61449b11cd22965ea1944" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. New world translation of the Holy Scriptures rendered from the original languages by the new world translation committe -- revised 1984 -- Brooklyn, N.Y.: Watchtower Bible and Tract Society of New York, Inc. International Bible Students Association</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1986/1986">[1986]</unitdate><container id="aspace_824fe5daa1719cc88e3dc5d1b389a4b6" label="box" type="box">26</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9610cad052734c08b9ae93bc878e91ae" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible containing the old and new testaments translated out of the original tongues: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his Majesty's special command authorized King James Version with explanatory notes and cross references to the standard works of the church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints. Salt Lake City: Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1987/1987">1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_0fb7f3dea541003937a32143961572e7" label="box" type="box">18</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fa4555c67c56684dd0e641cc595abb77" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Webster bible. Grand Rapids, MI, Baker Book House</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1987/1987">1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_90cbc07965b5f501bb34e01258f0a2a4" label="box" type="box">50</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_afb0f5f6f9b1a1e2a483036b0da2d560" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible international children's bible new century version. Dallas, London, Sydney, Singapore: Word Publishing</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1988/1988">1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_625870d49a53dd7fff06f4088fd36344" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_36280c01b1176ced7955dc3cb519771f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Everyday Bible New Century Version clearly translated for life. Carmel, N.Y.: Guideposts</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1988/1988">1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_90b2d9d74a5f18470cee9bccbccd77e6" label="box" type="box">24</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b6d14999868a681db15f702de75b8fe4" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Catholic one year bible arranged in 365 daily readings the living bible a thought-for-thought translation with Deuterocanonical Books. Wheaton, IL: Tyndale House Publishers, Inc., and Huntington, IN: Our Sunday Visitor Publishing Division</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1988/1988">1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_13bd67da7e92eeaba3c44a752d194958" label="box" type="box">35</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0e2b05f2e240cbaafaa157bfa2308a55" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Holy Bible contemporary English version. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995">1995</unitdate><container id="aspace_3aaa2a2a5da0fc4957dea5e3e5c1cb24" label="box" type="box">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2cc752af2a628deaf612fbc51ef0d1ad" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Selections. Stepping stones -- the complete bible narratives brought together chronologically in the text of the King James version edited and arranged by John Thomas Clark. New York: Grosset &amp; Dunlap</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_241db809e10741d54c3c0aa57401e9cd" label="box" type="box">42</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5e0c0de5b850cb3ca759129251ffe4e1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. Selections. Reader's bible a narrative selections from the King James version edited with an introduction and ntoes by Roland Mushat Frye. Princeton: Princeton University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_090f698889acf972403fc785f0c7c77c" label="box" type="box">42</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_bb5726fdf89bfa418b4b0c34e901fd8a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T.? (Beginning of title in Greek) ... vetus testamentum, ex versione septuaginta interpretum. Juxta exemplar vaticanum, ex editione holmesh et Lamberti Bos. Tom .I Glasguæ : Ex Prelo Academico; Impenis Rivingtons &amp; Cochran, Longman, Hurst &amp; Soc., G. &amp; W. B. Whittaker, R. Priestley, Et. G. Cowie &amp; Soc., Londini : Bell &amp; Bradfute, Et. A. Black, Edinburgi</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1822/1822">1822</unitdate><container id="aspace_519ffc9ae6a94996a0344d8f2ba04673" label="box" type="box">31</container></did><c03 id="aspace_c2059f2fac59e6f067df06aeabbe702d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Tom. I</unittitle><container id="aspace_4cd240bd1ef74f77970ee8d5123e4d36" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_863be8a719a0199e73fd346e21941353" level="item"><did><unittitle>Tom. II</unittitle><container id="aspace_660c4b50685a26e7887d9a57324a0d68" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_c6358617761110e1e3640d6eeccecce1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Collateral Bible; or, A key to the Holy Scriptures: in which all the corresponding texts are brought together in one view, and arranged in a familiar and easy manner. Philadelphia, John Lavel and Samuel F. Bradford</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1826/1829" type="inclusive">1826-1829</unitdate><container id="aspace_f7330f1936974a25cb6a37640b481db2" label="box" type="box">2</container></did><c03 id="aspace_f667f03f99dc61df38f8b35502afeacf" level="item"><did><unittitle>v.II, pt.I whole number 5;-- in paper wrappers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1827/1827">1827</unitdate><container id="aspace_33f688c15922c521feb12deda7cbc9d0" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_c7e5b40f4e444ec5a753ea86e33c4daa" level="item"><did><unittitle>v.II, pt.III? whole number 7;-- in paper wrappers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1828/1828">1828</unitdate><container id="aspace_9387eea39e4df54b50df39967c29292a" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_52379f9c05bd138f480bcb778d4085b6" level="item"><did><unittitle>v.II, pt.IV whole number 8;-- in paper wrappers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1828/1828">1828</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3f3a522ee3d60fb9e3c614a59eeecbf" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_64538e5fe049f3bce0c8419dce00d5e2" level="item"><did><unittitle>v.III, pt.II whole number 11 -- in paper wrappers</unittitle><container id="aspace_1b4aa70f0fff427aac6a4cdb55aa364e" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_0bed12761b593a1793f0e4d01402c86f" level="item"><did><unittitle>v.III, pt.? bottom of wrapper gone</unittitle><container id="aspace_08a61d631c25dca79be72933ee843625" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_8c2a839f002388f9428b5d74df1bc0da" level="item"><did><unittitle>[v.1?] Philadelphia, Samuel F. Bradford-- bound</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1826/1826">1826</unitdate><container id="aspace_230dd025f6847c6170e77f96e132faf5" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_b1a86f67d5d3f37735f3bbac58344706" level="item"><did><unittitle>v.III; -- bound</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1828/1828">1828</unitdate><container id="aspace_c6f850a26703ec8a0377ccb2e143b56f" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_00ed73567fcb4834f33632f143deb5dd" level="item"><did><unittitle>[?] no t.p. -- bound</unittitle><container id="aspace_65182d6b8c0070485c18c88e6a505e15" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_e62ef8ae4268dc447e67b0ca2d0efc0c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Old testament, arranged in historical and chronological order, (on the basis of Lightfoot's chronicle) in such a manner, that the books, chapters, psalms, prophecies, &amp;c. &amp;c. may be read as one connected history, in the words of the authorized translation. With notes and copious indexes. By the Rev. George Townsent, M.A. ... Boston: Perkins and Marvin and Philadelphia: Henry Perkins</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1838/1838">1838</unitdate><container id="aspace_9552d37bb5cfd11a438d1997435d9e1f" label="box" type="box">50</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_12f9beae3f8ab318bcf5d13cb417b678" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. (lacks title page from Genesis to Job) [S.l.: s.n.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1850/1850">1850-?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_e9eb7e122504f898badd683fc0b8e311" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0866fa0f98813cbc2d284f7bd0ccf47c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Old Testament a new translation by James Moffatt D.D., D.Litt., M.A. (Oxon) Vol.I Genesis - Esther. London: Hodder and Stoughton</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1923/1923">[1923] (Date from note by Hodge)</unitdate><container id="aspace_c59805c1f1ab9d2e53d712f8339ee154" label="box" type="box">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8f234ad2a1436f3ed0b52c19d6b083f4" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Old testament a new translation by James Moffatt D.D., D.Litt., M.A. (Oxon) Vol.II Job - Malachi. London: Hodder and Stoughton</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1924/1924">[1924] (Date from note by Hodge)</unitdate><container id="aspace_9fd36114918e3aa2a9fb5724db8c7d81" label="box" type="box">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3836c128d1d8b5f750f5fcb136745264" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Old testament an American translation by Alexander R. Gordon, Theophile J. Meek, J.M. Powis Smith, Leroy Waterman Edited by J.M. Powis Smith. Chicago: University of Chicago Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d3b3eea18571250b52678d7ff98d378" label="box" type="box">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a6d03dbd38532f278e27899bbd5d847f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Holy Bible the old testament Volume I, Genesis - Nehemiah revised standard version translated from the original tongues being the version set forth A.D. 1611 ... Toronto: New York: Edinburgh: Thomas Nelson &amp; Sons</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1ff303c06654ee4549dc3361ffd757b" label="box" type="box">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_29a8294eebd143e2d6c4adfb2bf1cf64" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Holy Bible the old testament Volume II, Esther - Malachi revised standard version translated from the original tongues being the version set forth A.D. 1611 ... Toronto: New York: Edinburg: Thomas Nelson &amp; Sons</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a6a74990fb815d3bd70c8be16959d32" label="box" type="box">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ee2aa9ae8ce688b53f5fcdfd20033fec" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Old testament authorized catholic edition abridged from the holy bible sponsored by the Episcopal Committee of the Confraternity of Chritian Doctrine ... New York: Guild Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_f2edb59beaad272cb9231d0076e98c11" label="box" type="box">42</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_63fae6375e0356f98c1f628a9e9e243b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Old testament complete with annotations by Rev. Joseph A. Grispino, S.M., S.S.L. The text is the new translation sponsored by the Episcopal Committee of the Confraternity of Christian Doctrine for the books Genesis to Ruth, Job to Sirach, ... New York: Guild Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_d4e374e0afb7a979e13ece37adc865f8" label="box" type="box">26</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_28a4a6aa30bb5caaf1cb0a0d5fa148d3" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Old testament of the Jerusalem Bible. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday &amp; Company, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_9df96ddf7c05aaaa28e41be3e6fe9a24" label="box" type="box">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4c8ca2f2b0c15f111e290ad2f2f5a657" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. New English bible the Apocrypha. Lower half of t.p. missing. On verso of t.p. Delegates of the Oxford University Press and the Syndics of the Cambridge University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_f343fb77c496f9a45a57a1de54828075" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_25db236b458ca3917e34086329218d78" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. (Beg. of t.p. is in Hebrew) Biblia Hebraica Stuttgartensia quae antea cooperantibus A.Alt, O. Eißfeldt, P. Kahle ediderat R. Kittel Editio funditus renovata ... Stuttgart : Deutsche Biblegesellschaft</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1977" type="inclusive">1976/77</unitdate><container id="aspace_1739337339ffcf92df7d4a0228c177e0" label="box" type="box">41</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_667c8f2f085356e89b9152e03d82bd61" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Good news bible today's English version old testament. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1978/1978">1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_13022ed9c0d6030941e7f8c08eb52171" label="box" type="box">52</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6186570b4f54017b43ce490851e3eae5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Konkordanz zum Hebraischen alten testament nach dem von Paul Kahle in der Biblia Hebraica edidit Rudolf Kittel besorgten Masoretischen Text ... Zweite Auflage. Stuttgart : Deutsche Bibelgesllschaft</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1981">1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_4afcc48f924d99e241701c76aba01f42" label="box" type="box">42</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3b28608508999afedc5e150d6fd245a2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Genesis. First book of Moses called Genesis. Yellow Springs: OH: Kahoe and company(no. 29 of 950).</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1929/1929">1929</unitdate><container id="aspace_e9c7dccc691495e33c1dbe626e6c0cc6" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8b4cf2cfdc361482c90330b8b06554b7" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Genesis. Book of Beginnings a new translation of the Book of Genesis with special attention to its poetic values. By Alexander Marlowe. Grand Rapids, MI: Wm. B. Eerdmans Publishing Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_6a869e8a6ab754becbdfcd9ae589674f" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7b18795432ca78956694e864272a0ab2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Genesis. Path through Genesis by Bruce Vawter, C.M. New York: Sheed &amp; Ward</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_6c29e8ae198d3ce0f05891c4e60ad4b5" label="box" type="box">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d2c7e6d6424681b1f4e1458148cf0230" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Genesis. In the Beginning a new English rendition of the book of Genesis translated with commentary and notes by Everett Fox. New York: Schocken Books</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_a567cb8ce6ac96fb2cb84f38db4424a4" label="box" type="box">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_274bc50c40412dc2313a3d75e0609b29" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Exodus. Now these are the names a new English rendition of the Book of Exodus translated with commentary and notes by Everett Fox. New York: Schocken Books</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1986/1986">1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_8715d21c9bb9c8f19488b4f11bb96d25" label="box" type="box">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ec8ca19cec6c969e54ca2ef0e9fbf8ec" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Samuel I. &amp; II. Books of I. &amp; II. Samuel, translated out of the original Hebrew: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his Majesty's special command. Oxford: Printed at the University Press for the British and Foreign Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1896/1896">1896</unitdate><container id="aspace_de2546d1b5af020da555992f23979a47" label="box" type="box">52</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8b71386e84d33870f0eb3b5553dedf86" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Kings I &amp; II. Books of I. &amp; II. Kings, translated out of the original Hebrew: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his Majesty's special command. Oxford: Printed at the University Press for the British and Foreign Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1896/1896">1896</unitdate><container id="aspace_e73014485c0b068eb183cc6d9d2b2978" label="box" type="box">52</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_893811ae503de5eec9eb3f653bc15770" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Psalms. Psalms in modern speech and rhythmical form by John mcFadyen, D.D. ... Third edition. London: James Clarke &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1917/1945" type="inclusive">[1917-1945?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_6e9397b65dc8dd1a01eeb8114b40152f" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4ec8497fa22a6ea80d930060b960106c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Psalms. Psalms for the modern man today's English version. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_11f1735430f6369d03d25b2c20771031" label="box" type="box">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e9844e07a9f403c30681ba290a611f73" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Song of Solomon. Song of songs translated from the original Hebrew with an introduction and explanations by Hugh J. Schonfield, D.S. LITT. [S.l.]: New American Library</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_93c4f46efd4794723ee0593d23952f10" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a8e14442ea2fa568ff0a3b4f82a09082" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Proverbs. Proverbs. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1900/1980" type="inclusive">[1900-1980?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_e6553dfa603c6ec25b68af70a8b8cc11" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_715ef6fda5d95dd7bcaedcd07ebee2c7" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Ecclesiastes. Ecclesiastes with an essay by Irwin Edman. New York: Odyssey Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_70d7df914d4691f39ca131ac17a25dd6" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_140e47c9ff6b3704f8d5a99ff7052491" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Isaiah. Isaiah in modern speech by John Edgar McFadyen, D.D. ... second impression. London: James Clarke &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1918/1918">[1918]</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a09830627f2993a64cfc93e00c85687" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_738218bcf69e147c85feba29a81adf0e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Isaiah. Book of the prophet Isaiah, translated out of the original Hebrew; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his majesty's special command. London: British and Foreign Bible Society printed at the Cambridge University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1920/1920">1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ec7143ec2d67c70842423ad1effcd47" label="box" type="box">52</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9436885c2bd6cf0d97968a1f674b0da9" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Isaiah. Book of Isaiah from the new international version. Grand Rapids, MI: Zondervan Bible Publishers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_6951d883eaefcd8ac01754c328859a3d" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6cbca9d6faead02ac048e97f442cca65" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. O.T. Jeremiah and Lamentations. Book of Jeremiah including the Lamentations with fifteen drawings in black and white by William Saphier. New York: Privately Printed by Nicholas BrownReview copy of 975 printed.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1921/1921">1921</unitdate><container id="aspace_cede0a0a1576f545e883c60aef6e75c9" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7b9d016ce56b1c65000d8af3c335afe1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. (Beg. of title page in Greek) ... Novum Testamentum Graece ex recenione Jo. Jac. Greisbachii cum selecta lectionum varietate. Tomus Primus. Lipsiae : Sumtibus G.J. Cöschen[Lacking both covers]</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1805/1805">1805</unitdate><container id="aspace_102bd872fb35fd52e480bb2cb8275bde" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ae6f762ceee5b974760ae221f311ece0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Bible. Neue testament unser Herrn und Heilandes Jesu Christi, nach der deutschen uebersetzung D. Martin Luthers. Mit kurzen inhalt eines jeden capitels, und ... Fünfte Auflage. Germantaun : Michael Billmener</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1808/1808">1808</unitdate><container id="aspace_eab0458c5d2f66366f0c2fd054cb9fd8" label="box" type="box">29</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9e7cd01b4c6aae4f14b6a9ae8d9e0cfb" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: Translated out of the original Greek, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. London: Stereotyped for the Bible Society at Philadelphia by T. Rutt2 copies.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1812/1812">1812</unitdate><container id="aspace_68b8f543a57d22cc836cce542994f1f8" label="box" type="box">15</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ba010acb9eebf576a30aa0e1433ab7d7" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, Newly Translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: Mathew Carey</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1813/1813">1813</unitdate><container id="aspace_8990d4e82f6d9fcd46fbfd04cb3a548a" label="box" type="box">14</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_eb41bf850fcf60b7d7ed661b72045737" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Novum testamentum domini nostri Jesu Christi, ob frequentes omnium interpretationum hallucinations, nunc demum ex codice Alexandrino, adhibitis etiam compulribus mss. Variantibusque lectionibus editis, summa fide ac cura Latine Redditum. ... Londini : Typis Schulze et Dean, Prostat apud J. Bohn</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1817/1817">1817</unitdate><container id="aspace_6fbaae55c6a54185d803622de7b6e841" label="box" type="box">38</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f817f7310cf5a638171d4cb3ceba29ad" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Apocryphal New Testament, being all the Gospels, Epistles, and other pieces now extant, attributed in the first four centuries to Jesus Christ, his apostles, and their companions, and not included in the New Testament by its compilers. translated from the original tongues, and now first collected into one volume. London: Printed for William Hone</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1820/1820">1820</unitdate><container id="aspace_5c275803c15faf9181e54e7f304f3571" label="box" type="box">38</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7f0eaf9cbd431d954d242fe820a0a8bf" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. (Beg. of title page in Greek. Title page is also torn) ... Greek according to Griesbach; the English upon the basis of the fourth London edition of the improved Version, with an attempt to further improvement from the translations of Campbell, Wakefield, Scarlett, Macknight and Thomoson. In two volumes. By Abner Kneeland, ... Vol. II. Philadelphia: Published by the Editor, no. 31 ... William Fry, Printer</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1823/1823">1823</unitdate><container id="aspace_1eb2d65787bd1f35c8d131cd0be0c913" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5bb0d43cd2d22f56bacc36170a3aec9d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, Newly Translated out of the original Greek, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: Samuel Wood and Sons and Samuel S. Woods &amp; Co. in Baltimore</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1825/1825">1825</unitdate><container id="aspace_7a89869a3278e4dc35aa47e1a23f0f35" label="box" type="box">15</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_600dcd27593ddef64e933e9c9b2b4f1e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Scientia Biblica: containing the new testament, in the original tongue, with the English vulgate, and a copious and original collection of parallel passages, printed in words at length in three volumes. London: W. Booth</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1825/1825">1825</unitdate><container id="aspace_400dbf143ad57ad8111145ef1d4a0f5d" label="box" type="box">21</container></did><c03 id="aspace_4e9581655243356f3aca6acd22f3e0fd" level="item"><did><unittitle>v.1</unittitle><container id="aspace_16e44f565a3a1fba019dd83201c5e7bd" label="box" type="box">21</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_fb1e69e254d362b831a1234e4bb5563e" level="item"><did><unittitle>v.2</unittitle><container id="aspace_99298d3adf4f29e8f730d1c010acf6ac" label="box" type="box">21</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_fa9da68f609f010a8bce658b3b68c5da" level="item"><did><unittitle>v.3</unittitle><container id="aspace_d95f72b2cb9433d268031b1aa473ad57" label="box" type="box">21</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_8c45df380fdb9aac1764f3baedf3d57a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. (Beg. of title in Greek) ... Novum testamentum Graece. Recognovit atque insignioris lectionum varietatis et argumentorum notations subiunxit Gerog. Christian. Knappius. Tomus I complectens quatuor evangelia. Editio Quarta. Halis Saxonum : E. Libraria Orphanotrophei</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1829/1829">1829</unitdate><container id="aspace_e63c53100acfee921db5cab228dd82cc" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_67648d7bf252893efa6793ebf0e2c856" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: Printed and Published by William F. Geddes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1831/1831">1831</unitdate><container id="aspace_542b59d7b2bc52ae6fc8092cd1dcda04" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0be16636cd819849936e3bb096ad4102" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Clavis Novi Testamenti philological usibus scholarum et iuvenum theologiae studiosorum accommodata auctore Christiano Abrahamo Wahl, ... editio minor. Lipsiae: Joh. Ambrosium Barth</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1831/1831">1831</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0154c4302d5feb867917a2a24435695" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_af69295bce359f6b09b0bdc6495fcbda" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. (Beg. of title in Greek) ... novum testamentum, cum versione Latina Ariæ Montani, in quo tum selecti versiculi 1900, ... auctore Johanne Leusden, New York: Stereotyped by Hammond Wallis &amp; Co. Published by Collins &amp; Hannay(Spine title: Leusden's Gr. &amp; Lat. Testament).</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1831/1831">1831</unitdate><container id="aspace_f332c37145a471000a026c524ef5e4c4" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0835352e505bfaffa09ae18109fc62ec" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Novi testamenti libri historici Græce. Textui recepto appsitæ sunt lections griesbachianæ. Cum commentaries D. Christiani Theophili Kuinoel, ... Londini: Jos. Booker</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1835/1835">1835</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a3c5d46a417dae60a27df6632af69d9" label="box" type="box">21</container></did><c03 id="aspace_de944f54b5507c8714c1912b5462c2a6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Tomus 1</unittitle><container id="aspace_eef6a363b2537acf4491a8072c793e74" label="box" type="box">21</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_164167baf54f40ff3daee5d2d86b49d1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Tomus 2</unittitle><container id="aspace_e42c47a201644ea347747f260080449f" label="box" type="box">21</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_0f49a281da0ad9ea715059cefeb13a66" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: G.W. Mentz</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1836/1836">1836</unitdate><container id="aspace_ebf3336c897718acef4e65dbe77ce7ac" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_085971429e677dff2b38a8e06ff5552b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: Joseph McDowell</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1830/1839" type="inclusive">183? (date from note by Hodge)</unitdate><container id="aspace_98210c9578fbc2d51be71c3860828510" label="box" type="box">12</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_11689342f8a8071be4464a04dd85be57" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Novum testamentum Graece Post Ioh. Aug. Henr. Tittmannum Olim Prof. Lips. Ad Fidem Optimorum librorum secundis curis recognovit lectionumque varietatem notavit Augustus Hahn in Acad. Vratisl. Prof. Editio Americana stereotypa curante Edvardo Robinson, S.T.D. Neo-Eboraci: Sumtibus et typis Leavitt et Trow and Bostoniae: Apud Crocker et Brewster</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1835/1835">1835</unitdate><container id="aspace_351387de744319739b489b8397196edb" label="box" type="box">21</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_560b0be7c0f616fce0f9f9889f381f0f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Stereotype edition. New York: Stereotyped by A. Chandler for the American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1838/1838">1838</unitdate><container id="aspace_985bafbd89d682da75941b1c820ee06a" label="box" type="box">51</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_fca1ef0af0150f73f8d1f2b4081f0292" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Polyglott school testament the new testament of our lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: with the marginal readings, compendious annotations, and the copious references to parallel and illustrative passages. Keene, N.H.: J. &amp; J.W. Prentiss</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1840/1840">1840</unitdate><container id="aspace_cf02fcd2ae1ce6d9824279e6eb90b9f9" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_97d45caac0f9d040bde48822fec43403" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Philadelphia: Thomas Sutton</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1842/1842">1842</unitdate><container id="aspace_89a2ac10988864d00ddbeeba16e0c3ec" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9774a5842c64850ce4ab5aec283fd92e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society(Also in German parallel columns and a German t.p.)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1849/1849">1849</unitdate><container id="aspace_66c25d4f580994e1b88f965dde774397" label="box" type="box">40</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_95086db15647bc36bb92cb117328dc09" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ. Translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1850/1850">1850</unitdate><container id="aspace_4baeb03b6b441cb86baf41ea0f93ce82" label="box" type="box">54</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f93f8bcfa33e5f9bf3a2d879807fb377" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1854/1854">1854</unitdate><container id="aspace_01a5dfddacb631922149dc90d0c20c12" label="box" type="box">52</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c4fb4b9c763400eb0d807ee65dd1daf2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. (Beg. of title in Greek) Novum testamentum ad exemplar millianum, cum emendationibus et lectionibus Griesbachii, præcipuis vocibus ellipticis, thematibus ominum vocum difficiliorum, atque locis scripturæ parallelis. Studio et Labore Gulielmi Greenfield. ... Philadelphia: H.C. Peck &amp; Theo. Bliss.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1856/1856">[1856?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_b883f3dcb6ca29ba4a4d92999aa5c393" label="box" type="box">50</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c99ff88039d5db0c5c170495e3cf2e9b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1857/1857">1857</unitdate><container id="aspace_98897f205514971450871d847ca09518" label="box" type="box">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f02c4778afbc29667a19685f770779d6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ, translated out of the original Greek, and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible SocietyIn 4 vols. Only v.1 has t.p. rest of vols are continuously paged.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1857/1857">1857</unitdate><container id="aspace_c3a7894b8756efe708deb1369eeb6a0e" label="box" type="box">54</container></did><c03 id="aspace_ff9b0b9ae495eb917e632110c943ad85" level="item"><did><unittitle>1. St. Matthew - St. Mark p. 180</unittitle><container id="aspace_d3ee9ad8efde13ef07f29f585d8d46f8" label="box" type="box">54</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_61854558c276f2d82c9da9693f179067" level="item"><did><unittitle>2. St. Luke - St. John p. 181-382</unittitle><container id="aspace_5ac84e2cc9727d8e62b5b29d6e7705ba" label="box" type="box">54</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_65ee346902665a8f625443d0dc25c918" level="item"><did><unittitle>3. Acts I - I Corinthians p. 383-572</unittitle><container id="aspace_14fca7c23a3d6603d6f3b0236205c48c" label="box" type="box">54</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_bbe1f65f7f40abaae283ee9875756893" level="item"><did><unittitle>missing v. 4</unittitle><container id="aspace_75201b28f4645c8a102314676e414fee" label="box" type="box">54</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_d713b966af3275feee73e97528ccdeb6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ translated out of the original Greek: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1860/1860">1860</unitdate><container id="aspace_029195524045cfe1a9013c6781edc18f" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_93d44966b6e3008cf40f8e401d13dc7b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Savioiur Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1861/1861">1861</unitdate><container id="aspace_f68bed0423174045045f8a43cd3bcf22" label="box" type="box">54</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9b3b53c0a02d7584c35c72ae9e28de58" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament, from the family bible: with brief notes and instructions, designed to give the results of critical investigation. and to assist common readers to understand the meaning of the Holy Spirit in the inspired word. ... New York: American Tract Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1862/1862">1862</unitdate><container id="aspace_5050e6e29b57aa2938be7d6cd2de470a" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_05a73bb763acada1ce2c1d69a718315c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. (Beg. of title in Greek) ... nove testamentum Graece e codice vaticano edit Valentinus Lock, SS. Theologiae Doctor et Professor in Lyceo Amvergensi. Ratisbonae: Typis ac Sumptibus Georgh Joseph Manz</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1862/1862">1862</unitdate><container id="aspace_b61b7923e5e64928e7807c136655c370" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6e92b5dcf1bca0fd87d831edb2f8d7dc" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. (Beg. of title in Greek) ... novum testamentum, cum versione Latina Ariæ Montani, in quo tum selecti versiculi 1900, ... auctore Johanne Leusden, Philadelphia: J.B. Lippincott &amp; Co(Spine title: Leusden's Greek &amp; Latin Testament)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1863/1863">1863</unitdate><container id="aspace_470843c457f347dca3a4a3736b7b0c65" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_27a85fd0e12b91c29afdb5dd5260d7e1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1863/1863">1863</unitdate><container id="aspace_2be2c3b7ab70a55b25fa892dcf9ee1cd" label="box" type="box">54</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ecc32fd1f04db7d069c9f18782816060" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament: the authorized English version; with introduction, and various readings from the three most celebrated manuscripts of the original Greek text. by Constantine Tischendorf. Tauchnitz edition, volume 1000. Leipzig: Bernard Tauchnitz</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1869/1869">1869</unitdate><container id="aspace_5e7e712304a0bca6490c940e75e446e1" label="box" type="box">Box before 25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_283dd97a911ed7d6b3c6b4c86407ebb1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New testament: translated from the Greek text of Tischendorf, by George R. Noyes, D. D. ... Boston: American Unitarian Association</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1869/1869">1869</unitdate><container id="aspace_6e6d3e8982e777ea35a504d2d3eb6236" label="box" type="box">54</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d0ed88712389a2c7e89c0bb5d42d6960" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Neue Testament unsers herrn heilanders Jesu Christi, nach der Deutschen uebersetzung Doctor Martin Luthers. Mit kurzen inhalt eines jeden Capitels, ... Lancaster: Johann Bär's Göhnen</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1871/1871">1871</unitdate><container id="aspace_b11ee175c2b9c6d17de5b9853f134223" label="box" type="box">40</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6d7bde51f687fda0f756d2e52edd2903" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New testament of our Lord and Savious Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible SocietyIn 4 vols. Only 1st vol has t.p. pages are continuously numbered.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1871/1871">1871</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f0446e9557e2cc5cbf169c721459be0" label="box" type="box">53</container></did><c03 id="aspace_609b878149d8ea2d5f3311466cdc5fd0" level="item"><did><unittitle>1. St. Matthew - St. Mark p. 180</unittitle><container id="aspace_f261d7d52927f625a4e6431501dafeb9" label="box" type="box">53</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_226d9c5d9ad0429876c4f5cdb8c7bda2" level="item"><did><unittitle>2. St. Luke - St. John p. 181-382 (2 copies)</unittitle><container id="aspace_b2b91c8e65d98f7a91a568bc1dc5def0" label="box" type="box">53</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_69ecb7ae959a6b40198df805b5ebef55" level="item"><did><unittitle>3. Acts I - II Corinthians p. 383-612</unittitle><container id="aspace_ca82bbf7b34bd044c7d75d4e51b8f41b" label="box" type="box">53</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_fbb5d5dd3da217cc2f336c7622bed906" level="item"><did><unittitle>4. Galatians I - Revelations p. 612-844</unittitle><container id="aspace_16638caf8faeac20523b884b6424bb89" label="box" type="box">53</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_c11952a53e45d4a3b8abbe3b2d8c913a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1886/1886">1886</unitdate><container id="aspace_4fdde71bb4757f41354f6aaecd52a4c9" label="box" type="box">52</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9c2ff8a059315248c50578a4eb31795d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1891/1891">1891</unitdate><container id="aspace_56e4544e70f6491df4d9ef21f6aac5db" label="box" type="box">51</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_11d5611559bb0a5d809ce14bfc4c9dac" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1891/1891">1891</unitdate><container id="aspace_f549435929ab460a250cb827f8ff0e03" label="box" type="box">53</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_924618734efbb8e0cedbfeab82122427" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1896/1896">1896</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b0f78c220f24ec2406935f0f71c689c" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_22cc243f64d5c56db6fafa6d39130ce3" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Potter's standard editions the new testament of our lord and saviour Jesus Christ translated out of the original Greek and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. Chicago: Thompson &amp; Thomas</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1905/1905">[ca. 1905]</unitdate><container id="aspace_1f61cfec576394cee587b73f9a668928" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_657d4d5c9ed87ce81fc8ae8bc47f9cde" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament narrative in the words of the sacred writers translated according to the vulgate with notes, maps, chronological and other tables. Eighteenth edition. London: St. Anselm's Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1912/1912">1912</unitdate><container id="aspace_47f1588fa26ba5c9d87c77bc948ebb16" label="box" type="box">37</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_edbcb48c7d312a71c16990a6a79086af" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament a new translation by James Moffatt D.D., D. Litt. Yates professor of new testament Greek and Exegesis, Mansfield College, Oxford. New York: Hodder and Stoughton and George H. Doran Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1913/1913">[1913?] (Date from a note by Hodge)</unitdate><container id="aspace_7118883b0c3298b64d20f8549275bcd2" label="box" type="box">26</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_41bd95341011de238e431ef3b884837f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New testament a new translation by James Moffatt, D.D., Litt., M.A. (Oxon) together with the authorized version parallel edition with introduction. New York and London: Harper &amp; Brothers, Publishers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1922/1922">1922</unitdate><container id="aspace_2b3337564c9f15e7a6b6b167b77fee5c" label="box" type="box">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_bfed484a5c7db9c2e801c6ec7c248c09" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Shorter Bible the New Testament translated and arranged by Charles Foster Kent ... Third edition, revised. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1922/1922">1922</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e91074b2d64d78c75cb1b2973fa6947" label="box" type="box">37</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a0659c5f32948a6c90d024180dc1651e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1924/1924">1924 (date printed, and note by Hodge)</unitdate><container id="aspace_3cc4be25d236594fbec3abe5410fdb20" label="box" type="box">51</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8120867a527a9ff2f3af9aaca3f52994" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New covenant commonly called the new testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ translated out of the Greek being the version set forth A.D. 1611 compared with the most ancient authorities and revised A.D. 1881 newly edited by the new testament members of the American revision committee A.D. 1900 standard edition. New York: Thomas Nelson &amp; Sons</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1929/1929">1929</unitdate><container id="aspace_121fe7170d05913c2e6daa259962ce9b" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_88ac405837029a18adf1af912044be3e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ translated from the Latin Vulgate, ... and first published by the English College at Rheims, A.D. 1582 with annotations, references and an historical and chronological index. New York: Cincinnati: Chicago: San Francisco: Benziger Brothers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1931/1931">1931</unitdate><container id="aspace_d27b9705034f0b4d91ad7627d5b13549" label="box" type="box">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_aa6429e90b0a0ff1ebbafbb612711793" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Layman's New Testament being the Rheims text as first revised by Bishop Challoner edited with introduction &amp; notes by Father Hugh Pope, O.P., S.T.M., D.S.S. New York: Sheed &amp; Ward Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1934/1934">1934</unitdate><container id="aspace_04986b5c0a5575b835675fe297d0be3e" label="box" type="box">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_61bfd97452ffb02ac376300909bdc004" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. National edition of the new testament of our lord and Saviour Jesus Christ conformable to the edition of 1611 commonly known as the authorized or King James version. Philadelphia: National Bible Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1941/1941">1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_a2d468d38c90395cc2a1d2672617b380" label="box" type="box">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_81d25803b05e48a656a7a015f946d8bd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. National edition the new testament of our lord and Saviour Jesus Christ conformable to the edition of 1611 commonly known as the authorized or King James version. Philadelphia: Gideons by the National Bible Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1943/1943">1943</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f4713dca86c34e1fe96eb46d9c63f95" label="box" type="box">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0285bcce9aff313d16526d7a6b897b0f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ translated into English from the original Greek by the very rev. Francis Aloysius Spencer, O.P. Edited by Charles J. Callan, O.P. and John A. McHugh O.P. New York: Macmillan Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_934ea1a991e30d4a3604b2c018d20faa" label="box" type="box">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3456107e903d4ee587891280c9d2cb49" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament an American translation by Edgar J. Goodspeed. Chicago: University of Chicago Press(21st impression)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1946/1946">1946</unitdate><container id="aspace_4eb4dc28f4e2b9019c624408ddadcc13" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_12f91f0036ea29f813cd1476f67ba872" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament and American translation by Edgar J. Goodspeed. Chicago: University of Chicago Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1948/1948">1948</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3d74123bf394000d1ac40b037fe5da6" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cc311f8c7e368c6cea0379b01fb067cb" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament a translation in the language of the people by Charles B. William. Chicago: Moody Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_192c451e62d95776fd6f744d288414eb" label="box" type="box">25</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8193cb9bc34e121d9cfe7a712e6d454b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Saviour Jesus Christ in eight 32-page portions, with over 500 illustrations and with 14 maps. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1953/1953">[1953]</unitdate><container id="aspace_234fb975ccc26c64f55bb41dc91654e4" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_60515683d289cbbc379ae83274e03d08" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. National edition the new testament of our lord and Saviour Jesus Christ conformable to the edition of 1611 commonly known as the authorized or King James version. Philadelphia: Gideons by the National Bible Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_3dec670724ad06becc1080c897423123" label="box" type="box">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_95eabe5af2416171df9de35e57fc54bf" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New English bible New Testament. Cambridge: Oxford University Press and Cambridge University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_b1fd18ffa50205838e89cccd6b3b3d98" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1ed3af710350980ae35faa23ddbe68bd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New English bible New Testament. S.l.: Oxford University Press and Cambridge University Press(Printed in the United States of America).</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_1e8c59580506b2e60e10d18ff1f35eab" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cf35331f0b19adbc76be8a801fc84bd0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ Holy Land edition The words of our Lord printed in red ... New York: C. Wilderman Co., Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_d18a440f7361151c18d51e9a773ac254" label="box" type="box">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7120a672ca39351d0ad556d5478e327f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Children's 'King James' Bible new testament. Evansville, IN: Modern Bible Translations, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_14d4d489276554e26a847d322c59587b" label="box" type="box">37</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ff2f8f4397e3a37ae1dca86ab8d5d300" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of our Lord and Savior Jesus Christ revised standard version with pictures. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">[1963]</unitdate><container id="aspace_274d060a1002b50d5e0f9a077e0a4223" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_58fbc7d61ae04f320254116104af9014" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New English bible New Testament second edition. S.l.: Oxford University Press and Cambridge University Press(Printed in the United States of America)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_051f462e5e21fa1f8001c47bb423e550" label="box" type="box">6</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_78c6c115ad3f84a42b66410050d889ac" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Saint Joseph edition of the New Testament of the new American Bible the New Testament translated from the original languages with critical use of all the ancient sources by members of the Catholic Bible Association of America ... New York: Catholic Book Publishing Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_cacde553ff163558a268df64da2cc30b" label="box" type="box">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3c6d8c8689ff0b3cddcbfdbe22242bec" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Simple English Bible New Testament American edition. New York: International Bible Publishing Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1981">1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_e141650ce4a3278011230cf0cdc4d78f" label="box" type="box">30</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ed11bae747c7602cae47cacb681b3f8b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New testament of our lord and Saviour Jesus Christ with Psalms and Proverbs translated out of the original tongues and with the former translations diligently compared commonly known as the authorized (King James) version. S.l.: Gideons International</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1982/1982">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_5b795c59a9562d3c9fa172d89d9deb72" label="box" type="box">11</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f06ae2d9bae3ddc53d71e48d9663a3f1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Gospels. Greek. Harmonies. 1885. [Harmony of the four gospels in Greek. Newly arranged, with explanatory notes, by Edward Robinson. Revised edition, ... additional notes by M.B. Riddle. Boston, New York: Houghton Mifflin(t.p. is missing. Information from OCLC)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1885/1885">[1885]]</unitdate><container id="aspace_c2aa887c31a23ed91d496d62b11c19f0" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_72c71747d98a30750551c084654e93b2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Gospels. Harmonies. 1958. Knox. Gospel story: based on the translation of the four Gospels by Ronald Knox, arranged in a continuous narrative with explanations by Ronald Cox. New York: Sheed and Ward</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">[1958]</unitdate><container id="aspace_46af93c2fdf4184848b37e4b3031cd01" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_211b5939fcedeb90ff421809592cde78" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. New Testament of the Jerusalem Bible. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday &amp; Company, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_29f20b4f7ff56f14cf32cc97801d5e9e" label="box" type="box">23</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6a6053dfab65bd72478707ee55fb8f86" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Greek-English New testament. Third Printing. Washington, D.C.: Christianity Today</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976">1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3d40cfaba4099501fcba2233291cfb8" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_94e2a89ca9c13aaab9d1d57f6ea38cdf" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Original New Testament Edited and translated from the Greek by the Jewish historian of Christian beginnings Hugh J. Schonfield. San Francisco: Harper &amp; Row, (Cambridge, Hagerstown, New York, Philadelphia, London, Mexico City, Sao Paulo, Singapore, Sydney)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1985/1985">1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_112212ac49bb07e74391033a79096f29" label="box" type="box">32</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_691a4c7545d6efc0aff883174799a326" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Matthew. Gospel according to Saint Matthew: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1897/1897">1897</unitdate><container id="aspace_d3f183459e1c483df6dfc1484dd07be7" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2174347cf0ce3ae3007620fc3ecd15da" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Matthew. Gospel according to St. Matthew: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1910/1910">[1910]</unitdate><container id="aspace_65226d0cec56f14fb6b0ac04ff751c5b" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c3a01d7c7d22a70322d5d59d6bf2474e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Matthew. New testament {text in Hebrew} containing the record of the new covenant with the House of Israel and the House of Judah. Revised by the revision committee of the Hebrew Christian Alliance. Chicago: Hebrew Christian Alliance of America</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_814b30c26bee9eb1e6f80f9a781ce537" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f9d13f37e7ddadb2a0aced8fc03391ce" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Mark. Gospel according to Saint Mark: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1910/1910">1910</unitdate><container id="aspace_c15e9b1e62feac83eaac2d630e08cb58" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_86bab8bfaadad3456fb97ff222e53262" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Mark. Gospel of St. Mark a new translation in simple English from the Nestlé Greek text by Edward Vernon. New York: Prentice-Hall, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1952/1952">1952</unitdate><container id="aspace_738f855fd7dc3a75e98d681e77083a77" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ad6a4bfb29212d47fec34c90c2b0b329" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Luke. Gospel according to Saint Luke: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. By his majesty's special command. Appointed to be read in churches. London: British and Foreign Bible Society printed by Eyre and Spottiswoode</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1920/1929" type="inclusive">[ca. 1920s?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_dd81512c3c48c95db765b212a1a092f3" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2e945927ed63b7576b048377547b4792" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. John. Gospel according to Saint John: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1885/1885">1885</unitdate><container id="aspace_8ebd2d3d30b2495b3e9620b5c6027832" label="box" type="box">53</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_76f35c463aee988d8f540f216ef88fe7" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. John. Emphasized gospel of John. Sixth million. Framingham, MA: Miss Elizabeth Merriam</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1920/1929" type="inclusive">[ca. 1920?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_cecdf4ec52731381b8e9d96001ff27f9" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_06589232c0afd089a2502ace76b0dce6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. John. Gospel according to Saint John. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">[1942?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_b9dff13a605f3244e65d4191544287a5" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_55d474b6b0b24faf57c3e22ba909cb62" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. John. Revelation of John. Translated by Richard Lattimore. New York: Harcourt, Brace &amp; World, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_58b52533bb50ebf5944a66eac875c058" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_11c4468d8beeaebfa7d1a95b4fb8e862" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. John. Gospel according to John the new international bible. Grand Rapids, MI: Zondervan Bible Publishers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973">1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_f90bda3b64f004408874ca24aa4b9e3c" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c473e7248dd6a4c635a638d0d7e72357" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Acts. Acts of the apostles: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1913/1913">[1913?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c8db40866d8b1989c15c6a2ff1e8ff2" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2001d1a4133c43671aa9ebcc047bf7cd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Acts. Acts of the apostles: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised. New York: American Bible Society Printed for Massachusetts Bible Society, Boston</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1913/1913">1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_9c446825759d8a0acceb283262c8bcc6" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5a2eb137209686ffe0c89d6509de767d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Acts of the apostles translated out of the original Greek: and with the former translations diligently compared and revised by his majesty's special command appointed to be read in churches. London: British Foreign Bible Society printed by Eyre and Spottiswoode, Ltd.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1920/1940" type="inclusive">[ca. 1920-1940?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_43fbc8330f2551d1c5a9bcc126b452c0" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0c97018e6cd2fbd9581e5a5701a8afd5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Acts. Good news in action the acts of the apostles from the new testament in today's English version. Third edition. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_d79c8e9470fc925467cc7ca7cb215a67" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8bb3e93830ade12c77d9302129a12d4e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible. N.T. Revelation of St. John the divine: translated out of the original Greek; and with the former translations diligently compared and revised, by his majesty's special command. Appointed to be read in churches. London: British Foreign Bible Society printed by Eyre and Spottiswoode</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1920/1929" type="inclusive">[ca. 1920s?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_6751b28811da53efdd0911af90c5aa8b" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f07a35de8ab2868e266a5ccff6c6b447" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bible of the sick from the French of Frederic Ozanam. New York: Christian Press Association Publishing Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1901/1901">1901</unitdate><container id="aspace_4986d2ba3d9df1d8b754ccd334592909" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_bd1d1ce448ef81ac9983d6af50f0333f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bílek, František. Chvála svaté lásky. Brno : "Zvlášstní vydání"</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_f1ef3065f445e9b4e482c36ca652a106" label="box" type="box">36</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b3350cae31fa88d4053a8bb9c6d9afb1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Book of proverbs from the authorized King James version with an introduction by Robert Gordis and decorations by Valenti Angelo. New York: Heritage Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_846059887e525723b7c10a9261153828" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e1b71bcc36c7950a82e54455bb21f69e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Brandt, Leslie F. Epistles / now. St. Louis: Concordia Publishing House</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1976">1976</unitdate><container id="aspace_615b2628921530af0ee037ae540d51d2" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7782a13939e29f8a52e57f71fcd1b706" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bread of life the gospel of John New King James version gospel notes for witnessing and Christian living. Bradenton, FL: Bible Alliance, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1982/1982">1982</unitdate><container id="aspace_d832b91fdb738d46b8127e5db1ab0d3a" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a92cdc9e234fdca41cd6bafdf33d881b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Burton, Ernest de Witt. and Edgar Johnson Goodspeed. Harmony of the synoptic Gospels in Greek. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, c1920, ninth impression</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1945/1945">1945</unitdate><container id="aspace_5abd43fd5adc73e19a6e84b43572b3a0" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_289cc90df3c57f1c7c425b4b6a8aaf64" level="item"><did><unittitle>Burton, Ernest de Witt. and Edgar Johnson Goodspeed. Harmony of the synoptic Gospels in Greek. Chicago: University of Chicago Press, c1920 and 1947, fourteenth impression</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_9fbb12bc4e72409168e5bc24b4d618d9" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6ee17127a0e449b81f09109f8acf9182" level="item"><did><unittitle>Burton, Ernest de Witt. Records and letters of the Apostolic age the new testament Acts, Epistles, and Revelation in the version of 1881 arranged for historical study. Eleventh edition. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1909/1909">1909</unitdate><container id="aspace_9b3ce5cb7c7a14f75c83998fea58546e" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_c1c0cfe0fa1a8feae9b521db4cb16de3" level="file"><did><unittitle>C</unittitle><container id="aspace_2fc29a8a5ab1df99aab5778cb9f68ecf" label="box" type="box">55</container></did><c02 id="aspace_6add122ccbf20dff98ad891284a3bdf0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Cambridge history of the Bible the west from the reformation to the present day. Edited by S.L. Greenslade, F.B.A. Cambridge: University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_f3ab1f113b6e5ad2d60d8c405586eb58" label="box" type="box">28</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b68b210868818e910ea5cef5fcbc6923" level="item"><did><unittitle>Clark, George W. New harmony of the four gospels in English, according to the common version. Arranged with explanatory notes, brief description of customs, words, names, ... Philadelphia: American Baptist Publication Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1870/1870">1870 (entered as an act of congress 1870)</unitdate><container id="aspace_fce46cfadaa67dc9c8dbb981d75a23df" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d448b63363f9fc9c794ad1d6a32a1aad" level="item"><did><unittitle>Codex Alexandrinus (Royal Ms. 1 D v-viii) in reduced photographic facsimile Printed by order of the Trustees sold at the British Museum and ... Oxford: University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1915/1975" type="inclusive">1915-1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_5023e5a45887694e5c16e98315d2fa3d" label="box" type="box">29</container></did><c03 id="aspace_30b15dc71a71d8fd85c9d9989b9bc0b3" level="item"><did><unittitle>Old testament part I Genesis - Ruth</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1915/1915">1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_eb7e547b08b78c54e795bd1c42749e20" label="box" type="box">29</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_cc58a66f169a09695ba825de3054afd2" level="item"><did><unittitle>Old testament part II 1 Samuel - 2 Chronicles</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1930/1930">1930</unitdate><container id="aspace_5b2fcb8394f79a46126ace0bd4724137" label="box" type="box">29</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_d018587b3580aace60df978d652fe797" level="item"><did><unittitle>Old testament part III Hosea - Judith</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1936/1936">1936</unitdate><container id="aspace_cad840c6dc0a2f4d23d5137a9a6ac179" label="box" type="box">29</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_db860c1748b8d0553c5a35c68ba90da6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Old testament part IV I Esdras - Ecclesiasticus</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1957">1957</unitdate><container id="aspace_ab526a16320151f187583d86abcd2133" label="box" type="box">29</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_4c4bf81d72e84bcccd679b547b9d4cf8" level="item"><did><unittitle>Cohen, Mortimer J. Pathways through the bible. Philadelphia: Jewish Publication Society of America</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_27081374ff3611d4eb86319d3d817162" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5d0519136fee315e6ae202732423ee98" level="item"><did><unittitle>Combined Gospels of Matthew, Mark, Luke and John. Russell Hubbard White, comp., arr., publ. Boston: Russell Hubbard White2 copies: 1 gilt edges; 2 dj &amp; red edges.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1947">1947</unitdate><container id="aspace_8562b4378b03e39f682d8f6e02ce0550" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0de720faa52f7ecc5d24939d31f61d15" level="item"><did><unittitle>Complete sayings of Jesus the King James version of Christ's own words without interpolations and divested of the context, ... assembled and arranged in sequence by Arthur Hinds ... Philadelphia and Toronto: John C. Winston Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1955/1955">1955</unitdate><container id="aspace_25217a2e34308c6d7e05db15a3a9869c" label="box" type="box">37</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_83a7881e5743a7635b19a2e41e3490b0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Concise Gospel and the Acts. Christopher J. Christianson comp. Plainfield, N.J.: Logos International</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973">1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_9b7ba06bb15cce76bdf7c400767d335b" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d468073cd2ff5e8bc1d472104531a412" level="item"><did><unittitle>Copenhagen Haggadah Altona-Hamburg, 1739 The artist: Uri Pheibush son of Isa Eisik Segal Facsimile edition introduction by Chaya Benjamin (title information from insert about the book, publisher information printed in book.) New York: Rizzoli International Publications</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1986/1986">1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_548ce8480bfbf716ab0bc74799112d64" label="box" type="box">29</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_230b03fdc1dce8f45dd04cbd45c65a4e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Coutler, Frederick R. Harmony of the gospels in modern English: The Life of Jesus Christ. Monterey, CA: York Publishing Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_8023e7e4426fcb530465a0f4c666835c" label="box" type="box">7</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_9a59cdf08295d2295504ae8da05570dd" level="file"><did><unittitle>D</unittitle><container id="aspace_3b61855e67e4bd7a9ef73469095f3faa" label="box" type="box">7</container></did><c02 id="aspace_92e770cc872b40e9b705f1796e8962d0" level="item"><did><unittitle>Dale, Alan T. Winding quest the heart of the old testament in plain English. New York: Morehouse-Barlow Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973">1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_36df1fb3699190eb9194035bc930a15d" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d60fbbf731d8b31b18975a9472e34203" level="item"><did><unittitle>Davidson, Benjamin. Analytical Hebrew and Chaldee lexicon. : Every word and inflection of the Hebrew old testament arranged alphabetically and with grammatical analysis ... Grand Rapids, MI: Regency Reference Library Zondervan Publishing House</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_1fa3c4a7e28fe3ce1e53074ed3a3a3ac" label="box" type="box">41</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_866485e2396b59a13cd8feb96c26ed10" level="item"><did><unittitle>De Vinck, José. Words of Jesus with key readings from new and old testaments translated from the Greek. Allendale, N.J.: Alleluia Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1977">1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_ed949f99918b21f2fa6742cb04408d0f" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_be1e447488c6ce2b49cf0d1c74355d48" level="item"><did><unittitle>Dictionary of the Targumim, the Talmud Babli and Yerushalmi, and the Midrashic literature compiled by Marcus Jastrow, Ph.D. Litt. D. with an index of scriptural quotations. Brooklyn, N.Y.: P. Shalom Pub, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1967">1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_0a4d5aec32bb14a9322326a185478282" label="box" type="box">41</container></did><c03 id="aspace_682a15f48894434b8dc6111f5c059278" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. I</unittitle><container id="aspace_649a5877180fccb1553d246cf7f9cdf2" label="box" type="box">41</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_d528e186d9fabe543483635cfbf83f3d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. II</unittitle><container id="aspace_92ba26310c9a1d4721189ec86cebb807" label="box" type="box">41</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_bba3d89cfa85020d17f1edc7dd26ebbb" level="item"><did><unittitle>E</unittitle><container id="aspace_7460a3f1961904410e8e3c37f123680f" label="box" type="box">41</container></did><c02 id="aspace_ef5eb6b94a65b6f1556d2c3e8e3ceec3" level="item"><did><unittitle>Elkins, R. William. Song of songs. New York: Washington: Hollywood: Toronto: Vintage Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_97a08a97c7174b769f02b96404dfff8b" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_29a6c087a43a803a5b97038b4a68c8f7" level="item"><did><unittitle>English harmony of the four evangelists, generally disposed after the manner of the Greek of William Newcome, archbishop of Armagh: ... Philadelphia: Published by Kimber and Conrad</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1809/1809">1809</unitdate><container id="aspace_97173f7db4d00f500f3df86301354960" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_72e2e510b6ec49565203961cabd6f50a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Epitome Historiæ Sacræ, auctore Lhomond. Editio nova prosodlæ signis vocumque interpretatione adornata. Baltimore: Printed and Published by Kelly, Hedian &amp; Piet</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1859/1859">1859</unitdate><container id="aspace_19dc99a3a9ae9d5cf8492c9aa378ed88" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_b0c6afedb0371d02638abafc50ed683e" level="file"><did><unittitle>E</unittitle><container id="aspace_d9253bcd8aca832b2137991b2c5cb675" label="box" type="box">56</container></did><c02 id="aspace_f425dee0b94c2298509d63e2df107346" level="item"><did><unittitle>Fitzmyer S.J., Joseph A. Wandering Aramean collected Aramaic essays. Ann Arbor, MI: Edwards Bros., Inc.(Series title on pg. across from t.p. Society of Biblical Literature Monograph series. ... No. 25)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1979/1979">1979</unitdate><container id="aspace_f4d8ead803732c1500cc8a7962c393ff" label="box" type="box">42</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ffd3e56c763a6e79ecd933526cf5332f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Four Gospels and the Acts of the Apostles in the authorized version. Oxford: Oxford University Press and London: Humphrey Milford</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1930/1930">[ca. 1930?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe3de3ea0162615517aa3981e39308e8" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_bb0737c9407d71648e2db6736260cfae" level="item"><did><unittitle>Four prophets Amos • Hosea • First Isaiah • Micah a modern translation from the Hebrew by J.B. Phillips. New York: Macmillan Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8573eb20bc38986cb60420ed46377cc" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_8990f6d265d30699fda04b6bd5f11399" level="item"><did><unittitle>G</unittitle><container id="aspace_ac8714a8cad1b5a20009aba7a2b510c2" label="box" type="box">55</container></did><c02 id="aspace_26a1bcef23a5130dea7effa573424e16" level="item"><did><unittitle>Genuine Epistles of the Apostolical fathers; St. Barnabas, St. Ignatius, St. Clement, St. Polycarp, the Shepherd of Hermas, and the martyrdoms of St. Ignatius and St. Polycarp, written by those who were present at their sufferings. ... First American from the third London edition. New York: Printed and Published by Southwick and Pelsue</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1810/1810">1810</unitdate><container id="aspace_b60e6fead8b5e2fc2703cf98258f5bfc" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_63c86743ae8a74efe381abbd85d134fa" level="item"><did><unittitle>Gill D.D., John. An exposition of the Old Testament: in which are recorded the origin of mankind, of the several nations of the world, and of the Jewish nation in particular: the lives of the patriarchs of Israel: ... in six volumes. Philadelphia: Printed by William W. Woodward</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1817/1817">1817</unitdate><container id="aspace_5a7504f681d6114234d182dfe765c5fe" label="box" type="box">24</container></did><c03 id="aspace_be9b25b416dc4d035d7111d6e9791ddc" level="item"><did><unittitle>v.1</unittitle><container id="aspace_4250c0223d4d7a45571a9970472ac791" label="box" type="box">24</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_7284a0b3f61b2245e6bc3768724e4d90" level="item"><did><unittitle>v.2</unittitle><container id="aspace_bace6829a09803049c2c4193ca6c4cf2" label="box" type="box">24</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_3730306b04fbb1b075cc16ea36f9403b" level="item"><did><unittitle>v.3</unittitle><container id="aspace_db8ab74e7a50fac6010a0beb3668ce44" label="box" type="box">24</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_60af79b73ac8c515615056c51cb79d37" level="item"><did><unittitle>God's Bible an epochal revelation sponsored by God's angels Part IV, Papers 120-196 The life and teachings of Jesus. [S.l.]: Pathways, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1995/1995">[1995?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7e33e393c62bdb4f582159c1b9e2d4b" label="box" type="box">30</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3785d1550de45ddfbdf40230b1b83a2e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Goodman, Philip. Hanukkah anthology. Philadelphia: Jerusalem: Jewish Publication Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1992/1992">1992</unitdate><container id="aspace_153d86be32dccb2d4bc13c96a61e238e" label="box" type="box">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b1d167d38bc01b81e2a7c2c96f1b3561" level="item"><did><unittitle>Gospel of Jesus Vicenza: Edizioni Istituto S. Gaetano</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_d1a07d439cda6e1319037a9d9cc0f348" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_4a0b161b91ced1cacc4e0562d7245d96" level="item"><did><unittitle>Gospel of Jesus Vicenza: Edizioni Istituto S. Gaetano</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_16475c17ef9342a2ea45072763ca1df2" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8d0714c794428c4df0aa426fea70d2fe" level="item"><did><unittitle>Gospel treasury and extraordinary harmony of the four evangelists. The text in the words of the authorized version, arranged according to Greswell's harmonia evangelica. with analytical introductions; scripture illustrations; notes, selected from the most approved commentators; practical reflections; ... compiled by Robert Mimpriss. Second edition. New York: Dodd &amp; Mead, Publishers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">[ca. 1965] (date from Hodge note in front cover, also at bottom of pg. vii)</unitdate><container id="aspace_e5f081e1e6947d0f3735d015da528edc" label="box" type="box">7</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a03414d759f68deb4b17fea01197386e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Gospels of Saint Matthew, Saint Mark, Saint Luke &amp; John together with the Acts of the apostles according to the authorized King James version with reproductions of religious paintings in the Samuel H. Kress collection arranged and printed by Richard Ellis for the Samuel H. Kress Foundation. New York: Samuel H. Kress Foundation</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_dfba7e971fb3808badbd8f0f21d5220d" label="box" type="box">29</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_dc431bccd4a59e95738cec0c8b5718fa" level="item"><did><unittitle>Green, William Henry. Higher criticism of the Pentateuch. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1902/1902">1902</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0073e6a18df5e2599d8d94cda784d78" label="box" type="box">28</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_6af25fb54d7cf4d8cf5f4aed43048bb7" level="file"><did><unittitle>H</unittitle><container id="aspace_3d96921346f7b3cfec76a23fa1d744ac" label="box" type="box">28</container></did><c02 id="aspace_60dba900e55e226c081d75ecd0415a10" level="item"><did><unittitle>Harper, William R. Hebrew word lists to accompany "Hebrew Vocabularies" Chicago: American Publication Society of Hebrew</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1884/1884">1884</unitdate><container id="aspace_de8954db884899572d001889479e3ab1" label="box" type="box">35</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_19fc33a93a91b5afd2414a002a488bdd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Heart of the Bible its promises. Cleveland, OH: Edwards &amp; Franklin Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_b969caf7fd455cb62a40e7456e1ee755" label="box" type="box">37</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_92c84441144f9e574ed9f97b851d443e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Heim, Ralph Daniel. Harmony of the Gospels for students. Philadelphia: Muhlenberg Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1947/1947">1947 (Third Printing)</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a51c121841e897d136ef357927edfc8" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5c4f8c248fd0f562280de61623d424ac" level="item"><did><unittitle>Hertz, Dr. Joseph H. Authorized daily prayer book revised edition Hebrew text, English translation with commentary and notes. New York: Bloch Publishing Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1959/1959">1959</unitdate><container id="aspace_9166c2ffc895ccd0f37295d792bbd98f" label="box" type="box">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_cddc53819a8205ee427703d69ab6b791" level="item"><did><unittitle>Hinkle, John Ray. Our salvation bible. [S.l.]: John Ray Hinkle</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1954">1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_2d8b2f0f0e75a9ccc92f3c2d0d47152c" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_25ef7ad1f76cb60dafeea5c4152db898" level="item"><did><unittitle>His great apostle the life and letters of Paul using the text of the American standard revised bible. Prepared by Sydney Strong, William E. Barton Theodore G. Soares ... Chicago and New York: Hope Publishing Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1906/1906">1906</unitdate><container id="aspace_60f57f26a5d5c56bd3620ce7afb2b379" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_1c11ca9b6ce817c5e1bc7e6a996badb6" level="item"><did><unittitle>His life a complete story in the words of the four Gospels prepared by William E. Barton, Theodore G. Soares, Sydney Strong using the text of the American standard revised bible. Chicago and New York: Hope Publishing Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1940/1940">1940</unitdate><container id="aspace_6a0a6e096a648e210b3521a9ded6e781" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0b90c7b6f35303f6e3a1ba1190d07dc6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Huck, Albert. Synopsis of the first three gospels. Albert Huck Ninth edition. Revised by Hans Lietzmann English edition by F.L. Cross. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1954/1954">[1954?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_7c668815a2ceb7d8207ac7b9bd361a06" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_a441be075344a3eaef217fc4d098f21b" level="file"><did><unittitle>I</unittitle><container id="aspace_a99946fc9da6c80b33c3b484d049e80e" label="box" type="box">55</container></did><c02 id="aspace_602c27c9fc1572f1223626ea9e835885" level="item"><did><unittitle>Interwoven gospels and gospel harmony the four histories of Jesus Christ blended into a complete and continuous narrative in the words of the Gospels, with a complete interleaved harmony ... compiled by Rev. William Pittenger ... seven thousand. New York: Fords, Howard &amp; Hulbert</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1893/1893">1893</unitdate><container id="aspace_4d24ccc6070f4f145c367e8d0bdcf94a" label="box" type="box">37</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_35aed75e753b2668b97229302d1998ac" level="file"><did><unittitle>J</unittitle><container id="aspace_8d52c14e74d17d4fd483ece12fb28e8f" label="box" type="box">37</container></did><c02 id="aspace_63e7a07ad34c1bc333601a1fe70468e4" level="item"><did><unittitle>James, Fleming. Hale lectures personalities of the Old Testament. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1939/1939">1939</unitdate><container id="aspace_5bbad11b506d8b30cb2fdbb6f59c0858" label="box" type="box">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6a47cabc5094c8a4f4ceb2a26d7b3ca8" level="item"><did><unittitle>Jefferson, Thomas. Life and morals of Jesus of Nazareth extracted textually from the Gospels in Greek, Latin, French and English. Washington: Government Printing Office</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1904/1904">1904</unitdate><container id="aspace_ec89a22ac45b4691089372090ede1de6" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2ba6a457feb21a8283b52d788b8e6577" level="item"><did><unittitle>Jesus the four gospels, Matthew, Mark, Luke, and John, combined in one narrative and rendered in modern English. New York: Simon and Schuster</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1973/1973">1973</unitdate><container id="aspace_b6b7546bb7073ea819f85e03006265a5" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f19c605ac7f98bf532b92192d09d25d6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Job for the modern man today's English version. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_7434ae94f984656863367036cf4598b8" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ef6f79f1f584089b20ba9b80b6f0e7bb" level="item"><did><unittitle>Johnson, Allan Chester, ed. John H. Scheide biblical papyri Ezekiel. Princeton: Princeton University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938/1938">1938</unitdate><container id="aspace_bf5b5dc18acd2569d017b288a60dc360" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_92a9117b1a9fa88154d38d849496a3f5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Jordan, Clarence. Cotton patch version of Paul's epistles. New York: Koinonia Publication Association Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_44a7de044816a8804d56f3dd6d84dfbf" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_28dc6b5679787bc62adddb33add6c5ac" level="file"><did><unittitle>K</unittitle><container id="aspace_b8e2e112d2350a3e3e8f0b23b43d8481" label="box" type="box">56</container></did><c02 id="aspace_7c71a425f8adea2bb29eed57ab314a80" level="item"><did><unittitle>Knopf, Carl Sumner. Old Testament Speaks. New York: Thomas Nelson and Sons</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1933/1933">1933</unitdate><container id="aspace_0fa4c6235dbec0f7d4174db06fd83ceb" label="box" type="box">27</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9234373c2c12d8b3d03954419b334bfc" level="item"><did><unittitle>Koinonia "Cotton Patch" version. Americus, GA, Clarence L. Jordan</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1969" type="inclusive">1963-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_690eb3d1a728e726878edee14c95359f" label="box" type="box">56</container></did><c03 id="aspace_69d1cc0291d74c3dacae9132a17533d5" level="item"><did><unittitle>A Letter to the Christians in Atlanta or First Corinthians(2 copies)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_dfec859a0ec39677d2cd95b8d7e205f2" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_5ef7d5d869c73e82740643178619450b" level="item"><did><unittitle>A Second Letter to the Christians in Atlanta or the Second Corinthiansand (2 editions)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_25ebda22cedb4e14538bfaf4de83a81b" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_7694c813893c5e70724e5fcdf40a1f79" level="item"><did><unittitle>Letters to -- The Georgia Convention (Galatians) and to the Alabaster African Church</unittitle><container id="aspace_51a6704c877539d1e6fb8efa353fa9f9" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_eae00bbe41aad094dc249e546358b004" level="item"><did><unittitle>Smithville, Alabama (Philippians)and (2 editions)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_cda689a4f1c4bef0053d9ee2c2c08998" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_e17eee2222e648b887606a7852cc548f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Letter to God's people in Columbus (Colossians) and Selma (I &amp; II Thessalonians)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_d82b70e1348452648e081d1225aa31d0" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_bc76f05a3060ab698e5fd0375a7fd4de" level="item"><did><unittitle>Letters to young Christains (I &amp; II Timothy and Titus)(2 copies)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1967">1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_5bd540e64cca4f0d436792076e17365f" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_43a7161bfa0e6a256dc497b20cf731df" level="item"><did><unittitle>Letter to the Hebrews or A first-century manual for church renewal(2 copies)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_cebf2befbf3e67e425db6baf6d5b6808" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_5effceb0773de2040ac878e9a80692c7" level="item"><did><unittitle>Letters from partners Rock, Jack &amp; Joe I &amp; II Peter; I, II, III John &amp; Jude(2 copies)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1969">1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_6e778ad0d27471217dcbada26bf4c065" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_e8fef5176488cccfee1d4bd3ba417e56" level="item"><did><unittitle>Letters to Ephesians and Philemon(2 copies)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_4a057378bf6c022ba32f80d40e01d9bd" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_c9e72619b9dbeb494bedd7b92e1abd7f" level="file"><did><unittitle>L</unittitle><container id="aspace_bb1b0cb206c5571d956894426978691d" label="box" type="box">56</container></did><c02 id="aspace_b4903951f5f8b109a2ed92525e7566ab" level="item"><did><unittitle>Lattimore, Richmond. Four gospels and the revelation newly translated from the Greek. New York: Washington Square Press published by Pocket Books</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1981/1981">1981</unitdate><container id="aspace_6b0dd79a9ad7f9c5f34602429dbed3ff" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3a5f9c29d1644ab47cfbe02f0c75bf97" level="item"><did><unittitle>Lipsky, Abram. Nārrātiōnēs biblicae from the vulgate by Abram Lipsky ... and Harry E. Wedeck ... New York: Newark: Boston: Chicago: San Francisco: Silver, Burdett and Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1928/1928">1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_790a0673a731b655f921ee31dadd4357" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_06ee1132e58ba10e532ca712e00a4638" level="item"><did><unittitle>Looman, T.M. Handboek der Bijbelverklaring voor huisgezinnen; de voornaamste gedeelten der heilige schrift in geschiedkundigen zamenhang uitgelegd, ... derde deel. Oude testament: van rehabeam tot aan den ondergang van het Rijk van Israël. Te Amsterdam: Bij H. Höveker(Series title? Christelijke Huis-Bibliotheek. III. Pg. opposite of t.p.)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1855/1855">1855</unitdate><container id="aspace_0f0f51025d225591d2edcfc5da1590f5" label="box" type="box">38</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_af645e55a8d371726cf6ecdfe46bc7df" level="file"><did><unittitle>M</unittitle><container id="aspace_ef09e8bd4e858e753574ea388ab441c9" label="box" type="box">38</container></did><c02 id="aspace_50ef6381c332527003e6b5786c317714" level="item"><did><unittitle>MacKnight, James. New literal translation, from the original Greek of all the apostolical epistles. With a commentary, and notes, philological, critical, explanatory, and practical. To which is added, a history of the life of the apostle Paul. A new edition, to which is prefixed, an account of the life of the author. New York: M.W. Dodd</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1850/1850">1850</unitdate><container id="aspace_ac6dcf962c71ed505632b493a34054e3" label="box" type="box">20</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_96cbde0a72a7fa7e90eb341c3be5af53" level="item"><did><unittitle>McFayden, John Edgar. Wisdom books (Job, Proverbs, Ecclesiastes) also Lamentations and the Song of Songs in modern speech and rhythmical form. Second edition. London: James Clarke &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1920/1920">[ca. 1920]</unitdate><container id="aspace_ff2eb36476902da39249734b9d7997aa" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e3c4b4183d0ef77ca22663e892891b75" level="item"><did><unittitle>Mertens-Fonck, Paule. Glossary of the Vespasian Psalter and hymns Pt. One -- the verb. Paris: Société d'Édition</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_94cabe30abe51cf2ac0f504385b196f9" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_a3d4ceed39b621ef419bc976cd969de4" level="file"><did><unittitle>N</unittitle><container id="aspace_4924d24d32425079423ef3a9c6465ff1" label="box" type="box">2</container></did><c02 id="aspace_339bf5998fa787a2b62bf84ac6ba4eb6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Nave's topical bible a digest of the holy scriptures more than twenty thousand topics and subtopics, and one hundred thousand references to the scriptures, embracing all doctrines of biblical religion, and all phases of ancient society history, ... Nashville, TN: Southwestern Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_4cb10093cc92871e83914304ccae2581" label="box" type="box">48</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_11922e28ebaff79586d5844c7b7a0175" level="file"><did><unittitle>O</unittitle><container id="aspace_ba6d6ec1c5000e84e07924c53c54efea" label="box" type="box">48</container></did><c02 id="aspace_f0bfbb54ecd5c9b4d9fc90ad0c1b1b3a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Old testament pseudepigrapha. Edited by James H. Charlesworth. New York, London, Toronto, Sydney and Auckland: Doubleday</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1983/1985" type="inclusive">1983-1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_16c572a79eead0f1adf488e00f0ce8cb" label="box" type="box">46</container></did><c03 id="aspace_ab671497d326d083c6f273356209a293" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 1 Apocalyptic literature and testaments</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1983/1983">1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_73d36ccd00edaa65172b2f489ab1cbb1" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_dd4a0f0e2df3ec6d2555f1384a47c1f9" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 2 Expansions of the "Old testament" and legends, wisdom and philosophical literature, ...</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1985/1985">1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_80a5f3ce553ceec0f53391a5f8531a51" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_c3bc5a4ce3a931fd47b08d574a3a849f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Olson, Genevieve P. Life of Christ Jesus in bible language from the King James version of the bible. Fifth edition, revised Wheaton edition. Bonita, CA: Genevieve Olson</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1966/1966">1966</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c84765e06a6e31cef6ddcbb024eb6f7" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_686621df154674b92c072db26f72d036" level="item"><did><unittitle>Osgoodby, William W. Matchless life the records of the four evangelists arranged in a continuous narrative. Rochester, N.Y.: Life Publishing Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1913/1913">1913</unitdate><container id="aspace_5271de9b412f8eb6b449b1e7e72d7005" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f69d43219974fa6a50d1663fb82a1aec" level="item"><did><unittitle>Oursler, Fulton. Greatest book ever written the old testament story. Garden City, NY: Doubleday &amp; Company, Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1951/1951">1951</unitdate><container id="aspace_22fb3be1366b3a4e60bda920ae355d2e" label="box" type="box">39</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_864c8c0a060d08792cc436423cdf0ebb" level="file"><did><unittitle>P</unittitle><container id="aspace_7591dc3432d432fb912606b07f32f94d" label="box" type="box">39</container></did><c02 id="aspace_5113afec2d5b21fe7f7b8c38ffee32ad" level="item"><did><unittitle>Pamplona bibles by François Bucher a facsimile compiled from two picture bibles with martyrologies commissioned by King Sancho el Fuerte of Navarra ... New Haven and London: Yale University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_138abaddb8757328b221c5cc100b5d3b" label="box" type="box">48</container></did><c03 id="aspace_7b31aeadbb5e7a18753b82f4b836c9d5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol.1 Text</unittitle><container id="aspace_f2c62c3b03dedffeede9acc75d7dddde" label="box" type="box">48</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_b9cd5e508e539721ffdf1ff92d055469" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol.2 facsimile</unittitle><container id="aspace_cd9aadf862c9fb67ea0e11ba2b38400f" label="box" type="box">48</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_1e858a98d57526e1efeb65e582b3239b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Pandzhabsko-russkiĭ solvar'. Sostavili I.S. Rabinovich I I. D. Serebriakov. Okolo 35 000 solv. ... Moskva: Gos. Izd-vo inostrannykh I natsional'nykh solvareĭ</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_12384e177e318b810ea8217aa692f930" label="box" type="box">38</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a911656b2d3c330e3c961d13a36cc91d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Papyrus Bodmer II Evangile de Jean chap 1-14. Cologny-Genéve: Bibliothéque Bodmer</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1956/1956">1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_7a72c82e16e017943cc9aca9c4da18d0" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_44b663efa9723a6f67fe406884a5b73b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Papyrus Bodmer XIV-XV Evangiles de Luc et Jean Tome I XIV: Luc chap. 3-34. Cologny-Genéve: Bibliothéque Bodmer(In box w/ Tome II)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_951e152b58d26b0a8abc16ac7f53922c" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d70c0d8a1bbb0ceabceec321a4a4090b" level="item"><did><unittitle>Papyrus Bodmer XIV-XV Evangiles de Luc et Jean Tome II XV: Jean chap. 1-15. Cologny-Genéve: Bibliothéque Bodmer(In box w/ Tome I)</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_4ab8cbe9e28bf90ad42f51e23105f0d3" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0c20d268a697a805813fcff49101ff89" level="item"><did><unittitle>Papyrus Bodmer II Supplément Evangile de Jean chap14-21 Nouvelle édition agumentée et corrigée ... Cologny-Genéve: Bibliothéque Bodmer</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_f8d8761948819ed05f9c6712f0a3a805" label="box" type="box">31</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2146a71cd78c22c911fdc203c35677d7" level="item"><did><unittitle>Paul's letters to the Corinthians -- The twentieth century translation. Lincoln, NE: Back to the Bible Publishers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1961/1961">1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_9f6fac6aa3b2ade943abc0d40c883f9f" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0b12e2b888773ffa5aed4055b92417f1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Pietersma, Albert. Chester Beatty biblical papyri IV and V a new edition with text-critical analysis. Toronto: Samuel Stevens Hakkert and companyAmerican studies in papyrology volume sixteen.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1977/1977">1977</unitdate><container id="aspace_99d740ad0aeeeab168f62f295703a2d3" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7c97d9ec3980b13c4a93f33740ed2af5" level="item"><did><unittitle>Posner, Raphael and Israel Ta-Shema eds. Hebrew book an historical survey. New York: Leon Amiel Publisher</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1975/1975">1975</unitdate><container id="aspace_0518721047da104289937560779388b2" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a335b89c62a970c3ea6ad6c4d9195a81" level="item"><did><unittitle>Psaumes de David. Proverbes de Salomon. Ecclésiaste. A Toulouse: De l'Imprimerie d'Antoine Navarre</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1819/1819">1819</unitdate><container id="aspace_c6d73386344378a661467a5e452df832" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_94874a8b4e0492702e9fbfb7d6d6258b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Q</unittitle><container id="aspace_d00ea4e4aacdc3c0512fd6421b1d97d4" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_539e38d3686bc895164dab0e1aab7be7" level="file"><did><unittitle>R</unittitle><container id="aspace_6fb0cc799de3e246a967e99adbb3f227" label="box" type="box">55</container></did><c02 id="aspace_595a6f74ad227377820355273cab8e21" level="item"><did><unittitle>Readings from the holy scriptures prepared for the use of Jewish personnel of the army of the United States Published under the direction of the chief of chaplins. Washington: Government Printing Office</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_1d3692e8c76773ee3d20a49ba03b3e83" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e740725dc5b5bea3b7d2fca58f7bc2ec" level="item"><did><unittitle>Robertson, A.T. Harmony of the gospels for students of the life of Christ based on the Bradus Harmony in the revised version. New York, Evanston and London: Harper &amp; Row</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1950/1950">1950</unitdate><container id="aspace_2c2032d1e2d5d9a85fe3f6cbfa93f317" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_e3779e7638d7776f13d4b3d51ae818a8" level="item"><did><unittitle>Robertson, Edward. Harmony of the four gospels in English. According to the common version. Newly arranged, with explanatory notes. Tenth edition. Boston: Crocker &amp; Brewster and London: Wiley &amp; Putnam</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1862/1862">1862</unitdate><container id="aspace_965853e079727d02ae79682a04b80c56" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a45f90b44a45b6ccbe9439e093079d5e" level="item"><did><unittitle>Romer, John. Testament the Bible and history. New York: Henry Holt and Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1988/1988">1988</unitdate><container id="aspace_1b7b5617160be8417de969a62c477dd2" label="box" type="box">27</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_30a80a7107bfaaee2170b870a325e623" level="file"><did><unittitle>S</unittitle><container id="aspace_8bb125e6ce792f88566cfe56ec743d90" label="box" type="box">27</container></did><c02 id="aspace_a18d9324cb2e5b65df9f521611b35f5c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Sanders, Henry A. and Carl Schmidt. Minor prophets in the Freer Collection and the Berlin Fragment of Genesis. New York: Macmillan Company and London: Macmillan and Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1927/1927">1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_55377dd66e2a66af2573389ce3bff2df" label="box" type="box">30</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f83b372bf89d05edfcb662b1b40a93c6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Schouppe, F.X. Explanatio Psalmorum qui juxta breviarium romanum in officiis communibus recitantur, ad mentem optimorum interpretum adornata. Bruxellis: Ex Officinia Catholica M.Closson et Sociorum and Buscoduci: Apud W. Van Gulick and Parisiis: Apud Bray et Retaux</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1880/1880">[1880?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8cee490617f65e3b5d29b0584411622" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_d7b9018911de2ac26c8c59cbbbf4c1a1" level="item"><did><unittitle>Serendipity New Testament for groups Second edition New international version. Littleton, CO: Serendipity HousePreview Sample: Gospel of Matthew &amp; Mark.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1987/1987">1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_ce5c25f5029dc1c405fe2b20076f07a5" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_670918efd3780c2ff441bf166085ad1c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Sermon on the mount. New York: Chicago: Los Angeles: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1960/1960">[ca. 1960]</unitdate><container id="aspace_71178d634690dc1962ac17596b830561" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_3639cb4bc4bebb04deb7ae91ea19c10d" level="item"><did><unittitle>Sermon on the mount being the fifth, sixth &amp; seventh chapters of the gospel according to St. Matthew in the King James version of the holy bible. Chicago: Monastery Hill Bindery</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1968">1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_0347897e3ac9b21485e52c7decf59147" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_7ff384cc9d64ffb1d4940c28fc4f93cd" level="item"><did><unittitle>Smith, Wade C. Little Jetts Bible. Boston: W.A. Wilde Company</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_3ebe7f3e6ec15d858c8680600a33dafb" label="box" type="box">20</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_08838b6de4c40c806ca5618d17687b93" level="item"><did><unittitle>Steinmueller, John E. Gospel harmony using the confraternity edition of the new testament. New York and Chicago: W.H. Sadlier Inc.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1942">1942</unitdate><container id="aspace_79e707b6f3eaa78b56ba7680ec7642b5" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_aa7615125fda9f29a2920e6cc4228ac4" level="item"><did><unittitle>Stevens, Wm. Arnold and Ernest Dewitt Burton. Harmony of the Gospels for historical study an analytical synopsis of the four Gospels in the version of 1881. New York: International committee of Young Men's Christian Associations</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1903/1903">1903</unitdate><container id="aspace_f885c89f7108b9dcd14d060404ae46d3" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_8ba43704baf8be6a675639afc770dbe6" level="item"><did><unittitle>Stevens, Wm. Arnold and Ernest Dewitt Burton. Harmony of the Gospels for historical study an analytical synopsis of the four Gospels. Tenth edition, revised. New York: Charles Scribner's Sons</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1911/1911">1911</unitdate><container id="aspace_fb0ac73b5033fc374dbcf61dfc6b214a" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_2367ccf67bcbe5469ee8a3dadba95dfc" level="file"><did><unittitle>T</unittitle><container id="aspace_5903f3c962642cb642b0c8e723b84a01" label="box" type="box">8</container></did><c02 id="aspace_27c6ad2a3d66798459e93209ff6b3148" level="item"><did><unittitle>Treasures from the bible. New York: Essential Books</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1944/1944">1944</unitdate><container id="aspace_028183edb895a3baa03146a3bdfd8f25" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_2b19b5f5208c49718220129fe16f5836" level="file"><did><unittitle>U</unittitle><container id="aspace_5c2ebd89afbf06cad11aec1a4924330f" label="box" type="box">46</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_446673e6753c24f8c4e0d53c05e0bfb6" level="file"><did><unittitle>V</unittitle><container id="aspace_23887576775c2d8bfee5fc0f5217d27b" label="box" type="box">46</container></did><c02 id="aspace_e964ecde8113cd6477bb6fcbd10ee717" level="item"><did><unittitle>Van Loon, Hendrik Willem. Story of the bible. New York: Boni &amp; Liveright</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1923/1923">1923</unitdate><container id="aspace_71033a283e15a427e05161c370983dd2" label="box" type="box">55</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_7ab8af1c7036bbdb2ff635cda45814b6" level="file"><did><unittitle>W</unittitle><container id="aspace_52e91b8183de5f9e54fe0c0355471612" label="box" type="box">55</container></did><c02 id="aspace_8cf83001771c96bd290acecb8891342c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Walks and words of Jesus a paragraph harmony of the four gospels originally compiled by Rev. M.N. Olmsted to which is added "New saying of Jesus" revised edition. New York: Oxford University Press</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1918/1918">1918</unitdate><container id="aspace_f5ad06a6d1b3c696cd9d6e4a13ec2952" label="box" type="box">37</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_c077c1b81098d1c72bf18ebfba057fd4" level="item"><did><unittitle>Watkins, I.B. Scripture history; containing all the important passags in the Old and New Testaments. Designed for the improvement of youth, and as a useful introduction to the knowledge of the sacred scriptures. In twenty five numbers, embellished with 200 engravings. ... New York: Printed and published by Thomas Kinnersley</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1829/1829">1829</unitdate><container id="aspace_8cb3ae2fdd35ecf1d607951418f6ed8b" label="box" type="box">38</container></did><c03 id="aspace_5ce5a741bc7f411d55ae3b276cd5ca3a" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 1</unittitle><container id="aspace_caf956b3c942fd6ad987b50a75175327" label="box" type="box">38</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_fe269b39249f3b71f62c1f103697de09" level="item"><did><unittitle>Vol. 2</unittitle><container id="aspace_1d404642ea5814b3ee9abd49f8038824" label="box" type="box">38</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_e5660e51103459eac13e3aade4630f9f" level="item"><did><unittitle>Watts, Isaac. Psalms of David, imitated in the language of the New Testament, and applied to the Christian state and worship. Walpole, N.H.: Isaiah Thomas &amp; Co.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1812/1812">1812</unitdate><container id="aspace_b080309d754f7e16f934154d8d52c0a4" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_675f9c9f2e59bf9984e469a2777dc794" level="item"><did><unittitle>Wilkins, Chester. Four Gospels arranged as a single narrative. Berne, Ind.: Light &amp; Hope Publishing</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1974/1974">1974</unitdate><container id="aspace_4aba0d86f1c858e7389f4ee5d26bf7d4" label="box" type="box">8</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_b7bf26d454d2a4290a530e2a73f0b31c" level="item"><did><unittitle>Wisdom for modern man Proverbs and Ecclesiastes from the old testament in today's English version. New York: American Bible Society</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1972/1972">1972</unitdate><container id="aspace_692d8b0eb5cca73f0a910b452f5fc7e6" label="box" type="box">56</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_9fb67757e9300ac6ecac4e9430db7bb3" level="item"><did><unittitle>Words of Jesus as recorded in the authorized King James version of the Holy Bible comprising the words of Jesus with authoritative adaptations of the Bible text of which the are a part arranged and chronicled by Gilbert James Brett ... Chicago: Consolidated Book Publishers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1965/1965">1965</unitdate><container id="aspace_40a90b75e461185edcd6db4b43eaceef" label="box" type="box">37</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_b4dd915e1668b6e46ea110442fd74735" level="file"><did><unittitle>X</unittitle><container id="aspace_8b43be37c19155dd34e9f94f0e8c7078" label="box" type="box">37</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_0bd6755c007408f1f68d0b97d8ad2f98" level="file"><did><unittitle>Y</unittitle><container id="aspace_4f4777ff9d76ed2d0ce18e78cca8b82b" label="box" type="box">37</container></did><c02 id="aspace_5dd12610d1007790458de18c44e5e9a4" level="item"><did><unittitle>Young, Robert. Young's literal translation of the Holy Bible. Revised edition. Grand Rapids, MI: Baker Book House</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1976/1977" type="inclusive">[1976-1977?]</unitdate><container id="aspace_064a9f51f10015404c3b116f82f92fb2" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_4213002a08c0c36a42b09630fdbd0c79" level="file"><did><unittitle>Z</unittitle><container id="aspace_52c8e78654fc055f5033de0c43402dde" label="box" type="box">22</container></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
