<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Li-VAD7014</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Secker mss., 1894-1969</titleproper><titleproper>Secker mss., 1894-1969 <num>LMC 2203</num></titleproper><subtitle>Papers of Martin Secker, 1894-1969, at the Lilly Library, Indiana University</subtitle><author>Mary McSparran</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Lilly Library</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/lilly.png" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>10/30/2020</date></p><address><addressline>1200 E. Seventh St.</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-5500</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-2452</addressline><addressline>liblilly@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-18 22:20:59 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is written in: <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English, Latin script</language>.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>March 10, 2017</date><item>Encoded finding aid created.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Lilly Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Secker mss.</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname authfilenumber="n88156499" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Secker, Martin, 1882-1978</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LMC 2203</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">4 Boxes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">4 standard</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 bound</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1894/1969" type="inclusive">1894-1969</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_b7abf274cf017d4e6a501faef1f28e6a">The Secker mss., 1894-1969, consists primarily of letters to publisher Martin Secker, 1882-1978, from various authors, illustrators, and acquaintances with whom he had business dealings.</abstract>
    <physloc audience="internal" id="aspace_0d8ea896489c30ee98870b3d648b669f">Lilly - Stacks</physloc>
    <langmaterial>
      <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_86c1ef4247f977e61545c4ea4b3b8bab">
    <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p>Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/ask">make an appointment</extref> a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_d447007f16bd2520e0e812625c07385f">
    <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
<p>Photography and digitization may be restricted for some collections. Copyright restrictions may apply. Before publishing, researchers are responsible for securing permission from all applicable rights holders, then filling out the <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/permission-to-publish" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest">Permission to Publish form.</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_e6c3d97ac6f5a84f869b735fadbda05e">
    <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
<p>Purchase: 1975</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_a0e13debabf90455e41847a092aadf2f">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Martin Secker, 1882-1978, was born Percy Martin Secker Klingender on 6 April 1882 in London, England. He entered the publishing world in 1908, when he started working for James Eveleigh Nash, 1874-1956. In 1910, Secker established his own publishing company, Martin Secker, Ltd.; novelist Rafael Sabatini, 1875-1950, joined the business as a partner from 1916 to 1918, and Percival Presland Howe, 1886-1944, became a partner in 1918. In its first decade, the company published novels by Norman Douglas, Arthur Machen, Compton Mackenzie, Viola Meynell, Oliver Onions, Frank Swinnerton, and Francis Brett Young, and poetry by Maurice Baring, T. W. H. Crosland, Emily Dickinson, James Elroy Flecker, Ford Madox Ford, and D. H. Lawrence. By the mid-1920s, Secker was the pre-eminent British publisher of European works in translation, with novels by Thomas Mann, Hermann Hesse, Arnold Zweig, Franz Kafka, and Leon Feuchtwanger. In 1936, Fredric Warburg and Roger Senhouse bought Secker's company and changed the name to Secker &amp; Warburg. In 1937, Secker bought Richards Press, formerly run by Grant Richards, and published works by Richard Le Gallienne, James Elroy Flecker, A. E. Housman, and Enid Blyton. In 1938, Secker created the Unicorn Press, which published works by Arthur Symons, Robert Hichens, and Oscar Wilde. He continued to publish until 1962, when he sold his business to John Baker. Secker died in Bridgefoot, England, on 6 April 1978. He is most famous for publishing works by George Orwell, D. H. Lawrence, and Henry James.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_5d98641f846b93ed55a805b61437e41c">
    <head>Scope and Contents</head>
<p>The majority of the material relates to three publishing firms with which he was associated: Martin Secker, Ltd., (1910-1936), The Richards Press, Ltd., (after 1937) and The Unicorn Press, Ltd., of which he continued as proprietor until his death.</p><p>Among the correspondents are Alan Anderson; John Redwood Anderson; Terrence Ian Fytton Armstrong; Balint Stephen Biro; John Charles Edward Bowen; Mary Chevalita (Dunne) Bright; Sir Arthur Bryant; Daniel George Bunting; Coulson T. Cade; Sir Neville Cardus; John Waynflete Carter; Edward W. Colman; John Connell; John William Counsell; Rupert Croft-Cooke; Sir William Young Darling; Guy Stephen Deghy; Powell Edwards; John Farleigh; Hugh I'Anson Fausset; Patrick Michael Leigh Fermour; Marta Feuchtwanger; Constantine FitzGibbon; Kenelm Foss; Brian Fothergill; Elizabeth (Hollister) Frost; John Gloag; Douglas Goldring; Alyse Gregory; Felix Guggenheim; Sir William John Haley; Sir Julian Henry Hall; Hamish Hamilton; Sir Cecil Hanbury; Archie Harradine; Michael de Courcy Fraser Holroyd; Emil Otto Hoppe; Percival Presland Howe; Derek Rommel Hudson; Benjamin W. Huebsch; Harford Montgomery Hyde; Storm Jameson; Cecil Keeling; John Patrick Douglas Balfour, Baron Kinross; Alfred A. Knopf; Edward William Bootle-Wilbraham, Earl Lathom; Maria Xenia (de Tunzelman) Bootle-Wilbraham, Countess of Lathom; Gwendolyn Le Gallienne; Winifred M. Letts; Roger A. Lhombreaud; Stuart Petre Bordie Mais; Sir Edward Howard Marsh; John Nicolas Mavrogordato; Leonard Morgan May; Amy Gwen (Wilson) Mond, Lady Melchett; Mara Meulen; Sir Francis Meynell; Viola Meynell; Malcolm Muggeridge; Willa (Anderson) Muir; Gerald O'Donovan; Edith Maud Olivier; Hesketh Pearson; Alan Pryce-Jones; Francis Archibald Kelhead Douglas, Marquis of Queensberry; Grant Richards; Madelein Grant Richards; Michael B. Rubinstein; Alfred Patrick Ryan; Rafael Sabatini; Hon. Victoria Mary Sackville-West; Michael Sadleir; Martin Secker; Paul Selver; Geoffrey Smerdon; Sir John Collings Squire; Oliver Stonor; John Symonds; Julian Symons; Joseph Edward Harold Terry; Louis Tracy; Walter James Turner; Royall Tyler; Sir Stanley Unwin; John Cushing Varney; Rainforth Armitage Walker; Alexander Raban Waugh; Terence de Vere White; William Cecil James Philip John Paul Howard, Earl Wicklow; Norman Wilkinson; Sir Ormonde de l'Epee Winter; Cecil Woolf; and Francis Brett Young.</p><p>Most of the early correspondence, that is, at least through 1910, consists of letters to Grant Richards or to the Richard Press prior to Secker's association with that firm.</p><p>Also present are manuscripts of works by Coulson T. Cade ("The Black Poppy") and Sandys Wason ("The Stilt-Birds"); photographs of several Secker authors, three of which were taken and signed by photographer E.O. Hoppe; and a bound "Publication Ledger," dating from April 1938-Dec. 1954, indexed by title of publication.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_2a9e2aebc532d5a5cca91a5e3983ca71">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is arranged chronologically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_a16c605fc4d00d777d8c0309caefe31a">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Secker mss., Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </prefercite>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_5a06bedf479c1247206ebf382bc8f3fd">
    <head>Related Materials</head>
<p>See Secker mss. II, also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Publishers and publishing</subject>
    <persname authfilenumber="n88156499" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Secker, Martin, 1882-1978</persname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="no2009044785" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Martin Secker Ltd.</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="n 86094408" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Secker &amp; Warburg</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_352a0748c5b1dba3be5fb4a63e54a748" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1894/1941" type="inclusive">1894-1941</unitdate><container id="aspace_3b541e656ed9e0e2b21795c81cdc5e30" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_db690cfd474cff4ee5800ceb67138010" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1942/1956" type="inclusive">1942-1956</unitdate><container id="aspace_75bbdeefeb03593a49240fe0b6849441" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_d7ace3b88f9bf51a243a78d834bd16a4" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1969" type="inclusive">1957-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_493e3c10f203a72da463daab52337a15" label="box" type="box">3</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_14ec54808deb88d1b2d4b3bdce25c619" level="file"><did><unittitle>Undated</unittitle><container id="aspace_435049ce04163e0d60cc806bbc97d0be" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_69cdfae5a730e11f979b8b28ef014803" level="file"><did><unittitle>Photographs</unittitle><container id="aspace_db0fa849952dd967ceed323959a74925" label="box" type="box">4</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_bf7c8cf6e534bb4a456bf07d9d3f8f38" level="file"><did><unittitle>Publication ledger</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1938-04/1954-12" type="inclusive">April 1938-December 1954</unitdate><container id="aspace_207657268d51208186d8bd7a3f4ad840" label="bound" type="bound">1</container></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
