<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="originaldraft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Li-VAD6565</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Illingworth mss., 1816-1880 </titleproper><titleproper>Illingworth mss., 1816-1880  <num>LMC 1536</num></titleproper><subtitle>Papers of Various, 1816-1880, at the Lilly Library, Indiana University</subtitle><author>Alyssa Mertka </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Lilly Library</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/lilly.png" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>10/23/2020</date></p><address><addressline>1200 E. Seventh St.</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-5500</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-2452</addressline><addressline>liblilly@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p>Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-18 22:12:43 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>March 10, 2017</date><item>Encoded finding aid created.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>January 8, 2019</date><item>Edits and rearrangement of content into requisite Lilly EAD structure, including addition of abstract, bioghist, scopecontent, controlaccess, and c01 levels of container list. Mahaley Evans.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Lilly Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Illingworth mss.</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="crp" source="ingest">Illingworth, Richard Stonhewer, 1797-1884</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="ingest">Illingworth, Stonhewer E.</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="crp" source="ingest">Stephenson, Robert</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="crp" source="lcnaf">Bolivar, Simon, 1783-1830</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="crp" source="lcnaf">Bolivar, Fernando, 1808-1898</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LMC 1536</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folio</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 folio</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">oversize</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">3 Boxes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">2 standard, 1 custom</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1816/1880" type="inclusive">1816-1880</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_0faaffbd15fcc0d4d2ec6c172ee32d84">The Illingworth mss., 1816-1880, consists of the papers of businessman Richard Stonhewer Illingworth, 1797-1884. The papers deal with personnel matters, finances, the returns on cocoa, cotton, sugar, and tobacco, and the mining of coal, copper, emeralds, gold, lead, salt, and silver.</abstract>
    <physloc audience="internal" id="aspace_454724ce9e172ae33e4e82f452718e29">ALF (Auxiliary Library Facility) - OVFlat; ALF (Auxiliary Library Facility); Lilly - Folio</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_aee9f1bbd9258cec547d6c7f55be039d">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>; <language langcode="spa">Spanish</language>; <language langcode="fre">French</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_fe1e07035745095e0cbc556339634d1e">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p>Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/ask">make an appointment</extref> a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b32bb60a4dff96b7f88ce918f7a5416d">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Photography and digitization may be restricted for some collections. Copyright restrictions may apply. Before publishing, researchers are responsible for securing permission from all applicable rights holders, then filling out the <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/permission-to-publish" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest">Permission to Publish form.</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_cc72dc4ca6ea2dca51e8b5c1df4f67d1">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Purchase: <date normal="1968" type="acquisition">1968</date>, <date normal="1969" type="acquisition">1969</date></p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_5c36d25332612dacdd51e26d2dd7be81">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
Richard Stonhewer Illingworth, 1797-1884, was a British businessman and speculator. He was born in 1797, son of Richard Stonhewer Illingworth, 1768(?)-1847. From April 1812 to March 1815 he was in the Army pay department in Lisbon; from March 1815 to April 22, 1817 the commissariat department; and from March 1819 to December 1822 the pay office in Whitehall. In December 1822 Illingworth was engaged by Jones, Powles, Hurry &amp; Co. (Herring, Graham, Powles Co.) as commercial manager in Bogotá, Colombia; and was later director of St. John d'El Rey Mining Co. for thirty-two years. He died in England in 1884. 
 
<p>
During the first part of the second decade of the nineteenth century, the Colombian Mining Association proposed to recommence working the gold and silver mines in Spanish America and to concentrate on the mineral wealth of Colombia. Thomas Richardson of the Association and partner of the Stephenson Company in Newcastle offered the post of engineer to Robert Stephenson, the son of George Stephenson. Leases were obtained from the Colombian government for the mines of Santa Ana and La Manta. In October 1825 operations began on the mines, but soon the Governor of Honda became angry with the conduct of the miners, as proper care had not been taken in England to select sober, steady men.
</p>
  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_f367f7210e3187a340c559518924a457">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>In the collection are one hundred and fifteen letters from Robert Stephenson to Illingworth mostly written from Mariquita, Colombia, between September 1824 and November 1828 on the management of mining affairs in Colombia, mining laws in general and how they could be adapted to conditions in Colombia. Fourteen letters were written by Stephenson to Illingworth between 1848 and 1858 when both men were living in England which deal with news of their native country. Among the papers are also fifteen diaries of Illingworth, kept between 1816 and 1842, on the location of mines, including small sketches and positions of mines, reports, an informative and vivid description of a journey on land and aboard the Bongo boats giving a clear idea of the life, people, geographical position, and conditions in Colombia in 1829, a list of the staff and miners with comments on their work and character, supplies required, calculations and cost of mines, detailed mining information on selection and treatment of ores, and an account of a journey to the United States. Another important item is a thirty-nine-page report to the Board of Directors of the Colombian Mining Association. Of interest is also a detailed and descriptive itinerary of a journey from Mariquita to Arma in August 1826 written by Ed Walker.</p><p> A memoir, reports, observations, and several letters on mining written in French between 1823 and 1836 from Jean Baptiste Boussingault, the French agricultural chemist, who became famous for his discoveries on the absorption of nitrogen by plants, add to the value of the collection. Boussingault went to Colombia about 1813 as a mining engineer for the Colombian Mining company. During the insurrection of the Spanish colonies he was attached to the staff of Simon Bolivar and traveled widely in the northern parts of the continent. Included are also two letters, August 15, 1870, and March 20, 1872, discussing the Franco-Prussian war.</p><p> Four letters from Simon Bolivar and one from his nephew and secretary, Fernando Bolivar, in Spanish are of interest to the scholar because of their content. The first two letters to Jose Fernandez Madrid dated September 27, 1827, refer to finances in connection with his mines in Venezuela with special reference to a bill of exchange for twenty thousand pesos made out to Joseph Lancaster, the noted British educator, to help him further the cause of primary education in Caracas by importing the benefits of his system. The third letter was writen to the naval officer Juan Illingworth. In this letter of June 9, 1830, the Liberator expresses his affection and trust in Illingworth and asks him to turn over to Manuela Saenz the money coming from the impending sale of a mule. In the fourth letter which was written to Richard Stonhewer Illingworth dated August 2, 1830, Bolivar profusely thanks Illingworth for fulfilling a mission for him and adds that he is thinking of going to England at once to show how deplorable conditions are in Colombia and how much damage ships leaving the harbor of Cartagena have suffered. A brief note was appended to the letter from Bolivar's nephew, Fernando. On January 9, 1831, Fernando Bolivar wrote to Juan Illingworth thanking him for the valuable services rendered to his uncle and discussing the circumstances surrounding the Liberator's death. Something of a more personal nature in this collection is a lock of Bolivar's hair which was cut after his death and was given to Juan Illingworth on January 10, 1831, at Guaduas.</p><p> Six documents and copies of six letters in Spanish on the Panama Canal, 1825-1829, concerned with the mines and the Isthmus of Panama, add to the value of the collection.</p><p> Included are also forty-two water color drawings, one pencil sketch, and one pen and ink sketch by Stonhewer E. Illingworth, son of Richard Stonhewer Illingworth, 1797-1884; pen and ink drawing and description of a plan for the use of a distilling furnace; certificates of stock in the New Granada Mining company; and a printed account of the St. John del Rey Mining Co.</p><p> Some of the material is in an oversize folder.</p><p> Among the correspondents in the collection are William Pitt Adams, Juan de Dios Aranzazu, Charles G. Austin, Antoine Cesar Becquerel, William Matthews Blackford, J.H. Bodmer, Fernando Bolivar, Simon Bolivar, Jean Baptiste Boussingault, Patrick Campbell, John Chapman, Michael Adrian Coppinger, Juan Garcia del Rio, Thomas Longridge Gooch, Edward Hurry, Manuel Jose Hurtado, Jorge Illoyo, John Cordy Jeaffreson, Sir John Kirkland, F. Marcos, Jose Vicente Martinez, Santos Michelena, Jose Maria Obando, Thomas Parker, William Parker, Edward P. Penny, Lino de Pombo, John Deston Powles, Jose Manuel Restrepo, Vicente Rocafuerte, J.E. Sanderson, James Smyth, Robert Stephenson, Jonas Stowell, Rafael Urdaneta, Jose Felix Valdivieso, Fred J. Warre.</p><p> Note on Indexing Terms - "Art": Of interest are Illingworth's diaries which include small sketches and positions of mines in Colombia. Also included are forty-two watercolor drawings, one pencil sketch, and one pen and ink sketch by Stonhewer E. Illingworth, son of Richard Illingworth; and a pen and ink drawing and description of a plan for the use of a distilling furnace.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_c391a7cbc430349ec81d97f0abf63461">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is arranged following original order.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_7cd3c9c3db5a4b7f0b701f10d1ee0c77">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Illingworth mss., Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Art</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh2010101948" source="lcsh">Mines and mineral resources -- Colombia</subject>
    <geogname authfilenumber="sh2008116517" source="lcsh">Panama Canal (Panama) -- History</geogname>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh85085717" source="lcsh">Mining law</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAD6565-00001" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1817/1829" type="inclusive">1817-1829</unitdate><container id="aspace_5813a19c20de1cb6809c7871967fd21f" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD6565-00002" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1830/1880" type="inclusive">1830-1880</unitdate><container id="aspace_12f0a2025ea6d98da96b889ad0991ebf" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD6565-00003" level="file"><did><unittitle>Diaries</unittitle><container id="aspace_d4603dc206753e7dcb94600fb8cd2737" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD6565-00004" level="file"><did><unittitle>Illingworth, Stonhewer E. water color drawings</unittitle><container id="aspace_6580f282ddb5e53f421a981b09c603cc" label="Mixed Materials" type="foliobox">9</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD6565-00005" level="item"><did><unittitle>Illingworth, Richard Stonhewer letter copybook</unittitle><container id="aspace_63d4d0f8a2bd77ef49eccf71dacdd32f" label="bound" type="box">3</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD6565-00006" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sketches, printed account, and certificate</unittitle><container id="aspace_7cb55c78bd2e131f758f1a19be2876db" label="Mixed Materials" type="ovflat">13</container></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
