<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="originaldraft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Li-VAD6609</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Kelley mss., 1907-1935</titleproper><titleproper>Kelley mss., 1907-1935 <num>LMC 1568</num></titleproper><subtitle>Papers of Sinclair Lewis, 1907-1935, at the Lilly Library, Indiana University</subtitle><author>Alyssa Mertka</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Lilly Library</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/lilly.png" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>11/13/2020</date></p><address><addressline>1200 E. Seventh St.</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-5500</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-2452</addressline><addressline>liblilly@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p>Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-18 22:17:01 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>March 10, 2017</date><item>Encoded finding aid created.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>September 13, 2017</date><item>Edits and rearrangement of content to create sections for abstract, bioghist, controlaccess, scopecontent, acquisitioninfo, and levels for container list were applied. Madison Chartier</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>September 14, 2017</date><item>Adjusted creator name in origination tag per instructions of Erika Dowell. Madison Chartier</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>April 27, 2018</date><item>Batch update to change subject links.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Lilly Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Kelley mss.</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="ingest">Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="crp" source="lcnaf">Kelley, Edith Summers</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LMC 1568</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.25 Linear Feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1907/1935" type="inclusive">1907-1935</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_5e65d20e47ce227168afd3264f585749">The Kelley mss., 1907-1935, consists of letters written by writer Sinclair Lewis, 1885-1951, to novelist Edith Summers Kelley, (Mrs. Clyde F. Kelley), 1883-1956.</abstract>
    <physloc audience="internal" id="aspace_bffa394f406c9a504e05aac4afadb7e5">Missing</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_290abffd78a7074ee7674fca11118f38">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_0c720b409a07b49a040780155159c510">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p>Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/ask">make an appointment</extref> a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_ca6e3718eefef1751883f771ed4a23e6">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Photography and digitization may be restricted for some collections. Copyright restrictions may apply. Before publishing, researchers are responsible for securing permission from all applicable rights holders, then filling out the <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/permission-to-publish" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest">Permission to Publish form.</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_abcfd6247c7970645fe42509818d4aac">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Purchase: 1957</p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_85567bc33b9075b67bf15970e4d635f9">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>
Sinclair Lewis, 1885-1951, was a writer known for his short stories and novels. He was born on February 7, 1885 in Sauk Centre, Minnesota. He received his bachelor's degree from Yale in 1907, and his first publications appeared in the <title render="italic">Yale Courant</title> and the <title render="italic">Yale Literary Magazine</title>. He also worked as a janitor in Upton Sinclair's Helicon Home Colony from 1906 to 1907, where he met Edith Summers Kelley. His first novel, <title render="italic">Our Mr. Wrenn: The Romantic Adventures of a Gentle Man</title>, was published in 1914, but he would not attain widespread success until the publication of his novel <title render="italic">Main Street</title> in 1920. Throughout the 1920's Lewis published several novels satirizing various aspects of American life, including <title render="italic">Babbitt</title> (1922), <title render="italic">Arrowsmith</title> (1925), <title render="italic">Elmer Gantry</title> (1927), and <title render="italic">Dodsworth</title> (1929). In 1930, he became the first American writer to receive the Nobel Prize in Literature. He continued to write novels, most memorably <title render="italic">It Can't Happen Here</title> (1935), a speculative exploration of a fascist takeover of the United States, but his reputation and the quality of his work began to decline. Lewis struggled with alcoholism throughout the latter portion of his life, and he died from it on January 10, 1951.
</p>

<p>
Edith Summers Kelley, 1883-1956, was a novelist and secretary of Upton Sinclair at the Helicon Home Colony, Englewood, New Jersey. She was born on April 28, 1884 in Toronto, Ontario, Canada. After graduating from the University of Toronto in 1903, she moved to New York City and settled in Greenwich Village to begin her career as a writer. In 1905 she became Upton Sinclair's secretary and joined his experimental community, the Helicon Home Colony, when it was established in 1906. The building that housed the community burned down in 1907, and Kelley returned to supporting herself by writing stories and poems for magazines. She and Sinclair Lewis, whom she met at the colony, were engaged for two years, but Kelley broke the engagement. She chose instead to marry Lewis' roommate Allan Updegraff in 1908. They had two children before divorcing. Kelly then began a relationship with sculptor Clyde Fred Kelley, and the family eventually moved to a tobacco farm in Scott County, Kentucky. This experience provided the inspiration for Edith Kelley's novel <title render="italic">Weeds</title> (1923). The family moved again to Imperial Valley, California, where Kelley spent the remaining years of her life. Her second novel, <title render="italic">The Devil's Hand</title>, remained unpublished when she died on June 9, 1956.
</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_c51727413a656d927faffe3b8c5a1512">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>
The collection includes a typewritten copy of a group of Sinclair Lewis' poems including "Foreword," "To Alethea in Her Old Age," "Gold in Umber," "An Invocation," "The Mystery," "Fear on Calvary," "Uninspired," "The Burgeoning," and "City Sanctuary" ; photographs of the stairway, east exterior, south end of court, and north end of court of Helicon Home Colony, founded by Upton Sinclair at Englewood, New Jersey, in 1906; and a copy of a photograph of the ruins of Jack London's home, Wolf House, in Sonoma County, California.
</p>
<p>
The letters relate to Lewis' proposed marriage to Edith Summers, his 1928 trip to England, his Vermont farm, his writing, her writing, personal and family news, friends, and opinions of other authors.
</p>
<p>
The letters and poems are accompanied by typescripts, and each of the photographs of Helicon Home Colony are accompanied by a photographic copy made in 1957 by O. K. Harter, photographer, Monrovia, California.
</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_70a730d305a270c4f3c8880ec1068367">
    <head>Arrangement </head>
<p>This collection is arranged following original order.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_cd7a6dcba1de121fba740cec315bfcfc">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Kelley mss., Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Authors, American--20th century--Correspondence</subject>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951</persname>
    <persname authfilenumber="n79127862" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968</persname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="sh2019000762" source="naf">Wolf House (Glen Ellen, Calif.)</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAD6609-00001" level="collection"><did><unittitle>Kelley mss.</unittitle><physdesc altrender="whole"><extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 Items</extent><extent altrender="carrier">(1 box)</extent></physdesc></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
