<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Li-VAD9929</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">James, J. mss., 1835-1852 </titleproper><titleproper>James, J. mss., 1835-1852  <num>LMC 2586</num></titleproper><subtitle>Papers of Various, 1835-1852, at the Lilly Library, Indiana University </subtitle><author>Alyssa Mertka </author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Lilly Library</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/lilly.png" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>10/30/2020</date></p><address><addressline>1200 E. Seventh St.</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-5500</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-2452</addressline><addressline>liblilly@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p>Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-18 22:27:52 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>April 5, 2018</date><item>Encoded finding aid started. Madison Chartier</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>April 10, 2018</date><item>Encoded finding aid completed. Madison Chartier</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Lilly Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>James, J. mss.</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="lcnaf">Various</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="crp" source="lcnaf">James, J. H. (John Haddy), 1788-1869</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="crp" source="lcnaf">Noble, Noah, 1794-1844</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname role="crp" source="ingest">Walker, John</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LMC 2586</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1 Box</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 standard</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1835/1852" type="inclusive">1835-1852</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_97e599449c7097bfccd0c8bef30d43f5">The James, J. mss., ca. 1835-1852, consists of letters, land inventories, and financial papers relating to Indiana land investments.</abstract>
    <physloc audience="internal" id="aspace_eeb8181d9e15463d7f2e697aa186c73f">Lilly - Stacks</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_7c526ca02eb398eef4f027037f52e64b">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e9de5ad3de55d2d26c8c98f9ecb9d8ae">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p>Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/ask">make an appointment</extref> a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3bbeede157f3b7a4b73c8f97dd9740ad">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Photography and digitization may be restricted for some collections. Copyright restrictions may apply. Before publishing, researchers are responsible for securing permission from all applicable rights holders, then filling out the <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/permission-to-publish" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest">Permission to Publish form.</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_772880f79d0a81217119ee9e6fa075e5">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Purchase: <date normal="2007" type="acquisition">2007</date></p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_0deb3bacfce8ecb02a3d82a4f9ed6457">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p><P>
Colonel John H. James, 1800-1881 was an American lawyer, legislator, banker, and railroad builder. He lived the majority of his life in Urbana, Ohio and  graduated from Cincinnati College. As a prominent lawyer in Urbana and an Ohio State Senator from 1835-1839, he supported and advised members of the Whig party in Congress and the General Assembly of Ohio, including his friends William Henry Harrison and Henry Clay. In addition to his law career, James worked as a banker and railroad builder. He was a pioneer in the development of western banking and transportation, building one of the earliest railroads in the United States: the Mad River and Lake Erie Railroad. After attending the Kentucky Military Institute and achieving the rank of Lieutenant-Colonel in 1829, James traveled briefly throughout the Midwest as a land surveyor. As recorded in a contract, during the summer of 1835, he formed a partnership with Indiana's fifth governor, Noah Noble (served 1831-1837), and land agent Captain John Walker to speculate in Indiana land "with a capital of twelve thousand Dollars which is to be procured from the Urbana Bank in the names of Noah Noble and John Walker on notes payable at such times as may be agreed on by the Bank and renewed from time to time until the lands shall be sold, and the partners shall decide it best to pay up the loan." 
</P></p><p><P>
Noah Noble, 1794-1844 was the fifth governor of the state of Indiana. He was born in Clarke County, Virginia, on January 14, 1794. In 1816, he moved to Indiana and settled in Brookville, where he worked in land speculation and wool carding. He joined the 7th Regiment of the Indiana militia as lieutenant colonel in 1817 and was promoted to colonel in 1820. That same year, Noble entered politics. He served as sheriff of Franklin County and was reelected in 1822. He served in the Indiana House of Representatives in 1824. From 1825-1829, he was receiver of public money for the Indianapolis land office; and in 1830, he was the commissioner responsible for the Michigan Road project. Noble was elected to the Indiana governorship in 1831. He was reelected to a second term in 1834 and served until 1837. While governor, Noble established a state bank, revised the state's school system, put an amended tax law into effect, and started the construction of canals and roads across the state. He ran for the U.S. Senate in 1836 and 1838 but was defeated both times. He served on the Internal Improvement Board, 1839-1840, and was a fund commissioner from 1841-1842. He died February 8, 1844, and was buried at the Green Lawn Cemetery. He was later reinterred at the Crown Hill Cemetery in Indianapolis, Indiana.
</P>
 
<P>
The biographical details of Governor Noah Noble were derived from the websites of the National Governors Association and the Indiana Historical Bureau. These biographies were originally accessed 3 April 2007.
</P>
 </p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_231cf5898a35c15ba39f9b12f38a994f">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The James, J. mss. consists of letters, land inventories, and financial papers, ca. 1835-1852, relating to Indiana land investments. These papers were sent to or kept by Indiana land investor John H. James of Urbana, Ohio, including letters from Indiana Governor Noah Noble of Indianapolis, and James' and Noble's land agent John Walker of Shelbyville, Indiana. These records specify many aspects of James' work with Noah Noble, as well as the locations of the tracts they bought and sold, and their purchasers' names.</p><p> Walker invested in specified lots in LaPorte, Fulton, Marshall, and Porter Counties, which Walker or his assistants sold to named individuals for recorded prices. Accompanying these business records and the cancelled notes with which Nobel and Walker made installment payments on the Urbana Bank loan, are 14 quarto letters from Noah Noble, 1836-1844, totaling 42 pages to John H. James on various aspects of their business, and 5 quarto letters from Captain John Walker, 1836-1839, totaling 10 pages, to James on diverse aspects of the same. Noah Noble's death on February 8, 1844, complicated the partnership's resolution; a later notarized copy of his last will and testament is included with the collection.</p><p> Scope and content details provided by Carmen D. Valentino, Catalogue 65, American Historical Manuscripts, Philadelphia, PA.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_5fd3c128e51f5bc5dd1f45df63130ac1">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is arranged following the original order</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_27eaedefb05426ac838518ecbc47a96b">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], James, J. mss., Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="LCSH">Indiana--History</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 audience="internal" id="aspace_24c57a7042085e57a13a3de2ba0b8418" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1835/1852" type="inclusive">1835-1852</unitdate><container id="aspace_45c8a16ebc7e756eba39061e22f7e6e8" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_c8c7b6ed8b674b1c6c6b5945a31dbe29" parent="aspace_45c8a16ebc7e756eba39061e22f7e6e8" type="Folder">1</container></did></c01><c01 audience="internal" id="aspace_b710caae762c3ff796f73c914bae159b" level="file"><did><unittitle>Land Inventory</unittitle><container id="aspace_4f653403c727ed97d21279b0f8263fad" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_fa4c686ff656d8a4d282af91ea44f89a" parent="aspace_4f653403c727ed97d21279b0f8263fad" type="Folder">2</container></did></c01><c01 audience="internal" id="aspace_ef3f983dc83325b9cbeb1d404f1749b2" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial Papers, Loose</unittitle><container id="aspace_27d0fc5719c1436a60de2b1c83d2b2eb" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_297c21b6dc6254933f63bb440e6ecd95" parent="aspace_27d0fc5719c1436a60de2b1c83d2b2eb" type="Folder">3</container></did></c01><c01 audience="internal" id="aspace_4d561c536ad7f51f2943407e3c3b06d8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial Papers, Bound</unittitle><container id="aspace_f2077b73e1d54bbf6d0c53432d0e1eda" label="Mixed Materials" type="Box">1</container><container id="aspace_050d1962d6c0a4a0c3d225e7398191b6" parent="aspace_f2077b73e1d54bbf6d0c53432d0e1eda" type="Folder">4</container></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
