<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="originaldraft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Li-VAD6247</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Cronin mss., <date calendar="gregorian" normal="1957/1958" era="ce">1957-1958</date> <num>LMC 1234</num></titleproper><subtitle>Papers of Anthony Cronin at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana</subtitle><author>Kristina Krasny</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Lilly Library</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/lilly.png" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>6/30/2021</date></p><address><addressline>1200 E. Seventh St.</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-5500</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-2452</addressline><addressline>liblilly@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2017">© 2017</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-18 21:51:51 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>March 10, 2017</date><item>Encoded finding aid created.</item></change><change><date>January 16, 2018</date><item>Edits and rearrangement of content into requisite Lilly EAD structure, including addition of abstract, bioghist, scopecontent, controlaccess, relatedmaterial, and c01 levels of container list. Haley Suby.</item></change><change><date>April 27, 2018</date><item>Batch update to change subject links.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>May 15, 2023</date><item>Duplicate record merged into this one.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Lilly Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Cronin mss.</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="lcnaf">Cronin, Anthony.</persname>
    </origination>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="ingest">Cronin, Anthony</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LMC 1234</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.2 linear feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 box; 4 items.</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1957/1958" type="inclusive">1957-1958</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_940ca9a5478d771874c981942c7970e2">The Cronin mss., 1957-1958, consists of two holograph notebooks, a study of James Joyce, draft of an essay on Joyce's Ulysses, and galley proofs of the first half of the review of Stanislaus Joyce's My Brother's Keeper of author Anthony Cronin, 1923-.</abstract>
    <physloc audience="internal" id="aspace_8d92770540065df268fdf27de3179073">Lilly - Stacks</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_a216eac67739eeb43ba5c48e1bf87980">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_6c21b6418468a58a837df453156cd39e">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p>Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/ask">make an appointment</extref> a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_8a2a4b5e92e4a8ab0221b6d7f2bc3950">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Anthony Cronin, 1923-2016, was a prominent Irish poet and writer. He was born in Enniscorthy, Ireland, 1923. He was associate editor of <title render="italic">The Bell</title> from 1953-1955 and literary editor of <title render="italic">Time and Tide</title> from 1956-1958. He contributed essays to the literary quarterly <title render="italic">X</title>. Among his books are <title render="italic">Poems</title> (1957), <title render="italic">The Life of Riley</title> (1964), and <title render="italic">A Question of Modernity</title> (1966). One of his poems was included in <title render="italic">The Faber Book of Twentieth Century Verse</title> (revised edition of 1966).</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_5e825e2d814264560bd50eac30213296">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is arranged following original order.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_384d1e5d507f361edc06741262e17a00">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The Cronin mss., 1957-1958, consists of two holograph notebooks, a study of James Joyce, draft of an essay on Joyce's Ulysses, and galley proofs of the first half of the review of Stanislaus Joyce's <emph render="italic">My Brother's Keeper</emph> of Anthony Cronin, 1923-2016, author. </p><p> The notebook bound in blue cloth contains seventy-eight pages of notes and drafts of poems, a ten-page prose passage, and a four-page letter to "Dear Mrs. Hutchinson." </p><p> The notebook bound in brown cloth may formerly have been the property of George Barker bearing the words <title render="doublequote">Notebook 1957-58. G.B.</title> on one page. A five-word phrase "This face won no smile" in purple ink on a page about quarter way into the book and a drawing of an erotic nature in pencil on another page near the beginning of the notebook are both attributed to George Barker. All other entries in pencil and blue ink on one hundred and twenty-four pages are in Cronin's hand. They consist of drafts for poems which range from single-line entries to poems, heavily revised, of fifteen or more lines; penciled notes on James Joyce, including a brief study of the early essay <title render="doublequote">Ibsen's New Drama</title>; a check list of books on Joyce; a list of chapter headings for a study of Joyce; brief notes towards reviews of books; and a draft list of twelve chapters of <emph render="italic">Finnegans Wake</emph>. </p><p> The original typescript of the critical and biographical study of James Joyce bears many deletions, revisions, and insertions in the hand of Cronin. The first chapter of twenty-eight pages is entitled <title render="doublequote">God Be With Old Times,</title> and the second chapter of only sixteen pages is entitled <title render="doublequote">Father John Conmee And All</title> is incomplete. A group of nine pages are largely concerned with the autobiographical element in <emph render="italic">Finnegans Wake</emph>. </p><p> Some phrases are underlined on the typescript in red of a draft of an essay on Joyce's <emph render="italic">Ulysses</emph> and page references and twelve words in pencil were added. </p><p> The galley proofs of the first half of Cronin's review of Stanislaus Joyce's <emph render="italic">My Brother's Keeper</emph> as printed in <emph render="italic">Time and Tide</emph>, May 10, 1958, were used for the essay on Joyce's <emph render="italic">Ulysses</emph>. </p><p> For biographical information on Anthony Cronin see L.G. Pine, <emph render="italic">The Authors &amp; Writers Who's Who</emph> (4th ed. London, 1960), p. 87. </p><p> Collection size: 4 items</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_943f0c1fa849a02d0c37a8af90335e77">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Purchase: <date normal="1970">1970</date></p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_3152e40828d01c425d8cb4e44c0be467">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Photography and digitization may be restricted for some collections. Copyright restrictions may apply. Before publishing, researchers are responsible for securing permission from all applicable rights holders, then filling out the <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/permission-to-publish" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest">Permission to Publish form.</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_937a59ee8ebff392f86142548616194b">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Cronin mss., Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Notebooks.</genreform>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Poetry</geogname>
    <subject source="lcsh">Poets</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh85068113" source="lcsh">Irish poetry</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Poets, Irish --20th century --Biography.</subject>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Cronin, Anthony</persname>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Joyce, James, 1882-1941</persname>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Joyce, James, 1882-1941. Ulysses.</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAD8236-00001" level="item"><did><unittitle>Notebook</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_c13163af8659acb118f8bfda7d655017"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Bound in blue cloth. Contains seventy-eight pages of notes and drafts of poems, a ten-page prose passage, and a four-page letter to "Dear Mrs. Hutchinson."</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD8236-00002" level="item"><did><unittitle>Notebook</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1957/1958" type="inclusive">1957-1958</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_ea7bd2d4e70b9c8ecc56930168ec1911"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Bound in brown cloth. May formerly have been the property of George Barker. Bearing the words "Notebook 1957-58. G.B." on one page. A five-word phrase "This face won no smile" in purple ink on a page about quarter way into the book and a drawing of an erotic nature in pencil on another page near the beginning of the notebook are both attributed to George Barker. All other entries in pencil and blue ink on one hundred and twenty-four pages are in Cronin's hand. They consist of drafts for poems which range from single-line entries to poems, heavily revised, of fifteen or more lines; penciled notes on James Joyce, including a brief study of the early essay "Ibsen's New Drama"; a check list of books on Joyce; a list of chapter headings for a study of Joyce; brief notes towards reviews of books; and a draft list of twelve chapters of <title render="italic">Finnegans Wake</title>.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD8236-00003" level="item"><did><unittitle>Typescript</unittitle></did><scopecontent id="aspace_966f0316148bb30ae7814c9668386916"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The original typescript of the critical and biographical study of James Joyce bears many deletions, revisions, and insertions in the hand of Cronin. The first chapter of twenty-eight pages is entitled "God Be With Old Times," and the second chapter of only sixteen pages is entitled "Father John Conmee And All" is incomplete. A group of nine pages are largely concerned with the autobiographical element in <title render="italic">Finnegans Wake</title>.</p><p> Some phrases are underlined on the typescript in red of a draft of an essay on Joyce's Ulysses and page references and twelve words in pencil were added.</p></scopecontent></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD8236-00004" level="item"><did><unittitle>Galley proofs</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1958/1958">1958</unitdate></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6f4c5492618fbfdb2b421ea03b593277"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>The galley proofs of the first half of Cronin's review of Stanislaus Joyce'e My Brother's Keeper as printed in Time and Tide, May 10, 1958, were used for the essay on Joyce's Ulysses.</p></scopecontent></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
