<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="originaldraft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Li-VAD6426</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Gissing mss., <date normal="1863/1958" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1863-1958</date> <num>LMC 2218</num></titleproper><subtitle>Papers of Various at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana</subtitle><author>Electronic finding aid encoded by Indiana University Libraries.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Lilly Library</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/lilly.png" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2018</date></p><address><addressline>1200 E. Seventh St.</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-5500</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-2452</addressline><addressline>liblilly@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2018">© 2018</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-18 22:12:28 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>March 10, 2017</date><item>Encoded finding aid created.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>August 2, 2018</date><item>Edits and rearrangement of content into requisite Lilly EAD structure, including addition of abstract, bioghist, scopecontent, controlaccess, relatedmaterial, and c01 levels of container list. Madison Chartier.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Lilly Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Gissing mss.</unittitle>
    <unitid>LMC 2218</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">5 Boxes</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">5 standard</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <physdesc altrender="part">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 bound</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1863/1958" type="inclusive">1863-1958</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_4951ad2c0a54209688f5b34c54fa2228">The Gissing mss., 1863-1958, consist of correspondence, financial records, writings, photographs, and miscellaneous materials by and about writer George Robert Gissing, 1857-1903.</abstract>
    <physloc audience="internal" id="aspace_a4302cd7c4acf95975a488afb15b1ff7">Lilly - Stacks</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_aba20ec8b0bd6368913f233d3491a2ee">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_a878e10f0f9a2f6f77bf738277c2e8f1">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p>Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/ask">make an appointment</extref> a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_d3841e7f65b2644993c88b64180192a1">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>The Gissing mss., 1863-1958 consists of correspondence and writings by English novelist George Gissing (1857-1903). Born in Yorkshire, Gissing studied at Back Lane School in Wakefield and then at Owens College, where he had won a scholarship. His tenure at the school and his academic career as a student famously ended when he fell in love with Marianne Helen Harrison; his relationship with her, starting to drain him of money, tempted him to steal from fellow students, and he was found guilty and expelled from Owens College. In the 1870s, Gissing moved to the United States, spending time tutoring and teaching in classics as well as writing short stories for American newspapers. Such experiences collectively informed many of his novelistic works, including <emph render="italic">Workers in the Dawn</emph> (1880), <emph render="italic">Thyrza</emph> (1887), and <emph render="italic">New Grub Street</emph> (1889). Stylistically, these and Gissing's other novels are known for their naturalism, gritty realism, and thematic confrontations of poverty, sexuality, and marital discontent.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_d9f1ff31f9f9d923b0ca90d2474f4007">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The contents of this collection are arranged into two series, based on the provenance of the contributed materials: I. Gissing Papers &amp; II. Pforzheimer Collection.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_39e85f6bbef2231fab90a6b7ca884cfc">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The Gissing mss., 1863-1958, consist of correspondence, financial records, writings, photographs, and miscellaneous materials by and about writer George Robert Gissing, 1857-1903. This collection documents his own emphasis on writing as a business and shows that, following his death, Gissing's family continued to regard his works in the same way. </p><p> Correspondence includes Gissing's earliest known letter, written to his father on July 21, 1863. It begins, "Mi der farter," and ends, "kind luv and kisis to yo mi der Further... Gog robut Gising." In addition to an extensive file of letters to his brother, Algernon, there are also several letters from Gissing to his sister, Ellen, and a few letters to his son, Walter. Gissing also wrote frequently to his two literary agents, William Morris Colles, 1855-1926, and later, James Brand Pinker, 1863-1922. Other correspondents in the collection include Arthur Henry Bullen, Edward Clodd, William Leonard Courtney, Alfred Charles Gissing, Frederic Harrison, Jerome Klapka Jerome, Otto Kyllman, William Maxse Meredith, Sir Algernon Marshall Stedman Methuen, and George Herbert Thring. </p><p> The later correspondence (1931-1958) provides information about the provenance of individual items in the collection and includes letters between collector Carl H. Pforzheimer and members of the Gissing family. </p><p> Gissing's financial records include statements from Colles' agency, called the Authors' Syndicate, 1893-1899; and Gissing's own literary accounts, 1899-1901. </p><p> Writings present include an autograph draft manuscript of <title render="italic">An Author at Grass: The Private Papers of Henry Ryecroft</title>, the only known extant copy. Accompanying it is a 1903 edition of the book carrying penciled notations about variances with the manuscript. Other manuscripts in the collection include a few items of juvenalia, supporting the impression that Gissing chose early on to make writing his life's work. [See separate listing in Vertical File for Gissing's writings that are present in the collection.] In addition to the manuscripts by George Gissing, there is also a short biographical piece written by Gissing's son, Alfred Charles Gissing (1891-1975), titled <title render="doublequote">Frederic Harrison and George Gissing.</title> </p><p> The collection includes two photographs of George Gissing, one being a formal studio portrait taken by Elliott &amp; Fry and the other being a posed snapshot. </p><p> The last item in the collection is a scrapbook compiled by George Gissing, consisting of fragments or story ideas, clippings from various sources on topics of interest to him, and miscellaneous notes and lists he devised, all probably for use in creating characters or scenes in his fiction. [See Vertical File for a more complete description of the contents of the scrapbook.]</p>  </scopecontent>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_1aff17d9150118a182a592724bae29da">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Purchase: <date normal="1992" type="acquisition">1992</date></p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_7f111a099bc2cab386621eac6158abb9">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Photography and digitization may be restricted for some collections. Copyright restrictions may apply. Before publishing, researchers are responsible for securing permission from all applicable rights holders, then filling out the <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/permission-to-publish" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest">Permission to Publish form.</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_fec9806d87164d307726d4a449699318">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Gissing mss., Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="ingest">English literature</subject>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Naturalism in literature</genreform>
    <genreform source="lcsh">Three-decker novels</genreform>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Bullen, A. H. (Arthur Henry), 1857-1920</persname>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Clodd, Edward, 1840-1930</persname>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Colles, William Morris, 1855-1926</persname>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Courtney, W. L. (William Leonard), 1850-1928</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Gissing, Alfred Charles</persname>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Gissing, Algernon, 1860-1937</persname>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Gissing, George, 1857-1903</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Gissing, Ellen</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Gissing, Walter</persname>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Harrison, Frederic, 1831-1923</persname>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Jerome, Jerome K. (Jerome Klapka), 1859-1927</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Kyllman, Otto</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Meredith, William Maxse, 1865-1937</persname>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Methuen, Algernon, 1856-1924</persname>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Pinker, James B.</persname>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Thring, George Herbert, 1859-1941</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc/>
</archdesc>
</ead>
