<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Li-VAD7061</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Southey mss. II, <date calendar="gregorian" normal="1834/1843" era="ce">1834-1843</date> <num>LMC 2091</num></titleproper><subtitle>Papers of Robert Southey, 1834-1843, at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana</subtitle><author>Electronic finding aid encoded by Indiana University Libraries.</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Lilly Library</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/lilly.png" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2017</date></p><address><addressline>1200 E. Seventh St.</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-5500</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-2452</addressline><addressline>liblilly@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2017">© 2017</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-18 22:21:52 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>March 10, 2017</date><item>Encoded finding aid created.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>September 25, 2017</date><item>Edits and rearrangement of content into requisite Lilly EAD structure, including addition of abstract, bioghist, scopecontent, controlaccess, relatedmaterial, and c01 levels of container list. Haley Suby.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>April 27, 2018</date><item>Batch update to change subject links.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>October 30, 2020</date><item>Finding aid enhancement project: update to bio note. Kyra Triebold</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Lilly Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Southey mss. II</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="ingest">Southey, Robert, 1774-1843</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LMC 2091</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">7 bound</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1834/1843" type="inclusive">1834-1843</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_9c6544ce1a33295892f388c7f684c8a9">The Southey mss., II, 1834-1843, consist of poet Robert Southey's own annotated copy of his only published work of fiction <title render="italic">The Doctor, &amp;c</title> (London: Longman, Rees, Orme, Brown, Green and Longman, 1834-1847).</abstract>
    <physloc audience="internal" id="aspace_a791d7904d8bd805ecd25b06643afbd5">Lilly - Stacks</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_25aee24990b06a650e54e6fe768d712a">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English.</language></langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_83691a98159b592adeec81b379b72298">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p>Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/ask">make an appointment</extref> a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_38865c1d253027975255d51d315ea1bd">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Robert Southey, 1774-1843, was an English poet whose work fell within the Romantic school. He was part of the "Lake Poets" group and was friends with poets William Wordsworth and Samuel Taylor Coleridge. Despite his vocal support for the French Revolution at the beginning of his career and his initial reputation as a radical, he served as poet laureate of the United Kingdom from 1813 to 1843 and was subsequently derided by his contemporaries for his support of the Tory establishment. His prolific output included poetry, reviews, and histories, but his poetic reputation rests on his "exotic" epic poems, including <title render="italic">Thalaba the Destroyer</title> (1801), <title render="italic">Madoc</title> (1805), <title render="italic">The Curse of Kehama</title> (1810), and <title render="italic">Roderick the Last of the Goths</title> (1814).</p><p>Born the son of a Bristol linen draper, he was expelled from Westminster school for producing with his friends a satirical magazine, the <title render="italic">Flagellant,</title> in 1792, which included a critique of the school's system of corporal punishment. Afterwards he matriculated at Balliol College, Oxford. In addition to <title render="italic">Wat Tyler,</title> a poem about the 1381 English peasant rebellion, and <title render="italic">Joan of Arc,</title> a poem in which the eponymous Joan of Arc defends France from English invaders, and in 1794 he coauthored with Samuel Taylor Coleridge the play <title render="italic">The Fall of Robespierre.</title> He and Coleridge also planned to set up a utopian "Pantisocracy" in Pennsylvania, a plan that never materialized due to lack of funds. Instead, in 1795, Southey married seamstress Edith Fricker and Coleridge married Fricker's sister Sara, and in 1800 the two couples settled at Greta Hall in the Lake District in Spain. Southey would remain there for the rest of his life as one of the "Lake Poets."</p><p>Southey learned Spanish and Portuguese and began translating literature from these languages into English as well as writing Spanish and Portuguese literary biographies. The Peninsular War (1807-1814), during which the UK assisted Spain and Portugal against the invasion of Napoleon, turned Southey's sympathies toward the Tory establishment. He began writing for the conservative <title render="italic">Quarterly Review,</title> and in 1813, Southey accepted the post of poet laureate of the United Kingdom. For his political turn he was criticized by William Hazlitt and parodied ruthlessly by Lord Byron in <title render="italic">The Vision of Judgment</title> (1822).</p><p><title render="italic">The Doctor,</title> a 7-volume miscellany containing Southey's observations on a wide variety of subjects, was written during a period of Southey's declining mental faculties due to old age. Robert Southey died in 1843 at Greta Hall, and the last two volumes of The Doctor were published posthumously.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_6ed02522c8eb51f245a4df0c6e4af191">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The Southey mss., II, 1834-1843, consist of poet Robert Southey's own annotated copy of his only published work of fiction <title render="italic">The Doctor, &amp;c</title> (London: Longman, Rees, Orme, Brown, Green and Longman, 1834-1847). Volumes 1-5 were published anonymously between 1834 and 1838; volumes 6-7, edited by Southey's nephew, John Wood Warter, appeared posthumously in 1847. The first five volumes are marked by Southey, apparently with the intention of producing a second edition, and include a detailed note about type sizes, suggested word changes and insertions, and some quotations from other writers. Most of the notes are appended to pages of the book but some are on inserted slips of paper. A small photograph of an unidentified woman is loosely laid in vol. 2, between pages 246-247. [Lilly PR5464 .D6 1834 copy 2]</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_2300c73b7fda9c757c181849b1e2c379">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>See Southey mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_37bec7ade785d2c61f655dc7609b25cb">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Purchase: <date normal="1995">1995</date></p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_b2fcf880aecc99dbdf3518482311da6a">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Photography and digitization may be restricted for some collections. Copyright restrictions may apply. Before publishing, researchers are responsible for securing permission from all applicable rights holders, then filling out the <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/permission-to-publish" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest">Permission to Publish form.</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_003a8211e912124a162c5f1fb54e0433">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Southey mss. II, Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject authfilenumber="https://id.loc.gov/authorities/subjects/sh85043932.html" source="lcsh">English Poetry</subject>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Southey, Robert, 1774-1843</persname>
    <persname source="ingest">Warter, John Wood</persname>
    <persname source="lcnaf">Southey, Robert, 1774-1843. Doctor</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAD7061-00001" level="collection"><did><unittitle>Southey mss., II, 1834-1843</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_VAD7061-00002" level="item"><did><unittitle>Published anonymously between 1834 and 1838 and marked by Southey, apparently with the intention of producing a second edition. Include a detailed note about type sizes, suggested word changes and insertions, and some quotations from other writers.</unittitle><container id="aspace_ae12aabad6a54bc40723b40b4e91af9c" label="volumes" type="item">1-5</container></did><odd id="aspace_d31104e7996396f7ddbe0c7cbe831d52"><head>General</head><p>A small photograph of an unidentified woman is loosely laid-in vol. 2, between pages 246-247.</p></odd></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAD7061-00003" level="item"><did><unittitle>Edited by Southey's nephew, John Wood Warter; appeared posthumously in 1847.</unittitle><container id="aspace_60323befec13358aeb87f43dd56c82ac" label="volumes" type="item">6-7</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
