<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="originaldraft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Li-VAD6619</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper type="filing">Kimball mss., 1828-1908</titleproper><titleproper>Kimball mss., 1828-1908 <num>LMC 1583</num></titleproper><subtitle>Papers of Various, 1828-1908, at the Lilly Library, Indiana University</subtitle><author>Alyssa Mertka</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Lilly Library</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/lilly.png" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>12/1/2020</date></p><address><addressline>1200 E. Seventh St.</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-5500</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-2452</addressline><addressline>liblilly@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p>Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-02-18 22:17:19 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>March 10, 2017</date><item>Encoded finding aid created.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>February 5, 2019</date><item>Edits and rearrangement of content into requisite Lilly EAD structure, including addition of abstract, bioghist, scopecontent, controlaccess, and c01 levels of container list. Mahaley Evans.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Lilly Library</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Kimball mss.</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname source="lcnaf">Kimball, Nathan, 1823?-1898</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LMC 1583</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 Boxes</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1828/1908" type="inclusive">1828-1908</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_b750c1e9301a1a19c3c589814d7b8725">The Kimball mss., 1828-1908, consists of the letters and papers of physician and soldier Nathan Kimball, 1822-1898.</abstract>
    <physloc audience="internal" id="aspace_30a23d6779e2ffc5ab0d8624faeee5b6">ALF (Auxiliary Library Facility)</physloc>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_1e055be876850e5af3f44bd353a7f81f">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_633c88218105661ac7d828dbcd5ac136">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p>Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/ask">make an appointment</extref> a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <userestrict id="aspace_0eba8edf98dba13cf5cc02886baf484a">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Photography and digitization may be restricted for some collections. Copyright restrictions may apply. Before publishing, researchers are responsible for securing permission from all applicable rights holders, then filling out the <extref xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/lilly-library/permission-to-publish" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onrequest">Permission to Publish form.</extref></p>  </userestrict>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_cf042fd0b0509d92d208eb1477158e25">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Purchase: <unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate></p>  </acqinfo>
  <bioghist id="aspace_36eecc3446add4968e854664a14d4ab0">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>Nathan Kimball, 1822-1898, was an Indiana physician and a Major General in the American Civil War. He was born on November 22, 1822 in Fredericksburg, Posey Township, Washington County, Indiana. He matriculated in 1839 at Asbury College but did not graduate. In 1841 after leaving college he taught school in Independence, Missouri, for a time and tried farming before undertaking the study of medicine in 1843. In May, 1846 he raised in his native town a company known as the Posey Guards, for service in the Mexican War, which became Company G of the 2nd Regiment of Indiana volunteers, of which Kimball was commissioned captain. This company served in the battle of Buena Vista.</p><p> In 1847 Kimball was mustered out of the service at New Orleans and returned to Indiana. At the outbreak of the Civil War he was practicing medicine at Loogootee, Martin County, Indiana. Immediately upon the receipt of the news of the fall of Fort Sumter he recruited a company of volunteers in Martin County, which was assigned as part of the 14th Indiana Volunteer Infantry, of which Kimball was commissioned colonel on May 22, 1861. Kimball served throughout the war rising to the rank of Brevet Major General. He saw service in the Shenandoah Valley, in the Army of the Potomac, in the Vicksburg campaign, in Arkansas, and in the Army of the Cumberland. In Arkansas in 1864 after the capture of Little Rock he was placed in charge of the registering of loyal citizens preparatory to the reorganization of the Arkansas state government.</p><p> Following his discharge on August 24, 1865 Kimball returned to Indiana in which state he helped to organize the Grand Army of the Republic and became its state commander. He was elected Indiana state treasurer in 1866 and 1868 and a member of the state legislature in 1872. On Dec. 27, 1873 Kimball was appointed surveyor general of Utah by General Grant. He lived in Utah for the remainder of his life, holding an appointment as postmaster of Ogden City from 1879 until his death on January 21, 1898.</p>  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_84339e7a5fa72c57b5e439d2377bd2c3">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The Kimball mss. include in the main papers relating to the services of the Posey Guards in the Mexican War and papers relating to Kimball's Civil War service. The Civil War papers relate particularly to the campaigns in which he took part in Virginia, Tennessee, Mississippi and Arkansas, and are to a large extent of an official military nature, including many orders, letters from superior officers, etc. There are, in addition, some non-military papers of the Indiana and Utah periods of his life. </p><p> A number of prominent persons are represented in the collection, including two presidents of the United States, Ulysses Simpson Grant and Rutherford Birchard Hayes; three governors of Indiana, James Whitcomb, Oliver Perry Morton, and Conrad Baker; some other political figures, Joseph Lane, James C. Denny, William H. H. Terrell, Richard Wigginton Thompson, David McKendree Key, Robert James Walker, John Wanamaker; numerous Civil War generals, William Henry French, Oliver Otis Howard, Stephen Augustus Hurlbut, Richard James Oglesby, Joseph Jones Reynolds, William Starke Rosecrans, John McAllister Schofield, Philip Henry Sheridan, William Tecumseh Sherman, David Sloan Stanley, Frederick Steele, John Milton Thayer, George Henry Thomas, Cadwallader Colden Washburn, James Grant Wilson, Oliver Morris Wilson, and Thomas John Wood; two physicians, James S. Athon and Frisby S. Newcomer; and a lawyer, Elijah H.C. Cavins.</p><p> The collection contains manuscript maps of Cheat Mountain, the Vicksburg campaign, Peach Tree Creek, and Snake River.</p><p> See the reference to the Kimball mss. in Herman J. Viola, "Zachary Taylor and the Indiana Volunteers," <emph render="italic">Southwestern Historical Quarterly </emph> 72:3 (January 1969), pp. 335-346.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <arrangement id="aspace_91ffeb5badf0f77b0d8a9ebe0801f7bc">
    <head>Arrangement </head>
<p>This collection is arranged following original order.</p>  </arrangement>
  <prefercite id="aspace_e2c6a08369fcb5377bedd999c5ba79b7">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Kimball mss., Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.</p>  </prefercite>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="ingest">Indiana--Politics and government</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Medicine</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865</subject>
    <geogname authfilenumber="sh85140246" source="lcsh">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Maps</geogname>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh2008109959" source="lcsh">Presidents -- United States -- Correspondence</subject>
    <subject authfilenumber="sh85140201" source="lcsh">Mexican War, 1846-1848</subject>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAD6619-00001" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1828/1864" type="inclusive">1828-1864</unitdate><container id="aspace_bff99c5f8d0b2e7ef13bf5a5f2341134" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD6619-00003" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1865/1908" type="inclusive">1865-1908</unitdate><container id="aspace_c402377358558d83f4357799b0c28b7d" label="box" type="Box">2</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD6619-00004" level="file"><did><unittitle>Certificate electing Nathan Kimball "to the office of Captain of the Company called the Posey Guards in the Indiana Volunteers, raised in the said State under the Act of Congress entitled, 'An Act providing for the prosecution of the existing War between the United States and the Republic of Mexico,' approved May 13, 1846" signed by Indiana governor, James Whitcomb.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1846-06-09/1846-06-09">June 9, 1846</unitdate><container id="aspace_36609238a981400b9bc99ec9929e02a0" label="oversize" type="oversize">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD6619-00005" level="file"><did><unittitle>Appraisel of "damages done by United States troops (Cavalry) (under command of General Kimball) in breaking into his house."</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1861-10-07/1861-10-07">October 7, 1861</unitdate><container id="aspace_fe5aa77c9da3e435b6ff5358f3415600" label="oversize" type="oversize">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD6619-00006" level="file"><did><unittitle>Abstract of ordnance and ordnance stores received by Col. Nathan Kimball commanding 14th Regiment Indiana Volunteer Infantry.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1861/1861">1861</unitdate><container id="aspace_d21d63b07abaef939a25265f3402e2f9" label="oversize" type="oversize">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD6619-00007" level="file"><did><unittitle>Abstract of ordnance and ordnance stores issued by Col. Nathan Kimball commanding 14th Regiment Indiana Volunteer Infantry.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1861/1861">1861</unitdate><container id="aspace_2e7621198c389bc1b6ce905fc9c31df0" label="oversize" type="oversize">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD6619-00008" level="file"><did><unittitle>Quarterly return of ordnance and ordnance stores received, issues, and remaining on hand by Col. Nathan Kimball commanding 14th Regiment Indiana Volunteer Infantry.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1861/1861">1861</unitdate><container id="aspace_8e5d90be4a5a52bbdaf67412cda6fb31" label="oversize" type="oversize">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD6619-00009" level="file"><did><unittitle>Rutherford B. Hayes appointing Nathan Kimball as postmaster at Ogden City, Weber County, Utah.</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1879-08-23/1879-08-23">August 23, 1879</unitdate><container id="aspace_9a7cec5515d69710a706f6636f3304f3" label="oversize" type="oversize">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD6619-00010" level="file"><did><unittitle>"...a narrative of the part performed by our old division in the war against rebellion which will recall memories of weary marches, and hardfought battles in the mountains and valleys of West Virginia, and in the beautiful valley of the Shenandoah..."</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1887/1887">1887?</unitdate><container id="aspace_94df78db256b4d5d3292662e6ae14e00" label="oversize" type="oversize">1</container></did></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAD6619-00011" level="file"><did><unittitle>Maps</unittitle><container id="aspace_e55c2cfeaf48a3a331ee5466ecf83106" label="oversize" type="oversize">1</container></did></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
