<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">VAC3310</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>The W.A. Whitten Collection, <date normal="1962/1991">1962-1991</date> <num>LCP2009/004</num></titleproper><author>Electronic finding aid encoded by Megan MacDonald</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Liberian Collections</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/lcp.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>2012</date></p><address><addressline>Indiana University</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405</addressline><addressline>afstlib@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/african-studies" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/african-studies" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-03-03 21:05:09 -0500</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Liberian Collections</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle><persname>The W.A. Whitten</persname> Collection</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname authfilenumber="no2013115024" rules="rda" source="ingest">Whitten, W.A., Jr.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>LCP2009/004</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2 cubic feet;</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">2 records cartons; 86 artifacts; 669 color transparencies</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1962/1991" type="inclusive">1962-1991</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_33d51a7d39cd3ef8a4d42f7faffb945d">Willie A. Whitten completed his Ed.D. from Indiana University in 1966. He made several trips to Liberia throughout the 1960s and 1970s as a United States Agency for International Development (USAID) worker in order to gather research for his dissertation. His research interests include education in Liberian villages with an emphasis on adult education and the conducting and planning of town meetings. This collection consists of newspaper and magazine articles from Liberia, government reports, and materials from the Voinjama School District, as well as 11 open reel tape recordings of town meetings and music from Liberian tribes. Also included are a collection of color transparencies showing images of tribal villages and culture, as well as a set of 86 artifacts containing items such as musical instruments, household tools, textiles, and decorative figurines.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_8ca98bfbce47e39beafcd3d9794b6df8">Materials are primarily in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_e7500bab21aecffe30afd673b39779fb">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Closed for research.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_20088eea4ef22e22f1531c38c558fe05">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p><persname>Willie Amzie Whitten, Jr.</persname>, was born on <date normal="19290814"> August 14, 1929</date>, in a small rural community in <geogname normal="Choctaw County (Miss.) " source="lcsh"> Choctaw County, Mississippi </geogname>. His formal education began at Weir High School, from which he graduated in <date normal="1946">1946</date>. He attended <corpname normal="Mississippi College" source="lcnaf">Mississippi College</corpname> during the <date normal="1946/1947"> 1946-1947</date> academic year and served in the <corpname normal="United States. Army. " source="lcnaf"> United States Army</corpname> in <date normal="1947">1947</date>. Whitten married <persname>Anna Lucille Stinnett</persname> from <geogname>Addison, Kentucky</geogname>, on <date normal="19480606">June 6, 1948</date>. They enrolled in <corpname normal="Mississippi College" source="lcnaf">Mississippi College</corpname> together in September,<date normal="1948"> 1948</date>, and graduated in June, <date normal="1951">1951</date>. Thereafter, Willie attended the <corpname normal="Southern Baptist Theological Seminary" source="lcnaf">Southern Baptist Theological Seminary</corpname> in <geogname source="lcnaf" normal="Louisville (Ky.) ">Louisville, Kentucky</geogname> and received a Bachelor of Divinity degree in <date normal="1954">1954</date>. </p><p> From <date normal="1956/1963">1956 to 1963</date>, <persname>Whitten</persname> served as associate director of the <corpname normal="Southern Baptist Convention. Seminary Extension Dept. " source="lcnaf">Seminary Extension Department of the Southern Baptist Convention</corpname>. His main duties were establishing and operating adult religious education learning centers in <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Mississippi"> Mississippi</geogname>, <geogname normal="Tennessee" source="lcsh">Tennessee</geogname>, <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Kentucky">Kentucky</geogname>, <geogname normal="Louisiana" source="lcsh">Louisiana</geogname> and <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Texas">Texas</geogname>. Other duties included curriculum development and the preparation of course-writing guides.</p><p> <persname>Whitten</persname> began a doctoral program in adult education at <corpname normal="Indiana University" source="lcnaf"> Indiana University</corpname> in <date normal="1959"> 1959</date>. In <date normal="1963">1963</date>, while completing his graduate studies, <persname>Whitten </persname> accepted an assignment to <geogname normal="Liberia" source="lcsh">Liberia</geogname> with the <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="United States. Agency for International Development"> United States Agency for International Development (USAID)</corpname> to conduct research that would address the urgent educational needs of people living in traditional communities in rural <geogname normal="Liberia">Liberia</geogname>. The goal of his research was to discover ways for educational leaders and other visitors to improve the use of town meetings for educational purposes. He found the research to be valuable not only in <geogname normal=" Liberia" source="lcsh">Liberia</geogname> at the time, but in similar circumstances in other developing nations in the years that followed. His four-year assignment in <geogname normal="Liberia" source="lcsh"> Liberia</geogname> provided a rare opportunity for Whitten and changed the direction of his dissertation research and his professional career. He graduated with a doctorate in education in <geogname normal="1966">1966</geogname>.</p><p> During the early stages of his research, <persname>Whitten</persname> began an informal collection of rice farming tools, musical instruments, small furniture and other artifacts and items that were in use by the traditional peoples with whom he worked. Priority was given to items commonly recognized, accepted and in actual use at the time. These items would form part of the <title>W.A. Whitten Collection</title>, which he donated to the <corpname normal="Indiana University" source="lcnaf">Indiana University</corpname> Liberian Collections in <date normal="2009">2009</date>.</p><p> <persname>Whitten</persname> received career status in the <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="Diplomatic and consular service">Foreign Service</corpname> in <date normal="1965"> 1965</date> while on assignment in <geogname normal="Liberia" source="lcsh">Liberia</geogname>, and was later commissioned as a <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="Diplomatic and consular service">Foreign Service </corpname> Officer. During his career of nearly twenty-five years, he achieved the personal rank of FS-1 before retiring in <date normal="1987">1987</date>. <persname>Whitten</persname> had two assignments at <corpname normal=" United States. Agency for International Development" source="lcnaf"> USAID Washington</corpname> and four separate assignments to foreign posts. The first was to <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Liberia"> Liberia</geogname>, as described above. This was followed by two years in <geogname normal="Tanzania. " source="lcsh">Tanzania</geogname> from <date normal="1968/1970">1968 to 1970</date>, two years in <geogname normal="Afghanistan. " source="lcsh">Afghanistan</geogname> from <date normal="1970/1972"> 1970 to 1972</date> and a second assignment to <geogname normal="Liberia" source="lcsh">Liberia</geogname> for over three years from <date normal="1977/1981">1977 to 1981</date>. Additionally, he was given numerous short-term assignments overseas to Anglophone countries in <geogname normal="Africa" source="lcsh">Africa</geogname> and parts of <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Asia">Asia</geogname>.</p><p> This variety of overseas experiences brought the Whittens in close personal and professional relationships with many foreign leaders and local citizens. Occasionally, <persname>Whitten's</persname> work led to contacts with senior government officials and, in some instances, heads of state. However, the typical experience was with local government ministries, donor agencies of other governments, and private organizations, in the design and implementation of joint project undertakings involving <corpname normal="United States. Agency for International Development" source="lcnaf"> USAID</corpname> funding. <persname>Whitten</persname> welcomed cross-cultural exchanges throughout his career, and focused in particular on advocating and testing new educational technologies and approaches for their use in local communities. </p><p> <persname>Whitten</persname> is currently busy in retirement in the <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Atlanta (Ga.) ">Atlanta, Georgia</geogname> area. He remains active in the <corpname normal="American Foreign Service Association. " source="lcnaf"> American Foreign Service Association</corpname> (AFSA) and returns to the <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="United States. Dept. of State">Department of State </corpname>for Foreign Affairs Day in early May of each year. From <date normal="1991/2002">1991 to 2002</date>, he served as State Chaplain of the Georgia Good Sams, a national association of campers. Willie and Lucille Whitten continue to be active in the <corpname>Johns Creek Baptist Church</corpname> and other community organizations.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_217d8ef0b250c9b3fec907f72493b0ac">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The W.A. Whitten Collection is organized into three series:</p>    <list type="ordered">
      <item>Printed materials</item>
      <item>Audiovisual</item>
      <item>Artifacts</item>
    </list>
<p>.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_cdea571cd9559dbc2d7c5180cfb015f5">
    <head><emph render="bold">Scope and Content</emph></head>
<p>The <title>W.A. Whitten Collection</title> spans the period from <date normal="1962/1991" type="inclusive">1962-1991</date> and is organized into three series: <emph render="bold">Printed Materials</emph>, <emph render="bold"> Audiovisual</emph>, and <emph render="bold">Artifacts</emph>. </p><p>  The <emph render="bold">Printed Materials</emph> series contains the sub-series <emph render="italic">Published Materials</emph>, <emph render="italic"> Government Reports</emph>, and <emph render="italic">School Materials</emph>. All items are organized alphabetically by the author's last name. If an author is unavailable, the title is used instead. <emph render="italic">Published Materials</emph> includes books and articles from newspapers, magazines, and journals published in <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Liberia">Liberia</geogname> or covering topics pertinent to Liberian culture or history. Dates span <date normal="1964/1991">1964-1991</date>. The <emph render="italic">Government Reports</emph> sub-series contains an economic survey from <date normal="1962">1962</date>, some of <persname source="lcnaf" normal="Tolbert, William R., 1913-1980 ">William Tolbert</persname>'s presidential papers, and education reports. The sub-series spans <date normal="1962/1983"> 1962-1983</date>. <emph render="italic">School Materials</emph> include an annual report, commencement exercises, and a student tribute program to President <persname source="lcnaf" normal="Tubman, William V. S.,--1895-1971. ">Tubman</persname>, all from the <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Voinjama (Liberia)">Voinjama District</geogname> spanning 1963-1977.</p><p> The <emph render="bold">Audiovisual</emph> series contains two sub-series: <emph render="italic">Open Reel Tape</emph> and <emph render="italic">Color Transparencies</emph>. The <emph render="italic">Open Reel Tape</emph> sub-series contains 11 reels of open reel tapes with recorded town meetings and music from Liberian villages. Dates span <date normal="1965/1977"> 1965-1977</date>. Tapes are numbered and arranged as received by <persname>Whitten</persname>. There are 669 color transparencies that have been digitized and are available through the <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="Indiana University">Indiana University</corpname> Image Collections Online. These slides are largely images of Liberian villages and include topics such as village life, parades and processions, town landscapes, dancers, musicians, agricultural facilities, art and handicrafts, village leaders, and rituals. Images span <date normal="1961/1978">1961-1978</date>. </p><p> The <emph render="bold">Artifacts</emph> series includes physical objects brought back from Liberia by Willie and Lucille Whitten. Examples of objects include textiles, tools, musical instruments, masks, and decorative carvings. These artifacts are cataloged and stored by the <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="William Hammond Mathers Museum (Bloomington, Ind.)">Mathers Museum of World Cultures</corpname> at <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="Indiana University">Indiana University</corpname>. The dates of these objects are unknown. They are arranged alphabetically according to subject, with descriptions and sub-categories provided by <persname>Whitten</persname>.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_683d10c62da9e75d319bd954c71aba40">
    <head>Separated Materials</head>
<p>A total of 86 artifacts and textiles are housed at the <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="William Hammond Mathers Museum (Bloomington, Ind.)">Mathers Museum of World Cultures</corpname>. Color transparencies have been digitized and all 669 are available online through the <corpname normal="Indiana University" source="lcnaf">Indiana University </corpname><extref xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/images/public-index.htm"> Image Collections Online</extref>, courtesy of the <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="Indiana University. Digital Library Program">Indiana University Digital Library Program</corpname>. <persname>Willie A. Whitten's</persname> dissertation is available upon request at the <corpname normal="Indiana University" source="lcnaf"> Indiana University</corpname> Auxiliary Library Facility.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <userestrict id="aspace_c97c660dc308eb061337a70cdd25d478">
    <head>User Restrictions</head>
<p>All research at the Liberian Collections Project is <emph render="underline"> by appointment only. </emph></p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_f016ad551e7c6e92e012bd4cdccae4a9">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[item], <title>W.A. Whitten Collection</title>, <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Bloomington (Ind.) ">Bloomington, IN</geogname>: Liberian Collections, <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="Indiana University. Libraries. ">Indiana University Libraries</corpname>, <date normal="2009">2009</date>.</p>  </prefercite>
  <custodhist id="aspace_d68e409e994a57eb447dc78bae4ae21d">
    <head>Copyright Transferred</head>
<p>Copyright interests for this collection have been transferred to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, contact the Indiana University Liberian Collections.</p>  </custodhist>
  <custodhist id="aspace_528d93ac7c37472c3f28ae642c22f49d">
    <head>Custodial History</head>
<p>Materials were collected during <persname>Whitten's</persname> visits to <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Liberia">Liberia</geogname> in the <date normal="1960/1979">1960s and 1970s</date> and were donated to the <corpname normal="Indiana University" source="lcnaf">Indiana University</corpname> Liberian Collections in <date normal="2009">2009</date>.</p>  </custodhist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_e3310c1d916ef09ddb2549eb692e1247">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Alison Reynolds. </p><p> Completed in <date normal="2012">2012</date>.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Liberia</geogname>
    <geogname source="lcsh">Voinjama (Liberia)</geogname>
    <persname authfilenumber="no2013115024" rules="rda" source="ingest">Whitten, W.A., Jr.</persname>
    <persname authfilenumber="n50013869" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Tolbert, William R., Jr., 1913-1980</persname>
    <persname authfilenumber="n50051802" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Tubman, William V. S., 1895-1971</persname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="n82167227" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">United States. Agency for International Development</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAC3310-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>Printed Materials</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_VAC3310-00002" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Published Materials</unittitle></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00003" level="file"><did><unittitle><title><emph render="underline">african arts/ arts d'afrique</emph></title>. <edition> Volume 1, Number 1, Autumn 1967 </edition></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_09319721f5f1c8487877e74864daf71a"><head>General</head><p><corpname source="lcnaf" normal="University of California, Los Angeles. African Studies Center ">The African Studies Center of the University of California at Los Angeles</corpname></p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00004" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Balk, Diane M.,</persname><title> <emph render="italic">"Liberian takeover came as no surprise to vice president"</emph></title></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_d017d0bbacb95d22d1c408589d4bf052"><head>General</head><p>From the <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="Courier-journal (Louisville, Ky.) ">Courier-Journal</corpname>, <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Louisville (Ky.) "> Louisville, KY </geogname>, <date normal="1980">April ____, 1980</date></p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00005" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Corder, S. Henry</persname>, editor.<title><emph render="underline">Lofa Times </emph></title></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_baabb97b4e839dab12a5c1aa23814b74"><head>General</head><p>A newspaper published bi-weekly by the <corpname>Lofa County Publication Project</corpname>, a writing association, <date normal="19661104"> November 4, 1966</date>, <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Voinjama (Liberia) ">Voinjama, Liberia.</geogname></p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00006" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname normal="Dash, Leon" source="lcnaf">Dash, Leon.</persname><title> <emph render="italic"> "Liberia Moves Toward Civilian Rule 3 Years After Military Took Power" </emph></title></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_6e3df70ecc9894cb3f33a7e32a3f2b67"><head>General</head><p>From The <corpname>Washington Post</corpname>, <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Washington (D.C.) ">Washington, D. C.</geogname>, <date normal="19830417">April 17, 1983</date></p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00007" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname normal="Dash, Leon" source="lcnaf">Dash, Leon. </persname><title> <emph render="italic">"Tolbert Dies in Liberian Army Coup"</emph></title></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_a085ebe46ca5234d7d35e9c11fac3d85"><head>General</head><p>From <corpname>Washington Post Foreign Service</corpname>, <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Washington (D.C.) ">Washington, D. C.</geogname>, <date normal="1980">April __, 1980</date></p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00008" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Dennis, James C. Sr.</persname>, Publisher, <title><emph render="underline">Palm </emph></title>, <edition>Volume 1, Number 1, April 1966</edition></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_2833cbb8217fcde8c47146a923251106"><head>General</head><p><geogname source="lcsh" normal="Liberia">Liberia's</geogname> Monthly Newsmagazine</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00009" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Dennis, James C. Sr.</persname>, Publisher, <title><emph render="underline">Palm </emph></title>, <edition>Volume 5, Number 10-12, circa November 1969</edition></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_4e8b61f47dcf8cd7c96b6db3f9622d5e"><head>General</head><p><geogname source="lcsh" normal="Liberia">Liberia's</geogname> Monthly Newsmagazine</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00010" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Dennis, James C. Sr.,</persname><title> <emph render="underline">Unificiation</emph></title><edition> Volume 1, Number 1, August 1966 </edition></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_f9c763656b4ba85b4083abff589f4474"><head>General</head><p><geogname source="lcsh" normal="Liberia"> Liberia's</geogname> Cultural, Social and Economic Review. Pp. 2-3 missing</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00011" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Dennis, James C. Sr.,</persname><title> <emph render="underline">Unificiation</emph></title><edition> Volume 1, Number 2, October 1966 </edition></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_37394bfab04928cf334b31cf6bf2b88e"><head>General</head><p><geogname source="lcsh" normal="Liberia"> Liberia's</geogname> Cultural, Social and Economic Review.</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00012" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname normal="Dietz, Betty Warner " source="lcnaf">Dietz, Betty Warner</persname> and <persname normal="Olatunji, Babatunde" source="lcnaf"> Michael Babatunde Olatunji. </persname><title><emph render="underline">Musical Instruments of Africa</emph>- Their Nature, Use and Place in the Life of a Deeply Musical People.</title><imprint><publisher>The John Day Company</publisher>, <geogname normal=" New York (N.Y.)" source="lcsh">New York</geogname>, <date normal="1965">1965.</date></imprint></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_1cee4e0d4b6a5254c8c60a64e647f0ba"><head>General</head><p>Introduction by <persname source="lcnaf" normal="Turnbull, Colin M. "> Colin M. Turnbull</persname>, Curator of African Ethnology, <corpname source="lcnaf" normal=" American Museum of Natural History"> American Museum of Natural History</corpname> including his LP plastic record of African music</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00013" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname normal=" Dostert, Pierre Etienne" source="lcnaf">Dostert, Pierre Etienne. </persname><title><emph render="underline">Africa 1980</emph> – The World Today Series.</title><imprint><publisher>Stryker-Post Publications, Inc</publisher>, <geogname normal="Washington (D.C)" source="lcsh">Washington, D. C.</geogname>, <geogname normal="Harpers Ferry (W. Va.) " source="lcsh"> Harpers Ferry, W. Va.</geogname></imprint></unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00014" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Kennedy, Robert H., </persname>Editor. <title><emph render="underline"> Inside Lofa County </emph></title></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_6d457955727ad5d2aad6f1b50e9e4dd9"><head>General</head><p>With introduction by <persname>Bill Frank.</persname></p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00015" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Martin, Donald M.</persname><title render="italic">"Tragedy in Liberia" </title>, <title render="underline">The Commission.</title></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_65434621a55345f5f2e3d162028d1bb1"><head>General</head><p>Magazine of the <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="Southern Baptist Convention. Foreign Mission Board">Foreign Mission Board of the Southern Baptist Convention</corpname>, <date normal="1991">June/July 1991</date>.</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00016" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname normal="Robbins, Warren M." source="lcnaf">Robbins, Warren M. </persname><title> <emph render="underline">African Art in American Collections. </emph></title><imprint><publisher>Fredrick A. Praeger Publishers</publisher>, <date normal=" 1966">1966</date></imprint></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_acc183986f60e466c26034600a356ca3"><head>General</head><p>In English and French.</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00017" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname normal="Sarkesian, Sam C. (Sam Charles), 1927- " source="lcnaf">Sarkesian, Sam. </persname><title> <emph render="underline">Faces of Africa.</emph></title><imprint><publisher> American Cultural Center, United States Information Service </publisher>, circa 1965-1969</imprint></unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00018" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Schwab, George </persname> and <persname normal="Harley, George W. (George Way), 1894-1966 " source="lcnaf">George W. Harley.</persname><title><emph render="italic">"Tribes of the Liberian Hinterland."</emph></title><title><emph render="underline">Papers of the Peabody Museum of American Anthropology and Ethnology</emph></title>, <edition>Vol. 31, 1947, 536 pp</edition></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_e7edcfeb0391da3f1f7c76eea017de99"><head>General</head><p>An authorized reprint of the original edition, produced by <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="University Microfilms">University Microfilms</corpname>- Xerography by <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="University Microfilms">University Microfilms, Inc.</corpname>, <geogname normal="Ann Arbor (Mich.)">Ann Arbor, Michigan</geogname>, <date normal="1964">1964</date></p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00019" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname normal="Sutherland, Efua Theodora Morgue, 1924-1996 " source="lcnaf">Sutherland, Efua</persname>. <title><emph render="underline"> Playtime in Africa </emph></title>. <imprint><publisher>Murray Printing Company, </publisher><geogname>Forge Village, Massachusetts, </geogname><date normal="1969">1969.</date></imprint></unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00020" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Wilkinson, David R.</persname>, editor. <title><emph render="italic"> "Couple maintains faith during Liberian civil war." </emph></title><title><emph render="underline">The Tie</emph>, News about the Southern Baptist Theological Seminary </title>, <edition>Volume 59, Number 2 Spring 1991</edition></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_9114c4ee4d7614040ae0bd8bbfad6872"><head>General</head><p>From <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Louisville (Ky.) ">Louisville, Kentucky.</geogname></p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00021" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname normal="Wreh, Tuan, 1929- " source="lcnaf">Wreh, Tuan.</persname><title><emph render="underline">THE LOVE OF LIBERTY </emph>, The Rule of President William V. S. Tubman in Liberia 1944-1971.</title><imprint> <publisher>, C. Hurst &amp; Company,</publisher><geogname normal="London (England)" source="lcsh">London, </geogname><date normal="1976">1976</date></imprint></unittitle></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC3310-00022" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Government Reports</unittitle></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00023" level="file"><did><unittitle><emph render="underline">Economic Survey of Liberia</emph>. <imprint><publisher>Nortwestern University</publisher>, <date normal="1962">1962 </date></imprint></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_95d5a794a804929197cbe40f7b0a5f3e"><head>General</head><p>This is the final report of a study conducted January-August, <date normal="1962">1962</date> by <corpname source="lcaf" normal="Northwestern University (Evanston, Ill.) ">Northwestern University</corpname> under a contract with the <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="United States. Agency for International Development">Agency for International Development</corpname> (Now known as the <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="United States. Agency for International Development">United States Agency for International Development – USAID</corpname>).</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00024" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Hartzler, Lynn P. </persname><title><emph render="underline"> Rural School Development </emph>.</title></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_a8bc047f16be6262fe75f45d9ffff7c0"><head>General</head><p><geogname source="lcsh" normal="Liberia">Liberia</geogname>, Rural School Development Project No. 669-11-640-037, U-520 report for the period <date normal="1958/1967">1958-1967</date>, (Internal agency mimeo-graphed report, 197 pp., August <date normal="1967">1967</date>, <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="USAID/Liberia">USAID/Liberia</corpname>).</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00025" level="file"><did><unittitle><title><emph render="underline">LIBERIA, EDUCATION AND TRAINING SECTOR ASSESSMENT</emph>.</title></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_72fa3fe5d3dacfff28cf72903e8018e3"><head>General</head><p>Government of Liberia (GOL) and <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="United States. Agency for International Development. ">United States Agency for International Development (USAID)</corpname>, December. 1983</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00026" level="file"><did><unittitle><title><emph render="underline">Specialist Services and Fellowships for Staff Development</emph>.</title><imprint><publisher>Ministry of Education</publisher>, <geogname normal=" Monrovia (Liberia)" source="lcsh">Monrovia</geogname>, <date normal="19820820">August 20, 1982</date></imprint></unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00027" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname normal="Tolbert, William R., 1913-1980" source="lcnaf">Tolbert, William R., Jr. </persname><title><emph render="underline">Republic of Liberia Presidential Papers</emph>, Documents Diary and Record of Activities of the CHIEF EXECUTIVE, <date normal="19710723/19720731"> July 23, 1971- July 31, 1972</date></title>. Published by the <imprint><publisher>Executive Mansion</publisher>, <geogname normal="Monrovia (Liberia)" source="lcsh">Monrovia</geogname>, R.L.</imprint></unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00028" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname normal="Tolbert, William R., 1913-1980" source="lcnaf">Tolbert, William R., Jr. </persname><title><emph render="underline">Republic of Liberia Presidential Papers</emph>, Documents Diary and Record of Activities of the CHIEF EXECUTIVE, <date normal="19720801/19730731">August 1, 1972- July 31, 1973</date> &amp; <date normal="19730801/19740731">August 1, 1973- July 31, 1974</date></title>. Published by the <imprint><publisher>Press Division of the Executive Mansion</publisher>, <date normal="1975">1975.</date></imprint></unittitle></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC3310-00029" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>School Materials</unittitle></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00030" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Kennedy, Robert H., editor.</persname><title> A Tribute to President Tubman and His Unification Policy by Students of the Western Province </title><date normal="19630214/19630219">February 14-19, 1963</date></unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00031" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Korvah, Frederick</persname>, principal. <title>The Annual Report of Voinjama Public School Covering the Period of June 23, 1964 to June 24, 1965.</title></unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00032" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Whitten, Willie A.</persname>, speaker. <title> Travelers on the Road to Higher Heights. </title></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_ef9a903c2a385492a75c877d41a5ae91"><head>General</head><p>Commencement Address, Voinjama High School, Transcript from tape recording by ELWA radio, <date normal="19771209">December 9, 1977</date>. (see Part II., Reel # 9, Item # 109.waw for the original tape).</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00033" level="file"><did><unittitle><persname>Zaizay, Augustine J.</persname><title>Voinjama High School and Voinjama Extension High School, Eighteenth Commencement Exercises.</title></unittitle></did><odd id="aspace_2e428aaf07f78cca9c9c6e03b731ad92"><head>General</head><p>Program schedule and list of graduates, <date normal="19771204">December 4, 1977</date> (with attached sheet of notes on school history).</p></odd></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAC3310-00034" level="series"><did><unittitle>Audiovisual</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_VAC3310-00035" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Open Reel Tapes</unittitle></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00036" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reel 1: Town Meeting</unittitle><physdesc><dimensions id="aspace_e008a782891f6b77e455c80acc9c300a">7 inches</dimensions></physdesc></did><odd id="aspace_561292b6527592bcbda95a4f273591d4"><head>General</head><list type="ordered"><item><title><emph render="bold">Side A</emph></title> Tape Counter (0-end) <geogname>Lawalazu</geogname> – Town Meeting #1 – <date normal="19650316">March 16, 1965</date>, 61 min.</item><item><title><emph render="bold">Side B</emph></title> Blank Recording of <geogname> Lawalazu</geogname> Town Meeting discussing the impact of the road being built through the <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Voinjama (Liberia) "> Voinjama</geogname> province linking <geogname>Lawalazu</geogname> to other villages and <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Monrovia (Liberia)">Monrovia</geogname>. Town improvements, such as the creation of a clinic and larger schools, farming conditions, and ways for getting more girls to attend school are also discussed. Meeting is led by <persname>Willie A. Whitten</persname> and the Lawalazu Chief, with assistance from interpreter <persname>James K. Kimmah</persname></item></list></odd><odd id="aspace_21fa009837d2c77fee8ee8bfa8e31471"><head>General</head><p>Includes nine pages of the meeting transcript text copied from <persname>Whitten</persname>'s dissertation. Also includes a diagram and list of participants in the meeting and photocopies of correspondence between <persname>Whitten</persname>, <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Lofa County (Liberia) "> Lofa County</geogname> Superintendent <persname>Robert H. Kennedy</persname>, Bandie Chief Kollie, Kissie Chief Taylor, and P.C.V. <persname>Bob Sable</persname> discussing plans for scheduling the meeting.</p></odd><relatedmaterial id="aspace_3c70ee8375b95473f54e75f967bd7baa"><head>Related Materials</head><p>See color transparencies # for images of the Lawalazu and Borkezar sessions</p></relatedmaterial></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00037" level="file"><did><unittitle>Reel 2: Town Meetings and Interviews</unittitle><physdesc><dimensions id="aspace_b4e00810983c0699b757fcc145788b4b">7 inches</dimensions></physdesc></did><odd id="aspace_0a40fdc58d54afa91cf2a37b019eee9b"><head>General</head><list type="ordered"><item><title><emph render="bold">Side A</emph></title> Tape Counter (1-367) – Town Meeting #2: <geogname>Bazagizia</geogname> – <date normal="19640409">April 9, 1965</date>, 62 min. Tape Counter (367-end) – Town Meeting #3: <geogname>Ngokorhun</geogname> –<date normal=" 19650518"> May 18, 1965</date>, 63 min.</item><item><title><emph render="bold">Side B</emph></title> Tape Counter (1-339) – Interview #1: Chief Jigbeh – <date normal="19650615"> June 15, 1965</date>, 58 min. Tape Counter (340-end) – Interview #2: Elder Akoi – <date normal="19650602">June 2, 1965</date>, 67 min. <geogname>Bazagazia</geogname> town meeting discusses town improvements and sanitation, solutions to farming problems, and the need for a health clinic and furniture in schools. Also discusses different levels of town leadership. Meeting is led by <persname>W.A.Whitten</persname> in dialogue with the Bazagazia Chief and Interpreter <persname>Gabriel Gizzie</persname>. <geogname>Ngokorhun</geogname> town meeting discusses teachers and the state of education in the town, the need for sturdier school buildings, and other improvement needed in town. These improvements include more land for agricultural development and a school kitchen for feeding students. The meeting is led by <persname> Ernest Carmo</persname> and <persname>W.A. Whitten</persname>, with <persname>James K. Kimmah</persname> as interpreter. Chief Jigbeh from <persname>Lawalazu</persname>, <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Voinjama (Liberia)">Voinjama District</geogname>, <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Lofa County (Liberia)">Lofa County</geogname> interviewed by <persname>W.A. Whitten</persname> with <persname>James Kimmah</persname> as interpreter. This interview was part of research being conducted by the <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Lofa County (Liberia)">Lofa County</geogname> Education Office. It sought specific information about social and economic conditions of tribal people in the <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Voinjama (Liberia)"> Voinjama District</geogname>. A major focus of this interview was on the past and present role of town meetings in traditional life in the county. Elder Akoi from the town of <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Voinjama (Liberia)"> Voinjama</geogname>, <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Lofa County (Liberia)">Lofa County</geogname> interviewed by <persname>W.A. Whitten</persname> with <persname>James Kimmah</persname> as interpreter. This interview was part of research being conducted by the <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Lofa County (Liberia)">Lofa County</geogname> Education Office. It sought specific information about social and economic conditions of traditional people in the <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Voinjama (Liberia)"> Voinjama District</geogname>. The focus of this interview was on activities and changes that occurred in tribal living during the lifetime and experience of the interviewee.</item></list></odd><odd id="aspace_64c6a0b07b5ae5e2ba7e0b46b182efce"><head>General</head><p>Includes transcripts of <geogname>Bazagazia</geogname> and <geogname>Ngokorhun</geogname> town meetings and highlights of the interviews with Chief Jigbeh and Elder Akoi</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00038" level="item"><did><unittitle>Reel 3: Town Meeting</unittitle><physdesc><dimensions id="aspace_476c140a9f7ff70f4d785c07fe4fa0f3">7 inches;</dimensions></physdesc></did><odd id="aspace_7d7a95904a36525a9b33bebcb672814b"><head>General</head><list type="ordered"><item><title><emph render="bold">Side A</emph></title> Tape Counter (0-end) – Town Meeting #4: <geogname>Zawadamai</geogname> – <date normal="19650515">May 15, 1965</date>, 105 min.</item><item><title><emph render="bold">Side B</emph></title> Tape Counter (0-end) – Town Meeting continued with interview and music at end School vegetable gardens, first-aid in the schools, the benefits of education and trained teachers in the village, and the need for a road through town are discussed. Meeting is led by <persname>Earnest Carmo</persname>, Adult education Supervisor for <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Lofa County (Liberia)">Lofa County</geogname>, and <persname>W.A. Whitten</persname>, <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="United States. Agency for International Development.">USAID</corpname> Education Advisor, with assistance from interpreter <persname>James K. Kimmah</persname>.</item></list></odd><odd id="aspace_21504704bed0135cb2f2419ef6d0072a"><head>General</head><p>Includes <geogname>Zawadamai</geogname> Town Meeting Transcript, fifteen pages of text copied from <persname>W.A. Whitten's</persname> dissertation</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00039" level="item"><did><unittitle>Reel 4: Town Meeting</unittitle><physdesc><dimensions id="aspace_34b94635873600646e2dd9ae2ac6ba39">7 inches;</dimensions></physdesc></did><odd id="aspace_9cb106b0d997df72aa4230ee8449cb40"><head>General</head><list type="ordered"><item><title><emph render="bold">Side A</emph></title>Tape Counter (0-end) – Town Meeting #5: <geogname>Korwahun</geogname> – <date normal="19650318">March 18, 1965</date>, 61 min.</item><item><title><emph render="bold">Side B</emph></title>Tape Counter (0-end) – Town meeting continued Meeting designed to offer education officials the opportunity to discuss key problems and needs of local town people in the Kolahun area. Topics discussed include schools, roads, health clinics, and a possible hospital. Meeting led by <persname>W.A. Whitten</persname> and Paramount Chief of the Bandi Tribe, <persname>Thomas Kollie</persname>.</item></list></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00040" level="item"><did><unittitle>Reel 5: County Adult Education Workshop #1</unittitle><physdesc><dimensions id="aspace_6ecbf3375f1b3d98fe6d973d6074a53e">7 inches;</dimensions></physdesc></did><odd id="aspace_92e9528402c050d78fe123a09adf2e76"><head>General</head><list type="ordered"><item><title><emph render="bold">Side A</emph></title> Tape Counter (1-984) – <geogname normal="Voinjama (Liberia)">Voinjama</geogname> Workshop – <date normal="19650326/19650327"> March 26-27, 1965</date>, 132 min.</item><item><title><emph render="bold">Side B</emph></title>Blank Workshop provides hands on in-service training for Fundamental Education (FE) workers assigned to teach in remote towns and villages in <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Lofa County (Liberia)"> Lofa County</geogname>. Supervised by Ernest Carmo with assistance from <geogname>Raymond B. Jallah</geogname>, <geogname>W.A. Whitten</geogname>, and other <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="Peace Corps Institute (U.S.) ">Peace Corps</corpname> volunteers.</item></list></odd><odd id="aspace_f41f8a551dcdf69480dea6ef749237bc"><head>General</head><p>Includes list of workshop highlights.</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00041" level="item"><did><unittitle>Reel 6: County Adult Education Workshop #2</unittitle><physdesc><dimensions id="aspace_52fe41c87ee1f93812faf6d85ba59af3">7 inch;</dimensions></physdesc></did><odd id="aspace_3efba29f414514392b812cf65753a770"><head>General</head><list type="ordered"><item><title><emph render="bold">Side A</emph></title> Tape Counter (0-654) – County Supervisors Workshop – <geogname normal="19650369/19650327"> March 26-27, 1965</geogname>, 178 min.</item><item><title><emph render="bold">Side B</emph></title>Blank Workshop provides hands on in-service training for Fundamental Education (FE) workers assigned to teach in remote towns and villages in <geogname normal="Lofa County (Liberia)"> Lofa County</geogname>. Supervised by <persname>Ernest Carmo</persname> with assistance from <persname>Raymond B. Jallah</persname>, <persname>W.A. Whitten</persname>, and other <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="Peace Corps Institute (U.S.) ">Peace Corps</corpname> volunteers.</item></list></odd><odd id="aspace_c6d027af7d792a2d5782a0f997af39dc"><head>General</head><p>Includes list of workshop highlights. Reel #6 is a continuation of the workshop proceedings begun on Tape #5</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00042" level="item"><did><unittitle>Reel 7: Lofa School Supervisors Meeting</unittitle><physdesc><dimensions id="aspace_98cc16cf6141e11eefdc58a0f7556259">7 inches</dimensions></physdesc></did><odd id="aspace_c35b9202a68155547e2774ff1202d165"><head>General</head><list type="ordered"><item><title><emph render="bold">Side A</emph> Tape Counter (1-376 at 1 7/8 ips) – Supervisors Workshop – <date normal="19650312/19650313">March 12-13, 1965 </date>, 153 min. Tape Counter (377-800 at 3 ¾ ips) </title></item><item><title><emph render="bold">Side B</emph></title>Tape Counter (0-end at 3 ¾ ips) This was a regular meeting of <geogname source="lcnaf" normal="Lofa County (Liberia)">Lofa County</geogname> school supervisors to review and plan the county school program. Status and problem reports were discussed, acted on and/or referred to the <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="Liberia. Ministry of Education ">Ministry of Education (MOE)</corpname>. Meeting chaired by <persname> Raymond B. Jallah</persname>, <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Lofa County (Liberia)"> Lofa County</geogname> Supervisor of Schools, and attended by <persname>W.A. Whitten</persname>, <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="United States. Agency for International Development. "> USAID</corpname> <geogname normal="Lofa County (Liberia)">Lofa County</geogname> Education Advisor. District school supervisors were also in attendance.</item></list></odd><odd id="aspace_9d910b4a865f4dddd579a4f9e321c868"><head>General</head><p>Includes list of Supervisors Meeting Highlights.</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00043" level="item"><did><unittitle>Reel 8: <persname normal="Tubman, William V. S.,--1895-1971" source="lcnaf">President Tubman </persname>Inauguration</unittitle><physdesc><dimensions id="aspace_48e2daec9f3b284359ab551843380315">5 inches</dimensions></physdesc></did><odd id="aspace_3160bce33f58f758247823fd8842f7e5"><head>General</head><list type="ordered"><item><title><emph render="bold">Side A</emph></title>Tape Counter (1-633) – <persname source="lcnaf" normal="Tubman, William V. S.,--1895-1971">Tubman </persname> inauguration speech on ELWA Radio – <date normal="19680101">Jan. 1, 1968</date>, 57 min.</item><item><title><emph render="bold">Side B</emph></title>Tape Counter (1-570) – Speech continued with procession at the end <persname source="lcnaf" normal="Tubman, William V. S.,--1895-1971">Tubman's</persname> final inauguration address as president of <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Liberia"> Liberia</geogname>, recorded from a radio broadcast. The recording starts several minutes into the speech and proceeds through the remainder. It includes radio commentator excerpts and continues through the formal procession after the speech.</item></list></odd><odd id="aspace_2f5d3aac02fcbe147b442f2975cf5d79"><head>General</head><p>Includes written comments on the <persname source="lcnaf" normal="Tubman, William V. S.,--1895-1971">Tubman</persname> Address.</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00044" level="item"><did><unittitle>Reel 9: Voinjama High School Graduation</unittitle><physdesc id="aspace_d0adb42c9d41d764ccd2b2b1a8a90641">1 open reel tape; 7 inches; 3 3/4 ips</physdesc></did><odd id="aspace_58ac381e35dbfd30e2d2774a9b36e6e2"><head>General</head><list type="ordered"><item><title><emph render="bold">Side A</emph></title>Tape Counter (1-end) – Graduation Exercises ELWA Radio – <date normal="19771212">Dec. 12, 1977</date> (Guest Speaker –<persname> W.A. Whitten</persname>, <corpname source="lcnaf" normal="United States. Agency for International Development.">USAID</corpname> HRD Officer), 54 min.</item><item><title><emph render="bold">Side B</emph></title>Blank Speech entitled, <title>"Travelers on the road to higher heights"</title> presented by <persname>W.A. Whitten</persname> to graduates of the Voinjama High School in <date normal="1977">1977</date>. Recorded off of a radio broadcast.</item></list></odd><odd id="aspace_9fb2999cc07b0743e8282b5b18166cec"><head>General</head><p>Includes transcript of commencement address and comments on the commencement program.</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00045" level="item"><did><unittitle>Reel 10: <geogname normal="Lofa County (Liberia)" source="lcsh">Lofa County</geogname> Music – <geogname normal="Voinjama (Liberia)" source="lcsh">Voinjama District</geogname></unittitle><physdesc><dimensions id="aspace_76230cdf7f4a0f9363411c5833256598">7 inches;</dimensions></physdesc></did><odd id="aspace_af9c3391075093761e8c07e93a44402a"><head>General</head><list type="ordered"><item><title><emph render="bold">Side A</emph></title> Tape Counter (1-1127) – 13 Selections from <geogname>Lawalazu Town</geogname> – <date normal="19650316"> March 16, 1965</date></item><item><title><emph render="bold">Side B</emph></title>Tape Counter (1-139) – 4 Selections from <geogname>Betijima Town</geogname> – <date normal="19650317"> March 17, 1965</date> Tape includes examples of traditional music from the <geogname normal="Voinjama (Liberia)">Voinjama District</geogname>. Examples of songs for grand occasions or processions, songs of praise to the chief, work songs, and songs about daily labor tasks are included.</item></list></odd><odd id="aspace_34a2e2dd5070368882b3f07bbb97b5e1"><head>General</head><p>Includes commentary on music selections.</p></odd></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00046" level="item"><did><unittitle>Reel 11: <geogname normal="Lofa County (Liberia)" source="lcsh"> Lofa County</geogname> Music</unittitle><physdesc><dimensions id="aspace_dc5733d953bbce033cfc0708fcc19a55">7 inches;</dimensions></physdesc></did><odd id="aspace_5d97ac4d0a5d29ac5fce16115d32f280"><head>General</head><list type="ordered"><item><title><emph render="bold">Side A</emph></title>Tape Counter (1-398) – 5 Selections, Salayea, <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Zorzor (Liberia) "> Zorzor District</geogname> (Kpelle) – <date normal="19650128">January 28, 1965</date> Tape Counter (399-956) – 4 Selections, Shello, Kolahun District (Kissi) – <date normal="19650120">January 20, 1965</date></item><item><title><emph render="bold">Side B</emph></title>Tape Counter (1-867) – 6 Selections, <geogname source="lcsh" normal="Zorzor (Liberia) "> Zorzor</geogname>, (Zaza Loma) – <date normal="19650128"> January 28, 1965</date> Tape includes a Kpelle horn and drum group, Kissi music sung during farming and labor, and Loma songs about the problems, successes, and anxieties of modern change, such as the <corpname>Firestone Rubber Plantation.</corpname></item></list></odd><odd id="aspace_cf5aad298c3d90e8060f1fae8a575223"><head>General</head><p>Includes commentary on music selections.</p></odd></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC3310-00047" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Color Transparencies</unittitle><abstract id="aspace_adde6366c65a73324eef3dfed925bc05">The Willie A. and Lucille S. Whitten Photography Collection contains nearly 700 images reproduced from slides taken during the Whittens' stays in Liberia in the 1960s and 1970s. A native of Mississippi, Mr. Whitten first traveled to Liberia in 1963 on a United States Agency for International Development (USAID) project while completing his graduate studies in adult education. Whitten conducted research for his doctoral dissertation in Lofa County, receiving a Doctorate in Education from Indiana University in 1966. He continued as a USAID education officer in Liberia during the late 1960s. He returned to Liberia in the late 1970s and early 1980s, before and after the violent overthrow of the William Tolbert presidency in the military coup led by Samuel Doe in 1980. The collection includes photographs of the Liberian towns and schools Whitten visited in his USAID work, photographs of Liberian government and cultural events, and family photographs.

Available from the<extref xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/images/public-index.htm">Indiana University Image Collections Online</extref></abstract></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAC3310-00048" level="series"><did><unittitle>Artifacts</unittitle><abstract id="aspace_bb48a20fa3e7c56c3097d01955498d2e">Willie and Lucille Whitten collected these artifacts during their visits to Liberia in the 1960s and 1970s. They are currently housed at the Mathers Museum of World Cultures at Indiana University. In the finding aid, these items are arranged alphabetically by subject, with subcategories and descriptions provided by Whitten. For a more detailed classification scheme, contact the Mathers Museum.</abstract></did><c02 id="aspace_VAC3310-00049" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Arts and Crafts</unittitle></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00050" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Crafts-Contemporary</unittitle></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00051" level="file"><did><unittitle>Animal Figures</unittitle></did><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00052" level="item"><did><unittitle>Crocodile (large)</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00053" level="item"><did><unittitle>Crocodile (small)</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00054" level="item"><did><unittitle>Rooster</unittitle></did></c05></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00055" level="item"><did><unittitle>Early Settlers Dwelling</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00056" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wood Carving Wall Plaques</unittitle></did><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00057" level="item"><did><unittitle>Left Face</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00058" level="item"><did><unittitle>Moslem Male</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00059" level="item"><did><unittitle>Right Face</unittitle></did></c05></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00060" level="file"><did><unittitle>Wood Wall Plaques</unittitle></did><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00061" level="item"><did><unittitle>Plaque With Faces</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00062" level="item"><did><unittitle>Plaque With a Village</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00063" level="item"><did><unittitle>Wood Sword Plaque</unittitle></did></c05></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00064" level="file"><did><unittitle>Woven Baskets</unittitle></did><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00065" level="item"><did><unittitle>Large Basket</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00066" level="item"><did><unittitle>Small Tray</unittitle></did></c05></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00067" level="item"><did><unittitle>Kissi Pennies</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00068" level="file"><did><unittitle>Senufo Anklets</unittitle></did><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00069" level="item"><did><unittitle>Brass Cuff</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00070" level="item"><did><unittitle>Brass Open Ring</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00071" level="item"><did><unittitle>Steel Open Ring</unittitle></did></c05></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00072" level="file"><did><unittitle>Society Masks</unittitle></did><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00073" level="item"><did><unittitle>Poro Society Mask with Hood and Face Cloth</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00074" level="item"><did><unittitle>Poro Society Mask</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00075" level="item"><did><unittitle>Sande Head Piece for Young Female Initiate</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00076" level="item"><did><unittitle>Senufo Mask</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00077" level="item"><did><unittitle>Small Mask Probably for Young Female</unittitle></did></c05></c04></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC3310-00078" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Figurines and Carvings</unittitle></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00079" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Soapstone Figures</unittitle></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00080" level="item"><did><unittitle>Kissi Stone Face</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00081" level="item"><did><unittitle>Kissi Stone Family</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00082" level="item"><did><unittitle>Small Stone God</unittitle></did></c04></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00083" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Wood Bust Carvings</unittitle></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00084" level="item"><did><unittitle>Female with head piece (small)</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00085" level="item"><did><unittitle>Moslem male with cap (medium)</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00086" level="item"><did><unittitle>Moslem male without cap (medium)</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00087" level="item"><did><unittitle>Young female facing left</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00088" level="item"><did><unittitle>Young female facing right</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00089" level="item"><did><unittitle>Young female with braided hair</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00090" level="item"><did><unittitle>Young female with braided hair-high forehead</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00091" level="item"><did><unittitle>Young female with long braids</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00092" level="item"><did><unittitle>Young female with plain hair</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00093" level="item"><did><unittitle>Young female with side view</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00094" level="item"><did><unittitle>Young mother and child</unittitle></did></c04></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00095" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Wood Hand-God Figures</unittitle></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00096" level="item"><did><unittitle>Female Figure</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00097" level="item"><did><unittitle>Yoruba Ibeji Twin Figure</unittitle></did></c04></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC3310-00098" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Household Furniture and Utensils</unittitle></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00099" level="item"><did><unittitle>Broom</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00100" level="item"><did><unittitle>Carrying Net</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00101" level="item"><did><unittitle>Chief's Chair</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00102" level="item"><did><unittitle>Clay Water Pot (large)</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00103" level="item"><did><unittitle>Clay Water Pot (small)</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00104" level="item"><did><unittitle>Condiment Basket – Jar type</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00105" level="item"><did><unittitle>Fish/Carrying Basket</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00106" level="item"><did><unittitle>Large Wood Spoon</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00107" level="item"><did><unittitle>Rice Mortar</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00108" level="item"><did><unittitle>Scoop</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00109" level="item"><did><unittitle>Spice/Nuts Mortar</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00110" level="file"><did><unittitle>Stools With Four Legs</unittitle></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00111" level="item"><did><unittitle>Large Wood Stool</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00112" level="item"><did><unittitle>Medium Wood Stool</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00113" level="item"><did><unittitle>Medium Wood Stool</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00114" level="item"><did><unittitle>Small Wood Stool</unittitle></did></c04></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC3310-00115" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Leisure Items</unittitle></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00116" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Games</unittitle></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00117" level="item"><did><unittitle>Decorative Game Board</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00118" level="item"><did><unittitle>Plain Game Board (with Bean Tokens)</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00119" level="item"><did><unittitle>Society Game Board</unittitle></did></c04></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00120" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Musical Instruments</unittitle></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00121" level="item"><did><unittitle>Belly Harp</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00122" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Drums</unittitle></did><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00123" level="item"><did><unittitle>Medium Drum</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00124" level="item"><did><unittitle>Small Drum</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00125" level="item"><did><unittitle>Small Talking Drum</unittitle></did></c05></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00126" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Iron Bells</unittitle></did><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00127" level="item"><did><unittitle>Large iron Bell With Wood Stick &amp; Metal Ring</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00128" level="item"><did><unittitle>Medium Iron Bell With Wood Stick &amp; Metal Ring</unittitle></did></c05><c05 id="aspace_VAC3310-00129" level="item"><did><unittitle>Small Iron Bell With Wood Stick &amp; Metal Ring</unittitle></did></c05></c04></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00130" level="item"><did><unittitle>Marimba With Two Mallets</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00131" level="item"><did><unittitle>Sasa Gourd Rattler</unittitle></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC3310-00132" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Textiles</unittitle></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00133" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Boutique-Type Cloth</unittitle></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00134" level="item"><did><unittitle>Blue Cloth #1</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00135" level="item"><did><unittitle>Blue Cloth #2</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00136" level="item"><did><unittitle>Blue Cloth #3</unittitle></did></c04></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00137" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Chief's Robes</unittitle></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00138" level="item"><did><unittitle>Robe &amp; Cap from Local Weaved Cloth (black, blue, beige &amp; white)</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00139" level="item"><did><unittitle>Robe &amp; Cap Commercially made Cloth (bright black, white &amp; blue)</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00140" level="item"><did><unittitle>Robe Probably Made from Local Weaved Cloth (beige)</unittitle></did></c04></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00141" level="item"><did><unittitle>Female Dress (blue)</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00142" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Local Made Country Cloth Rolls</unittitle></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00143" level="item"><did><unittitle>Dark Color</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00144" level="item"><did><unittitle>Light Color</unittitle></did></c04></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00145" level="item"><did><unittitle>Male Shirt (blue &amp; white)</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00146" level="item"><did><unittitle>Raffia Bag (red &amp; beige)</unittitle></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00147" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Weaving Loom Parts</unittitle></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00148" level="item"><did><unittitle>Shuttle (oval)</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00149" level="item"><did><unittitle>Shuttle (rectangle)</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00150" level="item"><did><unittitle>Thread Filter</unittitle></did></c04></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC3310-00151" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Tools</unittitle></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00152" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Smithing</unittitle></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00153" level="item"><did><unittitle>Loma Blacksmith Bellows Pair from Vezela Town</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00154" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bellows</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00155" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bellows</unittitle></did></c04></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00156" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Upland Rice Farming Tools</unittitle></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00157" level="item"><did><unittitle>Axe</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00158" level="item"><did><unittitle>Machete (Cutlass)</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00159" level="item"><did><unittitle>Regular Hoe</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00160" level="item"><did><unittitle>Scratching Hoe for Rice Planting</unittitle></did></c04></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3310-00161" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Weapons</unittitle></did><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00162" level="item"><did><unittitle>Knife with Brass Blade and Bone Handle (copy)</unittitle></did></c04><c04 id="aspace_VAC3310-00163" level="item"><did><unittitle>Sword with Sheath (copy)</unittitle></did></c04></c03></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
