<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader findaidstatus="In_process" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="dc" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="waspc" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv66506" encodinganalog="identifier" identifier="80444/xv66506">OXFSPU05.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the Cascade College Records
                    
                <date encodinganalog="date" normal="1918/1969" type="inclusive">1918-1969</date></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Cascade College Records</titleproper>
        <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding aid prepared by Adrienne Meier</author>
        <sponsor>Funding for preparing this finding aid was provided through a grant awarded by the National Historical Publications and Records Commission.</sponsor>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Seattle Pacific University Archives</publisher>
        <address>
          <addressline>3307 3rd Avenue West</addressline>
          <addressline>Suite 306</addressline>
          <addressline>Seattle, Washington, 98119</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: http://www.spu.edu/depts/library/</addressline>
        </address>
        <date encodinganalog="date" calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2011">2011</date>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note>
          <p>1. how many photographs are in this collection? approximate number okay. Add to s&amp;c note. 2. subject and names (Alexander Beers), also Cascade College (subject)</p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced using the Archivists' Toolkit
                <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20110706">2011-07-06</date></creation>
      <langusage>English
                <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English</language></langusage>
      <descrules>Finding aid based on DACS (<title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content Standard</title>).</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="marc21" type="inventory">
    <did>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Cascade College Records</unittitle>
      <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="us" repositorycode="waspc">SPU05</unitid>
      <repository>
        <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Seattle Pacific University</corpname>
        <address>
          <addressline>3307 3rd Avenue West</addressline>
          <addressline>Suite 306</addressline>
          <addressline>Seattle, Washington, 98119</addressline>
          <addressline>URL: http://www.spu.edu/depts/library/</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <langmaterial>Collection materials are in <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langmaterial>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">26.0 linear feet</extent>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">22 cartons and 4 oversize boxes</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate normal="1941/1969" type="bulk" encodinganalog="245$g">1941-1969</unitdate>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1969" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1918-1969</unitdate>
      <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">Cascade College operated in Portland, Oregon from 1939 until June 1969, when its student body merged with Seattle Pacific College in Seattle, Washington. Included in this merger was the transfer of the college's institutional records and other materials to Seattle Pacific. This collection contains Cascade College records, publications and other materials as well as catalogs and photographs from its precursor entities, The North Pacific Evangelical Institute and the Portland Bible Institute.</abstract>
      <origination label="creator">
        <corpname rules="local" source="local" encodinganalog="110">Cascade College</corpname>
      </origination>
    </did>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
      <p>The bulk of this collection is comprised of Cascade College records and other materials, 1939-1969. It also contains North Pacific Evangelical Institute catalogs 1918-1930, Portland Bible Institute catalogs 1930-1939, and 25 class and all-school photographs 1919-1939, was well as Cascade College photographs.</p>
      <p>Cascade College records include: accreditation reports; alumni and student records; faculty and student writings; general records; mementos; publications including Cascade College Bulletin 1952-1969, Cascade College Lookout 1941-1969, Count Down, The Portrait, The Chalk Board (Education Office), The Cascade Pathfinder, The Cascade Idea, Cascade Intercessor, Faculty Manual, Student Handbook, yearbooks (various names) 1934-1968; photographs; theses and senior research papers presented to Dr. Lee M. Nash for History Courses 1961-1967, and others; trophies, and historical information.</p>
      <p>The collection also contains bound and manuscript copies of Our College: A History of Cascade College, 1918-1957 by Sophia E. Townsend, and a 23-minute video titled Campus Life at Cascade College.</p>
      <p>An inventory and subject index to this collection is available.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="5451_">
      <head>Historical Note</head>
      <p>Cascade College of Portland, Oregon, was incorporated as North Pacific Evangelistic Institute on June 19, 1918. In 1929 the name changed to Portland Bible Institute and in 1939 to Cascade College. Members of the founding Board of Trustees were Lurana Terrell, President of the Board; Alexander Beers, Vice President; Catherine L. Dickey, Secretary; Byron Morris, Treasurer; Lewis I. Hadley, Dean; and Marietta Lewis, Marion George, Marion Cook, and Robert Brymer. The first day of classes was October 1, 1918. Four students were enrolled: Marion Cook, his wife Libbie Cook, Ruth Piggot, and Pearl Boatwright. By the second year, 23 students were registered. The first teachers were Lewis Hadley and Erma Cook.</p>
      <p>The Presidents of Cascade College were: Lewis I. Hadley, Founder and Dean, 1918-1922; Edward Mott, President, 1922-1933; Clarence J. Pike, 1933-1956; Edison Habegger, 1956-1960; Earl P. Barker, Acting President, 1960-1961; Thomas A. Leupp, President, 1961-1966; Charles E. Fogg, 1966-1967; and Melvin Nathan Olson, 1967-1969.</p>
      <p>The college discontinued academic operations in June 1969 and its student body was merged with Seattle Pacific. Included in this merger was the transfer of academic records, teacher education files, alumni records, constituency records and mailing lists. Seattle Pacific became the new repository of Cascade College records, mementos and traditions.</p>
      <p>The entire library of approximately 30,000 volumes was purchased on December 24, 1969 by Judson Baptist College for $67,000. During the summer and fall of 1969, the Cascade College teacher education files, alumni records, constituence records and mailing lists were transferred and released to Seattle Pacific College. The final transfer of student academic (registration) records was completed by December 16, 1969.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690" altrender="nodisplay">Colleges and Universities</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690" altrender="nodisplay">Portland</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690" altrender="nodisplay">Religion</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690" altrender="nodisplay">Seattle</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" encodinganalog="690" altrender="nodisplay">Student Life</subject>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
  </archdesc>
</ead>

