<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="dc" scriptencoding="iso15924">
    <eadid countrycode="us" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv03778 " identifier="80444/xv03778" mainagencycode="wabecp" encodinganalog="identifier">XOE_CPNWS0067nwtribal</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the Northwest Tribal Oral History interviews
            1963-1973<date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1963/1973" type="inclusive"/></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Northwest Tribal Oral History
          interviews</titleproper>
        <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding aid prepared by the Center for Pacific Northwest
          Studies</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Center for Pacific Northwest Studies</publisher>
        <date encodinganalog="date" calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="2000">© 2000</date>
        <address>
          <addressline>Goltz-Murray Building</addressline>
          <addressline>808 25th St</addressline>
          <addressline>Bellingham 98225-9123</addressline>
          <addressline>cpnws@wwu.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>https://library.wwu.edu/center-pacific-northwest-studies</addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>This finding aid was produced by CPNWS staff on <date>2022-11-30</date>.</creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.</langusage>
      <descrules>Finding aid based on DACS (Describing Archives: A Content Standard), 2nd
        Edition.</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" relatedencoding="marc21" type="inventory">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Center for Pacific Northwest Studies</corpname>
      </repository>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Northwest Tribal Oral History interviews</unittitle>
      <unitid countrycode="us" repositorycode="wabecp" encodinganalog="099">XOE_CPNWS0067nwtriba</unitid>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">2 linear feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1963/1973" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1963-1973 1973</unitdate>
      <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1973/1973" type="bulk" encodinganalog="245$g">1973</unitdate>
      <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">Includes first-hand accounts of members and elders of Native
        American tribes in Washington State and Idaho who provide information on long-standing
        traditions such as language, education, genealogy, politics, religion, as well as hunting
        and fishing practices.</abstract>
      <langmaterial><language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language> .
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
      <p>The Northwest Tribal Oral History Project was initially produced under the direction of Dr.
        Donald Eklund, Associate Professor of History at Western Washington University and Professor
        Jeffery Wilner also of Western Washington University. In 1999-2000, the collection was
        described and duplicated by Stacy Rasmus of the Lummi Language and Cultural Department as
        part of a joint project between the Lummi Indian Nation and the Center for Pacific Northwest
        Studies.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
      <p> The Northwest Tribal Oral History interviews contains information pertaining to a wide
        variety of Native American tribes and peoples in Washington State and Idaho. The interviews
        reflect perspectives of tribe members as well as elders. The majority of these interviews
        are conducted with both members and elders of the Lummi and the Nooksack tribes. Other
        interviewees include members and elders from the Chinook, Chehalis, Cowlitz, Pachenant,
        Quinault, Colville, Sinkiuse, and Swinomish tribes. There is also an interview with a member
        of the Nez Perce Tribe. Some topics discussed in these interviews and recordings include
        Native American languages and word etymologies, religion, education, genealogy, songs,
        hunting and fishing as well as politics. Also contained within the collection are recordings
        of the Northwest Indians Executive Council meetings and conferences held in Spokane, WA in
        1973. </p>
      <p>Although the material in Northwest Tribal Oral History interviews span from 1963-1973, the
        majority of it dates from 1973. Eighteen interviews out of the fifty four audio tapes have
        transcriptions. Due to the age of the audio cassette recordings, some tapes are completely
        inaudible. </p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
      <p>The Northwest Tribal Oral History interviews is organized in accordance with the following
        series arrangement:</p>
      <list type="ordered">
        <item>Series I: Audio Recordings, 1963-1973</item>
        <item>Series II: Transcripts, 1967-1973</item>
      </list>
    </arrangement>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <p>The collection is open to the public.</p>
    </accessrestrict> 
    <processinfo><head>About Harmful Language and Content</head><p>This collection contains content about Northwest Indigenous peoples that may be culturally sensitive, harmful and triggering. Archives &amp; Special Collections acknowledges the potential harm that comes from engaging with these resources for the communities of origin and the need for ongoing review of this content. Archives &amp; Special Collections invites Tribal/First Nation communities to offer guidance regarding restriction or removal of sensitive materials from physical or online collections and/or agreements for limiting access or use, and any special care and handling. Researchers are also encouraged to consult with communities of origin regarding appropriate use of culturally sensitive content from this collection. See the following <extref href="https://library.wwu.edu/statement-on-harmful-language-content">Statement About Potentially Harmful Language and Content</extref> for more information about providing feedback or to request dialogue.</p></processinfo> 
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <p>Northwest Tribal Oral History interviews, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies, Western Libraries Archives &amp; Special Collections, Western Washington University, Bellingham WA 98225-9123.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <persname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="700">Eklund, Don.</persname>
        <persname source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="700">Wilner, Jeffrey D.</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Quinault Indians--Washington
          (State)--History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Lummi Indians--Washington
          (State)--History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Salish Indians--Washington
          (State)--History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Chehalis Indians--Washington
          (State)--History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Chinook Indians--Washington
          (State)--History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Nooksack Indians--Washington
          (State)--History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Nez Percé
          Indians--Idaho--History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Colville Indians--Washington
          (State)--History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Yakama Indians--Washington
          (State)--History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Cowlitz Indians--Washington
          (State)--History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Coast Salish Indians--Washington
          (State)--History -- Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Swinomish Indians--Washington (State)--History
          -- Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Washington
          (State)--Social life and customs--History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Washington
          (State)--Agriculture -- History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Washington
          (State)--Fishing--Law and legislation--History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Washington
          (State)--History -- Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Education--Washington
          (State)--History --Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Washington
          (State)--Folklore--History --Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Washington
          (State)--Languages--History --Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Fishing--Washington
          (State)--History -- Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Hunting--Washington
          (State)--History -- Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Washington
          (State)--Government relations --History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Washington
          (State)--Religion--History --Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Washington
          (State)--Social Conditions -- History--Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Washington
          (State)--Treaties--History --Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Washington
          (State)--Art--History -- Sources.</subject>
        <subject source="lcsh" encodinganalog="650">Indians of North America--Washington
          (State)--Music--History -- Sources.</subject>
            </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <genreform source="lcgft" encodinganalog="655">Oral histories.</genreform>
        <genreform source="cgft" encodinganalog="655">Interviews (Sound recordings)</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Native
          Americans</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Washington
          (State)</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Missionaries</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Oral
          Histories</subject>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc type="analyticover">
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Audio Recordings</unittitle>
          <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series I</unitid>
          <unitid identifier="33999" type="Archivists Toolkit Database::RESOURCE_COMPONENT" encodinganalog="099">33999</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1963/1973" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1963-1973</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Vern Dunning, Chehalis Pioneer, on the Chinook
              Language</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19650923/19650923" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1965 September 23</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">1</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape, 1, Side One: Vern Dunning speaks about origin and composition of Chinook jargon
              and counts in Chinook Jargon. Dunning speaks about varieties of language among the
              tribes along the Columbia and North Pacific Coast that made a trade or universally
              understood language (pidgin) necessary. Dunning goes over vocabulary in Chinook
              jargon. "King George Man" is an Englishman. Gives names for coat and canoe. [The
              quality of the tape is not so good as to be able to discern the pronunciation of the
              Chinook Jargon words absolutely.] <emph render="italic">Tum-tum</emph> meaning the
              beat of the heart - Tum River. <emph render="italic">Memaloose</emph> - to die,
              Memaloose Island. <emph render="italic">Hýoo</emph> - big, huge, a lot. <emph render="italic">Skookum</emph>, strong. <emph render="italic">Chickema</emph>,
              money. Dunning constructs sentences in Chinook Jargon. <emph render="italic">Chook</emph>, grandma, grandpa. <emph render="italic">Chuck</emph>, water. Dunning
              gives explanation of some of the words, how they degraded from their original English,
              French or Indian pronunciation. <emph render="italic">Ickta</emph>, what. <emph render="italic">Iskum</emph>, to get. Dunning notes the difference between the
              English pronunciation of Chinook Jargon and the Indian pronunciation where the "k"
              sound is replaced by the "g" sound by the Indians that Dunning has spoken with. <emph render="italic">Klootchman</emph>, wife, woman. <emph render="italic">Kootman</emph>, mare. <emph render="italic">Kuntucks</emph>, to understand,
              knowledge, recognize or believe. <emph render="italic">Piljob</emph>, the devil. <emph render="italic">Mosh</emph>, to leave, turn out, sail, throw away, quit, vanish,
              cast, dash, desert, dispatch, dismiss, detach, drop, apply, expel, exterminate,
              forsake, heave, insert, relinquish, remit, sling, toss, transmit etc. Speaks the
              contextual nature of Chinook Jargon. <emph render="italic">Mumook</emph>, to work.
                <emph render="italic">Nesatchi</emph>, bad, evil. <emph render="italic">Moose-moose</emph>, horned cattle. <emph render="italic">Mowwich</emph>, deer.
                <emph render="italic">Moosum</emph>, to sleep. <emph render="italic">Muck-a-muck</emph>, food. <emph render="italic">Mika</emph>, second person, you.
              Dunning speaks about learning Chinook Jargon from the Indian children around his home
              as a child fishing in the Chehalis River.</p>
            <p>Tape 1, Side Two:<emph render="italic">Tillicum</emph>, friend. <emph render="italic">Ticook</emph>, white. <emph render="italic">Tum-water</emph>, waterfall. <emph render="italic">Tyee</emph>, chief. <emph render="italic">Tenas</emph>, small. <emph render="italic">Wa-wa</emph>, speak or talk. Dunning speaks about the guttural
              nature of Chinook Jargon. Dunning speaks about being born in Quincy, Michigan. Dunning
              speaks about the railway system and traveling from Michigan by train to the Northwest.
              Interview concludes noting that Vern Dunning was reading through the book Chinook: A
              History and Dictionary, by Edward Harper Thomas, and examining a "birds-eye" picture
              of Centralia in 1884.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Silas Heck, Chehalis Shaker</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1963/1963" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1963</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">2</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 2, Side One [Tape speed varies]: Silas Heck &amp; Vern Dunning speak about the
              use of Chinook Jargon. Heck speaks about fur trading. Silas Heck speaks of the
              origination of the Chinook Jargon with the Hudson's Bay company. [Chinook Jargon was
              not a product of the contact brought about through the fur trade, it existed among the
              tribes along the Columbia and Coast who did not share a common dialect. The fur trade
              exacerbated its use.] Silas Heck speaks about his father trapping for beaver. Heck
              recalls his father living with the Ford family. Heck speaks about how Lizzie Ford and
              his father produced a child, with the last name Pickner, Reilly Pickner. Heck speaks
              about how Reilly Pickner and Pickner's family were not recognized by anyone as part
              Indian. Heck speaks about gathering camas and cedar. Dunning and Heck recall Ford's
              log house. Heck recalls Governor Stevens holding council at Ford's house to have the
              treaty read and interpreted. Dunning and Heck speak about Ford's cemetery. Heck speaks
              about being a Shaker, of the John Slocum denomination. Heck tells the story of John
              Slocum's death and resurrection, which marked the foundation of the Shaker religion.
              Heck speaks about what happens after death. Heck speaks about Wickasham's recollection
              of life after death. Heck speaks about being chief of police on the reservation. Heck
              continues to recount John Slocum's travels after death. Heck speaks about Slocum's
              promise of a new medicine for the people. Heck recounts how the coming of the medicine
              that makes up the "shaking" part of the church. Heck speaks about his living
              relations. Dunning speaks about living in Centralia. Heck speaks about Billy Mills and
              the Mills family who could speak the Chehalis language. Heck speaks about the
              importance of camas for his people, and who camas was utilized by the white people
              also. [Tape goes out, portion of interview lost]. Heck speaks about the preparation of
              camas. Heck speaks about hunting elk, most opportune times etc. Heck speaks about the
              medicine man of the early times, which worked as healers as well as seers.</p>
            <p>Tape 2, Side Two: Blank for about two minutes. Heck speaks about the coming of the
              white people as foreseen by the medicine men of the early days, who brought
              domestication. [Tape goes out] Heck continues speaking about animal domestication.
              Heck speaks about his religious beliefs. Integration of the teachings of Jesus Christ
              into Native American spiritual life. Heck gives his Indian name in the Chehalis
              language, <emph render="italic">Ts'e may'uks</emph>. Heck gives his age as 91. Heck
              discusses his views of Native American origin in North America; he speaks of his
              people being the people of the lost tribe of Israel. Heck speaks about playing the
              bone game. [Tape cuts out]</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Pachenant Indian Reserve</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">3</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 3, Side One: Tape begins with introduction, by Randy Lewis of Western Washington
              University. He is taping his travels to the Pachenant Indian Reserve, which is a
              fishing village town of Port Rentview, on the West Coast side of Vancouver Island. The
              entire tape is a narrative by Randy Lewis, as he acknowledges that the Pachenant are
              hostile to outsiders. He notes that to interview a tribal member requires a permission
              process approved only through the Tribal Council. Lewis speaks about the betrayal of
              the early anthropologists and sociologists that have made the Pechenant cautious about
              trusting outside researchers. Lewis will discuss the conversation he had with Chief
              Art Jones of the Pachenant people. Lewis speaks about visiting the past acting Chief,
              Charlie Jones. Lewis attests to his Indian heritage. Lewis describes Chief Art Jones,
              his character and appearance, and role as a traditional chief. Lewis discusses the
              history of the Pachenant people, their migrations in the early days and their
              relations among the other Native groups. Lewis recounts Chief Art Jones talking about
              the education of his people (which he refers to as his children). Lewis recounts Chief
              Art Jones speaking about the building reforms on the reserve. Lewis describes Chief
              Art Jones' concern for identify loss among his people due to Western education and
              influences. Lewis describes revitalization projects underway on the reserve. Lewis
              discusses the housing project on the Pachenant reserve. Lewis speaks about the income
              of the Pachenant people, which is almost entirely dependent on the lumber industry.
              Lewis relates Chief Art Jones' reasons why the Pachenant do not salmon fish. The main
              reasons are the expense of the equipment needed to be competitive in the commercial
              fish market and the governmental restrictions by the Canadian government on salmon
              retailing and harvesting by the Indians.</p>
            <p>Tape 3, Side Two: Lewis continues to speak about the income of the Pachenant. Lewis
              discusses the relations between the Pachenant and the white community at Port
              Rentview. Lewis relates the story of a murder of a young Pachenant Indian man by a
              white man of Port Rentview. This murder and the overall prejudice of the white
              community has made relations hostile. Lewis attests to the mending of relations
              between the Pachenant and the white community by Chief Art Jones. Lewis speaks about
              the problems that Chief Art Jones faces trying to lead his people. Lewis speaks about
              the problems of higher education for the young Indian people. Lewis speaks about the
              fishing rights of the Pachenant people, which is heavily restricted by the treaty made
              with the British. Lewis relates the fishing provisions of the Pachenant people by
              telling a story Chief Art Jones told him in their interview about the prosecution of
              the previous Chief Charlie Jones for fishing violations. Lewis speaks about Chief Art
              Jones' wish and plan to bring his people back to the reserve, i.e. annuities for
              returning members. Lewis speaks about social problems among the Pachenant community.
              Lewis speaks about the importance of the children for Pachenant people.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">George O. Pablo, Flathead counselor at Yakima, and
              Beatrice Black, Quinault interviewed by David Tuck</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1963/1973" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">4</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 4, Side One: George Pablo begins by introducing himself as a counselor for
              Native Americans in Yakima and along the coast to Canada. [Tape is of poor quality and
              cannot be understood. It gets a bit better after about five minutes.] Pablo speaks
              about the alcohol treatment programs on the reservation. Pablo speaks about the
              effects of alcohol on the young Indian people. Pablo speaks about the programs in
              place to help Indian people combat alcoholism. Pablo speaks about the nature of Indian
              people that keeps them from speaking out publicly. David Tuck asks about the
              acceptance level for the Indian Reorganization Act. Pablo speaks about the
              self-sufficiency of his people. Pablo speaks about the white-Indian relations in his
              area. Pablo attests to the movement of Indian people to the Urban areas, off the
              reservation. David Tuck asks about Pablo's knowledge of traditional Flathead ways.
              Pablo speaks about the retention of traditional hunting and fishing ways. Pablo speaks
              about the Shakers and about traditional religion, the "Feather religion" or "Bluejay
              religion." Pablo speaks about the Flathead language. David Tuck asks about myths or
              legends. Pablo dodges the question. Tuck tries to bait him into telling a legend.
              Pablo speaks briefly about the coyote. Tuck asks about the function of oral tradition
              in modern Native American life. Pablo speaks briefly about the retention of
              traditional ways. Pablo speaks about the Flathead reservation. Pablo speaks about the
              retention of smoke shacks on the Flathead reservation. Pablo speaks about the dams and
              the timber as the major sources of income on the Flathead reservation.</p>
            <p>Tape 4, Side Two: [Very poor recording.] Beatrice Black speaks about the traditional
              ways of travel by canoe on the river systems. Black speaks about walking the beach to
              get to a place. Black speaks about her brother, who hunted whale and seal. Black
              speaks about her father's homestead outside of Flatbush. Black speaks about obtaining
              and selling fish in her day. Black speaks about her father picking hops yearly. Black
              speaks about using cattails for mats, and where to find cattails. Beatrice Black
              speaks about gathering grasses. Black speaks about taking a canoe from Neah Bay to
              Seattle and then sleeping on the dock. Black speaks about traveling to Canada to fish
              the Fraser River. Black speaks about hunting sea lion. Black speaks about whale
              watching teams and whale hunting. Beatrice Black speaks about whale hunting. Black
              speaks about the cataloging of the whale meat. Black speaks about her husband
              fishing.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Ben Charles and Joe De La Cruz, Quinault, interviewed
              by Clifford Mowitch and Deanna Trotchie</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">5</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 5, Side One: Clifford Mowitch introduces Ben Charles who is a master carver on
              the Quinault reservation, who teaches the children. Ben Charles speaks about his
              beginnings as a wood carver. Ben Charles speaks about teaching carving at Gray's
              Harbor Community College. Ben Charles specializes in carving canoes and paddles. Ben
              Charles speaks about carving a 27-foot canoe for the World's Fair in Spokane for the
              Smithsonian. Ben Charles speaks about his father who was a canoe bearer. Ben Charles
              speaks about the different kinds of canoes and their functions. All kinds of canoes
              were made out of red cedar. Shovel-nose canoes. "Half-breed" canoes that were built by
              the white people were shoveled in the front but built with a place for a motor in the
              back. Ben Charles speaks about the profits made by the tribe from the carving
              industry. Deanna Trotchie tries to draw the "meaning" of totem poles out of Ben
              Charles, but Mr. Charles is not very responsive to her questions. Mr. Charles concedes
              that the paddles and the totem poles are related to different family lines. A second
              interview with Tribal Chairman of the Quinault Reservation, Joe De La Cruz begins. Joe
              De La Cruz begins with a brief history of the tribal council. 1922 as the year of the
              first set of bylaws adopted by the Quinault. Gives names of previous Chairmen and
              their relations to the original treaty signers. Explains the Tribal Constitution. Joe
              De La Cruz speaks about the Allotment Act of 1887, and the effects it had on his
              people and Quinault land. After the allotment of the reservation the timber companies
              zoned the timber, and eventually most of it was logged off by long-term contract. Joe
              De La Cruz speaks of closing off the Reservation, the beach, lake, highway and woods.
              The logging companies obtained restraining orders from the Federal government, but De
              La Cruz enforced the closure of the woods on the reservation.</p>
            <p>Tape 5, Side Two: Joe De La Cruz speaks about the monetary loss incurred by the tribe
              because of their battle to gain autonomy over their timber. De La Cruz speaks on the
              community outreach programs. Resource development. Resource rehabilitation.
              Improvement planning. Joe De La Cruz speaks about the beach restrictions, the
              penalties for trespass by non-Indian etc, and the hunting and clam digging regulations
              that were redefined by De La Cruz in the Tribal Constitution. De La Cruz speaks about
              the hatchery on Lake Quinault. Cruz speaks about the houses on the reservation, from
              the government shacks built in the 1930s to the more modern homes today, that were
              commissioned in the 1960s. "Self-help" houses.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Joe De La Cruz and Nina Baumgardner, interviewed by
              Clifford Mowitch and Deanna Trotchie</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">6</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 6, Side One: Joe De La Cruz speaks about the education system for the Quinault
              people. The addition of Native values and traditions to the standard curriculum to
              make education more meaningful to the children. Growing rate of Quinault people who
              attend college. De La Cruz speaks about when his people attended boarding school,
              mostly at Chemawa. Deanna asks about De La Cruz's feelings towards Wounded Knee. De La
              Cruz answers. De La Cruz speaks about the steelhead controversy. Washington State
              banned the sale of game fish, steelhead being a game fish, so tribes sold their
              steelhead harvest in Oregon while the battle was being fought in court. De La Cruz
              gives a bit of Quinault history. Primary subsistence during the pre-European contact
              period. Longhouse locations. Interview ends abruptly. Interview with Nina Baumgardner
              begins. Nina Baumgardner speaks about shearing sheep in Montana. This discussion leads
              into a recitation of the twenty-third psalm and her belief in Jesus Christ.
              Baumgardner speaks about fishing as the primary livelihood of the Quinaults. Nina
              speaks about attending boarding school at the Puyallup Indian School, which later
              became known as Cushman Hospital. Motus [Mawtoos] big goings-on, pow-wow, potlatch
              that she attended with her father put on by Anna Cotes. Nina recalls Puyallup children
              dipping for salmon on the river. Nina lists some of the prominent family lines of the
              Puyallup tribe. Nina recalls being brought back to the boarding school from the
              gathering. Nina speaks about witnessing children fish with a spear in the river. Nina
              speaks about picking berries. Nina describes a berry scoop that was used to gather
              loot (root)-berries.</p>
            <p>Tape 6, Side Two: Nina speaks about the lodges, made of split timber and open at the
              top, that her people use to inhabit. Interview cuts out.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Nina Baumgardner, Quinault (Part I), interviewed by
              Clifford Mowitch and Deanna Trotchie</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730504/19730504" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 4</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">7</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 7, Side One: Interview begins in progress with Nina Baumgardner telling of her
              experience in the Shaker Church. She speaks of the opening and the finishing of the
              table with a song and a prayer by a sister of the Church. Nina speaks about the apple
              orchard on North River. Nina describes the processing of the apples. Nina speaks about
              her family picking apples at the orchard, and her encounter with Sasquatch,
              Tsi'at'qwes (Ts'emekwes in Lummi). Nina speaks of an encounter with Tsi'at'qwes that
              her father had on the Nash River. A pear was thrown at her uncle, while there were no
              pear trees in the area, this is from Ske'kum, something unnatural. Squaxen Island as
              the headquarters for Tsi'at'qwes. Nina speaks about her holdings on Squaxen Island.
              Nina speaks about Sasquatch sightings at Gray's Harbor. Nina describes Tsi'at'qwes to
              her knowledge. Nina speaks about Indian and white relations. Deanna asks about the
              origin of the Quinault and Nina answers that the Quinault have always been there. Nina
              addresses the Bering Strait land bridge theory that was described to her as the true
              origin of her people. Another story claims that the Indian people never did cross the
              land bridge. Nina recalls speaking to a Mormon missionary, who claimed that Indians
              were the chosen people. Nina speaks of the "I" that watches you. Nina speaks about her
              knowledge of the Old and New Testament and upbringing. Nina addresses the belief that
              Indians are "superstitious." Nina speaks about the sacred nature of water. She tells a
              fable about water.</p>
            <p>Tape 7, Side Two: Blank</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Nina Baumgardner, Quinault (Part II)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730504/19730504" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 4</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">8</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 8, Side One: Nina Baumgardner speaks about the retaliation to Little Big Horn by
              the white soldiers on the Sioux. Nina speaks about the unjust nature of the military
              action against the Indians. Nina speaks about the singing among the Montana Indians.
              She recalls traveling to many reservations, the Blackfeet, Flathead, Coeur de Lane,
              Chehalis etc. Nina shows Deanna and others her stash of trade beads (wampum), abalone
              shells and other objects. Nina speaks about Cushman Indian Boarding School. She
              recalls beginning school at age six, her homesickness. Nina speaks about her treatment
              at boarding school. She recalls her sister's experience at St. John's Catholic
              Boarding School between Seattle and Tacoma, where Native language use was discouraged
              with physical abuses like lye soap mouthwashes. Nina speaks about working in Seattle
              during WWII. Nina speaks about Indian hospitality. Nina speaks about attending the
              Shaker Church. She recalls the singing and dancing. Nina tells the story of the
              foundation of the Shaker Church with the resurrection of John Slocum. Nina attests to
              John Slocum belonging to the Squaxen Island people. Nina repeats John Slocum's mission
              statement that he received from God.</p>
            <p>Tape 8, Side Two: Blank</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Louie Wapato, Colville (Part I), interviewed by Jeff
              Wilner</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19530515/19530515" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 15</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">9</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 9, Side One: Jeff Wilner introduces Louie Wapato. Louie Wapato introduces
              himself. He speaks about living on his family's original allotments and tending the
              apple orchards that his family began after the European expansion into their lands.
              Louie Wapato speaks about the uses of apples, and the raising up of apple orchards.
              Louie speaks about the early relations between the white people and the Native
              Americans. Louie speaks about the formation of the Colville reservation on land that
              was not particularly desirable to the white people at that time, who had already
              colonized the Colville Valley. He speaks about the mineral property rights of the
              Colville people. He gives a brief history of the Colville reservation land. The
              effects of the gold rush, and the minimizing of Colville land by the Federal
              government during the Allotment Act. Louie speaks to the derisive effects of the
              Wheeler-Howard Act (Allotment Act). Louie speaks about his role during the
              Wheeler-Howard Act hearings. He worked as an interpreter. Louie speaks about his
              grandfather, where he lived and his orchard. Louie speaks about how his grandfather
              traded for horses and canoes at The Dalles. Louie recalls Barnaby, who was a powerful
              Colville. Louie speaks about the qualities of an Indian chief in the early days as
              compared to what his people require from a chief in modern times. Louie speaks about
              past chiefs, Qe'mý'ekin who was Paloose etc. Wilner asks about other leaders of the
              Colville. Louie names a few.</p>
            <p>Tape 9, Side Two: [Recording is poor] Louie speaks about state taxation on tribal
              lands. Louie speaks about Judge John Marshall. Jeff Wilner asks about the 1920's
              before the New Deal. Louie speaks about the State's oppression of the Indian people.
              Louie speaks about the Commercial Club that use to be responsible for tribal affairs
              before the Colville had a business council in the 1910s and 1920s. Louie recalls
              traveling to Washington DC during the New Deal times and speaking to Emmens and
              Zimmerman, the assistant commissioner, and Secretary of the Interior. Jeff Wilner asks
              about the history of the Moses Allotments along the Columbia River. Louie speaks about
              the removal of the Indians from their traditional homelands along the Columbia River.
              Louie recalls Long Jim opposing the allotments in favor of a reservation. But the
              people were forced into taking individual allotments. Louie's wife tells why they were
              called Moses Allotments. Moses was the chief at the time U.S. officials forced the
              Indians to take up on allotments. Louie describes the delegation of allotments and
              tribal land. Louie attests to the Indian ownership of the river bottom and ore beneath
              it. This ownership was opposed later by the State. Jeff Wilner asks why the Medhows
              didn't like Moses. Louie and his wife speak about Moses' claim to the Medhows' land
              that caused friction. Louie's wife speaks of Moses' tyranny as a leader. Louie claims
              that it was Moses' father that was tyrannical. Moses' death fighting the Blackfeet.
              Louie's wife speaks about the take over of Wapato Point. She describes ownership
              practices from a Native perspective: it's the tribe that controls land not the
              individual. Louie speaks about State taxation on tribal lands. Jeff Wilner asks about
              Chief Tenasket. Louie recalls Chief Tenasket. Louie speaks to the familial nature of
              the chief's position, where there are certain family lines in a tribe who breed
              chiefs. Jeff Wilner asks about Sosopkin from Loomis. Louie speaks about Sosopkin
              leaving for Canada.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Louie Wapato, Colville (Part II)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730515/19730515" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 15</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">10</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 10, Side One: Jeff Wilner asks about Chelan Bob. Louie attests to him being his
              uncle. Chelan Bob was a Wenatchee Indian. Louie speaks about the Colville Reservation
              once being the Grant Reservation designed for many different tribes in the Eastern
              Washington area, and thus bringing his uncle from Wenatchee. Chelan Bob married Long
              Jim's sister. Louie described Chelan Jim. Louie speaks about the "real" Yakamas who
              only reside now in Nespelem. He claims the Yakama living on the Yakama Reservation are
              "imported" from the Columbia River basin. He claims the "real" Yakama were massacred
              by white colonizers. Louie speaks about some of the traditional camping places for
              Indian people. Louie speaks about his grandfather, the George's, living at Vantage
              Point along Crab Creek and running cattle. The George's are Moses' people. Louie
              speaks about being drafted when his father was ill and receiving a delay. Louie's wife
              speaks about the New Council's meeting where Louie was almost arrested. This was in
              1930. Louie recalls some of the first Council people, Pete Gunn, Jim James, etc.
              Louie, Louie's wife, and an unidentified woman speak about the tribal debate over the
              New Deal Policies. Louie speaks about the Dam that was built on the Columbia River,
              and the tribes involvement in the sale of their half of the river bed. Louie
              attributes the sale of the river bed land to the "half-bloods" that were in control of
              tribal politics at the time. Louie's wife speaks to how the "half-bloods" gained
              control of the council. Louie's wife speaks about her father building one of the first
              orchards. Jeff Wilner asks about the Medhow people. Louie speaks about Moses and Long
              Jim being forced onto the reservation. Louie's wife speaks about the death of Wapato
              John's grandson who was a baby when he fell from a horse on its way to the
              reservation. This was during the Indian removal time. Louie recalls the relocation of
              the Nez Perce to Nespelem.</p>
            <p>Tape 10, Side Two: Blank</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Joe Louie, interviewed by K. Lee and Judy
              Thompson</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730524/19730524" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 24</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">11-11A</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 11-11A, Side One: Joe Louie introduces himself as a Nooksack and describes his
              people's territory. Born in 1894, near Lynden. Father's name is Louie Saq'wel'ti,
              Mother's name is Annie. She was Nooksack and part Skagit. Recalls the first white
              settlements in Lynden, the first saw and shingle mills. Joe Louie speaks about his
              father's renown as a hunter. His father was contracted to hunt for funerals and
              gatherings. Joe Louie speaks to learning to hunt from his father. Hunts for his
              people, not for money. Speaks to the Native value of giving. Indian way of live is to
              offer. Speaks to the loss of this value for the sake of modernism. Treaty of 1855. The
              Nooksack were not a party to the Treaty due to the harsh winter weather, which made
              the river non-negotiable. White settlers began to take up homesteads on Nooksack land.
              Nooksack people couldn't take homesteads until 1884. Joe Louie recalls the traditional
              burial practice of placing the dead in trees. Homesteads where taken by white people
              on these burial grounds. Some on traditional spiritual beliefs. The white people that
              took the homesteads with burials didn't know what to do with the bones scattered on
              their property. After the Indian Homestead Act, Joe Louie's grandfather, father, and
              others worked to gather the bones and place them in a cemetery in Northwood. Joe Louie
              speaks about the way of life of the hunter. A hunter receives an invitation to provide
              for the people. A hunter then must prepare by understanding life. A hunter must hunt
              for a death. The search for the animal that is willing to give itself up. Joe Louie
              laments the fact that Indian parents do not teach their children about the real way of
              life, do not provide a true education. Education does not lead to acceptance within
              the white world for an Indian.</p>
            <p>Tape 11-11A, Side Two: Joe Louie speaks about sending a young Indian man to college
              and his eventual non-acceptance in a predominantly white firm. Joe Louie speaks about
              the importance of obtaining an education in the Indian way. Joe Louie speaks about
              meeting with Dr. Webb and discussing education. Joe Louie speaks about the problem of
              Indian homestead land that has too many heirs to be claimed without a cooperative sale
              of the land to the tribe. The Federal government disallows this practice, and the land
              remains unused due to family conflict. [Tape shuts off briefly] Joe Louie speaks about
              being confined to a reservation. Failure of the current programs to meet immediate
              needs for the elderly, and those not fit to work in jobs off the reservation. Joe
              Louie speaks about having to go to the Lummi Reservation for health services. Joe
              Louie speaks to working towards Indian autonomy from the Federal government. Speaks
              about building up farms for the Indian people to work. Joe Louie speaks about
              obtaining tribal recognition for his Nooksack people. He speaks about working with Dr.
              Reinhart at Western Washington University. Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Joe Louie, Nooksack (Parts I and II), interviewed by
              Jeff Wilner</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730601/19730601" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 June 1</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">12</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 12, Side One: Jeff Wilner begins by asking about the Wheeler-Howard Act
              (Allotment Act), and the negative attitudes towards it by the Indians. Joe Louie
              attests that the Nooksack did not act negatively to the Act. The Nooksack were an
              organized people. Joe Louie speaks about having no voice in the debate over the Act
              because the Nooksack were not recognized as a Treaty tribe. Reinhart from Western
              Washington University helped the Nooksack establish their tribal claim. Joe Louie
              speaks about the Act being another piece of bureaucracy that was not intended to help
              the Indian people's immediate needs. Joe Louie speaks about being asked to leave his
              homestead and move up to the Middle Fork to less desirable land. Some on the Indian
              Homestead Act as being comparable to Treaty land rights. Joe Louie speaks about being
              a part of an Indian organization that was active in petitioning for education and
              health benefits for the Nooksack. Joe Louie speaks about the problems with the
              programs that are designed to help Indian people. Superintendent Upchurch and Graves.
              Constitution and bylaws at Lummi and Swinomish. Forrest Kinley's wife as being
              responsible for drawing up the Constitution at Lummi. Joe Louie speaks about the
              general acceptance of the Wheeler-Howard Act as a being the result of the need of
              Indian Tribes for the Federal programs and protection provided under the Act.</p>
            <p>Tape 12, Side Two: [Poor recording] Joe Louie speaks about his desire for acceptance
              from the white community. Joe Louie speaks about feeling rejected from the churches
              and schools in the white community. Joe Louie speaks to not caring whether the Federal
              government recognizes his people as a tribe. He wants the people that surround him in
              his everyday life to recognize him as an Indian and an equal. Joe Louie speaks about
              including in the Nooksack Constitution and bylaws the ability for Nooksack relations
              not on the census to be able to enter the tribal roles. Joe Louie speaks about
              starting the "small tribe" which served to educate the rest of the Nooksack people on
              organizing and getting together as a people. Joe Louie speaks about Roy leading the
              Nooksack. Joe Louie speaks about Bob Davis, who is a Yakama, and is the Chairman of
              the Nooksack Incorporated, which is Roy's group. Joe Louie speaks about Tom Williams
              and Ed Roberts who are part of Roy's group. Joe speaks about being a part of Wilfred
              Cline's group, who are working on the Constitution and bylaws. Joe Louie speaks about
              Mickey Roberts.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Joe Louie, Nooksack (Part III)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730601/19730601" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 June 1</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">13</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 13, Side One: Joe Louie speaks about Mickey Roberts. Joe Louie speaks about
              Nooksack Tribal political matters. Joe Louie speaks about Mary Hillaire, and her role
              in Nooksack political dealings. Programs for economic development. Joe speaks about
              the deleterious effects of fish hatcheries for the river, but the benefits of
              hatcheries for the employment of Nooksack people. Joe speaks about the need for his
              people to thank life. Joe tells a story that teaches about thanking life. Joe speaks
              about the eradication of the cedar tree from over exploitation. Joe speaks about other
              uses for the cedar product. Joe Louie speaks about the function of the Indian dance as
              a right of initiation for a young person.</p>
            <p>Tape 13, Side Two: Blank</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Mrs. Alba Nettie Shawaway, Nez Perce/Warm
              Springs</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730508/19730508" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 8</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">14</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 14, Side One: Nettie is of Týx tribe, which is called Warm Springs now. Nettie
              speaks her mother and her father's names and tells where they are from. Nettie speaks
              about who her father was and where he was from. He grew up in Nespelem, and was half
              Nez Perce and half Warm Springs. Nettie gives both her father and mother's Indian
              name. Interviewer, Randy Lewis, asks about Klick Relander, who worked with the Warm
              Springs on the book, Drummers and the Dreamers. Nettie speaks about his[Klick
              Relander's] faith in Smohalla. Nettie speaks to the evil nature of Smohalla, who as
              her father tells her, often would tear up the Washat drums and gamble, before he found
              his faith through death. Nettie speaks to the origin of birth of Smohalla, who was a
              Wanapum from Priest Rapids. Nettie speaks to Smohalla's resurrection. Nettie attests
              that Rex Buck took the long house over from the man that took the long house over from
              Smohalla. Randy Lewis and Nettie discuss losing the long house at Priest Rapids to the
              wind. Nettie speaks about her husband, Alba, who was half Wanapum and half Yakama.
              Nettie explains the difference between a "drummer" and a "dreamer." Dreamers or the
              Wasklik are of the feather dance. Wasklik have more power, like the Shaker Indian
              doctor. The <emph render="italic">Washat</emph>, or drummers, don't dream, they just
              believe there is a heaven. Nettie and Randy Lewis list the Indian doctors in the
              Valley and the surrounding area. Nettie and Randy Lewis speak about the Chinook dances
              in the winter where <emph render="italic">Wasklik</emph>, or Indian doctors must prove
              themselves. There are different categories or degrees of Indian doctors, like the
              strongest would be the Bluejays. Nettie speaks about the preparation that is needed
              before roots are gathered in the springtime. This is part of Washat. There is the root
              feast in the spring time, then the salmon feast, and berry feast. Nettie speaks about
              having a root feast in Wanapum after gathering the roots. Nettie discusses the people
              involved in the gathering party as well as the doings at night after the gathering of
              roots. Nettie speaks about peeling the roots and then going to sweat. The next morning
              the cooking begins early, and everyone in the long house must wear new clothing for
              the root feast. Nettie explains about the significance of the seven drums for Washa.
              Randy Lewis concludes that Smohalla was not the founder of Washa, but was more a
              prognosticator for it. Randy Lewis adds that only those who belong to Washat have the
              right know about it. Transcript available.</p>
            <p>Tape 14, Side Two: Blank</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Nez Perce Songs: Root Feast songs, Social songs, Old
              Religious songs, War songs</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1963/1973" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">15</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 15, Side One: Tape is damaged due to degradation.</p>
            <p>Tape 15, Side Two: Tape is damaged due to degradation.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Moses Language: Sinkiuse, by Randy Lewis (Part
              I)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730509/19730509" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 9</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">16</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 16, Side One: The tape contains vocabulary of the Sinkiuse language by
              Qe'lheshp'eken and his wife Agnes. Included are kinship terms and place names.
              Colville pronunciations are included also.</p>
            <p>Tape 16, Side Two: More vocabulary. [Poor recording] Place names, toponyms, continue.
              Various verbs and nouns. Various fishing gear terminology. Many terms for horses.
              Vocabulary words for modern devices are Indian derivations.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Moses Language: Sinkiuse, by Randy Lewis (Part
              II)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730509/19730509" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 9</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">17</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 17, Side One: Vocabulary - human body parts. [Recording is good] Other
              vocabulary words, verbs, adjectives and nouns. Months of the year, etc.</p>
            <p>Tape 17, Side Two: Vocabulary - adjectives and various other types of words. Place
              names, days of the week.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Moses Language: Sinkiuse, by Randy Lewis (Part
              III)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730509/19730509" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 9</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">18-19</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 18-19, Side One: Vocabulary - diseases, modes of travel, horse outfittings.</p>
            <p>Tape 18-19, Side Two: Vocabulary - names of fish species, geographic terms and
              traditional identities for the people there, birds, insects and shellfish, plants,
              place names, counting in numbers, and kinship terms.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Jim Holy Cross, Cowlitz, interviewed by Karen
              Cota</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730630/19730630" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 June 30</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">20</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 20, Side One: Introduction to the Cowlitz people by Jim Holy Cross, their
              distribution, habitation. Upper and Lower Cowlitz are separated, in modern geography,
              by Ethel, Washington. Jim Holy Cross speaks about his family lineage. Jim Holy Cross
              speaks about the Cowlitz meetings, which he views as being governed by money now
              rather than by principle. Jim speaks about the Cowlitz being a non-treaty tribe. Jim
              speaks about the intent of the Cowlitz Council to reclaim tribal lands. Jim Holy Cross
              speaks about the two different rolls for the Cowlitz tribe. Jim Holy Cross speaks
              about the blood quantum issue, at what degree should someone be considered Indian. Jim
              speaks about living and working with the Suquamish as an alcohol counselor. Jim speaks
              about the problematic nature of forming a Cowlitz reservation. Jim speaks about being
              bought off by the Federal government in lieu of official recognition.</p>
            <p>Tape 20, Side Two: Blank</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Jim McKay and Ramona Morris. interviewed by Bill
              Clement</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1963/1973" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">undated</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">21</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 21: Jim McKay, Lummi Chief and head of the tribal council, and Ramona Morris
              head of HEW projects at Lummi were interviewed for KVOS-TV in Bellingham, Washington
              by Bill Clement. Tape was submitted by Bernie Thomas, Lummi, of the KVOS staff.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Ramona Morris, interviewed by Raynette
              Morris</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 Spring</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">22</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 22: Ramona Morris, Director of Health, Education, and Welfare for the Lummi
              Nation is interviewed by her daughter, Raynette Morris on Lummi political affairs from
              1960-1973, special programs and cultural as well as economic development. Topics
              covered include; Aquaculture, LIGHT, various councils- their purposes and composition,
              Lummi by-laws, and educational programs and concerns. Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Al Charles, Lummi (Part I), interviewed by Jeff
              Wilner</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730426/19730426" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April 26</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">23</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 23: Al Charles, Lummi elder, master carver and cultural leader, describes Lummi
              history. Topics covered include the delineation of the Lummi as opposed to other Coast
              Salish groups, toponyms (mostly in Xwlemi chosen, Lummi language) and traditional
              gathering and living areas, longhouse locations, treaty missionaries and educational
              practices and the effects of the Allotment Act. Note that any Lummi words will be
              spelled out using the Lummi phonetic alphabet, thus pronunciation will follow
              according to the rules of the Lummi alphabet which differs from the American English
              letter-sound assignment. Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Al Charles, Lummi (Part II), interviewed by Jeff
              Wilner</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730426/19730426" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April 26</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">24</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 24: Conclusion to the interview with Al Charles started on tape 23. The tape
              contains about 7 minutes of material that overlaps with tape 23 and presents no new
              information.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Felix Solomon, Dora Solomon, Angeline Alexander and
              Aurelia Celestine (Part I)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730413/19730413" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April 13</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">25</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 25: Topics covered in this interview include traditional fishing- implements,
              i.e. hooks, nets, weirs, anchors, locations, processing of the catch, i.e. smoking,
              drying, and butchering; <emph render="italic">Siowyn</emph>, the banning and release
              of winter dancing (pow-wow); and Dora Solomon discusses traditional floral resources.
              Lummi words and Skagit words appear in the Lummi alphabet. Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Felix Solomon, Dora Solomon, Angeline Alexander and
              Aurelia Celestine (Part II)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730413/19730413" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April 13</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">26</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 26: Conclusion to the interview started on tape 25. Topics covered on this tape
              include: Smokehouse (longhouse) life, treatment of visitors, and Skagit story of how
              the Creator gave the trees to the people in the beginning (told by Dora Solomon).
              Lummi words and Skagit words appear in the Lummi alphabet. Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Angeline Alexander, Lummi, interviewed by Laurence
              Thompson</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1969/1969" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1969</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">27</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 27: Lummi elder, Angeline Alexander, discusses genealogy. Only about 10 minutes
              long and most of the names recalled are the Indian names.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Angeline Alexander, Lummi (Part I), interviewed by
              Morrie Alexander and Ann Ware</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19690127/19690127" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1967 January 27</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">28</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 28: Topics covered include Family genealogy (as covered, though in less detail,
              on tape 27) and the Creation story of how the Lummi became a tribe, Sxweloxt and his
              brother. Lummi names and words appear in the Lummi alphabet. Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Angeline Alexander, Lummi (Part II), interviewed by
              Morrie Alexander and Ann Ware</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19690127/19690127" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1967 January 27</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">29</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 29: Continuation of interview started on tape 28. Topics covered include the
              conclusion of the story of Sxweloxt, family genealogy is continued, boarding school
              education- i.e. the Tulalip boarding school and Cushman, conduct and features of a
              traditional gathering, and toponyms. Lummi names and words appear in the Lummi
              alphabet. Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Angeline Alexander, Lummi (Part III), interviewed by
              Morrie Alexander and Ann Ware</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19690127/19690127" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1967 January 27</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">30</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 30: Conclusion to interview that began on tape 28. Only about 5 minutes of
              interview are contained on this tape and the topic of discussion is raiding.
              Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Morrie Alexander, Lummi master carver</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1973-04/1973-04" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">31</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 31: Similar to the lectures given on tape 32 and 40, however question and answer
              periods vary. Lecture given to CES class. Topics covered include: An introduction to
              the distinguishing features of Northwest Coast Indians, original use and inhabitation
              of the San Juan Islands, land mammal hunting- including materials and implements,
              traditional fishing implements- including materials used for making nets, hooks,
              traps, and weirs, duck hunting, snares, materials used for carving, masks- including
              who can wear them and when, naming ceremonies- including a description of the process
              or work involved. Question and answer period follows the lecture. All Lummi words are
              transcribed using the Lummi alphabet.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Morrie Alexander, Lummi master carver
              (MISSING)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1973-04/1973-04" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April</unitdate>
            <langmaterial><language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="546">English</language>.</langmaterial>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">32</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 32: Similar to the lectures given on tape 31 and 40, however question and answer
              periods vary. Lecture given to CES class. Topics covered include: An introduction to
              the distinguishing features of Northwest Coast Indians, original use and inhabitation
              of the San Juan Islands, land mammal hunting- including materials and implements,
              traditional fishing implements- including materials used for making nets, hooks,
              traps, and weirs, duck hunting, snares, materials used for carving, masks- including
              who can wear them and when, naming ceremonies- including a description of the process
              or work involved. Question and answer period follows the lecture. All Lummi words are
              transcribed using the Lummi alphabet. Tape 32 does not exist in the collection at
              CPNWS.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Louisa George, Sarah James, Ella Reid, Philoemina
              Solomon (Harry), Helen Paul, Rosemary Placid and Ernest Paul, Nooksack and Lummi
              Elders (Part I)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730427/19730427" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April 27</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">33</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 33: Topics covered in this interview include: Nooksack delineation; traditional
              fishing implements and materials; traditional floral and faunal resources- used for
              food, shelter, and clothing; boarding schools and educational experiences; early
              missionaries- i.e. Father Cheriouse; why the Nooksacks were not at the Point Elliot
              Treaty signing; longhouse location and construction; traditional dyes; appropriate
              etiquette at a gathering; and more on boarding school life. Words in Halkomalem,
              Lhacheslum (Nooksack), Skagit, and Lummi are transcribed using the Lummi alphabet
              system. Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Louisa George, Sarah James, Ella Reid, Philoemina
              Solomon (Harry), Helen Paul, Rosemary Placid and Ernest Paul, Nooksack and Lummi
              Elders (Part II)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730427/19730427" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April 27</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">34</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 34: This tape is a continuation of the interview that started on tape 33. Topics
              covered include: Introductions and personal identifications, and traditional marriage
              practices (partial). Words in Lummi and Skagit are transcribed using the Lummi
              alphabet system. Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Joe Louie and Nooksack Women (Part I)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730501/19730501" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 1</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">35</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 35, Side One: Transcript available.</p>
            <p>Tape 35, Side Two: Blank</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Joe Louie and Nooksack Women (Part II)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730501/19730501" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 1</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">36</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 36, Side One: Transcript available.</p>
            <p>Tape 36, Side Two: Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Louisa George, Ella Reid, and Helen Paul, Nooksack
              Elders (Part I)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730509/19730509" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 9</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">37</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 37: Topics covered in this interview include: Experiences with early Indian
              education policies of acculturation and assimilation through the boarding schools and
              reservation mission schools, early industrial opportunities for Nooksack people, land
              appropriation and compensation, some on Shaker religion and Methodist diffusion,
              Native language loss and restoration programs for the Nooksack language, traditional
              funerary customs, dancing and spirit doctoring. All Indian words are transcribed using
              the Lummi alphabet. Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Louisa George, Ella Reid, and Helen Paul, Nooksack
              Elders (Part I) (MISSING)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730509/19730509" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 9</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">38</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 38: Conclusion of the interview which began on tape 37. Tape 38 does not exist
              in the collection at CPNWS.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Morrie Alexander, Lummi master carver</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730412/19730412" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">39</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 39: [Poor recording quality] This speech at the Lummi Tribal Center given is a
              brief version of the one contained on tape 40.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Morrie Alexander, Lummi master carver</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1973 April</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">40</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 40: Appearance at VU (possibly Viking Union at WWU?)</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Morrie Alexander, Lummi master carver</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1973-04/1973-04" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">41</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 41: Similar to the lectures given on tape 31 and 32, however question and answer
              periods vary. This lecture given to CES class was held in the Viking Union on the
              campus of Western Washington University. Topics covered include: An introduction to
              the distinguishing features of Northwest Coast Indians, original use and inhabitation
              of the San Juan Islands, land mammal hunting- including materials and implements,
              traditional fishing implements- including materials used for making nets, hooks,
              traps, and weirs, duck hunting, snares, materials used for carving, masks- including
              who can wear them and when, naming ceremonies- including a description of the process
              or work involved. Question and answer period follows the lecture where questions
              concerning raiding and slavery are addressed. All Lummi words are transcribed using
              the Lummi alphabet. Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Christine Bosler, James McKay, James McKay Jr., and
              Rosemary Placid, Lummi Elders (Part I)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730601/19730601" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 June 1</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">42</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 42: Topics covered in this interview include: Genealogy, position of the "chief"
              within the community, early leaders including chief Tsi'li'xw, Chow'its'soot, and
              Kwina, repercussions of the Allotment Act, early industries, raiding and battles
              fought with the Northern peoples, and boarding school experiences. All Lummi names and
              words are transcribed using the Lummi alphabet. Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Christine Bosler, James McKay, James McKay Jr., and
              Rosemary Placid, Lummi Elders (Part II)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730601/19730601" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 June 1</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">43</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 43: Conclusion to the interview started on tape 42. Topics covered include:
              Boarding school experiences, modern issues including militancy, racism, land trust
              disputes, Bureau of Indian Affairs, the economy on the Lummi reservation, modern
              fishing, and treaty grievances. Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Pilot Meeting: Swinomish Elders, interviewed by Landy
              James in LaConner, Washington.</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730515/19730515" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 15</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">44</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 44, Side One: Morris Dan and his wife Bertha. Ken House, John Sheridan and
              William Baylis are students enrolled in the class. Bertha and Morris Dan express their
              concern over having the non-native students there. Bertha speaks about previous
              researchers who came in and take as fact the words of one individual. She is concerned
              that her words will be used improperly. Landy James, one of the interviewers, defends
              the practice of taping interviews with the elders as a means of cultural preservation
              for Indian people. Morris and Bertha Dan continue to rebuke the idea of having their
              words taped and taken away. A lengthy discussion of the goals of the project follows.
              Morris Dan speaks about the importance of knowing your family line. Bertha speaks
              about the division of the Swinomish people into certain sections on the reservation.
              Morris Dan speaks about the inclusion of the Samish, Lower Skagits and other groups on
              the Swinomish reservation when the land was allotted. Bertha and Morris try to figure
              out how many families are represented in the room.</p>
            <p>Tape 44, Side Two: Various talk. Landy James speaks about the importance of hearing
              from more than one family on an issue. Morris speaks about the formation of the
              reservation under the Indian Homestead Act of 1887. Morris Dan speaks to Landy James'
              lineage. Discussion of when would be the best time meet again. Morris Dan tells a
              story about Doug, his grandson. Morris speaks about the ties between the Samish and
              the Swinomish. Morris and Bertha Dan speak about the young woman researcher that lived
              among the Swinomish and then took the information she accumulated and left the area
              with it. The many examples of this kind of exploitation have created a great amount of
              cautiousness for future such endeavors.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Swinomish reservation, interviewed by Landy
              James</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730522/19730522" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 22</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">45</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 45: Landy hands out a couple of sheets that the people present and take some
              time to look over. [a basketball game in the background makes it difficult to hear the
              questions that are asked] Landy discusses some of the conceptions attached to being an
              Indian in the modern world. Landy discusses the idea of shame and the family that
              helps bring the person around. Landy speaks about the ritualistic nature of time. A
              question is asked about the growing importance for Western education for the Native
              American student. Landy speaks to why education is becoming a source of pride for
              families. Landy speaks about the traditional territory of the Swinomish. [Recording
              switches to high speed and fades out.]</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Affiliated Tribes of Northwest Indians Executive
              Council Meeting in Spokane</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730412/19730412" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April 12</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">46</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 46, Side One: Meeting begins in progress with Lucy introducing Webster Two Hawk.
              Mr. Two Hawk speaks about being new to Indian political affairs. He begins by
              explaining what his organization is seeking. The duties/mission statement for the
              members of the National Tribal Chairman's Association. Mr. Two Hawk is a Chairman of
              the Rosebud Sioux tribe. He outlines some of his and his people's frustrations with
              current and past Indian policies of the Federal government. Speaks to the Indian
              tribes' right to self-government. Mr. Two Hawk lists his tribe's grievances with the
              Federal government. Of these is the impossibility of tribal self-determination under
              the present structure of Indian policies. Mr. Two Hawk presents a projection to remedy
              the current situation, and aid in the establishment of self-determination for Indian
              Nations. Mr. Two Hawk speaks to allowing the tribe full control over education for
              their Indian children without interference by the BIA. He speaks of not equating
              self-determination with termination. The next speaker is introduced, Executive
              Director of the National Tribal Chairman's Association, Bill [Yulley]. Mr. Yulley
              speaks about the origin of the National Tribal Chairman's Association, which was
              founded for the leaders of the Federally recognized tribes who live and work with
              reservation policy.</p>
            <p>Tape 46, Side Two: The next speaker is introduced, Chairman Robert Jim of Yakama
              reservation. Mr. Jim speaks about upholding the treaty rights for the benefit of his
              people over all other things. Mr. Jim speaks about the proliferation of tribal
              policies, which see no action. Mr. Jim speaks about the function of the National
              Tribal Chairman's Association, who he feels represents all tribes with a land base. He
              feels the integrity of the NTCA is in jeopardy. He speaks of the danger of the Federal
              Government appending tribal land. He speaks to the function of such groups like the
              NTCA and the NCAI in reclaiming funds from the Federal Government that have not been
              rightfully distributed to the Indian tribes. Announcements are made and the next
              speaker is introduced. Nez Perce member Walter [Moltuck]. Mr. Moltuck reads a
              resolution he received from a different tribe that is an appeal for communication
              between Indian Nations. He speaks to the divided nature of Indian groups who are
              looking outside themselves for leaders. He speaks about FBI monitoring on the Spokane
              reservation and other Indian Nations. He speaks to tribal unity through an
              organization movement and a utilization of groups such as the NCTA and the NCAI.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Affiliated Tribes of Northwest Indians Conference
              (1973 Fishing Controversy)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">47</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 47, Side One: The meeting begins in progress with a speaker asking for an
              endorsement from the NCTA. Speaks about the urgency of the situation, which calls for
              a unity of Indian peoples, and the forgiveness of past grudges between tribes that
              will facilitate the lobby for fishing resolutions. Another speaker relating his
              experiences as an Indian fisherman confronting the myth that it's Indian fishing that
              is depleting the resource. The speaker dispels this myth, and speaks of the monopoly
              that the white man has on commercial fishing. The speaker introduces Mike Taylor, an
              attorney working for the Indian tribes to secure treaty fishing rights. Doug speaks
              about his organization, The Native American Rights to [Hunt], which is a law firm
              expert in treaty cases that work to protect tribal sovereignty. Speaks about pending
              suits, such as the suit against the Army Corps of Engineers on the Columbia River who
              are involved in the modification of the dams along the Columbia River, which is
              resulting in the loss of traditional fishing sites for the Tribes along the Columbia
              River. The questions asked to the attorneys are difficult to decipher. An unidentified
              speaker with the attorneys speaks about providing physical protection for Native
              people so they can fish unmolested. Dave [Weir] &amp; Jenny speak about a report that
              shows where the fish are really going. [The woman speaker is very hard to hear over
              the background noise] Negotiations between Canada and American Native fishing tribes.
              Annual catch of Coho salmon in the Puget Sound, by percentage taken by group. [Last
              five minutes of the tape are damaged]</p>
            <p>Tape 47, Side Two: [Tape is damaged, or recording is very poor for about the first
              seven minutes.] Speaker calls for a list of grievances from every fishing tribe.
              Explains articles of incorporation and bylaws as they pertain to fishing. Another
              speaker breaks in and speaks about the wish of the Canadian Indians to become involved
              in the fight for the right to fish as the treaty guarantees. A speaker from the
              Klamath people speaks to his grievances, and knowledge of traditional fishing land
              where the government says there is none. The lawyers address the issue of land the
              tribe claims to be traditional hunting and fishing grounds, but that is not recognized
              or protected by the Federal Government. The lawyer speaks of the process of
              ethno-historical reconstruction that must be completed for the Courts to recognize and
              protect traditionally utilized land. The Chairman of the committee lists the
              resolutions, and these resolutions are discussed and added to.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Affiliated Tribes of Northwest Indians Executive
              Council Meeting, Timber Conference</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730412/19730412" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April 12</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">48</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 48: Tape is irreparably damaged, due to degradation. No access tape
              available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Affiliated Tribes of Northwest Indians Executive
              Council Conference, Spokane, WA, NCAI - NTCA, Cook/Trimble</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730412/19730412" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April 12</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">49</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 49: Tape is irreparably damaged due to degradation.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Affiliated Tribes of Northwest Indians Executive
              Council Meeting. Spokane, Washington. Indian Rights, Fishing, Nation</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730412/19730412" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April 12</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">50</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 50, Side One: Speakers are difficult to decipher, as recording is poor. Some
              discussion of fishing rights and treaty bylaws. Discussion of a redefinition of the
              term "Nation", as it is applied to "Indian Nations." Discussion of the name to be used
              for the Organization being formed at this meeting to fight to uphold treaty rights and
              bylaws. Some of the names proposed were: Washington State Indian Treaty Rights
              Organization, Northwest Indian Treaty Rights Organization, Indian Fishing Rights
              Organization etc. John Solomon from Lummi speaks about the role of the Tribal Councils
              in the newly formed Treaty Rights organization. Chairman speaks about the intended
              purpose of the Affiliated Tribes of Northwest Indians as a functioning group. John
              Solomon speaks about the effectiveness of the Affiliated Tribes of Northwest Indians,
              and the need for bylaws within the organization.</p>
            <p>Tape 50, Side Two: [Recording is poor.] More discussion on the proposed names for the
              new organization. Discussion on the need for Native groups to be able to unite and try
              to solve issues in common. The Chairman addresses the issue of the benefit of making
              the new organization a corporation. The Chairman calls for resolutions from every
              tribe that wishes to be a part of the new Treaty Rights organization. Discussion of
              funds for future actions and formations of new organizations. Discussion of aboriginal
              hunting and fishing rights versus the hunting and fishing rights allowed in the
              Treaties, and the current pressures from the State level bureaucrats upon Indian
              tribes to conform to State regulations on hunting and fishing. Discussion on the right
              to erect smokehouses on the river banks.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Affiliated Tribes of Northwest Indians Executive
              Council Meeting, Spokane, Washington: Resolutions (Part I)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730412/19730412" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April 12</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">51</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 51, Side One: Preamble and bylaws of the organization. Certain representatives
              give resolutions, and motions are made. Resolution for the cooperation and
              coordination of the NTCA and Northwest Affiliated Tribes Organization. Resolution on
              the appointment of new board members.</p>
            <p>Tape 51, Side Two: Resolutions and motions continue. Resolution and discussion on the
              display for the upcoming Expo. Education Committee presents their resolutions.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Affiliated Tribes of Northwest Indians Executive
              Council Meeting, Spokane, Washington: Resolutions (Part II)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730412/19730412" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April 12</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">52</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 52, Side One: Resolution proposed by Cook and Trimble is discussed. Resolution
              to combat the BIA, right past wrongs by the Federal Government, and repeal Public Laws
              that have passed that violate the treaty rights of the tribe. John Solomon discusses
              the need for Indian voices to be acted on more than just heard. Some discussion over
              the distribution of funds to the NTCA and the NCAI. Some concluding statements
              focusing on the need for better communication.</p>
            <p>Tape 52, Side Two: Blank</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Affiliated Tribes of Northwest Indians Executive
              Council Meeting, Spokane, Washington: Resolutions (Part III)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce">1973 April 13</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">53</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 53, Side One: A roll is called for the delegates present at the meeting. Speaker
              reads the first of the resolutions. Jim McKay of Lummi seconds the resolution and it
              is passed. Speaker reads the second resolution, which had to do with the reevaluation
              of the Environmental Protection Policy Act. The Speaker is asked to clarify the
              Environmental Protection Act, and how it is effecting the Native communities around
              the country. Speaker presents a resolution for the repeal/revision of Public Law 9335,
              which negatively effects the Spokane Tribe. Resolution to pressure the Federal
              government to right past wrongs committed against the Indian tribes.</p>
            <p>Tape 53, Side Two: [Tape quality is poor.] Resolution concerning third party approval
              on grants for tribes. Other resolutions are proposed and adopted. Resolution
              concerning aid to Urban Indian Centers. Resolution concerning the delegation of funds
              to repair and restore Chemawa Indian school. Resolutions to promote
              self-determination.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Nooksack Women: Louisa George, Helen Paul, and Ella
              Reid (Part I)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730509/19730509" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 9</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">54</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 54: This is a duplicate copy of Tape 37 in this same collection, only this copy
              is much clearer and will be used to edit the transcript that was rendered from Tape
              37). Transcript available.</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Nooksack Women: Louisa George, Helen Paul, and Ella
              Reid (Part II)</unittitle>
            <unitdate calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="19730509/19730509" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May 9</unitdate>
            <container type="box">1</container>
            <container type="tape">55</container>
          </did>
          <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
            <p>Tape 55, Side One: Interview begins in progress. Louisa speaks about a religious
              leader. Helen Paul speaks about going to Chemawa and Mount Baker High School. Helen
              speaks about escaping the prejudiced nature of the boarding schools. Ella Reid speaks
              about her children's experience with the local school system. Louisa testifies to
              Helen having more problems being Pentecost than being Indian. Jeff Wilner asks about
              the Shaker Church attendance. Louisa and Helen discuss which families in Nooksack are
              affiliated with the Shaker Church. Helen speaks about attending a Shaker service.
              Helen and Louisa describe the doings at a Shaker Service. Ella, Louisa and Helen
              recall the songs sung in Indian at a Shaker service. Louisa tells the story of the
              formation of the Shaker church with the resurrection of John Slocum. Helen speaks
              about the dancing and singing that is part of the Shaker Church. Jeff Wilner asks
              about the Native American Church following in the area. Louisa speaks about her
              experience dancing in the Shaker Church. Louisa speaks about being a Pentecost after
              trying out the Shaker Church. Jeff Wilner asks about the railroad being built through
              Nooksack land without compensation. Helen speaks about a verbal agreement between the
              Nooksack people and the railroad company, which didn't come to pass. Helen mentions a
              lease that was made by the Nooksack people and that wasn't signed by the railroad.
              Helen and Louisa speak about riding the ferry to Victoria, and from Port Townsend, and
              receiving half-price fare. Helen speaks about the Coupeville races. Ella speaks about
              George Swanaset and his half-brother and Henry George (Sam George's uncle) racing at
              Carlisle. Ella speaks about the entrance process to race at Carlisle. Transcript
              available.</p>
            <p>Tape 55, Side Two: Blank</p>
          </scopecontent>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Master copies of interviews on cassette
              tapes</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1963-1973</unitdate>
            <container type="box">Box 2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="item">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Reference and back-up copies of interviews on CDs in
              mp3 and WAV formats</unittitle>
            <unitdate>1963-1973</unitdate>
            <container type="box">Boxes 3 and 4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Transcripts</unittitle>
          <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series II</unitid>
          <unitdate normal="1967/1973" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1967-1973</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Nina Baumgarner (Tape 7)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730504/19730504" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May
              4</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">1</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Joe Louie (Tape 11)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730524/19730524" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May
              24</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">2</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Nettie Shawaway (Tape 14)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730508/19730508" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May
              8</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">3</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Ramona Morris (Tape 22)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="1973/1973" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973
              Spring</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">4</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Al Charles (Tape 23)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730426/19730426" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April
              26</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">5</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Felix Solomon, Dora Solomon, Angeline Alexander and
              Aurelia Celestine (Part I: Tape 25)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730413/19730413" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April
              13</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">6</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Felix Solomon, Dora Solomon, Angeline Alexander and
              Aurelia Celestine (Part II: Tape 26)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730413/19730413" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April
              13</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">7</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Angeline Alexander (Part I: Tape 28)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19670127/19670127" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1967
              January 27</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">8</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Angeline Alexander (Part 2: Tape 29)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19670127/19670127" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1967
              January 27</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">9</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Louisa George, Sarah James, Ella Reid, Philoemina
              Solomon (Harry), Helen Paul, Rosemary Placid and Ernest Paul, (Part I: Tape
              33)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730427/19730427" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April
              27</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">10</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Louisa George, Sarah James, Ella Reid, Philoemina
              Solomon (Harry), Helen Paul, Rosemary Placid and Ernest Paul, (Part II: Tape
              33)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730427/19730427" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April
              27</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">11</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Joe Louie and Nooksack Women (Part I: Tape
              35)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730501/19730501" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May
              1</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">12</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Joe Louie and Nooksack Women (Part I: Tape
              35)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730501/19730501" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May
              1</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">13</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Louisa George, Ella Reid, and Helen Paul (Tape
              37)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730509/19730509" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May
              9</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">14</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Morrie Alexander (Tape 40)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730412/19730412" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 April
              12</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">15</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Christine Bosler, James McKay, James McKay Jr., and
              Rosemary Placid (Part I: Tape 42)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730601/19730601" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 June
              1</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">16</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Christine Bosler, James McKay, James McKay Jr., and
              Rosemary Placid (Part II: Tape 43)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730601/19730601" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 June
              1</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">17</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Louisa George, Helen Paul, and Ella Reid (Tape
              55)</unittitle>
            <unitdate normal="19730509/19730509" type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f">1973 May
              9</unitdate>
            <container type="box">5</container>
            <container type="folder">18</container>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>

