<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601">
    <eadid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="identifier" mainagencycode="wabecp" identifier="80444/xv85165" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv85165">XOE_CPNWS0009wfallsmill</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the Whatcom Falls Mill
			 Company Records and George W. Loggie Papers 
			 <date encodinganalog="date" normal="1886/1978">1886-1978</date></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Whatcom Falls Mill Co.
			 Records, George W. Loggie Papers</titleproper>
        <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding aid prepared by Tamma Farra,
			 revised by Amber Raney.</author>
        <sponsor encodinganalog="contributor">Funding for preparing this
			 finding aid was provided through a grant awarded by the National Historical
			 Publications and Records Commission. Funding for encoding the finding aid was
			 awarded by the National Endowment for the Humanities.</sponsor>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies</publisher>
        <address>
          
          <addressline>Goltz-Murray Building</addressline>
          <addressline>808 25th St</addressline>
          <addressline>Bellingham, WA 98225-9123</addressline>
          <addressline>Phone: 360 650 7534</addressline>
          <addressline>Email: cpnws@wwu.edu</addressline>
          
        </address>
        <date encodinganalog="date" normal="2003">© 2003</date>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation encodinganalog="description">Finding aid encoded by Ruth Steele
		  
		  <date normal="2003-09-16">September 16, 2003.</date></creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in
		  <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English.</language></langusage>
    </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
      <change>
        <date normal="2003">2003</date>
        <item>Collection and finding aid re-engineered by Amber Raney.</item>
      </change>
    </revisiondesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" type="inventory" relatedencoding="marc21">
    <did>
      <repository>
        <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Center for Pacific Northwest Studies</corpname>
        <address>
          
          <addressline>Goltz-Murray Building</addressline>
          <addressline>808 25th St</addressline>
          <addressline>Bellingham, WA 98225-9123</addressline>
          <addressline>Phone: 360 650 7534</addressline>
          <addressline>Email: cpnws@wwu.edu</addressline>
          
        </address>
      </repository>
      <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="us" repositorycode="wabecp" type="collection">XOE_CPNWS0009wfallsmill</unitid>
      <origination>
        <corpname source="lcnaf" role="creator" encodinganalog="610">Whatcom
			 Falls Mill Company; </corpname>
        <persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf" role="creator" rules="aacr2">Loggie, George W.</persname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a" type="collection">Whatcom Falls Mill
		  Company Records, George W. Loggie Papers </unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" normal="1886/1978">1886-1978</unitdate>
      <unitdate type="bulk" normal="1895/1940">1895-1940</unitdate>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">9 linear ft.</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">The collection contains administrative,
		  financial and operational records, maps and drawings and photographs
		  documenting the business interests of the Whatcom Falls Mill company and also
		  information relating to other regional lumber mills. Personal papers and
		  photographs further document the business and other interests of the George W.
		  Loggie family.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>Collection materials are in
		<language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English.</language></langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="5451_">
      <p>Whatcom Falls Mill Company was located on Bellingham Bay, in the
		  northwestern corner of Washington State. The mill, located on Whatcom Creek in
		  Bellingham, was originally the Washington Colony Mill, positioned on a site
		  established by Henry Roeder and J.E. Peabody in 1853. In 1895, George W.
		  Loggie, along with his brother James A. Loggie, rented the Washington Colony
		  Mill, creating the Whatcom Falls Mill Company.</p>
      <p>George W. Loggie and Samuel J. Knight filed papers for incorporation
		  of Whatcom Falls Mill Company 28 October 1895. The mill specialized in Western
		  Red Cedar and manufactured a variety of products including bevel siding, sash
		  and doors, and lumber. A new plant, built in 1903 at the bottom of “G” Street,
		  eventually produced only red cedar lumber and shingles. The company shipped its
		  product all over the world by rail and water. </p>
      <p>Loggie formed a partnership with Pat McCoy of Seattle, who had large
		  timber holdings in the Kulshan district. The McCoy-Loggie Timber Company,
		  formed in 1910, had McCoy as its President with Loggie as Secretary and
		  Treasurer. The McCoy-Loggie Timber Company supplied the Whatcom Falls Mill with
		  lumber until the Timber Company dissolved in 1926.</p>
      <p>The management of the mill was largely a family affair. G.W. Loggie
		  was President until his death in 1922. Upon his death, Loggie’s brother, James,
		  assumed the roll until 1933. D.H. Lowery, son-in-law of George, became
		  President in 1933, serving until the company filed dissolution papers on June
		  22, 1940. </p>
      <p>George W. Loggie was born 22 June 1851 near Loggieville, New
		  Brunswick, Canada. In 1879, he came out west and began an extensive career in
		  the logging business, working at mills along the Puget Sound as well as in
		  Oregon. Oregon mills were located in cities such as Portland and Coos Bay,
		  where he spent time as general manager for the large Southern Oregon Company.
		  Washington mills include the Puget Sound Mill Company at Utsaladdy and Port
		  Gamble. Loggie eventually became superintendent of the Utsaladdy plant. He also
		  worked in Seattle, and established mills in Snohomish and Port Angeles in 1893.
		  </p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
      <p>The Whatcom Falls Mill Company Records and George W. Loggie Papers
		  span the years 1886 to 1978, with the bulk of the material dated 1895-1940. The
		  collection primarily documents the story of Whatcom Falls Mill Company. The
		  remaining papers focus on Loggie's personal life. Little is known as to how the
		  collection arrived at the Center for Pacific Northwest Studies; however, it is
		  clearly a compilation of records from many facets of Loggie’s life. Few of the
		  personal papers are truly family oriented, and focus instead, on Loggie’s other
		  business interests prior to the creation of Whatcom Falls Mill Company.</p>
      <p>The first series of papers documents the business activities of
		  Whatcom Falls Mill Company from its incorporation in 1895 to its dissolution in
		  1940. Included are administrative and financial records, correspondence,
		  operations information, maps and drawings, and various advertising materials,
		  including a business envelope with a picture of the original mill, and business
		  cards printed on cedar. Included in this series are several records relating to
		  the McCoy-Loggie Timber Company. While not a subsidiary company, the Timber
		  Company supplied lumber to the mill, and records from both companies appear to
		  have been kept together. Enriching The Whatcom Falls Mill Company Records are
		  photographs of Whatcom Falls Mill, including a photo of a drawing of the
		  original mill, two Brubaker aerial surveys, and one Sandison aerial survey.
		  </p>
      <p>Separate from both the Whatcom Falls Mill Company Records and the
		  George W. Loggie Papers is information included on other regional lumber mills.
		  This information, collected after Loggie's death in 1922, bears no immediate
		  connections to Whatcom Falls Mill. It was possibly collected in order to assess
		  the competition of other regional mills. Included in this series is information
		  on the Bloedel-Donovan Lumber Mill, as well as Wood &amp; English Limited. </p>
      <p>The remainder of the collection focuses on personal materials of the
		  Loggie family, and in particular, the business activities of George W. Loggie
		  prior to his work with Whatcom Falls Mill Company. Included is early
		  correspondence of George W. Loggie, primarily with regard to his previous mill
		  experience in Oregon; papers, a ledger, and booklets that document G.W.
		  Loggie’s interest in Trotting Horses; copies of the certificate of Registry of
		  the Schooner Vigilant; a Family Expense Ledger (dated after G.W. Loggie’s
		  death); and family photos. Also included are photographs of other mills, as
		  well as those depicting various aspects of logging and milling operations. Some
		  of these photos date to the 1880s and 1890s. Identified mills include
		  Bloedel-Donovan, as well as other mills on Bellingham Bay, the Olympic
		  Peninsula, and mills near the Cascade Mountains. The Family Expense Ledger,
		  page 151, contains genealogical material of interest regarding the Lowery
		  family. </p>
      <p>The following items are of special note: Materials regarding the
		  Lumber and Sawmill Workers Union and Whatcom Falls Mill Company, including
		  correspondence and newspaper clippings dealing with the workers' strike in
		  1937; a 1914 Kroll Atlas section map showing McCoy land as well as other lumber
		  and mill company property; an 1887 Map Guide to the City of Seattle, Washington
		  Territory surveyed by Whitworth and Thomson which was probably a real estate
		  map; and a December 10, 1895 copy of the newspaper Daily Reveille. </p>
      <p>The artifacts in this collection include a wallet owned by George W.
		  Loggie, and Volume VI of the 14-volume set of Hough’s American Woods is also
		  part of this collection. Romeyn Beck Hough wrote and published the set between
		  1888 and 1928. Each volume consists of twenty-five species of trees specific to
		  a particular part of the United States. Volume VI represents trees of the
		  Pacific Slope. Actual wood samples of each tree are included; cut in thin
		  sections to show the various planes of the wood (transverse, radial, and
		  tangential sections).</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
      <p>The records from the Whatcom Falls Mill Company Records and George W.
		  Loggie Papers are organized in accordance with the following series and
		  sub-series arrangement:</p>
      <list>
        <item> Series I: Whatcom Falls Mill Co. Records, 1895-1941 
			 <list><item>Sub-series 1: Administrative Records, 1895-1941</item><item>Sub-series 2: Financial Records, 1895-1939</item><item>Sub-series 3: Operations, 1889-1937</item><item>Sub-series 4: Maps and Drawings, 1914-1934</item><item>Sub-series 5: Photographs, Undated; circa 1890-1934</item></list></item>
        <item>Series II: Regional Mill Information, 1919-1939</item>
        <item>Series III: G.W. Loggie Papers, 1880s-1978 
			 <list><item>Sub-series 1: Personal Papers, 1884-1978</item><item>Sub-series 2: Photographs, circa 1880-1950s</item></list></item>
        <item>Series IV: Artifacts, 1885/undated</item>
      </list>
    </arrangement>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <p>The collection is open to the public. </p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <p>Whatcom Falls Mill Company Records and George W. Loggie Papers, Center
		  for Pacific Northwest Studies, Western Libraries Archives &amp; Special Collections, Western Washington University, Bellingham WA 98225-9123.</p>
    </prefercite> 	
    <custodhist encodinganalog="561">
      <p>The exact provenance of these records is unknown.</p>
    </custodhist>
    <processinfo encodinganalog="583">
      <p>Tamma Farra originally processed the collection for the Center for
		  Pacific Northwest Studies in March 1999. In August 2003, Amber Raney
		  re-engineered the collection and finding aid. </p>
    </processinfo>
    <processinfo><head>About Harmful Language and Content</head><p>To learn more about problematic content in our collections, collection description and teaching tools (including how to provide feedback or request dialogue on this topic), see the following <extref href="https://library.wwu.edu/statement-on-harmful-language-content">Statement About Potentially Harmful Language and Content</extref></p></processinfo> 
    <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544 1">
      <p>The Loggie Photograph Collection is housed at the Photo Archives at
		  the Whatcom Museum of History &amp; Art, Bellingham, WA.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <controlaccess>
      <p>This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online
		  catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or
		  places should search the catalog using these headings.</p>
      <controlaccess>
        <corpname role="creator" source="local" encodinganalog="610">Whatcom
			 Falls Mill Company</corpname>
        <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf" rules="aacr2r" role="creator">Loggie, George W.</persname>
        <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf" rules="aacr2r" role="creator">Knight, Samuel J.</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject source="lcsh" rules="scm" encodinganalog="650">Lumber
			 trade--Washington (State) -- Bellingham.</subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject altrender="nodisplay" source="archiveswest">Logging</subject>
        <subject altrender="nodisplay" source="archiveswest">Business, Industry and
			 Labor</subject>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <p>The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in
		  the collection.</p>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series I</unitid>
          <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a"> Whatcom Falls Mill Company Records
				</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1895/1941">1895-1941</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">
              <emph render="bold">Sub-series
				  1</emph>
            </unitid>
            <unittitle>
              <emph render="bold"> Administrative
				  Records</emph>
            </unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1895/1941">
              <emph render="bold">1895-1941</emph>
            </unitdate>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1/1</container>
              <unittitle> Advertising </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1896-1932</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1/2</container>
              <unittitle> Articles of Incorporation &amp; By-Laws </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1895 (By-Laws amended in 1937)
					 </unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1/3 </container>
              <unittitle>Company History</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1937</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="otherlevel" otherlevel="sub-subseries">
            <did>
              <unittitle>
                <emph render="bold">Correspondence</emph>
              </unittitle>
            </did>
            <c04 level="file">
              <did>
                <container type="box-folder">1/4</container>
                <unittitle>Incoming</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1895-1941</unitdate>
              </did>
            </c04>
            <c04 level="file">
              <did>
                <container type="box-folder">1/5</container>
                <unittitle>Outgoing</unittitle>
                <unitdate type="inclusive">1933-1939 </unitdate>
              </did>
            </c04>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1/6</container>
              <unittitle>Daily Reports </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">October 1, 1938 – March 27,
					 1939</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1/7</container>
              <unittitle>Materials re. Dissolution of Company</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1940-1941</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1/8</container>
              <unittitle>Materials re. Relations between Whatcom Falls Mill and
					 Lumber &amp; Sawmill Workers Union </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1936-1938</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1/9</container>
              <unittitle>Minutes of special and annual meetings </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1910-1939</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="item">
            <did>
              <container type="Volume">1</container>
              <unittitle>Ledger of minutes of special and annual
					 meetings</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1939-1940</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">1/10</container>
              <unittitle>Minutes of special and annual meetings from
					 organization to dissolution of the McCoy-Loggie Timber Co.</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">November 30, 1910 – April 20,
					 1926</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">
              <emph render="bold">Sub-series
				  2</emph>
            </unitid>
            <unittitle>
              <emph render="bold"> Financial
				  Records</emph>
            </unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1895/1939">
              <emph render="bold">1895-1939</emph>
            </unitdate>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/1</container>
              <unittitle>Financial Reports</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1902-1926</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/2</container>
              <unittitle>Financial Reports</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1929-1931</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/3</container>
              <unittitle>Financial Reports</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1932-1939 </unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/4</container>
              <unittitle>Payroll information</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1918-1939</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/5</container>
              <unittitle>Report of Audit – Whatcom Falls Mill and McCoy-Loggie
					 Timber Co. </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive"> 1920 December 31</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/6</container>
              <unittitle>Reports of Audits – Whatcom Falls Mill </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1931-1937</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/7</container>
              <unittitle>Stock Certificates: Whatcom Falls Mill, McCoy-Loggie
					 Timber Co., Whatcom County Agriculture, and Whatcom County Fair Association
					 </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1895-1924</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">Sub-series 3</unitid>
            <unittitle>
              <emph render="bold"> Operations</emph>
            </unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1889/1937">
              <emph render="bold">1889-1937</emph>
            </unitdate>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/8</container>
              <unittitle> Manufacturing Statement </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1912</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/8</container>
              <unittitle>Operations Reference cards</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1928-1937 </unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/9</container>
              <unittitle>Reference Materials: Schedule of Prices, Standard
					 Grading and Dressing Rules for West Coast Lumber, Valuations of Lumber
					 Manufacturing Properties</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1889-1934</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">2/10</container>
              <unittitle>West Coast Price List of Lumber </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1921</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">
              <emph render="bold">Sub-series
				  4</emph>
            </unitid>
            <unittitle>
              <emph render="bold"> Maps and
				  Drawings</emph>
            </unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1919/1934">
              <emph render="bold">1914-1934</emph>
            </unitdate>
          </did>
          <c03 level="item">
            <did>
              <container type="OversizeFolder">1</container>
              <unittitle>Blueprint of Proposed New Fire Mains for Whatcom Falls
					 Mill </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1934</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3/1</container>
              <unittitle>Map: Kroll’s Atlas of Whatcom Co., T.38 N R.
					 5E</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1914</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3/2</container>
              <unittitle>Survey of Proposed Layout of Mains and Hydrants
					 </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1928</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">
              <emph render="bold">Sub-series
				  5</emph>
            </unitid>
            <unittitle>
              <emph render="bold"> Photographs</emph>
            </unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" certainty="approximate" normal="1890/1934">
              <emph render="bold">circa 1890-1934</emph>
            </unitdate>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3/3</container>
              <unittitle> Brubaker Aerial Survey of Whatcom Falls Mill
					 </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive"> undated </unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="item">
            <did>
              <container type="OversizeFolder">2</container>
              <unittitle>McCoy-Loggie Timber Company train engine
					 (framed)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive"> undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3/4</container>
              <unittitle>Sandison Aerial Survey of Whatcom Falls
					 Mill</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">3/5</container>
              <unittitle>Whatcom Falls Mill Photographs</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1890s-1934</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series II</unitid>
          <unittitle> Regional Mill Information</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1919/1939">1919-1939</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="box-folder">4/1</container>
            <unittitle>Bloedel-Donovan Lumber Mill</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1919-1933</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="file">
          <did>
            <container type="box-folder">4/2</container>
            <unittitle>Wood and English Limited, Vancouver, B.C.</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series III</unitid>
          <unittitle> G.W. Loggie Papers</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1880/1978" certainty="approximate">1880s-1978</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">
              <emph render="bold">Sub-series
				  1</emph>
            </unitid>
            <unittitle>
              <emph render="bold"> Personal Papers</emph>
            </unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1884/1978">
              <emph render="bold">1884-1978</emph>
            </unitdate>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4/3</container>
              <unittitle> Copies of Certificate of Registry for Schooner
					 <emph render="italic">Vigilant</emph></unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1920</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="item">
            <did>
              <container type="Volume">2</container>
              <unittitle>Family Expense Ledger </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1938-1978</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="item">
            <did>
              <container type="OversizeFolder">3</container>
              <unittitle>Guide Map of the City of Seattle, Washington
					 Territory, Whitworth and Thompson – Surveyors</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1887</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4/4</container>
              <unittitle> Ledger of Horses purchased by G.W. Loggie
					 </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1884-1891</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4/5</container>
              <unittitle>Materials re. Interest and investments in Trotting
					 Horses </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1890-1895</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4/6</container>
              <unittitle>Materials re. Employment with Southern Oregon Co.,
					 Empire Mill </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1886-1890</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4/7</container>
              <unittitle>Newspaper, <emph render="italic">Daily
					 Reveille</emph></unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">December 10, 1895</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4/8</container>
              <unittitle>Obituary of G.W. Loggie </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">March 25, 1922</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4/9</container>
              <unittitle>Personal Correspondence (Incoming) </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1897-1907</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="subseries">
          <did>
            <unitid encodinganalog="099">
              <emph render="bold">Sub-series
				  2</emph>
            </unitid>
            <unittitle>
              <emph render="bold"> Photographs</emph>
            </unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1880/1959" certainty="approximate">
              <emph render="bold">circa 1880-1950s</emph>
            </unitdate>
          </did>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4/10</container>
              <unittitle>Loggie Family Photos, USS Constitution, Mt. Baker
					 </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1900-1934</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4/11</container>
              <unittitle>Logging operations in Washington State (taken from a
					 scrapbook)</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1910-1920s</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4/12</container>
              <unittitle>Mills outside of Washington State</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1880s-1890s </unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">4/13</container>
              <unittitle>Washington State Mills </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1880s-1950s</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5/1</container>
              <unittitle>Coos Bay, Oregon </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1890s</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5/2</container>
              <unittitle>Coos Bay, Oregon, Old Mill </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1890s</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5/3</container>
              <unittitle>Goodyear Logging Co., Clallam Bay,
					 Washington</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">circa 1890s-1900s</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5/4</container>
              <unittitle>Lumber Mill, Coos Bay, Oregon – Coos Bay Photo and
					 Crayon Co. </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">undated</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5/5</container>
              <unittitle>Old Mill </unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1890s</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
          <c03 level="file">
            <did>
              <container type="box-folder">5/6</container>
              <unittitle>USS Constitution in Bellingham Bay</unittitle>
              <unitdate type="inclusive">1933</unitdate>
            </did>
          </c03>
        </c02>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid encodinganalog="099">Series IV</unitid>
          <unittitle>Artifacts</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1885">1885</unitdate>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" certainty="approximate" normal="1886/1978">undated</unitdate>
        </did>
        <c02 level="item">
          <did>
            <container type="box-folder">5/7</container>
            <unittitle>Hough’s American Woods Volume VI </unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">1885</unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
        <c02 level="item">
          <did>
            <container type="box-folder">5/8</container>
            <unittitle>Wallet belonging to G.W. Loggie</unittitle>
            <unitdate type="inclusive">undated </unitdate>
          </did>
        </c02>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>

