<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAA1625</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>John P. Lunstrum papers, <date normal="1959/1965" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1959-1965</date> <num>C273</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to the records at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Encoded by Ariel Weinberg and Rachael Stoeltje</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2005</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-1127</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/university-archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/university-archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-03-10 21:13:55 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>June 8, 2005</date><item>Encoded finding aid begun.</item></change><change><date>June 15, 2005</date><item>Encoded finding aid completed.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>John P. Lunstrum papers</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname authfilenumber="n78033741" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Lunstrum, John P.</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C273</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.8 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1959/1965" type="inclusive">1959-1965</unitdate>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960/1964" type="bulk">1960-1964</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_360f8839540c9b5927fe85e8cd42aa5e">An Indiana University Professor of Education, Lunstrum's primary area of interest was social studies and he was a strong proponent of incorporating non-western history into the social studies curriculums of both primary and secondary schools. Collection consists of correspondence, newspaper clippings, proposals, and syllabi. The Councils and committees series is comprised of records that reflect Lunstrum's membership and leadership in state, national, and university groups, including the National Council for the Social Studies Audio-Visual Committee.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_77fa4075714f86af8eb123d31ba17778">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_56ee018e87a68c4d2a7ed810123b28a6">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p> Advance notice is required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_13b7e9c311e6f6f26c5e7a649d72c1d5">
    <head>Biographical Note</head>
<p>John Paul Lunstrum was born on 4 June 1922 to Ruth Williams and Melvin A. Lunstrum in Terre Haute, Indiana. He served in the U.S. Army during World War II from 1943-1946. He married Joann Sisson and they had two children, Kathryn and Thomas John. </p><p> Lunstrum received his B.S. in 1948 from Indiana State University with majors in speech and social science and his M.S. in 1953 from Indiana State University with a major in social science. He received his Ed.D. from Indiana University, Bloomington, in 1960 with a major in secondary education and minors in guidance and history. </p><p> Lunstrum began his teaching career as a history teacher at Wiley High School in Terre Haute, Indiana. He held this position for ten years. During his time at Indiana University, Bloomington, from 1959-1965, he served as the Coordinator for School Social Studies in the College of Arts and Sciences and as an Associate Professor of Education. From 1965-1966, under Indiana University contract, he served as Education Advisor to the Peace Corps in Sierra Leone, West Africa. </p><p> Dr. Lunstrum was very active in the education community and held offices in various professional organizations. He served as the chairman of the I.C.S.S. (Indiana Council for the Social Studies) Academic Freedom Committee and as the chairman of the N.C.S.S. (National Council for the Social Studies) Audio Visual Committee. He was also one of the founders of the Asian Institute at Indiana University, which sponsored summer programs in Asian and Russian Studies for primary and secondary teachers. He was a strong proponent of incorporating non-western history into the social studies curriculums of both primary and secondary schools. </p><p> During his time at Indiana University Lunstrum contributed research to such publications as <title render="italic">Social Education</title>, <title render="italic">Phi Delta Kappan</title>, <title render="italic">Audio Visual Instruction</title>, and <title render="italic">Teaching About Communism: Bulletin of the Indiana State Department of Public Instruction</title>.
 
 Lunstrum died on March 21, 2018.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_3a422df4dbc2e8164774d54e69ad1290">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Papers organized into six series: Correspondence; Councils and committees; Proposals; Programs; and Syllabi; Series are arranged alphabetically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_2534468d30357e7cafa32278d7a9a29e">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The John Lunstrum papers span the time period of 1959-1965 during which Dr. Lunstrum was both the coordinator for Social Studies in the College of Arts and Sciences and an Associate Professor of Education at Indiana University Bloomington. The collection is organized into six series: Correspondence, Clippings, Councils and committees, Proposals, Programs, and Syllabi. Three sub-series exist within the series of Councils and committees: State, National, and Indiana University. </p><p> The majority of Lunstrum's correspondence is arranged alphabetically by subject. However, four general correspondence files exist within the series and are alphabetized by either author or recipient. The arrangement in this series reflects the original organization of Dr. Lunstrum's correspondence. This series consists of correspondence between Dr. Lunstrum and his professional colleagues at Indiana University, with colleagues in the community and within national organizations, and with individuals he met through his professional endeavors. No distinction has been made between personal and professional correspondence; this is in accordance with Lunstrum's original filing system. </p><p> The Clippings series consists of one file and contains an editorial written by Hugh S. Ramsey in response to changes in the Indiana high school social studies curriculum. The file also contains a response to Mr. Ramsey written by graduate students of Dr. Lunstrum. </p><p> The Councils and committees series is arranged alphabetically and is comprised of records about Dr. Lunstrum's membership in and leadership of various councils and committees on a state, national, and university level. These three levels reflect the sub-series: State, National, and Indiana University. Within each sub-series, individual files exist for each council and committee and are arranged alphabetically. </p><p> The State sub-series consist of files for each organization Dr. Lunstrum was involved with in Bloomington, Indiana, and throughout the state. Files exist for the Bloomington Citizenship Council and the I.C.S.S. (Indiana Council for the Social Studies) newsletter. Dr. Lunstrum was a proponent for change in the social studies curriculum, and this is reflected by his activity in both of these organizations. These files are arranged alphabetically. </p><p> The National sub-series consist of files about the National Council for the Social Studies. Lunstrum was the chairman of the NCSS audio-visual committee from 1961-1962. The purpose of this committee was to study the use of educational and instructional television in the social studies curriculum. These files are arranged alphabetically. </p><p> The Indiana University sub-series consist of files regarding campus organizations and committees in which Lunstrum was involved. The university became involved with the Asia Society when Lunstrum spearheaded the summer institutes on Asia and the Soviet Union with support from the organization. These institutes focused on the importance of non-western cultures, specifically Asia and Russia. These files are arranged alphabetically. </p><p> The Proposals series consists of proposals made at the university level and are arranged alphabetically. Included are the Langan-Gehrels proposal so named for the professors who penned it, it required incoming students to pass certain standards in language and mathematics upon entering the College of Arts and Sciences. This proposal failed to pass. The Anthropology Institute proposal details the development of a summer institute for Junior and Senior high school teachers in the subject areas of biology and social studies in anthropology. Lunstrum was actively involved in facilitating and coordinating both of these proposals. </p><p> The Programs series consists of files regarding both university and non-university programs and are arranged alphabetically. Files exist for High School Day and the All-Campus Party. These were university programs that Dr. Lunstrum advised. Files exist for non-university programs such as the John Hay Fellows Program. Dr. Lunstrum was heavily influenced by this program in designing the Asia Summer Institute at Indiana University. </p><p> The series Syllabi consists of one file that contains a syllabus for a course on the History of the Federation of Malaya. The uses of this syllabus are unknown.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_b36aacba362484ba6557db5e35fc33f8">
    <head>Separated Material</head>
<p>Duplicates have been removed. </p><p> Newspaper clippings have been photocopied for preservation purposes and the clippings discarded.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_7107eab5fc2643ccbd9355fe375a91ab">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession 9184</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_4b6b767fd88c0ba6865817089c5e6d47">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>The donor(s) of this collection have not transferred their copyrights for the materials to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_203b62f2a8392562bd3e55a3f3023f58">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], John P. Lunstrum papers, Collection C273, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_984f288f823e00ee97e89a9d89cb3f69">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Serena Olson.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2005" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2005</date>.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Social Sciences --Study and teaching (Primary) --United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Social Sciences --Study and teaching (Secondary) --United States.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Teacher educators --Indiana --Bloomington --Archives.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Teacher educators --Indiana --Bloomington --Correspondence.</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="no2005052938" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">National Council for the Social Studies. Audio-Visual Committee -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</corpname>
    <persname authfilenumber="n78033741" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Lunstrum, John P. -- Archives</persname>
    <persname authfilenumber="n78033741" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Lunstrum, John P. -- Correspondence</persname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_1724afac1e97528ae7fe8cd905bb3d9f" level="series"><did><unittitle>Clippings</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_0859132543c9de1511893a29a4127b96" level="file"><did><unittitle>Ramsey, Hugh S.—Newspaper Clippings</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1963-11/1963-11">November 1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_7c23aacad8b13ae5891180fffb01f8d0" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_c9c468785121a7e3dd1df809422b78be" level="series"><did><unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960/1964" type="inclusive">1960-1964</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_7d4730175b3e39bd95dbcdcf791a149b" level="file"><did><unittitle>A-E, General Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961/1964" type="inclusive">1961-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_7a59aeceff26adfcb7fd54f3e375a6c5" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5b43099b3ff21d151713dce7ceb9cdaa" level="file"><did><unittitle>Abbot, Mr. William L., United Rubber Workers</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1964-05/1964-06" type="inclusive">May 1964-Jun 1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_98a7fee2cdfd1b3021c694f7d78dd623" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_35100e37b3e7ac87a1d82eae940923be" level="file"><did><unittitle>Asia Society</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961-11/1963-05" type="inclusive">Nov. 1961-May 1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_9254218f68d6054742ec38b9bd76e7c1" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_7e1d09b0112768ee7c7495b0ccaf025a"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Correspondents include: Dr. Seymour Fersh.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_adaf6bd6c611d848ce8663cdc2fa364f" level="file"><did><unittitle>Asian Institute</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_de5b3c8e65ff6d996ea8048a7a5305ae" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6a11ffe8f5e1ab1cacea0d586c010333"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Correspondents include: teachers throughout the state of Indiana with inquiries about scholarships.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_b04ae0594d11ea0ab08b02dea74ecbf9" level="file"><did><unittitle>Blustain, Prof. Jonah; NYU</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1964-05/1964-07" type="inclusive">May 1964-Jul. 1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_7daf3d7b2584f646d5912e80d1a74d81" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_24b7623dadcde20f0fc1ccebd16ddd13" level="file"><did><unittitle>Chandler Press</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1962-02/1964-08" type="inclusive">Feb. 1962-Aug. 1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_f2da24c6f89154b79a6f2af213471ddf" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_6a76d8ee0be804a006080f576ce60122"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Correspondents include: Howard Chandler and Jon Sharp.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_5f94397ee921fd4b18abb85d49345465" level="file"><did><unittitle>Compton, Ruby H.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961/1962" type="inclusive">1961-1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_95a0c3d2aa7659a69ad684fe200ae8f7" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_186cc243d2d24723420253c371c1a647" level="file"><did><unittitle>Doctoral Degree (Mr. Lunstrum)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960-09/1960-09">September 1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_9b81a963372683cff8386566f55b06cf" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_69727828fb3c092b98e7854ff79d60a7"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Correspondents include: Indiana State University and Indiana University.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3fd5992dd0e9a377c56267b090b8cdd6" level="file"><did><unittitle>F-J, General Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1962/1964" type="inclusive">1962-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_30c1af9584dba7005d5cadd68cd4a830" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_6a74b6419ea5a0fa4dc78bace923889e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Foreman, John</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961-03/1961-05" type="inclusive">Mar. 1961-May 1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_1053e025dd77ad809586d1bb2eb1f060" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_0ce654a919224f982ff9fc6e56ce2291" level="file"><did><unittitle>L-P, General Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961/1964" type="inclusive">1961-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_a4f45c17484f4e6063488d00b6a7849c" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2838b3dc48b497c5726e59469799bacd" level="file"><did><unittitle>Letters, Workshop at Purdue Camp Limberlost</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1963-07/1964-03" type="inclusive">Jul. 1963-Mar.1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_528f58b672e84ef6563ad1defe35dc52" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_846d37b570ebdb4137f9e081635e7d0c"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Correspondents include: Elementary and Secondary educators participating in the Social Studies Revision Committee Workshop at Purdue Camp Limberlost.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_6424ab7c28e2bd79ea479d87b56e0975" level="file"><did><unittitle>Messner, William C.</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1962/1962">1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_44369956c43828c40f31798252b6fff5" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_25483b7bf878bf2fd64744ed60696112" level="file"><did><unittitle>N.E.A. Convention, Detroit 1963, Inquiries and Comments on Speech</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1963-06/1963-07" type="inclusive">Jun. 1963-Jul. 1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_ecf1d76f4622459731bffe7fd75a0cd1" label="box" type="box">1</container></did><scopecontent id="aspace_cd200fdc38e24f7b91c43ef6c3dac6ae"><head>Scope and Contents</head><p>Correspondents include: Educators who Lunstrum met at the National Education Association Convention who voiced interest in teaching about Communism.</p></scopecontent></c02><c02 id="aspace_3ec2159442a9092ab3eb34414bb8b8c5" level="file"><did><unittitle>R-W, General Correspondence</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961/1964" type="inclusive">1961-1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_c1d5db45f19a6e1a4bf05279de55d21a" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_5fdfc1def6579526db277851bbc35b9f" level="series"><did><unittitle>Councils and committees</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960/1964" type="inclusive">1960-1964</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_2ed7d02b434d2a270e1bcece39ae2d0c" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>National</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961/1962" type="inclusive">1961-1962</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_bbceb4ba0b72e4bdde0a08d86c9be2ac" level="file"><did><unittitle>Audio-Visual Materials Committee (NCSS)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961-10/1962-05" type="inclusive">Oct. 1961-May 1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_9b270a80f0effa69b18399f62925612b" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_5ee0145a0c34462c39ed687c9b8bdaba" level="file"><did><unittitle>Sub-Committees—NCSS Audio-Visual</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961-04/1961-10" type="inclusive">Apr. 1961-Oct. 1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_1fcd03efa04f62efbf9e81d74b282348" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_02c0c1f638fdd809750d2d811b88c3c6" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>Indiana University</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960/1964" type="inclusive">1960-1964</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_9866b3d03ba453d3adac0ba419019510" level="file"><did><unittitle>ACLS-Lunstrum-Statement of Account</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960-06/1962-04" type="inclusive">Jun. 1960-Apr. 1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_61f33938cefadfa3bbfdbbe1ef15084c" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_a4dcf2e474e28cce0ca39fdaf7e003a3" level="file"><did><unittitle>Asia Society—Lunstrum Asia Society</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961-01/1964-03" type="inclusive">Jan. 1961-Mar. 1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_557b1031da249563f1c16c124ff1ebaf" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_2073f1c78193a7edf6f3700aaa2d7967" level="file"><did><unittitle>Doctoral Committees</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961-03/1962-04" type="inclusive">Mar. 1961-Apr. 1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_a5bde4a85dd4b444e90387d4d2734457" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_e9b7708d19624c2e65e7ad2b60c82f3e" level="file"><did><unittitle>Receipts: Travel</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1962-11/1963-02" type="inclusive">Nov. 1962-Feb. 1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_50b9a0b2de878eaead36c03970c14ccd" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03></c02><c02 id="aspace_964a0e3f7e99301e99354702adf4beb3" level="subseries"><did><unittitle>State</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960/1964" type="inclusive">1960-1964</unitdate></did><c03 id="aspace_7358b6626fdd9697a9115f82783d058c" level="file"><did><unittitle>Bloomington Citizenship Council</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961-02/1964-05" type="inclusive">Feb. 1961-May 1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_0161b98c563ff95bba2733ec955786a8" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_b226ff1e7f69147f66e4fb28f7c183ad" level="file"><did><unittitle>Committee: High-School-College Relations</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960-10/1961-05" type="inclusive">Oct. 1960-May 1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_8a6dbba83f39307f6fe2017d56529d78" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_d6c63e2fcf3167e62113f339d9786141" level="file"><did><unittitle>ICSS Newsletter</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960-10/1964-08" type="inclusive">Oct. 1960-Aug. 1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_257ee1fac37dd3f1cdd84a2e71c8e98f" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_9f7971501234f20026175730e4bc10f8" level="file"><did><unittitle>Perry Township (Lunstrum), Marion County</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960-09/1960-11" type="inclusive">Sep. 1960-Nov. 1960</unitdate><container id="aspace_33ba431117c3317e3a015dae83c50d10" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_44781a59569fe6cf8d3cf069375c9bac" level="file"><did><unittitle>St. Joseph County Council for the Social Studies, South Bend</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1962-12-10/1962-12-10">Dec. 10, 1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_ea0850b9f0594a0caa3fe2e182e7acab" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_d7746bd81976bf9dccd383d33c1cff44" level="series"><did><unittitle>Proposals</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1962/1963" type="inclusive">1962-1963</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_aa84e24b204ab6db66400800eeab95a5" level="file"><did><unittitle>Anthropology Institute Proposal</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1963/1963">1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_77461f7f02b1a83b2737f4246ee98b57" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_a4c318ae48e1895dd589719d565a75ee" level="file"><did><unittitle>Langan-Gehrels Proposal</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1962-04/1962-12" type="inclusive">Apr. 1962-Dec. 1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_6b85121d75aa2f91033a1eff82992747" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_82a6da60cf51453f3ad0679a588a9e45" level="series"><did><unittitle>Programs</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1959/1964" type="inclusive">1959-1964</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_24af1c1cb9f12a5fe8822f049e6ac763" level="file"><did><unittitle>All-Campus Party</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1963-07/1963-09" type="inclusive">Jul. 1963-Sep. 1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_d77d0902fdc93adf191b603f33cfecd3" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_f51c5c38514895b58845d3a58cd0f8d1" level="file"><did><unittitle>High School Day</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1959-11/1963-11" type="inclusive">Nov. 1959-Nov. 1963</unitdate><container id="aspace_df0584f828baf65ec60b219fa75435c8" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_ec5eeb257655c633a91b9b4f14afea60" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Hay Fellows Program</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961-05/1964-11" type="inclusive">May 1961-Nov. 1964</unitdate><container id="aspace_9168b1e78a0d29313159439241c49830" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_2996be532e4bac2803008253cd552859" level="file"><did><unittitle>John Seward Johnson Charitable Trust</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1960-08/1962-11" type="inclusive">Aug. 1960-Nov. 1962</unitdate><container id="aspace_2d69a4cf96d89a2b98ad43861163a1ea" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_5f64767f5d49917f3a250de49930d904" level="file"><did><unittitle>Workshop-Non-Western Areas for Secondary Schools</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1961-04/1962-05" type="inclusive">Apr. 1961-May 1961</unitdate><container id="aspace_d0f1b3eb54e4849e94fe327391eb958a" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_afa7dfdd5100a539eb00e1ac7442545c" level="series"><did><unittitle>Syllabi</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1959/1965" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_08cab648326a3d1f070829a135318f14" level="file"><did><unittitle>History Syllabus of the Federation of Malaya</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1959/1965" type="inclusive">undated</unitdate><container id="aspace_aad742a48f820ca3d955216b04a286f8" label="box" type="box">2</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
