<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAC3199</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Indiana Club records, <date normal="1906/1978">1906-1978</date> <num>C464</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to the Records at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Finding aid prepared by Whitney Olthoff</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2012</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-1127</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/university-archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/university-archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2012">© 2012</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-03-10 21:26:42 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>June 27, 2012</date><item>Date finding aid started.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Indiana Club records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="no2012060621" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Indiana Club (Indiana University)</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C464</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.4 cubic feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1906/1978" type="inclusive">1906-1978</unitdate>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1915/1928" type="bulk">1915-1928</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_ebcf0d1432035da597d1dfc77566b648">The Indiana Club was established at Indiana University on December 9, 1904. The goal of the club was to advance the interests of the student body in the social, literary, political, and athletic realms. This collection consists of minute books, registers, a book on the history of the organization through 1915, records from the Alumni Association of the Indiana Club, and other documents.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_be80911e59fc789a6d161d2ea2315be0">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_6c1c7a275ecd80ca83874f0b2ccf7b30">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_b5269bd6e572c87ac26ba68aba0b2d2a">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>The Indiana Club was first established at Indiana University on December 9, 1904. The club was reorganized September 29th, 1905 in an effort to resolve issues that had been problems during its first year. For example, the club had trouble obtaining regular membership and lacked a system to keep track of who was a member and who was not. The club was created to deal with political issues among student clubs, primarily due to the fact that fraternity and sorority members (the "Greeks"), had more clout in campus clubs than did those who were unaffiliated (the "barbs"), despite the fact that the latter made up the majority of the student population. It got to a point where the "barbs" had trouble getting involved with student organizations unless they could gain political support. The Indiana Club was first called the Barb Organization, but the name was changed at its first official meeting.</p><p> The aims of the club were primarily social and literary, although politics and athletics were part of it as well. Social events were held for members and friends, and literary programs highlighting original works such as plays were regularly held. Any IU student who was not a member of a fraternity or other organization that stood "as a unit socially and politically" (1905 Arbutus) were eligible for membership. The club is last mentioned in the Arbutus in 1929, and a letter to Alumni members dated June 1, 1929, states as follows:</p><p> "As for the Club itself, there is not much to tell. The members were very hopeful last fall, but with a debt of over five hundred dollars… hanging over them, they say they do not feel encouraged to get new people into the organization. … The debt, of course, will be cared for… but the Club will not go on unless the alumni express a desire to have it do so."</p><p> On November 20, 1915, the Alumni Association of the Indiana Club was organized. Regular updates on members, including marriage and birth announcements, were given. Records in this collection suggest that the Indiana Club alumni group was still in existence in 1978, but it is not known how long it existed after that.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_032b113fa9cd707efffee56214439922">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Collection is organized into two series: Indiana Club records and Alumni Association of the Indiana Club records.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_09166588485153859352983e99c0beff">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection is organized into two series, Indiana Club records, 1906-1978 and Alumni Association of the Indiana Club records, 1915-1927. Both series are arranged alphabetically by folder heading. Items of note include letters from Cora B. Hennel, a book on the history of the Indiana Club up until 1915, and membership rosters.</p><p> Photographs and scrapbooks about the club are stored separately; consult the Archives Photographs Curator for access information.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_3660a0789fcb3b0a4c0b0d681b389378">
    <head>Separated Material</head>
<p>Two envelopes of scrapbook pages were separated and transferred to the photograph collection. Consult the Archives Photographs Curator for further information.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_f4de83c107537a0e39ca35aff7526642">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>Related photographs may be available in the <extref xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesphotos/">University Archives Photographs Database</extref></p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_281c6ce59e36b363fa8ccd65cee4b56d">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession numbers: 9142-9161, 1178</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_953af15dbe0fd807ac43f45f4c8ed88c">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>The donor(s) of this collection have not transferred their copyrights for the materials to the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_f759ea95380e7ec02dd790fd1cd4aa51">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Indiana Club records, Collection C464, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <custodhist id="aspace_b62c2c11c2c1321e0747fd24baea4e71">
    <head>Provenance</head>
<p>Some materials were donated by Clifford M. Blowers via Prof. Newell Long and Cecilia Wahl to the University Archives, Feb. 1984. The rest of the collection was transferred from Collection C413, the Cecilia Hennel Hendricks family papers. Dr. Hendricks served as vice president of the organization in 1907, and was a member of the Anniversary Publication Committee, which published a book on the history of the Indiana Club in 1915. Her sister, Cora, served as treasurer in 1905, secretary in 1906, and as the alumni secretary.</p>  </custodhist>
  <processinfo id="aspace_8bf35f162969e78f03f3326df087fd18">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Whitney S. Olthoff.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2012">2012</date></p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">College students --Indiana --Bloomington --Societies and clubs.</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="no2012060627" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Alumni Association of the Indiana Club (Indiana University) -- Archives</corpname>
    <persname authfilenumber="n85161595" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Hendricks, Cecilia Hennel, 1883-1969</persname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="no2012060621" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Indiana Club (Indiana University) -- Archives</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="no2012060621" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Indiana Club (Indiana University) -- Records and correspondence</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="no2012060621" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Indiana Club (Indiana University) -- History -- Sources</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="no2012060627" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Alumni Association of the Indiana Club (Indiana University) -- Records and correspondence</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="no2012060627" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Alumni Association of the Indiana Club (Indiana University) -- History -- Sources</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="n80126369" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Indiana University -- students -- Societies, etc. -- History -- Sources</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAC3199-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>Indiana Club records</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1906/1928" type="inclusive">1906-1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_591fb2c4938db67beb7f5757b9850249" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c02 id="aspace_VAC3199-00002" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence and Registers</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1906/1928" type="inclusive">1906-1928</unitdate><container id="aspace_f809ac6f10912620541be2880ba9eec6" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC3199-00003" level="file"><did><unittitle>Indiana Club</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1902/1915" type="inclusive">1902-1915</unitdate><container id="aspace_9e365e62bd319808555799db6f1e4fdc" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC3199-00004" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>Minutes</unittitle><container id="aspace_4848cd89c7eaff2b2421daea69623b3b" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC3199-00005" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1916/1919" type="inclusive">1916-1919</unitdate><container id="aspace_3653e9e78fa2495fc2c7812d21457009" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3199-00006" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1919/1920" type="inclusive">1919-1920</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0045e5681d60ff7294c1d5dfb9c122a" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC3199-00007" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1925/1926" type="inclusive">1925-1926</unitdate><container id="aspace_5286a6c4980505549f9055579efea908" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02></c01><c01 id="aspace_VAC3199-00008" level="series"><did><unittitle>Alumni Association of the Indiana Club records</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1915/1978" type="inclusive">1915-1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_e0f6c5cf4d25d15d6033668004864210" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did><c02 id="aspace_VAC3199-00009" level="file"><did><unittitle>Correspondence and reports</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1915/1978" type="inclusive">1915-1978</unitdate><container id="aspace_d26c437339f0a15a109705eb9011352b" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC3199-00010" level="file"><did><unittitle>Financial records</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1915/1927" type="inclusive">1915-1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_f81c0f0d6079d3c229c62dcef87941f5" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAC3199-00011" level="file"><did><unittitle>Minutes</unittitle><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1915/1927" type="inclusive">1915-1927</unitdate><container id="aspace_df9850e532dbad2e19efaf53008158d9" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
