<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="edited-full-draft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAC9612</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Indiana University's University of Dacca Institute of Business Administration Project records, <date normal="1964/1971">1964-1971</date> <num>C512</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to the Records at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Finding aid prepared by Alison Reynolds</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2013</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-1127</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/university-archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/university-archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt><notestmt><note><p><date normal="2013">© 2013</date> Trustees of Indiana University. All rights reserved.</p></note></notestmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-03-10 21:28:58 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change audience="internal"><date>May 30, 2013</date><item>Finding aid started.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>May 30, 2013</date><item>Finding aid completed.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Indiana University's University of Dacca Institute of Business Administration Project records</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <corpname authfilenumber="n78064045" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. School of Business</corpname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C512</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.2 cubic feet</extent>
      <extent altrender="carrier">1 box</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1971" type="inclusive">1964-1971</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_481cde24a7fecb49c0ed669ede44ae77">The University of Dacca Institute of Business Administration project in Dacca, East Pakistan was administered by the Indiana University School of Business from 1966-1970 through a grant from the Ford Foundation. The project was designed to establish a graduate level university program to provide training, research, and consulting services in modern management methods to students in East Pakistan. The IBA offered an MBA degree, diploma programs, and short courses in the fields of management, research studies on business problems, and consulting services for the business community. Conflict in the region forced the project to end when East Pakistan seceded from Pakistan and became the independent state of Bangladesh in 1971. The collection is organized into one series of Administrative files and is arranged chronologically.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_07a0a730472baf780aa9e7ccc2303b2b">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_f115df73dc4ffa84ccf3b04e95c62ca6">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>Collection is open for research. Advance notice required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_e4a37e67cf4b4a06f0ae6b6337ced33a">
    <head>Administrative History</head>
<p>The University of Dacca Institute of Business Administration project in Dacca, East Pakistan was administered by the Indiana University School of Business from 1966-1970 through a grant from the Ford Foundation. Danilo Orescanin, Costic Roman, and Lee Nehrt each served terms as Chief of Party. Edgar G. Williams, Associate Dean of the Business School, served as the Indiana University Campus Coordinator. Initial short-term consultants were Joseph Waldman and Maurice Mandell, with other faculty members serving one or two year appointments throughout the course of the project.</p><p> The project was designed to establish a graduate level university program to provide training, research, and consulting services in modern management methods to students in East Pakistan. It was the only institution of its kind in East Pakistan at the time. Groundwork for the Institute of Business Administration (IBA) began in 1965, and the institute officially opened on November 1, 1966. The IBA offered an MBA degree, diploma programs, and short courses in the fields of management, research studies on business problems, and consulting services for the business community. Indiana University assisted by providing consulting services in administration and in curriculum development and by providing teaching and advisory assistance.</p><p> Overall, the Institute of Business Administration was regarded as a successful program. By 1969, there were 750 student applicants for 158 positions, 8 faculty members at the IBA campus, and 9 IBA faculty members enrolled in graduate degree programs at Indiana University. The increase in faculty allowed for a move to a larger building, an increase in the number of courses offered, a higher degree of specialization within fields of study, and a greater research output. Additionally, an internship program was developed, giving students the opportunity to gain practical work experience between their first and second years in the MBA program.</p><p> Indiana University applied to the Ford Foundation for an extension of the grant for the period from 1970-1972, but conflict in the region forced the project to end when East Pakistan seceded from Pakistan and became the independent state of Bangladesh in 1971.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_54f4e97171ec1c23e3599d9fd74e075c">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The collection is organized into one series of Administrative files and is arranged chronologically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_8a7963fcd1bdfed03ca7eb0a6479b73a">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>The collection into one series of Administrative files (1964-1971), and contains general files which include preliminary research and reports discussing the needs and goals of the Institute of Business Administration in Dacca, notes about similar programs in India, correspondence about the project, budget information, and project progress reports.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_9c2171cafd989f5eb10ee7f44d912ada">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>Related photographs may be available in the University Archives Photographs Database: <extref xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesphotos/">http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesphotos/</extref> </p><p> This collection is one of four projects Indiana University administered in Pakistan between the 1950s and 1970s. For information about other similar projects, see the finding aids for C511, the University of Karachi Jinnah Postgraduate Medical Center Project records, C513, the University of the Panjab Teacher Education Program records, or C488, the University of Islamabad Project records.</p><p> Collection C488, the University of Islamabad Project records, contains a Reference series of reports, contracts, and books about international programs sponsored by other American universities that were used as reference materials for the international programs administered by Indiana University. Some of these files may have been used as reference materials for this program.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_3951a587da0e6f0984954fbb69a909a9">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession: 0499, 8129, 8132</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_13b093a8365accd99aaa8fa3d0e09f69">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Copyrights for records originating with Indiana University administrative units, departments, and other offices are held by the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_7a8a7727e21fee26214c79037c1ba851">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Indiana University's University of Dacca Institute of Business Administration Project records, Collection C512, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_5650264ba4c9d81a5038edf69d506509">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Alison Reynolds.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2013">2013</date>.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business schools --Bangladesh --Dhaka --History --Sources.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">Business --Study and teaching (Higher) --Bangladesh --Dhaka --History --Sources.</subject>
    <corpname authfilenumber="n84027270" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">University of Dacca. Institute of Business Administration -- Archives</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="n84027270" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">University of Dacca. Institute of Business Administration -- Records and correspondence</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAC9612-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>Administrative files</unittitle></did><c02 id="aspace_VAC9612-00002" level="otherlevel" otherlevel="undefined"><did><unittitle>General</unittitle></did><c03 id="aspace_VAC9612-00003" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1964/1967" type="inclusive">1964-1967</unitdate><container id="aspace_4c39ac19b4931ac78990468554325062" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC9612-00004" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1967/1968" type="inclusive">1967-1968</unitdate><container id="aspace_34669c9011002e411e2944b1b9d04ad6" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC9612-00005" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1968/1969" type="inclusive">1968-1969</unitdate><container id="aspace_98240e64353e083f4b374c112ea61f37" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC9612-00006" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1969/1970" type="inclusive">1969-1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_3895380a87d6bac167cf1e57225b236b" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC9612-00007" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1970/1970">1970</unitdate><container id="aspace_22f966de1dacb0fb88f26c91114e2776" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03><c03 id="aspace_VAC9612-00008" level="file"><did><unitdate datechar="creation" normal="1971/1971">1971</unitdate><container id="aspace_1ad0d334fcf4bd1c003cb94638331c6d" label="box" type="Box">1</container></did></c03></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
