<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd"><eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" findaidstatus="originaldraft" langencoding="iso639-2b" repositoryencoding="iso15511"><eadid countrycode="US" mainagencycode="US-InU">InU-Ar-VAA2759</eadid><filedesc><titlestmt><titleproper>Danilo Orescanin speeches, <date normal="1983/1987" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1983-1987</date> <num>C226</num></titleproper><subtitle>A Guide to his Speeches at the Indiana University Archives</subtitle><author>Encoded by Kristen R. Sanders</author></titlestmt><publicationstmt><publisher>Indiana University Archives</publisher><p id="logostmt"><extref xlink:actuate="onLoad" xlink:href="http://webapp1.dlib.indiana.edu/archivesOnline/repositoryImages/archives.jpg" xlink:show="embed" xlink:type="simple"/></p><p><date>© 2003</date></p><address><addressline>Herman B Wells Library E460</addressline><addressline>1320 East Tenth Street</addressline><addressline>Bloomington, Indiana 47405-7000</addressline><addressline>Business Number: 812-855-1127</addressline><addressline>archives@indiana.edu</addressline><addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="https://libraries.indiana.edu/university-archives" xlink:show="new" xlink:title="https://libraries.indiana.edu/university-archives" xlink:type="simple"/></addressline></address></publicationstmt></filedesc><profiledesc><creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2024-03-10 21:21:52 -0400</date>.</creation><langusage>Description is in English.</langusage></profiledesc><revisiondesc><change><date>December 22, 2003</date><item>Edited finding aid to be consistent with others.</item></change><change><date>July 17, 2003</date><item>Encoded finding aid begun.</item></change><change><date>July 17, 2003</date><item>Encoded finding aid completed.</item></change><change><date>November 3, 2003</date><item>Doc Type Declaration revised.</item></change><change><date>May 4, 2009</date><item>Updated to schema.</item></change><change audience="internal"><date>November 16, 2017</date><item>Batch update to change repository name, subject links, preferred citation, and user restrictions.</item></change></revisiondesc></eadheader><archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
    <repository>
      <corpname>Indiana University Archives</corpname>
    </repository>
    <unittitle>Danilo Orescanin speeches</unittitle>
    <origination label="Creator">
      <persname authfilenumber="no2003067033" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Orescanin, Danilo</persname>
    </origination>
    <unitid>C226</unitid>
    <physdesc altrender="whole">
      <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">.2 cubic feet</extent>
    </physdesc>
    <unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1983/1987" type="inclusive">1983-1987</unitdate>
    <abstract id="aspace_69aab88bf044b27318bf96b4d6c5b1d4">Danilo Orescanin was a long time administrator associated with Indiana University in a variety of administrative roles. This collection contains speech files from his time as Vice President for University Relations between 1983 and 1987.</abstract>
    <langmaterial id="aspace_448f4fb82ffb753ae1fcdc71901890d3">Materials are in <language langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
  </did>
  <accessrestrict id="aspace_18db638d793f2b85300a48426bb53d46">
    <head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>This collection is open for research.</p><p> Advance notice is required.</p>  </accessrestrict>
  <bioghist id="aspace_90a462ba818dbf18b97a19d74df904a1">
    <head>Biographical</head>
<p>Danilo Orescanin served Indiana University in a number of different capacities during his career, most notably as Chancellor of the Northwest campus and subsequently as Vice President for University Relations. In both positions, he spoke frequently to university and community groups, and worked to strengthen I.U.'s relationship with the community at large.</p><p> Orescanin was born 7 April 1932 in Mingo Junction, Ohio, to George and Nellie (Kukich) Orescanin; his father had come to the United States from Serbia at the age of nineteen. Orescanin earned a bachelor's degree in business administration from West Virginia University in 1953 and an M.B.A. from Indiana University in 1954. He became an industrial engineer at Colgate-Palmolive in Jeffersonville, Indiana; was drafted into the army, in which he served in 1955 and 1956; and returned to I.U. to pursue a doctorate in business in 1957. By the time he received his doctorate in 1960, he had already had a taste of administrative work, having served as administrative assistant to the Dean of the School of Business.</p><p> Orescanin became an Assistant Professor of Business at the University of South Florida in Tampa in 1960, where he also served as Assistant Coordinator of Evening and Summer Sessions. In 1963 he returned to Indiana University as Assistant Dean of the Division of University Extension. Over the next nine years, he performed a variety of administrative functions for the University and held appointments first as an assistant and then as an associate professor of business. He was acting director of the Southeast campus from April to August of 1965, following the sudden death of Dr. Byron K. Laird. In the fall of 1965, Orescanin went to Dacca, Pakistan to establish a new graduate program at the Institute of Business Administration, Dacca University, serving as Resident Advisor until 1967. He returned to I.U. and served first as Assistant Dean and later Associate Dean of Research of Advanced Studies, meanwhile serving as Acting Director of Data Systems and Services. In 1969, he was appointed Assistant to President Joseph L. Sutton and Associate Dean for Administration, and continued as Assistant to President John W. Ryan until he was invited to follow David R. Derge to Southern Illinois University following the latter's appointment as president there early in 1972.</p><p> Orescanin served as Derge's executive assistant at S.I.U. from February to July of 1972, when he became Vice President for Administration and Campus Treasurer. Between July 1973 and March 1974, he also held the position of Executive Vice President. However, in late February 1974, Orescanin called Derge's attention to procedural irregularities in the use of some $5,000 from the Southern Illinois University Foundation to buy alcohol for presidential functions. As the accounts were under his control, Orescanin resigned from his administrative duties and requested reassignment to a full-time teaching and research position in the business school, which Derge granted. Orescanin was charged with tampering with public records by a grand jury of Jackson County, Illinois, but was acquitted. </p><p> Orescanin served as Chancellor of Indiana University Northwest from the fall semester of 1975 until June of 1983, during which time he worked to improve the financial and physical state of the campus and to improve the image of the campus in the surrounding communities. He was involved in a large number of community organizations, and was awarded a National Award for outstanding contributions and service by the Association of Teacher Educators in 1979, the first time the award was ever given to a non-education faculty member. </p><p> In June 1983, Orescanin was appointed Vice President for University Relations, a position that had been vacant for nearly three years. In this capacity, he oversaw the News Bureau, and the offices of University Publications, Community Relations, and Special Events, as well as the offices of University Relations at all campuses. He expanded the staff, which had been reduced in size, and implemented programs intended to create a strong statewide image for I. U. He showed a special interest in communities that had not previously had a strong I. U. presence such as "the Batesvilles, the Lawrenceburgs, the Evansvilles, and the Terre Hautes," as one article put it (Heck, The Columbian, Nov. 1983). He also launched a "Speakers Team" project to invite faculty members with the needed expertise speak to community groups around the state that might have questions about a particular field. His public relations style tended to emphasize personal connections: he compiled a list of "Friends of Indiana" in a wide range of counties and occupations for University Relations use, and sponsored golf events to build ties between members of the administration and influential people outside I. U., such as the news media. He served in the position of Vice President until January 1, 1988, when he returned to teaching management and business policy classes in the business school. In 1992, he was given the Otteson Undergraduate Teaching Excellence Award. He retired in December 1992, and died 22 May 1999 at the age of 67 in Tampa, Florida. Orescanin and his wife, Kathleen, had a son, Danilo II, and a daughter, Lori, both of whom earned degrees from I.U.</p>  </bioghist>
  <arrangement id="aspace_ba58ea031fc1e79d49f3f73014b32660">
    <head>Arrangement</head>
<p>This collection is organized into one series, Vice Presidential Speeches. They are arranged chronologically.</p>  </arrangement>
  <scopecontent id="aspace_d5ca71cd62cb216f3a0c6cc695736f13">
    <head>Scope and Content Note</head>
<p>This collection consists of speeches given by Danilo Orescanin during his tenure as Vice President for University Relations; the material is arranged chronologically. The speeches were given to a variety of university and community organizations; roughly one-third were given to organizations such as Rotary and Kiwanis clubs, and another third at university functions or to university-affiliated groups. The collection also includes two speeches Orescanin gave at the Pro Football Hall of Fame. Most of the speeches are polished drafts, while a few are typewritten outlines.</p>  </scopecontent>
  <separatedmaterial id="aspace_0dd688110887ebcd471bb331ca963ee6">
    <head>Separated Material</head>
<p>Newsletter articles removed to clippings file, material relating to John W. Ryan removed to his clippings file.</p>  </separatedmaterial>
  <relatedmaterial id="aspace_e95f30960d7fd3c817fc6fbe52e058bb">
    <head>Related Material</head>
<p>See also <extref xlink:href="http://purl.dlib.indiana.edu/iudl/findingaids/archives/InU-Ar-VAA2758">Collection C225</extref>, Danilo Orescanin speeches. These are speech files from Orscanin's term as Chancellor of the Indiana University Northwest campus between 1976 and 1983.</p>  </relatedmaterial>
  <acqinfo id="aspace_d5882d084af5dea6ec14966937e99c42">
    <head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession 8221.</p>  </acqinfo>
  <userestrict id="aspace_46bc5854b6d83695da453abbc11c0748">
    <head>Usage Restrictions</head>
<p>Copyrights for records originating with Indiana University administrative units, departments, and other offices are held by the Trustees of Indiana University. For more information, please contact the Indiana University Archives staff.</p><p> The Indiana University Archives respects the intellectual property rights of others and does not claim any copyrights for non-university records, materials in the public domain, or materials for which we do not hold a Deed of Gift. Responsibility for the determination of the copyright status of these materials rests with those persons wishing to reuse the materials. Researchers are responsible for securing permission from copyright owners and any other rights holders for any reuse of these materials that extends beyond fair use or other statutory limitations.</p><p> Digital reproductions of archival materials from the Indiana University Archives are made available for noncommercial educational and research purposes only. If you are the copyright holder for any of the digitized materials and have questions about its inclusion on our site, please contact the Indiana University Archivist.</p>  </userestrict>
  <prefercite id="aspace_b6ca7a346783a26825dcc06cf83d482e">
    <head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>[Item], Danilo Orescanin speeches, Collection C226, Indiana University Archives, Bloomington.</p>  </prefercite>
  <processinfo id="aspace_2b757de113be956d4b8021b11869b7d9">
    <head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Processed by Elizabeth Rytting.</p><p> Completed in <date normal="2003" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2003</date>.</p>  </processinfo>
  <controlaccess>
    <subject source="lcsh">College orations --Indiana University.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">College administrators --Indiana --Bloomington --Speeches.</subject>
    <subject source="lcsh">College administrators --Indiana --Bloomington --Archives.</subject>
    <persname authfilenumber="no2003067033" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Orescanin, Danilo -- Speeches</persname>
    <persname authfilenumber="no2003067033" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Orescanin, Danilo -- Speeches -- Selections</persname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="no00030328" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Vice-President for University Relations -- Archives</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="no00030328" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Vice-President for University Relations -- Speeches</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="no94007336" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Office of University Relations -- Archives</corpname>
    <corpname authfilenumber="no94007336" rules="rda" source="lcnaf">Indiana University. Office of University Relations -- History -- 20th century -- Sources</corpname>
  </controlaccess>
  <dsc><c01 id="aspace_VAA2759-00001" level="series"><did><unittitle>Vice Presidential speeches</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1983/1987" type="inclusive">1983-1987</unitdate></did><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00002" level="item"><did><unittitle>United Way Luncheon</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1983-09-12/1983-09-12">12 Sep 1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_5b6617954fdc235ffda08c997af425d6" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00003" level="item"><did><unittitle>Student Organizations Forum</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1983-10-01/1983-10-01">1 Oct 1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_03b6b70febe98ffd8bdf265c1b114b42" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00004" level="item"><did><unittitle>Indiana Academy of Sciences</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1983-10-07/1983-10-07">7 Oct 1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_8041b83fa152025c1d79f97ba0903646" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00005" level="item"><did><unittitle>Pro Football Hall of Fame</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1983-10-31/1983-10-31">31 Oct 1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_ee957174fc6ba6de98c1fe6a92f8af48" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00006" level="item"><did><unittitle>Monroe County Education Association Banquet</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1983-11-16/1983-11-16">16 Nov 1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_b8de99b3f961ada0e8c09af93dd7eaec" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00007" level="item"><did><unittitle>Saint Sava Parish (Serbian Church)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1983-11-20/1983-11-20">20 Nov 1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_ee8e7713b102c9ecaf59205b93c0c627" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00008" level="item"><did><unittitle>Remarks to Rotary Club (Seymour)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1983-11-21/1983-11-21">21 Nov 1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_8306efc4584d1b34fe81f661cb826c10" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00009" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bloomington Press Club</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1983-12-16/1983-12-16">16 Dec 1983</unitdate><container id="aspace_62660528a495b4c3fb14470dbcf27f2d" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00010" level="item"><did><unittitle>Northwestern Indiana Regional Planning Commission Annual Meeting</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1984-01-19/1984-01-19">19 Jan 1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_ede4d53518348c4dc38a7f804314ffbb" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00011" level="item"><did><unittitle>Columbus, Ind. Rotary Club</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1984-06-11/1984-06-11">1984 Jun 11</unitdate><container id="aspace_be7cac4c0a226820d5da74aa5ff3036b" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00012" level="item"><did><unittitle>Welcoming Remarks—High School Science Institute</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1984-08-02/1984-08-02">12 Aug 1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_569b1db90c212cc71f1670d8f890471e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00013" level="item"><did><unittitle>Clevenger Award Ceremony</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1984-10-27/1984-10-27">27 Oct 1984</unitdate><container id="aspace_6ce7360fbbd405bfb74272a0f2e30bbd" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00014" level="item"><did><unittitle>Jasper Kiwanis Club</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1985-01-22/1985-01-22">22 Jan 1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_564c6b58e9cfba261da22328cc492af8" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00015" level="item"><did><unittitle>Indiana Business Leaders' Meeting</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1985-01-23/1985-01-23">23 Jan 1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_6d4ce8d29e55b200be72368f30204477" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00016" level="item"><did><unittitle>Dedication, Purdue University Engineering-Technology Program</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1985-01-31/1985-01-31">31 Jan 1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_44e6bd7f9f19270e2501674ff20f7318" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00017" level="item"><did><unittitle>Kiwanis Club (Petersburg)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1985-03-13/1985-03-13">13 Mar 1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_decec8f0ebb9c95a59f7e5334545f6c2" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00018" level="item"><did><unittitle>Founders Day--Cass &amp; Carroll Counties</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1985-03-19/1985-03-19">19 Mar 1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_c7e792b394252a3b13fd45f41e6711e0" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00019" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bloomington Downtown Kiwanis Club</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1985-06-27/1985-06-27">27 Jun 1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_78223975f4f82a88c3ba03a9ef9ba435" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00020" level="item"><did><unittitle>Indianapolis Public Relations Society</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1985-09-18/1985-09-18">18 Sep 1985</unitdate><container id="aspace_7c17659da74069ae0e41be19d22364ba" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00021" level="item"><did><unittitle>Bloomington Northside Rotary Club</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1986-01-23/1986-01-23">23 Jan 1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_8b841f2e6caed67456884dd4091654c2" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00022" level="item"><did><unittitle>Student Lecture Series</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1986-02-12/1986-02-12">12 Feb 1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_95bfe308864be18e912809ba4f6fd49e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00023" level="item"><did><unittitle>I. U. Foundation</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1986-02-28/1986-02-28">28 Feb 1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_ee9315779c9e578a85a4a1ae63db6678" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00024" level="item"><did><unittitle>Symposium on Japan</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1986-04-03/1986-04-03">3 Apr 1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_02e3126a06de25d43a8daba9e015821e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00025" level="item"><did><unittitle>IUSA Dinner</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1986-04-13/1986-04-13">13 Apr 1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_28724c2b783d4c95f6f3fe8009eecd20" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00026" level="item"><did><unittitle>Kiwanis Club (Evansville)</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1986-04-17/1986-04-17">17 Apr 1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_f65473ea19aacb9759cdd6b050af6d39" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00027" level="item"><did><unittitle>Alumni Executive Council Luncheon</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1986-06-13/1986-06-13">13 Jun 1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_0cf3956252cce5cdbd34f5217da89b88" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00028" level="item"><did><unittitle>Pro Football Hall of Fame</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1986-11-03/1986-11-03">3 Nov 1986</unitdate><container id="aspace_ea482bceea6c173306a5b6718c36b2f5" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02><c02 id="aspace_VAA2759-00029" level="item"><did><unittitle>ROTC Review</unittitle><unitdate calendar="gregorian" datechar="creation" era="ce" normal="1987-04-15/1987-04-15">15 Apr 1987</unitdate><container id="aspace_0c5de21a693f29052bcf76b7c798ed2e" label="box" type="box">1</container></did></c02></c01></dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>
