<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc" repositoryencoding="iso15511" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601">
    <eadid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="identifier" mainagencycode="orcs" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv31292" identifier="80444/xv31292">ORErg119.xml</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the Lower Division Records <date encodinganalog="date" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1929/1951">1929-1951</date></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Lower Division
					Records</titleproper>
        <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding aid prepared by Megan Guerre.</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Oregon State University Libraries, Special
					Collections &amp; Archives Research Center</publisher>
        <date encodinganalog="date" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2013">2013</date>
        <address>
          <addressline>121 The Valley Library</addressline>
          <addressline>Oregon State University</addressline>
          <addressline>Corvallis, OR 97331-4501</addressline>
          <addressline>Phone: 541-737-2075</addressline>
          <addressline>Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>Web:
				http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu</addressline>
        </address>
      </publicationstmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by Megan Guerre. <date era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2013">2013</date></creation>
      <langusage>Finding aid written in <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.</langusage>
      <descrules>Finding aid based on DACS ( <title render="italic">Describing Archives: A
					Content Standard</title>).</descrules>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <archdesc level="collection" type="guide" relatedencoding="marc21">
    <did>
      <repository encodinganalog="852">
        <corpname encodinganalog="852$a">Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections &amp; Archives Research Center</corpname>
        <subarea encodinganalog="852$b">Special Collections &amp; Archives Research
					Center</subarea>
        <address>
          <addressline>121 The Valley Library</addressline>
          <addressline>Oregon State University</addressline>
          <addressline>Corvallis, OR 97331-4501</addressline>
          <addressline>Phone: 541-737-2075</addressline>
          <addressline>Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu</addressline>
          <addressline>Web:
				http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu</addressline>
        </address>
      </repository>
      <unitid encodinganalog="099" countrycode="us" repositorycode="orcs">RG 119</unitid>
      <origination>
        <corpname role="creator" encodinganalog="110" rules="dacs">Oregon State College. Lower Division.</corpname>
      </origination>
      <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Lower Division Records</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1929/1951">1929-1951</unitdate>
      <unitdate type="bulk" encodinganalog="245$g" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1931/1933">1931-1933</unitdate>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">0.16 cubic foot</extent>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">1 box</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <physdesc>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">1 microfilm reel</extent>
        <extent encodinganalog="300$a">20 linear feet</extent>
      </physdesc>
      <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">The Lower Division Records contain correspondence,
				meeting minutes and notes, and reports that document the organization and
				establishment of a Lower Division curriculum at Oregon Agricultural College. A
				portion of the records were assembled by Mahlon Ellwood Smith, Dean of the Lower
				Division from 1932 until his retirement in 1949.</abstract>
      <langmaterial>Materials in<language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">
					English</language>.</langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="5451_">
      <head>Historical Note:</head>
      <p>In 1931, it was proposed that all students, those completing liberal arts degrees and
				those completing technical degrees, would have a common freshmen and sophomore year
				curriculum known as the Lower Division. This proposal was part of a larger attempt to organize and
				unify the public higher education system in Oregon in order to limit the challenges
				faced by students transferring between universities or from a junior college.
				Establishment of a Lower Division curriculum was not initially supported by many
				Deans at Oregon Agricultural College (OAC). They stated that it would disrupt the four-year timeline that
				had already been established for the completion of most technical degrees offered at
				OAC.</p>
      <p>A number of suggestions were made by OAC faculty in order to improve upon the initial
				proposal. Notably, Dean M. Ellwood Smith of the School of Basic Arts and Sciences
				and later Dean of the Lower Division, theorized that Lower Division curricula could
				be integrated throughout the four years of schooling received by students rather
				than being required in the first two years.</p>
      <p>By 1932 the Lower Division was established with M. Ellwood Smith acting as Dean. The
				majority of the college's administration and faculty had acknowledged that requiring
				Lower Division curricula as a part of every student's education would not disrupt
				the curriculum already in place within each School.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
      <p>The Lower Division Records document the reorganization of Oregon higher
				education in the early 1930s, specifically the establishment of Lower Division curricula for all
				students completing degrees at Oregon Agricultural College. The records describe the initial proposal as well as responses and
				reports produced by the Deans of the college concerning it. The materials include
				correspondence, meeting minutes and notes, research, studies, and reports, including
				the 1942-1944 biennial report describing the activities of the Lower Division, especially pertaining to the Army Specialized Training Program. The
				collection also contains correspondence pertaining to and with a number of Lower Division
				faculty, several of which were instructors in the Army Specialized Training Program during the war years.</p>
      <p>A portion of the records were created and assembled by Mahlon Ellwood Smith, Dean of
				the Lower Division from its establishment in 1932 until his retirement in 1949.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
      <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
    </accessrestrict>
    <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
      <p>The Lower Division Records are arranged in 5 series: I. Lower Division Organization,
				1929-1947; II. Meeting Minutes, 1940; III. Program Establishment Records, 1931;
				IV. Biennial Report, 1944; and V. Lower Division Faculty Correspondence, 1944-1951.</p>
    </arrangement>
    <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
      <p>Lower Division Records (RG 119), Oregon State University Special Collections &amp;
				Archives Research Center, Corvallis, Oregon.</p>
    </prefercite>
    <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
      <p>The microfilmed materials were received in the 1960s by the University Archives.  The bulk of the paper records were transferred from the Memorabilia Collection in 1991; a small addition was transferred from the History Department in 1995.</p>
    </acqinfo>
    <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="5441_">
      <p>Additional materials related to Dean Smith can be found in the <extref role="text/html" show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://nwda.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv29762/">M. Ellwood Smith
					Papers</extref> and the <extref role="text/html" show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://nwda.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv86533/">Memorabilia
					Collection</extref>. Additional information pertaining to the Lower Division can be found in the <extref role="text/html" show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://nwda.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv18878">President's Office
					Records of William Jasper Kerr (RG 013 - SG 07)</extref>.  The Dean of Undergraduate Studies Records (RG 113) provide information about general education at Oregon State beginning in the 1970s.</p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <persname encodinganalog="700" role="creator" source="lcnaf">Smith,
					Mahlon Ellwood, 1884-</persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject" source="lcnaf">Oregon Agricultural
					College--Curricula.</corpname>
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject" source="lcnaf">Oregon Agricultural
					College--Faculty.</corpname>
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject" source="lcnaf">Oregon State 				College--Curricula.</corpname>
        <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject" source="lcnaf">Oregon State 				College--Faculty.</corpname>
        <corpname role="creator" encodinganalog="710" rules="dacs">Oregon Agricultural College. Lower Division.</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Universities and
					colleges--Oregon--Corvallis--Administration.</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Universities and
					colleges--Curricula--Oregon--Corvallis.</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Education, Higher--Oregon.</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Military education--Oregon--Corvallis.</subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">World War, 1939-1945--War work--Schools.</subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Colleges and
					Universities</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Military</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Corvallis</subject>
        <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Oregon</subject>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <dsc type="combined">
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>Series I</unitid>
          <unittitle>Lower Division Organization</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1929/1947">1929-1947</unitdate>
          <container type="reel">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Series I consists of microfilmed materials prepared or assembled by M. Ellwood Smith, Dean of the
						School of Basic Arts and Sciences, pertaining to the organization and establishment of a Lower Division
						curriculum at Oregon Agricultural College (OAC). It contains regulations governing
						the operations of interinstitutional deans and directors in the fields of
						minor work at OAC and the University of Oregon; multiple studies pertaining
						to Lower Division organization as well as procedures for its establishment
						at other universities; and correspondence between Dean M. Ellwood Smith and
						individuals and organizations, including Registrar E. B. Lemon, President W.
						J. Kerr and the Administrative Council, regarding the reorganization of the
						Lower Division.  The bulk of the materials were created in 1932-1933.  The series also includes later correspondence regarding Lower Division
						summer session classes and other Lower Division matters.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>Series II</unitid>
          <unittitle>Meeting Minutes</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
          <container type="reel">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Series II consists of microfilmed minutes documenting a meeting about the general
						controversy between the University of Oregon and Oregon State College
						relative to courses taught in the Lower Division at each school as well as
						reference to the entire controversy.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>Series III</unitid>
          <unittitle>Program Establishment Records</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1931">1931</unitdate>
          <container type="box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Series III consists of memos, correspondence, and reports pertaining to the
						proposal for establishment of Lower Division curricula at Oregon
						Agricultural College. The collection contains reports and correspondence
						produced by Dean Peavy of the School of Forestry, Dean Hance of the School
						of Mines, Dean Milam of the School of Home Economics, Dean Ziefle of the
						School of Pharmacy, Dean Rogers of the School of Engineering and Dean Smith
						of the School of Basic Arts and Sciences describing the effect that a
						requirement of Lower Division curricula would have on existing curricula as
						well as the logistics of organizing Lower Division curricula at OAC. It also
						contains notes from Board of Higher Education meetings, documents describing
						credit requirements at OAC and contemporary universities, budgetary and
						general information related to the activities and administrative
						organization of a number of the Schools at OAC, and memos and reports
						pertaining to the effectiveness of training received by graduates of the
						College in a number of fields. </p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>Series IV</unitid>
          <unittitle>Biennial Report for 1942-1944</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1944">1944</unitdate>
          <container type="box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Series IV consists of a biennial report describing the activities of the
						Lower Division of Liberal Arts and Sciences in the Oregon State System of
						Higher Education in the 1942-1944 biennium.  The bulk of the report discusses the Army Specialized Training Program.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="series">
        <did>
          <unitid>Series V</unitid>
          <unittitle>Lower Division Faculty Correspondence</unittitle>
          <unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1944/1951">1944-1951</unitdate>
          <container type="box">1</container>
        </did>
        <scopecontent>
          <p>Series V consists of correspondence with and pertaining to the following Lower
						Division faculty: Ramona E. Berry, Lulu Garrett, A. Grajdanzev, Boyd F.
						Huff, Rolf W. Ordal, Clarence C. Hulley, Wentworth S. Morris, Sidney
						Phillips, and Lawrence Tyler. Several of these faculty were instructors in
						the Army Specialized Training Program during the war years.</p>
        </scopecontent>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>

