<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc">
      <eadid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="identifier" mainagencycode="orcs" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv34658" identifier="80444/xv34658">OREp333.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
                  <titlestmt>
               <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the Edward S. Curtis Photographs
                                 <date encodinganalog="date" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1900/1926">1900-1926</date>
                             </titleproper>
               <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Edward S. Curtis Photographs</titleproper>
                                <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding Aid Authors: Ruth Vondracek and Sanju Gharti Chhetri.</author>
                          </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
           <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections and Archives Research Center</publisher>
                           <date encodinganalog="date" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2017">2017</date>

                           <address>
                <addressline>121 The Valley Library</addressline>
                            <addressline>Oregon State University</addressline>
                            <addressline>Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501</addressline>
                            <addressline>Phone: 541-737-2075</addressline>
                              <addressline>Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu</addressline>
                              <addressline>Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids</addressline>
                        </address>
               
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was encoded in EAD by Archon 3.21 from an SQL database source on <date type="encoded" normal="2017-05-17" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">May 17th, 2017</date>. Encoding was modified by Elizabeth Nielsen for Archives West compliance.</creation>
        <langusage>Finding aid written in
          <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.</langusage> <descrules>Finding
              aid based on DACS ( 
              <title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content
                Standard, 2nd Edition</title>).</descrules> 
                         
      </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>

      <archdesc level="collection" type="guide" relatedencoding="marc21">
        <did>
                      <origination>
                        <persname role="creator" source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="100">Curtis, Edward S., 1868-1952.</persname>
          </origination>
            
                  <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Edward S. Curtis Photographs</unittitle>
                  <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" normal="1900/1926" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1900-1926</unitdate>
                  <unitid encodinganalog="099" repositorycode="orcs" countrycode="us">P 333</unitid>
                  <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">0.10 cubic feet, including 1 framed platinum print (platinotype), 1 mounted photogravure print, and 1  mounted photogravure print with embossed plate mark.</extent>
                    <extent encodinganalog="300$a">2 oversize boxes</extent>
          </physdesc>
                  <langmaterial>Materials in <language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
                        <repository encodinganalog="852$b">
                              <corpname>Special Collections and Archives Research Center</corpname>
                              <address>
                     <addressline>121 The Valley Library</addressline>
                                    <addressline>Oregon State University</addressline>
                                       <addressline>Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501</addressline>
                       <addressline>Phone: 541-737-2075</addressline>
                            <addressline>Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu</addressline>
                                         <addressline>Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids</addressline>
                              </address>
            </repository>
                              <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">The Edward S. Curtis Photographs consists of three photographic prints, a platinum print and two photogravures, acquired by Gerald W. Williams, that document aspects of Native American life between 1900 and 1926.  The prints are titled, <emph render="italic">Caches at Celilo</emph>, <emph render="italic">Woman's Costume and Baby Swing - Assiniboin</emph>, and <emph render="italic">The Clam Digger</emph>. All of these images appear in Curtis' 20-volume set, <emph render="italic">The North American Indian</emph>.  Edward S. Curtis was known for his exceptional photography andhis ethnological work that sought to document Native American groups and their cultures.</abstract>
                     
      </did>
      <!--COLLECTION LEVEL METADATA: -->
        <bioghist encodinganalog="5451_"><head>Historical Note:</head>
                        <p>Edward Sheriff Curtis was a notable photographer and ethnographer best known for his work <emph render="italic">The North American Indian</emph> a set of 20-volume photographic project that documents the Native-American tribes and their culture in North America. This monumental work was published over a span of 23 years between 1907 and 1930. Curtis was inspired to capture the native Indian people and their culture lest it would be infringed upon and disappear due to the white expansion and white culture. Curtis dedicated thirty years of his life traveling, exploring, documenting and living with the native tribes, which later ensued into one of his most celebrated work, ‘The North American Indian.</p>
                        <p>A self-taught photographer, Curtis was born in 1868 in Whitewater, Wisconsin. His interest in photography was evident from his early years as he assembled his own camera when he was only twelve years old with the help of the then popular manual <emph render="italic">Wilson’s Photographics</emph>. Curtis and his family moved to Puget Sound, Washington in 1887 and he later opened a portrait studio in 1892 in partnership with Thomas Guptill in Seattle. He renamed the photo studio to ‘Edward S. Curtis, Photographer and Photoengraver’ after he and partner Guptill parted ways in 1897. It was in Washington where Curtis first began photographing the local Native Americans. His images of Puget Sound Native Americans won him the grand prize at the National Photographic Convention of 1898.</p>
                        <p>In 1898, Curtis came across a group of scientists who were lost while he was photographing the Mt. Rainier. Anthropologist George Bird Grinnell, a noted expert in Native American cultures, was one of the scientists in the group. This happenstance meeting allowed Grinnell to learn about Curtis’ work. Grinnell invited Curtis to be the photographer for the Harriman Alaska Expedition of 1899 that was spearheaded by Edward H. Harriman and comprised of naturalist John Muir, and zoologist C. Hart Merriam in the team. Grinnell again appointed Curtis the following year to photograph Blackfeet Indian tribe in Montana. These experiences proved crucial for Curtis in perusing and bolstering his interest in studying and documenting the native tribes of North America.</p>
                        <p>Upon his return to Seattle, Curtis organized exhibitions featuring his work, published articles and gave lectures on native Indian tribes. His work garnered attention from many including the then President Theodore Roosevelt who asked Curtis to photograph family portraits. In 1906, Curtis reached out to John Pierpont Morgan, the railroad tycoon to finance his work, which set his project ‘The North American Indian’ in motion. It was decided that the project would be a set of 20 volumes of ethnographic text illustrated with photoengraving.  The final two volumes of the series was published in 1930. During his 30 years of extensive fieldwork, Curtis is believed to have taken more than 40,000 photographs, 10,000 cylinder sound recordings of Indian speech and music and taken more than 125 trips across country for the making of the project. He was also known as the ‘Shadow Catcher’, a name he earned from the Native Americans. ‘In the Land of the Head Hunters’, is his another notable work which is a first feature-length film to capture the Native Indian people in North America that premiered in 1914. Curtis’ work celebrated Native American culture and left a valuable legacy that offered a rich insight into indigenous people of North America and their way of living.</p>
                    </bioghist>
                        <!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS / SUBJECT TERMS -->
              <controlaccess>
               <controlaccess>
                <persname role="creator" source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="700">Williams, Gerald W.</persname>
                               </controlaccess>
              <controlaccess>
                   <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Photographic prints.</genreform>
                                      <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Photogravures (prints)</genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Platinum prints.</genreform>
                 </controlaccess>
        <controlaccess>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Assiniboine Indians.</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Clamming.</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Indians of North America--Clothing.</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Indians of North America--Northwest, Pacific.</subject>
          
                   
                 </controlaccess>
                <controlaccess> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Anthropology</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Native Americans</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Women</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Oregon</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Washington (State)</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Photographs</subject> 
                </controlaccess> 
                
      </controlaccess>
                  <!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS -->
      <!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->
                        <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
                           <p>These three prints were originally part of the Gerald W. Williams (MSS WilliamsG) collection,  Accessions 2007:100 and  2014:059.  The Edward S. Curtis photographs were separated from the Williams collection in 2016.</p>
                        </acqinfo>
                        <processinfo encodinganalog="583">
                                    <p>The three photographic prints in this collection were orginally part of the Gerald W. Williams collection (MSS WilliamsG).  "Caches at Celilo" was part of Accession 2014:059.  The other two prints may have been part of the main Gerald W. Williams collection acquired in 2007.  The three images were separated from the main collection in 2016 to form the Edward S. Curtis Photographs collection in 2016.</p>
                              </processinfo>
                              <userestrict encodinganalog="540">
                                          <p>Images in this collection are considered to be in the public domain.</p>
                              </userestrict>
                     <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
                                          <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
                           </accessrestrict>
                                 <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="5441_">
                                   <p>Other Gerald W. Williams collections contain images of Native Americans, such as Gerald W. Williams Photographs Collection (P 329); <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv79299" role="text/html">Frank Patterson Photographic Postcards</extref> (P 312); Gerald W. Williams Postcards Collection (P 323); and Gerald W. Williams Collection of Prints and Postcards of Native Americans Collection (P 317).  The <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv06701" role="text/html">Gerald W. Williams Regional Albums</extref> includes some modern reproductions of Edward Curtis' images, as well as images produced by his brother, Asahel Curtis, also a renowned photographer.  Other collections of interest include: <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv29095" role="text/html">Benjamin A. Gifford Photographs</extref> (P 218 – SG1) and <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv67092" role="text/html">Ralph I. Gifford Photographs</extref> (P 218 – SG2).  The <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://guides.library.oregonstate.edu/oma" role="text/html">Oregon Multicultural Archives</extref> is a rich source for information on Native American communities in Oregon</p>
                                 </relatedmaterial>
                        <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
                                 <p>This collection is arranged into a single series; Series 1: Photographic Prints.</p>
                        </arrangement>
            <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
                                 <p>The collection includes two mounted photogravures and one framed platinotype or platinum print. Each of the photographs appeared in various volumes of the <emph render="italic">The North American Indian</emph>, a 20-volume set that Curtis published between 1907 and 1930. <emph render="italic">The Clam Digger</emph>, a platinotype, one of Curtis’ best- known photographs and one of his first, depicts a Native American woman, possibly Princess Angeline, digging for clams on the shore of Puget Sound.  In <emph render="italic">Woman’s Costume and Baby Swing – Assiniboin</emph> a woman in native dress looks down at baby in a swing or hammock, that is suspended by ropes between two small trees. <emph render="italic">Caches at Celilo</emph> is dominated by three wooden cross-framed structures holding wooden planks used to construct seasonal summer homes.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                     <!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->
         <!-- END COLLECTION LEVEL METADATA -->
                        <!-- BEGIN SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS -->
            <dsc type="combined">
               <c01 level="series">
   <did>
                  <unitid>Series 1</unitid>
                  <unittitle>Photographic Prints</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1900/1926" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1900-1926</unitdate>
               </did>
         <c02 level="item">
   <did>
                  
            	<container type="box-item">1.1</container>
      <unittitle>Caches At Celilo</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1909</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Text below image: "E. S. Curtis. From Copyright Photograph.1909." Mounted photogravure print  (8 x 7 inches).</p>
                        <p>This image appears in <emph render="italic">The North American Indian</emph>, volume 8 and was used to illustrate "the method commonly enjoyed along the river of storing the summer-house materials at the fisheries."</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="item">
   <did>
                  
            	<container type="box-item">1.2</container>
      <unittitle>Woman's Costume and Baby Swing – Assiniboin</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1926</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Text below image: "E.S. Curtis. From Copyright Photograph. 1926." Mounted photogravure with embossed plate mark (13 x  11 inches). Assiniboin woman in native costume looking at baby in swing, that is attached by rope to two small trees. This image appears in <emph render="italic">The North American Indian</emph>, volume 18.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="item">
   <did>
                  
            	<container type="box-item">2.1</container>
      <unittitle>The Clam Digger</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1900</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Text below image: E.S. Curtis. Photo Number: 24. 1900.</p>
                        <p>Framed platinum print. (12 x 16 inches). Native American woman digging for clams using a clamming stick on the shoreline,  possibly on Puget Sound. The woman is Princess Angeline,daughter of Chief Seattle. A woven basket lies to the side of the woman and a canoe is pulled up on the shore next to her. This image appears in volume 9 of <emph render="italic">The North American Indian</emph>.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   
</c01>
   
            </dsc>
               <!-- END SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS -->
   </archdesc>
</ead>

