<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc">
      <eadid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="identifier" mainagencycode="orcs" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv39385" identifier="80444/xv39385">OREtegnell.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
                  <titlestmt>
               <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the Russell and Katherine Tegnell Scrapbook
                                 <date encodinganalog="date" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1931/1941">1931-1941</date>
                             </titleproper>
               <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Tegnell (Russell and Katherine) Scrapbook</titleproper>
                                <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding Aid Authors: Katy Roach, Chris Petersen.</author>
                          </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
           <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections and Archives Research Center</publisher>
                           <date encodinganalog="date" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2020">2020</date>

                           <address>
                <addressline>121 The Valley Library</addressline>
                            <addressline>Oregon State University</addressline>
                            <addressline>Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501</addressline>
                            <addressline>Phone: 541-737-2075</addressline>
                              <addressline>Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu</addressline>
                              <addressline>Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids</addressline>
                        </address>
               
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was encoded in EAD by Archon 3.21 from an SQL database source on <date type="encoded" normal="2020-01-24" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">January 24th, 2020</date>. Encoding was modified by Elizabeth Nielsen for Archives West compliance.</creation>
        <langusage>Finding aid written in
          <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.</langusage> <descrules>Finding
              aid based on DACS ( 
              <title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content
                Standard, 2nd Edition</title>).</descrules> 
                        
      </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>

      <archdesc level="collection" type="guide" relatedencoding="marc21">
        <did>
                      <origination>
                        <persname role="creator" rules="rda" encodinganalog="100">Tegnell, Katherine.</persname>
          </origination>
            
                  <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Russell and Katherine Tegnell Scrapbook</unittitle>
                  <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" normal="1931/1941" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1931-1941</unitdate>
                  <unitdate encodinganalog="245$g" type="bulk" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1931/1937">1931-1937</unitdate>
                  <unitid encodinganalog="099" repositorycode="orcs" countrycode="us">MSS Tegnell</unitid>
                  <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">0.15 cubic feet, including 9 photographs</extent>
                    <extent encodinganalog="300$a">1 oversize box</extent>
          </physdesc>
                  <langmaterial>Materials in <language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
                        <repository encodinganalog="852$b">
                              <corpname>Special Collections and Archives Research Center</corpname>
                              <address>
                     <addressline>121 The Valley Library</addressline>
                                    <addressline>Oregon State University</addressline>
                                       <addressline>Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501</addressline>
                       <addressline>Phone: 541-737-2075</addressline>
                            <addressline>Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu</addressline>
                                         <addressline>Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids</addressline>
                              </address>
            </repository>
                              <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">Russell and Katherine (Smith) Tegnell were students at Oregon State College who met on campus and married in 1934, just before their fourth year of college. The Russell and Katherine Tegnell Scrapbook was compiled by the couple, and contains numerous newspaper clippings as well as a smaller number of photographic prints. Much of the material included in the scrapbook is related to Russell’s time as the President of the Memorial Union as well as Katherine’s academic achievements. Initiation and award certificates, and a blank class officers ballot are also included.</abstract>
                     
      </did>
      <!--COLLECTION LEVEL METADATA: -->
        <bioghist encodinganalog="5450_"><head>Biographical Note:</head>
                        <p>Lieutenant Colonel Russell M. Tegnell was born in Helena, Montana in 1910. In the years that followed, his family moved to Hillsdale, Oregon and he ultimately graduated from Benson Polytechnic High School in 1928.</p>
                        <p>Tegnell enrolled at Oregon State College in 1932, majoring in chemical engineering. A very active student while at OSC, Tegnell served as President of the Memorial Union for the 1934-35 academic year. He was also a member of the Phi Delta Theta fraternity, the Blue Key Honor Society, and the Alpha Delta Sigma National Professional Advertising fraternity. In addition, Tegnell served as the business manager for the junior class play, manager of the <emph render="italic">Oregon State Technical Record</emph> magazine, member of the Board of Directors for the Memorial Union, chairman for the 1935 OSC Homecoming, chairman of the OSC Associated Student Dance, and chairman of the OSC Socials Committee. Even with his busy extracurricular schedule, Tegnell still maintained high marks and made several honor rolls.</p>
                        <p>Tegnell completed his chemical engineering degree in 1936 and enlisted into the US Army in 1940, serving for twenty-three years before retiring in 1963. The nature of Russell’s work was such that the Tegnell family moved often, and at various points Russell and Katherine lived in Colorado, Alabama, and Germany before finally settling in Maryland with their two daughters. Russell Tegnell passed away in 1983, at the age of 73.</p>
                        <p>Katherine J. Smith was born in Dallas, Oregon in 1912. She graduated from Dallas High School in 1931 and began attending Oregon State College that same year. She initially majored in commerce, but switched to home economics during her sophomore year. She married Russell Tegnell in 1934 at Westminster House in Corvallis, Oregon.</p>
                        <p>Katherine received many awards for scholastic achievement during her years at OSC. Before even entering college, she recorded the freshman class high score on the English entrance exam and also received an award for her excellent transcription skills. She was a member of, and secretary for, the Sophomore Spurs Honor Division, obtained the Phi Chi Theta award, and was a member of the Phi Kappa Phi Honor Society and the Alpha Lambda Delta Honor Society. Additionally, she was a member of the Alpha Delta Pi sorority. She obtained her home economics degree from Oregon State in 1937. She passed away at the age of 86 in 1998.</p>
                    </bioghist>
                        <!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS / SUBJECT TERMS -->
              <controlaccess>
               <controlaccess>
                <persname role="creator" rules="rda" encodinganalog="700">Tegnell, Russell.</persname>
                               </controlaccess>
              <controlaccess>
                   <corpname encodinganalog="610" rules="rda" role="subject">Alpha Lambda Delta. Oregon State College Chapter.</corpname>
                   <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Blue Key (Fraternity)</corpname>
                   <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Oregon State College--Students.</corpname>
                   <corpname encodinganalog="610" rules="rda" role="subject">Oregon State College. Memorial Union.</corpname>
                 </controlaccess>
        <controlaccess>
                   <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Photographic prints.</genreform>
                   <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
                 </controlaccess>
        <controlaccess>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Adult college students--Oregon--Corvallis.</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">College student government--Oregon--Corvallis.</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Greek letter societies--Oregon--Corvallis.</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Men--Oregon--Corvallis--Societies and clubs.</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Student activities--Oregon--Corvallis.</subject>
                   
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women--Education (Higher)--Oregon--Corvallis.</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Women--Oregon--Corvallis--Societies and clubs.</subject>
                 </controlaccess>
                <controlaccess> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Clubs and Societies</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Colleges and Universities</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Military</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Performing Arts</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Political Campaigns</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Student Life</subject>
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Women</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Oregon</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Corvallis</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Photographs</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Scrapbooks</subject> 
                </controlaccess> 
      </controlaccess>
                  <!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS -->
      <!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->
                        <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
                           <p>The materials were transferred to the University Archives by the Oregon State University Department of Alumni Relations in 2002.</p>
                        </acqinfo>
                     <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
                                          <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
                           </accessrestrict>
                              <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
                     <p>Russell and Katherine Tegnell Scrapbook (MSS Tegnell), Oregon State University Special Collections and Archives Research Center, Corvallis, Oregon.</p>
                  </prefercite>
                              <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="5441_">
                                          <p>The Special Collections and Archives Research Center holds multiple collections related to the Tegnell’s time at Oregon State College. After graduation, Lieutenant Colonel Tegnell was featured in the February 1956 issue of the <emph render="italic"><extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://oregondigital.org/catalog/oregondigital:fx71bk31d#page/18/mode/2up/search/tegnell" role="text/html">Oregon Stater</extref></emph> alumni magazine.Two photographs of him, stationed in Japan, are held in Harriet’s Photograph Collection (P HC), and appear in a <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://oregondigital.org/catalog/oregondigital:fx71bm599#page/16/mode/2up" role="text/html">1946 issue of the <emph render="italic">Oregon Stater</emph></extref>.</p>
                                <p>Tegnell acted as business manager for <emph render="italic">The Oregon State Technical Record</emph>, issues of which have been digitized and made <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://oregondigital.org/catalog/?_=1576105711855&amp;f%5Bdate_decades_ssim%5D%5B%5D=1930-1939&amp;q=oregon+state+technical+record&amp;search_field=all_fields&amp;utf8=%E2%9C%93" role="text/html">available in Oregon Digital</extref>. <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv52374" role="text/html">The University Theatre Photographs Collection</extref> (P 112) also contains photographic material from the junior class play <emph render="italic">The Tavern</emph>, 1934, a production Russell helped put on as business manager.</p>
                                <p>Materials related to the Phi Delta Theta fraternity, of which Russell was a member, are contained in the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv86533" role="text/html">Oregon State University Memorabilia Collection</extref> (MSS MC), and the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv84138" role="text/html">Bill Tomsheck Scrapbook</extref> (MSS Tomsheck) includes photographs of the Phi Delta Theta house at Oregon State College. Tegnell was also a member of the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv88696" role="text/html">Blue Key Honor Society</extref> (MSS BlueKey).</p>
                                <p>Records related to the groups that Katherine was a member of are also available in SCARC. The Phi Kappa Phi Honor Society is documented in the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv95428" role="text/html">Phi Kappa Phi - OSU Chapter Records</extref> (MSS PhiKappaPhi), as well as the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv86533" role="text/html">Oregon State University Memorabilia Collection</extref> (MSS MC) and the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv84822" role="text/html">J. Kenneth Munford Collection</extref> (MSS Munford). The Alpha Lambda Delta Honor Society is likewise documented in the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv52087" role="text/html">Alpha Lambda Delta - Oregon State University Chapter Records</extref> (MSS AlphaLambdaDelta).</p>
                                 </relatedmaterial>
                        <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
                                 <p>The scrapbook was arranged by the couple according to event, and remains in the same order in which it was constructed.</p>
                        </arrangement>
            <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
                                 <p>The Russell and Katherine Tegnell Scrapbook is neatly arranged and consists primarily of newspaper clippings documenting the couple’s wedding, scholastic success, and Russell Tegnell’s various student positions at Oregon State College. It also includes certificates, a blank ballot for the 1933 OSC Junior Class Officers election, and nine 8x10 black-and-white photographs of Memorial Union events. These photographs include shots of a banquet, as well as decorations for the 1934 All College Formal dance. Several group shots of Memorial Union staff are included as well, with Russell Tegnell pictured in each. Likewise included are three images of Russell’s trip to Oakland, California in 1937, to attend the Real Silk Western Convention.</p>
                                 <p>The news clippings pertain mostly to Russell Tegnell’s campaign to become president of the Memorial Union, as well as articles about events that he organized as Chairman of the Socials Committee. Of particular interest are articles and pamphlets related to the 1933 junior class play, “The Tavern,” which Tegnell presided over as business manager; various dance announcements; and two articles related to his budding military career. Tegnell, who enlisted in the Army after graduating from OSC, taught civilians how to handle live fire bombs, and also practiced gas warfare.</p>
                                 <p>Several pages contain articles regarding Katherine Tegnell’s impressive academic achievements. She was a member of three honor societies - the Sophomore Spurs, Alpha Lambda Delta, and Phi Kappa Phi - and received numerous awards. Included in the scrapbook is a pamphlet from the ninth annual Women’s Day Celebration, in which Tegnell received the Phi Chi Theta award, given to the woman with the highest scholastic standing in the School of Commerce. Katherine also successfully ran for the position of Secretary of the Sophomore Spurs during her junior year at OSC, an achievement that is documented in the volume.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                     <!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->
         <!-- END COLLECTION LEVEL METADATA -->
                  <!-- END SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS -->
   </archdesc>
</ead>

