<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc">
     <eadid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="identifier" mainagencycode="orcs" url="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:80444/xv474487" identifier="80444/xv474487">OREoh050.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
                  <titlestmt>
               <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the Mount St. Helens Oral History Collection
                                 <date encodinganalog="date" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2015">2015</date>
                             </titleproper>
               <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Mount Saint Helens Oral History Collection</titleproper>
                                <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding Aid Authors: Chris Petersen.</author>
                          </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
           <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections and Archives Research Center</publisher>
                           <date encodinganalog="date" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2023">2023</date>

                           <address>
                <addressline>121 The Valley Library</addressline>
                            <addressline>Oregon State University</addressline>
                            <addressline>Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501</addressline>
                            <addressline>Phone: 541-737-2075</addressline>
                              <addressline>Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu</addressline>
                              <addressline>Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids</addressline>
                        </address>
               
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was encoded in EAD by Archon 3.21 from an SQL database source on <date type="encoded" normal="2023-06-06" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">June 6th, 2023</date>. Encoding was modified by Chris Petersen for Archives West compliance.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in
            <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.</langusage> <descrules>Finding
                  aid based on DACS ( 
                  <title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content
                     Standard, 2nd Edition</title>).</descrules> 
      </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>

      <archdesc level="collection" type="guide" relatedencoding="marc21">
        <did>
                      <origination>
                        <persname role="creator" encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Schmieding, Sam</persname>
          </origination>
            
                  <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Mount St. Helens Oral History Collection</unittitle>
                  <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" normal="2015" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">2015</unitdate>
                  <unitid encodinganalog="099" repositorycode="orcs" countrycode="us">OH 050</unitid>
                  <physdesc>
                     <extent encodinganalog="300$a">10.90 gigabytes</extent>
                     <extent encodinganalog="300$a">7 audio files</extent>
          </physdesc>
                  <langmaterial>Materials in <language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
                        <repository encodinganalog="852$b">
                              <corpname>Special Collections and Archives Research Center</corpname>
                              <address>
                     <addressline>121 The Valley Library</addressline>
                                    <addressline>Oregon State University</addressline>
                                       <addressline>Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501</addressline>
                       <addressline>Phone: 541-737-2075</addressline>
                            <addressline>Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu</addressline>
                                         <addressline>Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids</addressline>
                              </address>
            </repository>
                              <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">The Mount St. Helens Oral History Collection consists of seven interviews conducted in 2015 by historian Samuel Schmieding with five scientists and one administrator who have played a leading role in the study and management of Mount St. Helens, a Cascades Range volcano that famously and catastrophically erupted on May 18, 1980. All of the interviews described in this collection have been transcribed and made <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/omeka/exhibits/show/forestryvoices/collections/" role="text/html">available online</extref>.</abstract>
                     
      </did>
      <!--COLLECTION LEVEL METADATA: -->
        <bioghist encodinganalog="5451_"><head>Historical Note:</head>
                        <p>Mount St. Helens is an active volcano located in the Cascade mountain range in southwest Washington state. For centuries a sacred space to the region's indigenous communities, the mountain became a popular site for recreation during the twentieth century, with many flocking in particular to Spirit Lake on its north side. In March 1980, a series of small earthquakes - followed by episodes of steam venting - indicated that the long dormant volcano was becoming geologically active again. On May 18, 1980, Mount St. Helens famously erupted in spectacular fashion, ultimately losing more than 1,300 feet in elevation from its peak, unleashing a fearsome landslide, and creating a cloud of ash that blanketed communities across the Pacific Northwest and eventually circulated around the world. At least fifty-seven people were killed by the explosion, with property damage estimates in the billions of dollars.</p>
                        <p>On August 26, 1982, an act of Congress designated the mountain and 110,000 acres that surrounded it as the Mount St. Helens National Volcanic Monument. This declaration restricted development activities within the monument to permit natural processes to "proceed substantially unimpeded" so that research could track responses of the land to the eruption. The resulting wealth of research findings have been conducted in part by the following individuals, who were interviewed for this collection in 2015.</p>
                        <p><emph render="bold">Lynn Burditt</emph> has served in a variety of leadership positions in the National Forest System of the US Forest Service, including tenures as Ranger at the Blue River Ranger District on the Willamette National Forest and Deputy Forest Supervisor on the Gifford Pinchot National Forest where the Mount St. Helens National Volcanic Monument is located.</p>
                        <p><emph render="bold">Charlie Crisafulli</emph>, an ecologist with the US Forest Service, Pacific Northwest Research Station and based at Mount St. Helens since the early 1980s, has conducted his own studies on a wide variety of topics, facilitated work of many others, spearheaded local and broader outreach programs, and advanced the field of volcano ecology globally.</p>
                        <p><emph render="bold">Virginia Dale</emph> began studying Mount St. Helens while a graduate student at the University of Washington and continued during her career as a scientist at Oak Ridge National Laboratory. Focusing on vegetation in the debris avalanche, Dale was a contributing author and editor for two books providing overviews of ecological research at Mount St. Helens.</p>
                        <p><emph render="bold">Jerry Franklin</emph> began his relationship with Mount St. Helens on family and Boy Scout camping trips, studied the vegetation as an early-career Forest Service scientist and later as a professor at the University of Washington, led Andrews Experimental Forest research program in the 1970s and early 1980s, and helped lead studies at Mount St. Helens.</p>
                        <p><emph render="bold">Bob Parmenter</emph> was an ecology graduate at Utah State University when Mount St. Helens erupted in 1980. Soon thereafter, he began studies of animals in collaboration with Charlie Crisafulli and others that ran for decades over his career as an ecologist with the US Geological Survey.</p>
                        <p><emph render="bold">Fred Swanson</emph> had a long career as a research geologist with the Pacific Northwest Research Station, focusing in particular on the geology-ecology interface in ecosystem research groups at Mount St. Helens and the H.J. Andrews Experimental Forest. His roles included conducting research, administration, and communications, including engagements of artists and creative writers in those places.</p>
                    </bioghist>
                        <!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS / SUBJECT TERMS -->
              <controlaccess>
               <controlaccess>
                <persname role="creator" encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Swanson, Frederick J. (Frederick John), 1943-</persname>
                               </controlaccess>
              <controlaccess>
                   <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Born digital.</genreform>
                   <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Oral histories (literary works)</genreform>
                 </controlaccess>
        <controlaccess>
                   <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh" role="subject">Saint Helens, Mount (Wash.)</geogname>
                   <geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcsh" role="subject">Saint Helens, Mount (Wash.)--Eruption, 1980.</geogname>
                 </controlaccess>
        <controlaccess>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Mount Saint Helens National Volcanic Monument (Wash.)</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Mountain ecology--Washington (State).</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Stream ecology--Washington (State)</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Volcanic eruptions</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Volcanoes--Washington (State).</subject>
                 </controlaccess>
                 
                 <controlaccess>
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Environmental Conditions</subject> 
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Fisheries and Wildlife</subject> 
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Forestry and Forestry Products</subject>
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Land Use</subject>
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Science</subject>
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Washington (State)</subject>
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Electronic Records</subject>
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Oral Histories</subject>
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Sound Recordings</subject>
                 </controlaccess>
                 
      </controlaccess>
                  <!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS -->
      <!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->
                        <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
                           <p>The collection was transferred to the Special Collections and Archives Research Center by Fred Swanson and Samuel Schmieding in 2019.</p>
                        </acqinfo>
                     <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
                                          <p>The collection is open for research.</p>
                           </accessrestrict>
                              <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
                     <p>Mount St. Helens Oral History Collection (OH 050), Oregon State University Special Collections and Archives Research Center, Corvallis, Oregon.</p>
                  </prefercite>
                              <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="5441_">
                                 <p>SCARC is home to numerous collections housing materials related to Mount St. Helens and documenting its 1980 eruption. These include the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:80444/xv95986" role="text/html">Norman H. Anderson Papers (MSS AndersonN)</extref>, the James R. Sedell Papers (MSS Sedell), the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:80444/xv143084" role="text/html">Chuck Williams Photograph Collection (P 345)</extref>, the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:80444/xv20022" role="text/html">T.J. Starker Papers (MSS Starker)</extref>, the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:80444/xv29141" role="text/html">Water Resources Research Institute Records (RG 251)</extref>, the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:80444/xv86533" role="text/html">Oregon State University Memorabilia Collection (MSS MC)</extref>, the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:80444/xv67169" role="text/html">Gerald W. Williams Slides (P 314)</extref>, and the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:80444/xv05149" role="text/html">Extension and Experiment Station Moving Images (FV 120)</extref>.</p>
                                 <p>Video footage of the mountain venting in spring 1980 as well as a southern view of its May 18th eruption is held in the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids/?p=collections/findingaid&amp;id=1422" role="text/html">News and Communication Services Motion Picture Films and Videotapes Collection (FV 057)</extref> and <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://media.oregonstate.edu/media/t/0_45vtbvcd" role="text/html">available online</extref>. An oral history interview with newspaper journalist Roger Werth, who photographed the eruption, is held in the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:80444/xv508206" role="text/html">Oregon State University Sesquicentennial Oral History Collection (OH 026)</extref> and is also <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/oh150/werth/video-werth.html" role="text/html">available online</extref>. Photographs of the mountain, both pre- and post-eruption, taken by Charles Rosenfeld, are available in the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:80444/xv58840" role="text/html">College of Science Records (RG 024)</extref>.</p>
                                 <p>SCARC also holds two topically related oral history collections that were generated, at least in part, by Samuel Schmieding with the assistance of Fred Swanson: the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:80444/xv88211" role="text/html">H.J. Andrews Experimental Forest Oral History Collection (OH 028)</extref> and the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:80444/xv314629" role="text/html">Northwest Forest Plan Oral History Collection (OH 048)</extref>. The full contents of both of those oral history collections are available online through the SCARC exhibit, <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/omeka/exhibits/show/forestryvoices/main/" role="text/html">Voice of the Forests, Voices of the Mills</extref>.</p>
                                          <p>Finally, a book titled <emph render="italic">After the Blast: The Ecological Recovery of Mount St. Helens</emph> (Eric Wagner, University of Washington Press, 2020), makes use of the interviews held in this collection in telling the story of scientific inquiry at Mount St. Helens since 1980.</p>
                                 </relatedmaterial>
                        <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
                                 <p>The interviews held in this collection have been organized into a single series, 1. Interviews, 2015, and arranged chronologically within the series.</p>
                        </arrangement>
            <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
                                 <p>The born digital interviews described in this collection were mostly conducted at the Mount St. Helens Scientific Pulse, a periodic gathering of members of the scientific community working on the ecological response to the 1980 eruption. One interview, with Virginia Dale, was collected in Baltimore, Maryland at a meeting of the Ecological Society of America. All interviews were led by historian Samuel Schmieding and collected to audio-only, sometimes in multiple parts. The original *.wav files collected by Schmieding have been preserved. In addition, *.mp3 derivatives have also been created for each file, and multiple files collected for a given interview have been compiled together for user access. Each interview has also been professionally transcribed and made <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/omeka/exhibits/show/forestryvoices/collections/" role="text/html">available online</extref>. The biographical sketches and abstracts used to contextualize each of these interviews in their online form were written by Frederick J. Swanson.</p>
                                 <p>Topics covered in these interviews include: narrators' personal backgrounds, mentors and colleagues; experiences of the mountain prior to the 1980 eruption, memories of the eruption itself and the immediate aftermath; research activities in the blast zone on mammals, birds and aquatic species, vegetation, and geology; the human toll of the eruption and its cultural and economic impact; the creation and importance of the National Volcanic Monument; conflicting opinions on how best to manage the Mount St. Helens ecosystem; the many safety risks inherent to field study at Mount St. Helens; comparative research at other eruption sites; the importance of the Pulse gatherings; and thoughts on the future of the mountain and its surrounding area.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                     <!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->
         <!-- END COLLECTION LEVEL METADATA -->
                        <!-- BEGIN SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS -->
            <dsc type="combined">
               <c01 level="series">
   <did>
                  <unitid>Series 1</unitid>
                  <unittitle>Interviews</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="2015">2015</unitdate>
            		<physdesc>
				<extent label="Extent">7 audio files				</extent>
		</physdesc>
   </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>All interviews were conducted by Samuel Schmieding and collected to audio-only. In addition to the item-level links provided below, the collected contents of this series are <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/omeka/exhibits/show/forestryvoices/collections/" role="text/html">also available online</extref>.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            <c02 level="file">
   <did>
            <unittitle><extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/omeka/exhibits/show/forestryvoices/item/35342" role="text/html">Fred Swanson</extref></unittitle>
                  <unitdate>July 25, 2015</unitdate>
            		<physdesc>
				<extent label="Extent">3:23:26				</extent>
		</physdesc>
   </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Interview conducted at the Swanson residence, Corvallis, Oregon.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
            <unittitle><extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/omeka/exhibits/show/forestryvoices/item/35340" role="text/html">Jerry Franklin</extref></unittitle>
                  <unitdate>July 27, 2015</unitdate>
            		<physdesc>
				<extent label="Extent">2:13:00				</extent>
		</physdesc>
   </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Interview conducted at Mount St. Helens Science Pulse base camp.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
            <unittitle><extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/omeka/exhibits/show/forestryvoices/item/35341" role="text/html">Bob Parmenter</extref></unittitle>
                  <unitdate>July 29, 2015</unitdate>
            		<physdesc>
				<extent label="Extent">1:27:37				</extent>
		</physdesc>
   </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Interview conducted at the Mount St. Helens Volcanic National Monument.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
            <unittitle><extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/omeka/exhibits/show/forestryvoices/item/35338" role="text/html">Virginia Dale</extref></unittitle>
                  <unitdate>July 30, 2015</unitdate>
            		<physdesc>
				<extent label="Extent">1:08:13				</extent>
		</physdesc>
   </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Interview conducted at the Mount St. Helens National Volcanic Monument.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
            <unittitle><extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/omeka/exhibits/show/forestryvoices/item/35336" role="text/html">Lynn Burditt</extref></unittitle>
                  <unitdate>July 31, 2015</unitdate>
            		<physdesc>
				<extent label="Extent">3:01:30				</extent>
		</physdesc>
   </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Interview conducted at the Mount St. Helens National Volcanic Monument.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
            <unittitle><extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/omeka/exhibits/show/forestryvoices/item/35339" role="text/html">Virginia Dale</extref></unittitle>
                  <unitdate>August 12, 2015</unitdate>
            		<physdesc>
				<extent label="Extent">1:23:47				</extent>
		</physdesc>
   </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Interview conducted at the Baltimore Convention Center, Baltimore, Maryland.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
            <unittitle><extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/omeka/exhibits/show/forestryvoices/item/35337" role="text/html">Charlie Crisafulli</extref></unittitle>
                  <unitdate>September 15, 2015</unitdate>
            		<physdesc>
				<extent label="Extent">4:13:09				</extent>
		</physdesc>
   </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Interview conducted in Chelatchie Prairie, Washington.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   
</c01>
   
            </dsc>
               <!-- END SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS -->
   </archdesc>
</ead>

