<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc">
      <eadid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="identifier" mainagencycode="orcs" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv775847" identifier="80444/xv775847">OREwsfpc.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
                  <titlestmt>
               <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the Western Small Fruit Pest Conference Records
                                 <date encodinganalog="date" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1968/1999">1968-1999</date>
                             </titleproper>
               <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Western Small Fruit Pest Conference Records</titleproper>
                                <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding Aid Authors: Elizabeth Nielsen.</author>
                          </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
           <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections and Archives Research Center</publisher>
                           <date encodinganalog="date" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2020">2020</date>

                           <address>
                <addressline>121 The Valley Library</addressline>
                            <addressline>Oregon State University</addressline>
                            <addressline>Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501</addressline>
                            <addressline>Phone: 541-737-2075</addressline>
                              <addressline>Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu</addressline>
                              <addressline>Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids</addressline>
                        </address>
               
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was encoded in EAD by Archon 3.21 from an SQL database source on <date type="encoded" normal="2020-09-24" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">September 24th, 2020</date>. Encoding was modified by Elizabeth Nielsen for Archives West compliance.</creation>
        <langusage>Finding aid written in
          <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.</langusage> <descrules>Finding
              aid based on DACS ( 
              <title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content
                Standard, 2nd Edition</title>).</descrules> 
                        
      </profiledesc>
            <revisiondesc>
        <change encodinganalog="583">
        <date type="encoded" normal="2020-09-24">September 24th, 2020</date>
                <item>This finding aid replaces information about the collection that was placed online in 2012.</item>
                </change>
      </revisiondesc>
      </eadheader>

      <archdesc level="collection" type="guide" relatedencoding="marc21">
        <did>
                      <origination>
                        <corpname role="creator" rules="rda" encodinganalog="111">Western Small Fruit Pest Conference.</corpname>
          </origination>
            
                  <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Western Small Fruit Pest Conference Records</unittitle>
                  <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" normal="1968/1999" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1968-1999</unitdate>
                  <unitdate encodinganalog="245$g" type="bulk" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1968/1973">1968-1973</unitdate>
                  <unitid encodinganalog="099" repositorycode="orcs" countrycode="us">MSS WSFPC</unitid>
                  <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">0.05 cubic feet
            </extent>
                    <extent encodinganalog="300$a">1 box</extent>
          </physdesc>
                  <langmaterial>Materials in <language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
                        <repository encodinganalog="852$b">
                              <corpname>Special Collections and Archives Research Center</corpname>
                              <address>
                     <addressline>121 The Valley Library</addressline>
                                    <addressline>Oregon State University</addressline>
                                       <addressline>Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501</addressline>
                       <addressline>Phone: 541-737-2075</addressline>
                            <addressline>Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu</addressline>
                                         <addressline>Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids</addressline>
                              </address>
            </repository>
                              <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">The Western Small Fruit Pest Conference Records document the establishment and annual meetings of the organization.  The first meeting of the Western Small Fruit Virus Disease Conference was held in Portland, Oregon, in January 1950 for breeders, plant pathologists, and entomologists to report on the detection, identification, and control of small fruit viruses, especially of raspberries and strawberries.</abstract>
                     
      </did>
      <!--COLLECTION LEVEL METADATA: -->
        <bioghist encodinganalog="5451_"><head>Historical Note:</head>
                        <p>The first meeting of the Western Small Fruit Virus Disease Conference was held in Portland, Oregon, in January 1950.  For many years prior to 1950, a number of agriculture-related groups met in Portland each year during the second week of January.  Many of the meetings were related to the control of insects and diseases.  Small fruit crops (specifically strawberries and raspberries) were included in those meetings, but there was not a specific meeting devoted to small fruit diseases.</p>
                        <p>Individuals working specifically on small fruit diseases held an informal gathering in Portland in January 1949 and decided to develop a more formal meeting, with a program, for January 1950 that would include breeders, plant pathologists, and entomologists.  Robert Rosenstiel, a faculty member in the Entomology Department at Oregon State College and specialist on insect pests of small fruits, especially strawberries, was involved in these initial meetings.</p>
                        <p>The conference included scientists from Oregon, Washington, California, and British Columbia; the role of chair rotated between the 3 states and British Columbia.  In the 1950s and 1960s the organization was known as the Western Small Fruit Virus Disease Conference; through the early 1970s, the name Western Small Fruit Disease Conference was used; by the 1990s, it was known as the Western Small Fruit Pest Conference.</p>
                        <p>Richard H. (Dick) Converse was a plant pathologist and small fruit virus specialist with the U.S. Department of Agriculture’s Agricultural Research Service Horticultural Crops Research Laboratory on the Oregon State University campus in Corvallis from the late 1960s until his retirement in 1990.</p>
                    </bioghist>
                        <!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS / SUBJECT TERMS -->
              <controlaccess>
               <controlaccess>
                <persname role="creator" source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="700">Converse, Richard H., 1925-</persname>
                               </controlaccess>
              <controlaccess>
                   <corpname encodinganalog="611" rules="rda" role="subject">Western Small Fruit Pest Conference.</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="611" rules="rda" role="subject">Western Small Fruit Virus Disease Conference.</corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="611" rules="rda" role="subject">Western Small Fruit Disease Conference.</corpname>
                 </controlaccess>
        <controlaccess>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Berries--Diseases and pests.</subject>
                   
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Strawberries--Diseases and pests.</subject>
                 </controlaccess>
                <controlaccess> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Agriculture</subject>
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">British Columbia</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">California</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Oregon</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Portland</subject> 
                  <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Washington (State)</subject> 
                </controlaccess> 
      </controlaccess>
                  <!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS -->
      <!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->
                        <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
                           <p>The materials were received in 1999 by the former University Archives in two donations.  The first donation, which was initially placed in the Memorabilia Collection, was likely received from Richard Converse.  The second transfer was from Peter Bristow of the Washington State University Puyallup Research and Extension Center.</p>
                        </acqinfo>
                        <processinfo encodinganalog="583">
                                    <p>The initial donation of materials pertaining to the Western Small Fruit Pest Conference was placed in the Memorabilia Collection.  These materials were transferred to this collection when a second donation was received several months later.</p>
                              </processinfo>
                           <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
                                          <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
                           </accessrestrict>
                              <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
                     <p>Western Small Fruit Pest Conference Records (MSS WSFPC), Oregon State University Special Collections and Archives Research Center, Corvallis, Oregon.</p>
                  </prefercite>
                              <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="5441_">
                                <p>The Special Collections and Archives Research Center's holdings include numerous collections pertaining to breeding, disease and pest control, harvesting, and processing of small fruits.  Of special note pertaining to stawberries and other berries are the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv21553" role="text/html">Robert G. Rosenstiel Papers (MSS Rosenstiel)</extref> and the records of the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv40994" role="text/html">Botany and Plant Pathology (RG 054),</extref> <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv87562" role="text/html">Entomology (RG 027)</extref>, and <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv64404" role="text/html">Horticulture (RG 187)</extref> Departments.</p>
                                 </relatedmaterial>
                     <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
                                 <p>The Western Small Fruit Pest Conference Records document the establishment and functioning of the organization through materials pertaining to the annual meetings held in 1968-1973 and a history of the organization prepared for the 50<emph render="super">th</emph> annual conference in 1999.  The conference materials include agendas and programs for the 1968-1973 conferences, lists of members, correspondence, notes of presentations, and related documentation.  A  historical summary of the establishment and development of the organization was prepared by Richard H. Converse and Richard Stace-Smith for the 50<emph render="super">th</emph> annual conference in 1999.  This summary describes the establishment of the conference and includes biographical information about the  founders and early leaders of the organization.  A composite image of attendees at the 1999 meeting is also included.   The annual conferences focused on the detection, identification, and control of viruses of raspberries and strawberries.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                     <!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->
         <!-- END COLLECTION LEVEL METADATA -->
                  <!-- END SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS -->
   </archdesc>
</ead>

