<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "ead.dtd">
<ead>
  <eadheader langencoding="iso639-2b" countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924" relatedencoding="dc">
      <eadid countrycode="us" encodinganalog="identifier" mainagencycode="orcs" url="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv87536" identifier="80444/xv87536">OREmorita.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
                  <titlestmt>
               <titleproper encodinganalog="title">Guide to the Richard Y. Morita Papers
                                 <date encodinganalog="date" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="1949/2005">1949-2005</date>
                             </titleproper>
               <titleproper type="filing" altrender="nodisplay">Morita (Richard Y.) Papers</titleproper>
                                <author encodinganalog="creator">Finding Aid Authors: Clare Sobotka and Elizabeth Nielsen.</author>
                          </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
           <publisher encodinganalog="publisher">Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections and Archives Research Center</publisher>
                           <date encodinganalog="date" era="ce" calendar="gregorian" normal="2018">2018</date>

                           <address>
                <addressline>121 The Valley Library</addressline>
                            <addressline>Oregon State University</addressline>
                            <addressline>Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501</addressline>
                            <addressline>Phone: 541-737-2075</addressline>
                              <addressline>Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu</addressline>
                              <addressline>Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids</addressline>
                        </address>
               
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was encoded in EAD by Archon 3.21 from an SQL database source on <date type="encoded" normal="2018-03-07" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">March 7th, 2018</date>. Encoding was modified by Elizabeth Nielsen for Archives West compliance.</creation>
         <langusage>Finding aid written in
            <language langcode="eng" encodinganalog="language" scriptcode="latn">English</language>.</langusage> <descrules>Finding
                  aid based on DACS ( 
                  <title render="italic">Describing Archives: A Content
                     Standard, 2nd Edition</title>).</descrules> 
                         
      </profiledesc>
        </eadheader>

      <archdesc level="collection" type="guide" relatedencoding="marc21">
        <did>
                      <origination>
                        <persname role="creator" source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="100">Morita, R. Y. (Richard Y.)</persname>
          </origination>
            
                  <unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Richard Y. Morita Papers</unittitle>
                  <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" normal="1949/2005" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1949-2005</unitdate>
                  <unitid encodinganalog="099" repositorycode="orcs" countrycode="us">MSS Morita</unitid>
                  <physdesc>
            <extent encodinganalog="300$a">1.60 cubic feet, including 75 photographs</extent>
                     <extent encodinganalog="300$a">3 boxes</extent>    
          </physdesc>
                  <langmaterial>Materials in <language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language>.</langmaterial>
                        <repository encodinganalog="852$b">
                              <corpname>Special Collections and Archives Research Center</corpname>
                              <address>
                     <addressline>121 The Valley Library</addressline>
                                    <addressline>Oregon State University</addressline>
                                       <addressline>Corvallis, OR, 97331-4501</addressline>
                       <addressline>Phone: 541-737-2075</addressline>
                            <addressline>Email: scarc@oregonstate.edu</addressline>
                                         <addressline>Web: http://scarc.library.oregonstate.edu/findingaids</addressline>
                              </address>
            </repository>
                              <abstract encodinganalog="5203_">The Morita Papers document the academic and research career of Richard Yukio Morita, a marine microbiologist who conducted extensive research on the effects of pressure, low temperature, and available energy on the physiology of marine bacteria.  Richard Y. Morita was a faculty member in microbiology and oceanography at Oregon State University from 1962 through 1988 and pursued an active research program as a Professor Emeritus of Microbiology and Oceanography from 1989 through the 2000s.</abstract>
                     
      </did>
      <!--COLLECTION LEVEL METADATA: -->
        <bioghist encodinganalog="5450_"><head>Biographical Note:</head>
                        <p>Richard Y. Morita was a faculty member in microbiology and oceanography at Oregon State University from 1962 through 1988 and pursued an active research program as a Professor Emeritus of Microbiology and Oceanography from 1989 through the early 2000s.</p>
                        <p>Richard Yukio Morita was born on March 27, 1923 in Pasadena, California. He graduated from Pasadena High School in 1941. In 1942 the Morita family was forced to enter an internment camp; they were first sent to Tulare Assembly Center in southern California, and then to the Gila River War Relocation Center in Arizona. Richard Morita left the camp later in 1942 to attend the University of Nebraska, but was drafted into and served in the U. S. Army 442<emph render="super">nd</emph> Regiment Combat Team in 1944-1946. Afterwards, he earned a B.S. in Bacteriology-Chemistry from the University of Nebraska in 1947, an M.S. in Bacteriology from the University of Southern California in 1949, and a Ph. D. in Microbiology-Oceanography from the University of California, Scripps Institution of Oceanography in 1954, where he was the first Nisei (second-generation Japanese American) to graduate. He held several assistant professorships before coming to OSU, where he was an Associate Professor of Microbiology and Oceanography in 1962-1964. In 1964 he became a full Professor at OSU, a post he held until 1988. OSU granted him Professor Emeritus status in 1989. He also served as program director for biochemistry at the National Science Foundation in 1968-1969. Morita married Toshiko Nishihara on March 14, 1953 and they had three children: Sally Jean, Ellen Jane, and Peter Wayne. He was the likely the first Nisei in biological oceanography, and one of the first Nisei with academic rank in microbiology.</p>
                        <p>During his career, Morita was part of several large research expeditions. He was a microbiologist for three of them: the Mid-Pacific Expedition of 1950 (where he was the first microbiologist to study the deep sea), the 1952 Royal Danish Navy <emph render="italic">Galathea</emph> Deep Sea Expedition, and the Trans-Pacific Expedition of 1953. In 1962 he was an invited investigator for Expedition Dodo. Morita studied microbiology in extreme earth environments, including the polar regions and the deep sea. Some of his important contributions to the field include: the discovery of barophiles (pressure loving bacteria) with his mentor Dr. Claude ZoBell; demonstrating that enzyme reactions can occur over 100°C; the discovery of psychrophiles (cold-loving bacteria); the concept of starvation-survival in bacteria; and with Francisco Torrella, the discovery that the marine environment has many phage particles. The genus <emph render="italic">Moritella</emph> was named after him to honor his work in marine microbiology. Several significant awards he received include the Fisher Scientific Company Award from the American Society of Microbiology in 1988; a Queen Elizabeth II Senior Fellowship from the Australian Government, 1973-1974; a King Fredericus IX Medal and Ribbon for participating in the <emph render="italic">Galathea</emph> Expedition; a Japan Society for the Promotion of Science Fellowship 1978, and an honorary membership in the American Society of Microbiology, 1990</p>
                    </bioghist>
                        <!-- CONTROLLED ACCESS / SUBJECT TERMS -->
              <controlaccess>
               <controlaccess>
                <persname role="creator" source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="700">Colwell, Rita R., 1934-</persname>
                                 <persname role="creator" source="lcnaf" encodinganalog="700">ZoBell, Claude E., 1904-1989.</persname>
                  <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Colwell, Rita R., 1934-</persname>
                  <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Morita, R. Y. (Richard Y.)</persname>
                  <persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf" role="subject">ZoBell, Claude E., 1904-1989.</persname>
                               </controlaccess>
              <controlaccess>
                   <corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Oregon State University. Department of Microbiology.</corpname>
                 </controlaccess>
        <controlaccess>
                   <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Photographic prints.</genreform>
                   <genreform encodinganalog="655" source="aat">Photomicrographs.</genreform>
                 </controlaccess>
       
        <controlaccess>
                  
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Marine ecology--Research.</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Marine microbial ecology.</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Microbiology--Research--Oregon.</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Oceanography--Research--Oregon.</subject>
                   
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Psychrophilic bacteria.</subject>
                   <subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Scientific expeditions.</subject>
                  
                 </controlaccess>
                 <controlaccess> 
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Colleges and Universities</subject>
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Japanese Americans</subject> 
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Science</subject> 
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Oregon</subject> 
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Corvallis</subject> 
                    <subject source="archiveswest" altrender="nodisplay" encodinganalog="690">Photographs</subject> 
                 </controlaccess> 
      </controlaccess>
                  <!-- END CONTROLLED ACCESS TERMS -->
      <!-- ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->
                        <acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
                           <p>The bulk of the materials were donated by Richard Morita in 2002; small additions to the collection were received in 2004 and 2009.</p>
                        </acqinfo>
                     <accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
                                          <p>Collection is open for research.</p>
                           </accessrestrict>
                              <prefercite encodinganalog="524">
                     <p>Richard Y. Morita Papers (MSS Morita), Oregon State University Special Collections and Archives Research Center, Corvallis, Oregon.</p>
                  </prefercite>
                              <relatedmaterial encodinganalog="5441_">
                                 <p>A 2010 oral history interview of Morita is part of the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv08966" role="text/html">Voices of Oregon State University Oral History Collection (OH 009)</extref> and additional materials pertaining to Morita are part of the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv87521" role="text/html">Oregon Multicultural Communities Research Collection (MSS OMCRC</extref>).  The Special Collections and Archives Research Center’s holding include several collections documenting microbiology research and teaching at Oregon State including the <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv56095" role="text/html">Microbiology Department Records (RG 191)</extref> and the papers of other microbiology faculty <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv97477" role="text/html">John L. Fryer</extref> and <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="http://archiveswest.orbiscascade.org/ark:/80444/xv36600" role="text/html">Paul R. Elliker</extref>.</p>
                                          <p>The Scripps Institution of Oceanography conducted an extensive oral history interview of Dr. Morita in 2006.  A transcript of the interview is available <extref show="new" actuate="onrequest" href="https://library.ucsd.edu/speccoll/siooralhistories/Morita.pdf" role="text/html">online</extref>.</p>
                                 </relatedmaterial>
                        <arrangement encodinganalog="351">
                                 <p>The Morita Papers are arranged in 5 series: 1. Biographical Information, 1953-2000; 2. Correspondence, 1949-2005; 3. Grant Projects, 1964-1988; 4. Publication Contracts and Financial Records, 1962-1997; and 5. Photographs, 1949-1972.</p>
                        </arrangement>
            <scopecontent encodinganalog="5202_">
                                 <p>The Richard Y. Morita Papers document the academic career and professional activities of Richard Yukio Morita, primarily his research in marine microbiology and marine ecology.  The Papers consist primarily of correspondence and also include biographical information, grant records, publication contracts, and photographs.  The correspondence includes extensive correspondence between Morita and his mentor and graduate advisor at Scripps Institution of Oceanography, Claude E. ZoBell, as well as other collaborators and scientific colleagues.  Correspondence and related materials document Morita’s numerous publications of journal articles, book chapters, and monographs.  Morita participated in some of the first expeditions to study the deep sea in the 1950s and 1960s.  These expeditions and the resulting scientific outcomes are extensively documented in this collection.</p>
                                 <p>Materials documenting Morita’s research on the interaction of pressure and temperature on marine bacteria, microorganisms in extreme environments, and bacteria in oligotrophic (nutrient poor) environments form the bulk of this collection.</p>
                                 <p>The biographical materials include an in-depth autobiographical essay in which Morita describes his childhood in southern California; his internment as a Japanese American during World War II and subsequent military service; and his education and career.  Morita’s numerous awards and recognitions are documented in the collection as well as his roles in the scientific community as a reviewer, consultant, journal editor, and organizer of symposia.</p>
                        </scopecontent>
                     <!-- END ADMINISTRATIVE INFORMATION -->
         <!-- END COLLECTION LEVEL METADATA -->
                        <!-- BEGIN SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS -->
            <dsc type="combined">
               <c01 level="series">
   <did>
                  <unitid>Series 1</unitid>
      <container type="box-folder">1.01</container>
                  <unittitle>Biographical Information</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1953/2000">1953-2000</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Series 1 consists of a complete Curriculum Vitae for Dr. Morita that lists all of the professional positions he held, his publications, honors received, awarded grants, and other aspects of his career; an autobiographical essay written in 1995 and updated in 2000; and a U.S. Government form “Statement of Personal History" completed in 1953. The autobiographical essay is of special note as Morita describes his experiences as a child and youth in southern California; his internment and later military service during World War II; and his education and career.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
   
</c01>
   <c01 level="series">
   <did>
                  <unitid>Series 2</unitid>
                  <unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1949/2005">1949-2005</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Series 2 comprises the bulk of this collection and consists of correspondence sent and received by Morita and associated documents and materials.  The correspondence is arranged by project, publication, or correspondent and documents Morita’s research and publishing, scientific expeditions, and the long-term relationships he developed with his collaborators and colleagues.  The series includes substantial correspondence with Claude E. ZoBell, Morita’s mentor and graduate advisor at Scripps Institution of Oceanography; Rita Colwell at the University of Maryland; and Francisco Torrella.  The ZoBell and Colwell correspondence files also include extensive biographical information about those two scientists.  The general correspondence pertains to publications, patents, and Morita’s research and also includes award nominations and tributes to Morita made at his retirement.  Materials documenting his teaching and service at Oregon State University are also included in the general correspondence.  This series includes 15 photographs, primarily photomicrographs.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.02</container>
      <unittitle>Bacteria in Oligotrophic Environments - General</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1995-1996</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.03</container>
      <unittitle>Bacteria in Oligotrophic Environments - Permission to Reprint</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1996</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.04</container>
      <unittitle>Bacteria in Oligotrophic Environments Project</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1996-1997</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.05</container>
      <unittitle>Biodiversity of Psychrofiles Project</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1999</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.06</container>
      <unittitle>Brochures and Certificates</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1966 - circa 1995</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.07</container>
      <unittitle>Rita Colwell</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1970-1981</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.08</container>
      <unittitle>Rita Colwell</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1979-2001</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.09</container>
      <unittitle>Dodo Research Expedition on the Vessel <emph render="italic">Argo</emph></unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1964-1965</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.10</container>
      <unittitle>Ian Dundas</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1986-1997</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.11</container>
      <unittitle>Encyclopedia of Life Sciences Project</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1997-2001</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.12</container>
      <unittitle>Galathea Deep Sea Expedition</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1951-1985</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.13</container>
      <unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1957-2000</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.14</container>
      <unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1962-1991</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.15</container>
      <unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1967-2001</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.16</container>
      <unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1978-2001</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.17</container>
      <unittitle>General Correspondence</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1968-2001</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.18</container>
      <unittitle>General - Publications of Articles and Book Chapters</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1998-1999</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.19</container>
      <unittitle>Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1951-1981</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.20</container>
      <unittitle>Office of Naval Research</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1984</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Proposal review process controversy.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.21</container>
      <unittitle>Patent for Microbial Methane Production</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1981-1982</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.22</container>
      <unittitle>Patent for Microbial Methane Production</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1981-1993</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.23</container>
      <unittitle>Publications and Clippings</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1991-2005</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.24</container>
      <unittitle>Task Force on the Forward Contamination of Europa: Space Studies Board</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1997-1998</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">1.25</container>
      <unittitle>Task Force on the Forward Contamination of Europa: Space Studies Board</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1997-2000</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">2.01</container>
      <unittitle>Task Force on the Forward Contamination of Europa: Space Studies Board</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1997-2000</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">2.02</container>
      <unittitle>Francisco Torrella</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1988-2001</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Includes 14 photographs of specimens (photomicrographs).</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">2.03</container>
      <unittitle>Francisco Torrella</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1978-1991</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">2.04</container>
      <unittitle>Trans-Pacific Research Expedition</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1953</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">2.05</container>
      <unittitle>U.S. vs. Milstein</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>2000</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Expert witness testimony.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">2.06</container>
      <unittitle>Claude E. ZoBell</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1949-1958</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Includes 1 photograph.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">2.07</container>
      <unittitle>Claude E. ZoBell</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1952-1964</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">2.08</container>
      <unittitle>Claude E. ZoBell</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1965-1997</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">3.01</container>
      <unittitle>Claude E. ZoBell</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1971-1993</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   
</c01>
   <c01 level="series">
   <did>
                  <unitid>Series 3</unitid>
                  <unittitle>Grant Projects</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1964/1988">1964-1988</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Series 3 consists primarily of correspondence between Morita and agencies that funded his research – primarily the National Science Foundation (NSF) and the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA).  The series also includes award notifications and grant accounting information from the Oregon State University Research Accounting Office.  A few grant applications and revised budgets are also part of this series.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">3.2</container>
      <unittitle>Grant Projects</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1967-1988</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">3.3</container>
      <unittitle>Grant Projects</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1964-1980</unitdate>
               </did>
         
</c02>
   
</c01>
   <c01 level="series">
   <did>
                  <unitid>Series 4</unitid>
      <container type="box-folder">3.4</container>
                  <unittitle>Publication Contracts and Financial Records</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1962/1997">1962-1997</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Series 4 consists of publication contracts and agreements, royalty payment statements, and related documentation and correspondence for book chapters and journal articles written by Morita.  The series also includes requests to reproduce illustrations published by Morita.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
   
</c01>
   <c01 level="series">
   <did>
                  <unitid>Series 5</unitid>
                  <unittitle>Photographs</unittitle>
                  <unitdate normal="1949/1972">1949-1972</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Series 5 consist of photographic prints assembled by Morita depicting himself, his scientific colleagues; and research activities at sea and in tropical settings, including Pago Pago.  The series includes 60 photographic prints.  All of the photographs (with the exception of 1 color print) are b/w.  Some of the images are formal portraits and professional photographs; others are informal snapshots.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">3.5</container>
      <unittitle>Research Activities</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>circa 1950s</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Images depicting fieldwork in a tropical setting and a close-up of laboratory set-up on the Mid-Pacific Expedition in 1950 that includes S.C. Rittenberg and Morita; 3 prints.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">3.6</container>
      <unittitle>Morita and others</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1949 - circa 1970</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Includes a 1949 portrait photo of Morita; snapshots and other photos of Morita working in the laboratory; photographs of Morita with groups of colleagues, including Claude E. ZoBell; a portrait photograph of Claude E. ZoBell; and photographs of a research vessel and research being conducted at sea.  22 prints</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">3.7</container>
      <unittitle>Pago Pago</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1952</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Snapshots of Morita and others at sea and in Pago Pago. 28 prints (1 color; 27 b/w).</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   <c02 level="file">
   <did>
      	<container type="box-folder">3.8</container>
      <unittitle>U.S. - Japan Conference at University of Maryland</unittitle>
                  <unitdate>1972</unitdate>
               </did>
         <scopecontent>
                  <p>Morita was the principal organizer and a participant in the 2nd U.S.-Japan Cooperative Conference on Marine Microbiology in College Park, Maryland.   Photographs depict participants at the conference including Morita and scientists from the United States and Japan.  7 prints.</p>
                     </scopecontent>
            
</c02>
   
</c01>
   
            </dsc>
               <!-- END SUBORDINATE COMPONENTS -->
   </archdesc>
</ead>

