<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 ead.xsd" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader audience="internal" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601">
   <eadid mainagencycode="US-txwabtc" countrycode="US" identifier="Baylor University /The Texas Collection/SKCA/40500/20210226101216" encodinganalog="856$u">urn:taro:baylor.tc.10013</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
   <titleproper>A.W. Dunn papers, <date normal="1907/1966" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">Inclusive: 1907-1966; Bulk: 1907-1966</date>
</titleproper>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<date normal="2021-02-26" encodinganalog="260$c" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">February 26, 2021</date>
<publisher>Baylor University, The Texas Collection</publisher>
</publicationstmt>
<notestmt>
<note>
<p>© 2021 The Texas Collection. All rights reserved.</p>
</note>
</notestmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding Aid was generated by The Texas Collection staff, using the STAR Knowledge Center for Archives (SKCA) task that automatically creates EAD files from the Archive's SKCA catalog records.
</creation>
<langusage><language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>


<archdesc level="otherlevel" otherlevel="papers">
<did>
<head>Papers Summary</head>
<repository encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository">
<corpname>Baylor University, <subarea>The Texas Collection</subarea>
</corpname>
<extref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/" xlink:type="simple">http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/</extref>
</repository>
<unitid encodinganalog="099" repositorycode="US-txwabtc" countrycode="US" label="Accession Number">2228</unitid>
<origination label="Creator">
<persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Dunn, Aaron Washington</persname></origination>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245" label="Title">A.W. Dunn papers</unittitle>
<unitdate normal="1907/1966" encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">Inclusive: 1907-1966; Bulk: 1907-1966</unitdate>
<physdesc encodinganalog="300$a">
<extent label="Quantity">1 box.</extent>
</physdesc>
<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract">The A.W. Dunn papers consists of manuscripts relating to Dunn’s pension for service in the Confederate army during the American Civil War.  These papers contain correspondence and pension applications.
</abstract>
<langmaterial encodinganalog="546$a" label="Language of the Material"><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech encodinganalog="340">
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Excellent.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>Aaron Washington Dunn, born in Macon, Georgia, in 1845 April 12, came to Texas with his family in 1854 and settled close to Belton.  With family and friends still in Georgia, Dunn moved back and forth between Georgia and Texas several times.  It seems he enlisted in Company B, 15th Texas
Infantry, under Colonel James Edward Harrison.  The 15th Infantry had originally been the 1st Texas Infantry Battalion under Joseph W. Speight, but was reorganized as a regiment in 1862, when Dunn enlisted.  Though it is not mentioned in the legally binding pension papers, Aaron seems to have
enlisted as a musician.  Dunn served with the 15th Texas for the rest of the war in Indian Territory, Louisiana, and Arkansas as part of Walker’s Texas Division, Trans-Mississippi Department.  His time in the army was marked by many small skirmishes, with probably his only big battle coming in
1864 at Mansfield, Louisiana, as part of the Red River Campaign.  The regiment disbanded on 1865 May 26.  It is said he served also in a Georgia unit during the Civil War, but there is no mention of Georgia service in the pension papers.</p><p>    After Aaron left the army, he went back to his
native Georgia for a time, but soon returned to Texas, this time settling in Coryell County.  In 1871 March 23, A.W. married Caledonia Elizabeth Pruitt Walker Dunn, who was from Coryell County.  During this time Dunn was very involved with Texas Baptist groups and was a trustee of Baylor University
in Independence in 1885.  At the Baptist state convention that year, he offered the resolution for removing Baylor University from Independence and merging Waco and Baylor Universities together to form present-day Baylor University.  Dunn later served on the committee to move Baylor Female College
to Belton, Texas, which became the University of Mary Hardin-Baylor.  Aaron and Caledonia were also major financial contributors to Texas Baptist programs in the late 1800s.  Aaron’s first wife Caledonia died in 1899.</p><p>    In 1901, Aaron married Margaret “Maggie” Bishop Dunn.  Dunn had
moved to West Texas in 1880, founding Colorado City, and was involved in mercantile, banking, and ranching activities in the area.  At the age of eighty-seven, Aaron Washington Dunn died in 1933 January 28.  Maggie lived on, close to her son who lived in Odessa, until 1966 July 31.  Maggie received
a pension for her husband’s service in the Civil War until her death, as documented in this collection</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520$b">
   <head>Scope and Content</head>
   <p>The A.W. Dunn papers begin in 1907 and end in 1966.  Records include correspondence and literary productions, though most of the manuscripts are pension papers from Dunn’s service in the American Civil War.  A.W. Dunn was a trustee of Baylor University in Independence, Texas, and also
served on the committee to move Baylor Female College to Belton, Texas.  All documents are copies.</p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>This small collection of Civil War-related pension information about  Aaron Dunn provides an example of the many families who benefited from  state-provided pensions for service in the American Civil War.  In the  late 1800s, Dunn donated much of his wealth to Baptist causes in Texas,  and
served on various boards overseeing Baylor University’s move from  Independence to Waco, and from Independence to Belton.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement encodinganalog="351">
<head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The A.W. Dunn papers are arranged in 2 series:  I. Correspondence and II. Literary Productions.</p>
</arrangement>
<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
<head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing.  Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on
use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially
exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
<head>Use/Re-use Restrictions</head>
<p>The collection is open for research.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
<head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>A.W. Dunn papers, Accession #2228, Box #, Folder #, The Texas Collection, Baylor University.</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession No. 2228. Acquired 1981-03-00</p>
</acqinfo>
<processinfo encodinganalog="583">
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Described by Paul T. Fisher. Released on 2013-06-17.</p>
</processinfo>
<descgrp>
<head>Related Resources</head>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544">
<head>Related references</head>
<bibref> Aaron W. Dunn, Founder of Colorado, Death Victim.” Sweetwater Daily Reporter, 1933 February 3.</bibref>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://www.tshaonline.org/handbook/online/articles/fhaac" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Cutrer, Thomas. “Harrison, James Edward.” Handbook of Texas Online. Accessed 2011 August 15.</extref>
</bibref>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://baylor.primo.exlibrisgroup.com/permalink/01BUL_INST/1idb1qn/alma991013414089705576" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Murray, Lois Smith. Baylor at Independence. Waco, Texas: Baylor University Press, 1972.</extref>
</bibref>
<bibref> The American Civil War Research Database. “Soldier Data:  Aaron W. Dunn." Alexander Street Press, LLC. Accessed 2011 August 15.</bibref>
</relatedmaterial>
</descgrp>
</descgrp>
<controlaccess>
<head>Index Terms</head>
<controlaccess>
<head>Subjects (Organizations)</head>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Baylor University  -- History.</corpname>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Places</head>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Texas -- Genealogy.</geogname>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Texas -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</geogname>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf" role="subject">United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</geogname>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Subjects</head>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Military pensions -- United States -- Civil War, 1861-1865.</subject>
</controlaccess>
</controlaccess>
<dsc type="combined">

<c01 id="recAWDUNN.level1.000001030" level="series">
<did>
<unitid>1</unitid>
<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1917-1966</unitdate>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech>
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Unknown.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>Series includes correspondence to and from Texas state officials about the pension applications.  All papers in this series are photocopies.  The series is in excellent condition.</p>
</bioghist>
<processinfo encodinganalog="583">
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Released on 2013-06-17.</p>
</processinfo>
</descgrp>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Letters</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1917/1966" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1917-1966</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 id="recAWDUNN.level1.000001031" level="series">
<did>
<unitid>2</unitid>
<unittitle>LIterary Productions</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1907-1933</unitdate>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech>
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Unknown.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>This series contains copies of pension applications for A.W. Dunn. This series is in excellent condition.</p>
</bioghist>
<processinfo encodinganalog="583">
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Released on 2013-06-17.</p>
</processinfo>
</descgrp>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Pension Application:  Veteran’s Application</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1907" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1907</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Pension Application:  Widow’s Application</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1933" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1933</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>

