<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 ead.xsd" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader audience="internal" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601">
   <eadid mainagencycode="US-txwabtc" countrycode="US" identifier="Baylor University /The Texas Collection/SKCA/40500/20210301075035" encodinganalog="856$u">urn:taro:baylor.tc.10089</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
   <titleproper>BU Records: Baylor Cadets, <date normal="1886/1902" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">Inclusive: 1886-1902, undated, Bulk: 1894-1896</date>
</titleproper>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<date normal="2021-03-01" encodinganalog="260$c" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">March 1, 2021</date>
<publisher>Baylor University, The Texas Collection</publisher>
</publicationstmt>
<notestmt>
<note>
<p>© 2021 The Texas Collection. All rights reserved.</p>
</note>
</notestmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding Aid was generated by The Texas Collection staff, using the STAR Knowledge Center for Archives (SKCA) task that automatically creates EAD files from the Archive's SKCA catalog records.
</creation>
<langusage><language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>


<archdesc level="otherlevel" otherlevel="records">
<did>
<head>Records Summary</head>
<repository encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository">
<corpname>Baylor University, <subarea>The Texas Collection</subarea>
</corpname>
<extref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/" xlink:type="simple">http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/</extref>
</repository>
<unitid encodinganalog="099" repositorycode="US-txwabtc" countrycode="US" label="Accession Number">BU/21</unitid>
<origination label="Creator">
<corpname encodinganalog="110" source="lcnaf">Baylor Cadets</corpname></origination>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245" label="Title">BU Records: Baylor Cadets</unittitle>
<unitdate normal="1886/1902" encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">Inclusive: 1886-1902, undated, Bulk: 1894-1896</unitdate>
<physdesc encodinganalog="300$a">
<extent label="Quantity">7 folders.</extent>
</physdesc>
<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract">BU Records: Baylor Cadets consist of correspondence, legal documents, and literary productions produced in connection with the Baylor Cadets, a university-sponsored military preparation program.
</abstract>
<langmaterial encodinganalog="546$a" label="Language of the Material"><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech encodinganalog="340">
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Poor.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>Baylor University students have been active in Texas military forces going back to the American Civil War in 1861-1865. The Baylor Cadets were an on-campus military organization that carried on this tradition from 1888 until 1904, preparing Baylor students for possible duty with the armed
forces.</p><p>The Baylor Cadets were formed in 1888 as a military company under the command of Albert Boggess, a mathematics professor at the time. Boggess, a graduate of Virginia Military Institute and veteran of the Civil War Battle of New Market in 1864, moved to Texas in 1866. He succeeded in
getting the student-soldiers navy-blue uniforms and an adequate amount of the gear necessary for an infantry company. It seems there were never enough firearms and ammunition to outfit the cadets; several manuscripts in this collection mention obtaining more of both. At some point the Baylor Cadets
became a department of Baylor University. Professor Albert Boggess, commander of the cadets, died in 1891.</p><p>From 1891 until 1893, the cadets ran their own military training program, probably under the supervision of faculty members. The collection contains a minute book detailing the cadets'
administration of their own department from 1888 until 1893. </p><p>In1893 December, Lieutenant Beaumont Bonaparte Buck arrived to command the cadets at the request of the Baylor Board of Trustees. Lieutenant Buck completely reorganized the department, issued new Springfield rifles to the cadets,
and added two cannons and signaling equipment. He also designed a new blue uniform for the cadets modeled on the Texas Volunteer Guard. The Baylor Cadets were now able to field two infantry companies, one artillery battery, and one signal unit. </p><p>In 1894,Baylor University began requiring all
male Baylor University students to serve in the cadet corps for three years. The Military Department, under Lieutenant Buck, was tasked with developing "manliness, courtesy, accuracy, promptness, and devotion to duty," as well as physical fitness, in the young men of the Baylor Cadets. To accomplish
this, the department conducted regular drills and offered lectures on a variety of military topics. Lieutenant Buck also hosted prize contests for the best drilled company, the best drilled squad, the best drilled cadet, and a rifle-shooting contest. The collection contains a drill and regulation
book from 1894, when Lieutenant Buck commanded the Baylor Cadets.</p><p>Lieutenant Buck served as commandant of cadets for only two years, but his reforms and establishment of professional standards for the department lasted for years. Beaumont Buck later became a major general in the United States
army and received many awards in World War I. He resigned in 1895 because of health reasons, and was replaced by Lieutenant Jonas A. Emery. </p><p>Lieutenant Emery made several changes to the Baylor Cadets. Because of all the new cadets, now that Baylor required military service from all male
students, the number of infantry companies was increased from two to ten. The uniform was also changed from blue to cadet grey, new flags were ordered for the signal corps, a military band was formed which eventually became the Golden Wave Marching Band, and the Baylor Cadets began to occasionally
hold "sham battles" on campus.</p><p>In 1898 Lieutenant Emery was recalled to active service for the Spanish-American War, and the cadets ran their own department for the next three years. Apparently the department was run well in the absence of a formal commander. New commander Major Edward G.
Mathey took command in 1901 as the last commander of the Baylor Cadets.</p><p>Major Mathey at the time of his appointment to command the Baylor cadets was a retired United States military officer. He had served in many campaigns against the American Indians, including the Little Bighorn Campaign in
1876 and the Nez Perce Campaign of 1877. When Major Mathey arrived at Baylor, he organized the 159 men into three infantry companies and an artillery battery. Regular drill was continued in the area around Burleson Hall until 1902, when they began to drill in the athletic field on campus. Apparently
requiring male students to serve in the Baylor Cadets had been discontinued at some point, but Major Mathey succeeded in requiring male students to serve for one year in the Baylor Cadets. </p><p>In 1902, the band and the cadets parted ways, with the band becoming a stand-alone program at the
university. The coming of football as an alternative physical exercise to military drill as a cadet irritated Major Mathey enough to claim "football has no more relation to physical culture than a bull fight to agriculture." Major Mathey resigned in 1903, probably to retire permanently. </p><p>In
1904, the Baylor trustees decided to end the Baylor Cadets program. A regular army officer could not be supplied to command the cadets, and students seemed to be losing interest in the program. Another reason was supplied by the Baylor <emph render="italic">Lariat</emph> publication, that many thought the most athletic men
should be helping Baylor in athletics, not military exercises. Whatever reasons were involved for ending the program, the Baylor Cadets organization had trained a generation of young men in the art of war, and this training was put to use by many Baylor men who fought in the Spanish-American War and
World War I.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520$b">
   <head>Scope and Content</head>
   <p>BU Records: Baylor Cadets begins in 1886 and ends in 1902, with some undated materials. Notable manuscripts include a minute book from the Baylor Cadet Club, a typed history of the Baylor Cadets, and the book<emph render="underline"> </emph><emph render="italic">Rules and Regulations Governing the Department of Military Science and Tactics in</emph>
<emph render="italic">Baylor University at Waco, Texas.</emph></p>
   <p>There are photographs associated with this collection in the general Photograph Files of The Texas Collection.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement encodinganalog="351">
<head>Arrangement</head>
<p>BU Records: Baylor Cadets was not organized prior to this finding aid. There was no inventory, past finding aid, or other supporting documentation available at the time this finding aid was written.</p>
   <p>Currently, BU Records: Baylor Cadets is arranged in three series: I. Correspondence, II. Legal Documents, and III. Literary Productions.</p>
</arrangement>
<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
<head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing.  Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on
use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially
exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
<head>Use/Re-use Restrictions</head>
<p>The collection is open for research.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
<head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>BU Records: Baylor Cadets, Accession #BU/21, Box #, Folder #, The Texas Collection, Baylor University.</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession No. BU/21. Acquired 1970-06-10</p>
</acqinfo>
<processinfo encodinganalog="583">
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Described by Paul Fisher. Released on 2012-09-27.</p>
</processinfo>
<descgrp>
<head>Related Resources</head>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544">
<head>Related references</head>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://www.baylor.edu/gwb/index.php?id=868908" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Baylor Golden Wave Band. "Our History." Accessed 2020 April 20.</extref>
</bibref>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://www.tshaonline.org/handbook/online/articles/fbu04" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> "Buck, Beaumont Bonaparte." Handbook of Texas Online. Accessed 2012 September 14.</extref>
</bibref>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://files.usgwarchives.net/in/greene/vitals/obits/jaemery.txt" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Burns, Judi. "Obituary of Major Jonas Aden Emery 1856-1915." Accessed 2012 September 14.</extref>
</bibref>
<bibref> Hatch, Thom. The Custer Companion: A Comprehensive Guide to the Life of George Armstrong Custer and the Plains Indians Wars. Mechanicsburg, Pennsylvania: Stackpole Books, 2005.</bibref>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://www.jstor.org/stable/30240723" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Jeffries, C.C. "Sketches of Old Baylor." The Southwestern Historical Quarterly 56, 4 (1953 April): 498-506. Accessed 2012 September 14.</extref>
</bibref>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://baylor.primo.exlibrisgroup.com/permalink/01BUL_INST/2cm1pj/alma991012313089705576" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Senior Class of Baylor University. The Round-Up. Waco, Texas: 1896.</extref>
</bibref>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://baylor.primo.exlibrisgroup.com/permalink/01BUL_INST/2cm1pj/alma991012313089705576" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Senior Class of Baylor University. The Round-Up. Waco, Texas: 1902.</extref>
</bibref>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://baylor.primo.exlibrisgroup.com/permalink/01BUL_INST/2cm1pj/alma991012313089705576" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Senior Class of Baylor University. The Round-Up. Waco, Texas: 1903.</extref>
</bibref>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://baylor.primo.exlibrisgroup.com/permalink/01BUL_INST/2cm1pj/alma991013506299705576" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Watson, Bert Allan. "Baylor University: A Military History." M.A., Baylor University, 1968.</extref>
</bibref>
</relatedmaterial>
</descgrp>
</descgrp>
<controlaccess>
<head>Index Terms</head>
<controlaccess>
<head>Subjects (Organizations)</head>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Baylor University  -- History.</corpname>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Baylor University -- History, Military.</corpname>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Baylor University.  Military Dept.</corpname>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Places</head>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Waco (Tex.) -- History -- 20th Century.</geogname>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Waco (Tex.) -- History.</geogname>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Genres</head>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Correspondence.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Essays.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Membership lists.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Minutes (Records)</genreform>
</controlaccess>
</controlaccess>
<dsc type="combined">

<c01 id="recBUCADETS.level2.000000129" level="series">
<did>
<unitid>1</unitid>
<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1895-1896, undated</unitdate>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech>
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Average.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>This series contains several correspondence documents from the Baylor Cadets.  One manuscript refers to their part in an 1895 carnival, and another is an invitation from the cadets to the first concert and reception by the Baylor Military Band, which eventually became the Golden Wave Marching
Band.  Also of note is the petition sent to the Baylor faculty asking for the Baylor Cadets to become an official university organization.</p>
</bioghist>
<processinfo encodinganalog="583">
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Released on 2013-06-17.</p>
</processinfo>
</descgrp>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Correspondence</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1895/1896" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1895-1896, undated</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Concert Invitation and Photograph</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1895/1896" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">circa 1895-1896</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 id="recBUCADETS.level2.000000130" level="series">
<did>
<unitid>2</unitid>
<unittitle>Legal Documents</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1886-1896, undated</unitdate>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech>
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Poor.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>This series contains loose minutes and a minute book from the Baylor Cadets organization.  These minutes provide information about the cadets from when they were first organized to the end of Lieutenant Emery's time as commandant of the cadets at Baylor University.</p>
</bioghist>
<processinfo encodinganalog="583">
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Released on 2013-06-17.</p>
</processinfo>
</descgrp>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Minutes</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1886/1896" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1886-1896, undated</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Minute Book</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1888/1893" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1888-1893</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>

<c01 id="recBUCADETS.level2.000000131" level="series">
<did>
<unitid>3</unitid>
<unittitle>Literary Productions</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1894-1902, undated</unitdate>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech>
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Poor.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>This series contains several literary documents on the Baylor Cadets. Included are a roll book of men who served as Baylor Cadets, an unpublished and untitled document on the history of the Baylor Cadets, and the handbook <emph render="italic">Rules and Regulations Governing the Department of Military Science and</emph>
<emph render="italic">Tactics in Baylor University, Waco, Texas.</emph></p>
</bioghist>
<processinfo encodinganalog="583">
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Released on 2013-06-17.</p>
</processinfo>
</descgrp>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">[History of the Baylor Cadets]</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">undated</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>Books: Department of Military Science and Tactics in Baylor University</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1894" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1894</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>Books: Cadet Roll</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1901/1902" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1901-1902</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>

