<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 ead.xsd" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader audience="internal" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601">
   <eadid mainagencycode="US-txwabtc" countrycode="US" identifier="Baylor University /The Texas Collection/SKCA/40500/20210301075023" encodinganalog="856$u">urn:taro:baylor.tc.10087</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
   <titleproper>Bolt Family Homestead and Legion Valley Indian Massacre collection, <date normal="1985/1985" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">Inclusive: 1985</date>
</titleproper>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<date normal="2021-03-01" encodinganalog="260$c" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">March 1, 2021</date>
<publisher>Baylor University, The Texas Collection</publisher>
</publicationstmt>
<notestmt>
<note>
<p>© 2021 The Texas Collection. All rights reserved.</p>
</note>
</notestmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding Aid was generated by The Texas Collection staff, using the STAR Knowledge Center for Archives (SKCA) task that automatically creates EAD files from the Archive's SKCA catalog records.
</creation>
<langusage><language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>


<archdesc level="collection">
<did>
<head>Collection Summary</head>
<repository encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository">
<corpname>Baylor University, <subarea>The Texas Collection</subarea>
</corpname>
<extref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/" xlink:type="simple">http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/</extref>
</repository>
<unitid encodinganalog="099" repositorycode="US-txwabtc" countrycode="US" label="Accession Number">3817</unitid>
<origination label="Creator">
<persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Herring, B.</persname></origination>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245" label="Title">Bolt Family Homestead and Legion Valley Indian Massacre collection</unittitle>
<unitdate normal="1985/1985" encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">Inclusive: 1985</unitdate>
<physdesc encodinganalog="300$a">
<extent label="Quantity">1 document box.</extent>
</physdesc>
<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract">The Bolt Family Homestead and Legion Valley Indian Massacre collection contains a scrapbook about an 1868 Indian raid on several families in Llano County, Texas.
</abstract>
<langmaterial encodinganalog="546$a" label="Language of the Material"><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech encodinganalog="340">
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Good.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>The Legion Valley Massacre was one of many violent events in the history of Texan-Indian relations. The scrapbook in this collection describes the homestead of one family in Llano County, Texas, and the violent confrontation between Comanche Indians and some Euro-Americans living in the
area.</p><p>With the American Civil War ending in 1865, Euro-Americans were moving West again, onto lands already controlled by American Indian tribes. Llano County, Texas, west of Austin, had just become a county in 1856, and people were still moving there in search of land for farms and ranches.
In south Llano County, several related families settled at the confluence of the Sandy and Legion Creeks. These families included the Friends and two related Johnson families, who were all involved in the 1868 massacre.</p><p>On 1868 February 5, the three men from these three families left to get
supplies from the nearby town of Fredricksburg. That left their three wives, Matilda Jones Friend, Elizabeth "Betsy" Townsend Johnson Bradford, and Samantha Johnson, as well as their infant children Nancy Elizabeth Johnson and Fielty Johnson. Lee Temple Friend, eight years old, son of Matilda Jones
Friend and the only male of the group, was present as well. Also staying with the group at this time were 18-year-old Amanda Townsend, cousin of the Johnsons, and 11-year-old Malinda Caudel, also a relative of the families.</p><p>At the end of the day, with the children playing in the yard, a group
of Indians rode in and began to steal horses at some distance from the house. Hearing the screams of the women and children, the Indians charged the house, taking everyone prisoner except for Matilda Jones Friend, whom they shot three times, scalped twice, and left for dead. Incredibly, Matilda
walked a mile and half to the nearest help with two or three arrows still in her. She recovered and lived near Marble Falls, Texas, until 1909.</p><p>Only Malinda Caudle and Lee Temple Friend of the captured women and children survived. The children were brutally killed and the women were sexually
assaulted and killed. Their bodies were found one by one by a group of men who set out to rescue them, but were too late. Malinda and Lee were reunited with what remained of their families several years after their capture, though Lee died shortly after coming into Anglo-American society.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520$b">
   <head>Scope and Content</head>
   <p>The Bolt Family Homestead and Legion Valley Indian Massacre collection begins and ends in 1985. Though all of the photographs, manuscripts, maps, and genealogical information dates from 1985, it all describes the people involved in the Legion Valley Indian Massacre Collection of 1868.</p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>This collection documents the Legion Valley Indian Massacre and the Bolt  Family homestead. It is not clear what relationship the Bolts had with  the Legion Valley incident. A large part of the scrapbook also traces  the history of the Johnson family, which was involved in the Legion  River
event.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement encodinganalog="351">
<head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The Bolt Family Homestead and Legion Valley Indian Massacre collection were organized in one scrapbook at the time of purchase by The Texas Collection. All materials were kept in their original order for this finding aid.</p>
   <p>Currently, the Bolt Family Homestead and Legion Valley Indian Massacre collection is arranged in one series: I. Scrapbook Materials.</p>
</arrangement>
<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
<head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing.  Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on
use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially
exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
<head>Use/Re-use Restrictions</head>
<p>The collection is open for research.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
<head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Bolt Family Homestead and Legion Valley Indian Massacre collection, Accession #3817, Box #, Folder #, The Texas Collection, Baylor University.</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession No. 3817. Acquired 2012-09-05</p>
</acqinfo>
<processinfo encodinganalog="583">
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Described by Paul Fisher. Released on 2012-09-27.</p>
</processinfo>
<descgrp>
<head>Related Resources</head>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544">
<head>Related references</head>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://www.tshaonline.org/handbook/online/articles/btlkt" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Reeves, Johnie Lee. "Legion Valley Massacre." Handbook of Texas Online. Accessed 2012 September 6.</extref>
</bibref>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://www.llanonews.com/news/47074/" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Russell, Karylon Hallmark. "History: Spirits Crying Out In The Wilderness." Llano News, 2011 October 26. Accessed 2012 September 6.</extref>
</bibref>
</relatedmaterial>
</descgrp>
</descgrp>
<controlaccess>
<head>Index Terms</head>
<controlaccess>
<head>Places</head>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Legion Valley Massacre (Llano County, Tex.), 1868.</geogname>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Legion Valley, Massacre, Tex., 1866.</geogname>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Subjects</head>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Frontier and pioneer life -- Texas.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">Indians of North America -- Wars -- Texas -- Llano County.</subject>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Genres</head>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Scrapbooks.</genreform>
</controlaccess>
</controlaccess>
<dsc type="combined">

<c01 id="recLVM.level2.000000122" level="series">
<did>
<unitid>1</unitid>
<unittitle>Scrapbook Materials</unittitle>
<unitdate normal="1985" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1985</unitdate>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech>
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Good.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>This small series contains a scrapbook and several loose pages that were at the back of the scrapbook.  The scrapbook contains information on the Bolt Family Homestead, the Johnson Family, and the Legion Valley Indian Massacre.</p>
</bioghist>
<processinfo encodinganalog="583">
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Released on 2013-06-17.</p>
</processinfo>
</descgrp>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Scrapbook</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1985" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1985</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Loose Materials</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1985" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1985</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>

