<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 ead.xsd" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader audience="internal" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601">
   <eadid mainagencycode="US-txwabtc" countrycode="US" identifier="Baylor University /The Texas Collection/SKCA/40500/20210318130730" encodinganalog="856$u">urn:taro:baylor.tc.10380</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
   <titleproper>Joe Lett Ward, Jr. papers, <date normal="1953/1972" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">Inclusive: 1953-1972, undated; Bulk: 1953-1954, 1963-1972</date>
</titleproper>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<date normal="2021-03-18" encodinganalog="260$c" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">March 18, 2021</date>
<publisher>Baylor University, The Texas Collection</publisher>
</publicationstmt>
<notestmt>
<note>
<p>© 2021 The Texas Collection. All rights reserved.</p>
</note>
</notestmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding Aid was generated by The Texas Collection staff, using the STAR Knowledge Center for Archives (SKCA) task that automatically creates EAD files from the Archive's SKCA catalog records.
</creation>
<langusage><language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>


<archdesc level="otherlevel" otherlevel="papers">
<did>
<head>Papers Summary</head>
<repository encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository">
<corpname>Baylor University, <subarea>The Texas Collection</subarea>
</corpname>
<extref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/" xlink:type="simple">http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/</extref>
</repository>
<unitid encodinganalog="099" repositorycode="US-txwabtc" countrycode="US" label="Accession Number">4029</unitid>
<origination label="Creator">
<persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Ward, Jr., Joe Lett, 1916 - 2009</persname></origination>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245" label="Title">Joe Lett Ward, Jr. papers</unittitle>
<unitdate normal="1953/1972" encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">Inclusive: 1953-1972, undated; Bulk: 1953-1954, 1963-1972</unitdate>
<physdesc encodinganalog="300$a">
<extent label="Quantity">10 folders.</extent>
</physdesc>
<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract">This collection contains various materials Joe Lett Ward, Jr. collected as a member of civic organizations in Waco from the 1950s to the 1970s.
</abstract>
<langmaterial encodinganalog="546$a" label="Language of the Material"><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech encodinganalog="340">
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Good.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>Joe Lett Ward, Jr. was born in Waco, Texas, on 1916 November 30.  Joe, Jr., the son of Joe Ward and Camille Webb, was a fifth generation Wacoan.  He graduated from Waco High School in 1933 and later earned a degree in Mechanical Engineering from the University of Texas in 1937. Following his
graduation on 1937 October 25 Joe married his high school sweetheart, Martha Harrison.</p><p> </p><p>Ward worked as a petroleum engineer for seven years but returned to Waco after his father passed away. He assumed control of his father's business, the Joe L. Ward Company, and ran the company until
he sold it in 1989. Alongside his business endeavors, Ward was involved in civic organizations throughout the Waco community.  He was a co-founder of the Ridgewood Country Club in 1946.  Ward and his wife Martha were one of fifteen couples to start the St. Alban’s Episcopal Church.  He also
served on numerous boards including those of the Waco Industrial Foundation, the Waco Business League, and the Citizens National Bank.  After serving four years as a member of the Waco city council, his fellow council members appointed him the Mayor of Waco from 1959 to 1960.</p><p> </p><p>As
reflected by the materials in this collection, Ward was also an active participant in the civil rights movement in Waco.  The city boasted a relatively peaceful integration of its schools and businesses thanks in large part to a nine-man committee chaired by Ward.  Operating alongside the
Progressive Community Council headed by Reverend Marvin Griffin, these local leaders subtly introduced integration to the community.</p><p> </p><p>Ward passed away on 2009 October 29 at the age of ninety-two.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520$b">
   <head>Scope and Content</head>
   <p>The Joe Lett Ward, Jr. papers provide a snapshot of Ward’s community involvement in Waco, Texas.  These materials range in chronology from 1953 to 1972 with some undated materials. The documents are in good condition.</p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>The collection is composed of a single series, I. Civic Organizations.  The first three folders contain materials related to Ward’s membership in the Waco Association for Good Government.  The organization was concerned primarily with local taxes, school programs, and political involvement.
 Largely falling within a two year time-frame (1953-1954), these materials consist of the organization’s constitution, clippings, correspondence, and rosters.</p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>The next three folders deal with the Community Relations Committee and its predecessor, a subcommittee operating under the Committee of Fifty.  Initially, this nine-man committee worked in cooperation with the Progressive Community Council --  which was comprised of prominent African American
leaders -- to integrate Waco’s schools, businesses, and work force. The collection contains correspondence, reports, and minutes from the Community Relations Committee.</p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>The final four folders in the collection stem from Ward’s work with the Human Relations Commission.  The commission was formed in 1969 July to handle any human rights infringements in Waco, particularly those dealing with race.  It was intended to act as a liaison between the community and
the city government.  These materials include correspondence, reports, minutes, and procedures.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement encodinganalog="351">
<head>Arrangement</head>
<p>Prior to the latest round of processing, the materials in this collection were housed in three acidic folders.  The documents were organized by the committee that produced them. The original titles have been maintained with one exception.  The "Inter-Racial Committee," which was initially a
subcommittee of the Committee of Fifty, transitioned into the Waco Community Relations Committee under the auspices of the Chamber of Commerce.  These materials are now housed in folders labelled "Community Relations Committee."</p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>The original order of the collection has been maintained, although some of the folders were over-stuffed and had to be broken down further according to material type.  The collection is currently arranged in a single series, I. Civic Organizations.</p>
</arrangement>
<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
<head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing.  Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on
use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially
exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
<head>Use/Re-use Restrictions</head>
<p>The collection is open for research.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
<head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Joe Lett Ward, Jr. papers, Accession #4029, Box #, Folder #, The Texas Collection, Baylor University.</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession No. 4029. Acquired 1988-07-11</p>
</acqinfo>
<processinfo encodinganalog="583">
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Described by Thomas DeShong. Released on 2017-09-08.</p>
<p>Archivist''s Notes: Box # [251], Folder #10 contains a 1963 report produced by the Community Relations Committee.  This report recounts, at great length, the history of a subcommittee which helped to integrate Waco's schools and businesses.  Prominent Waco leaders, including Joe L. Ward, Jr.,
Abner McCall, Jack Kultgen, and Harry Provence, worked in conjunction with an African American committee, the Progressive Community Council led by Reverend Marvin Griffin.</p>
</processinfo>
<descgrp>
<head>Related Resources</head>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544">
<head>Related collection materials</head>
<archref>Box 65, Folder 12 of the Marvin C. Griffin Papers (#3837) has similar materials from the Progressive Community Council.</archref>
</relatedmaterial>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544">
<head>Related references</head>
<bibref> “A True Leader: Remembering Former Mayor Joe L. Ward Jr., Who Changed Life in Waco for the Better.” Waco-Tribune Herald, 2009 November 5. Joe L. Ward, Jr.: Clippings [vertical file]. The Texas Collection, Baylor University.</bibref>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://digitalcollections.baylor.edu/cdm/ref/collection/buioh/id/6513" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Interview of Joe L. Ward, Jr. by Colbert Held. Waco and McLennan County Project, 2006 June 23. Transcript, Baylor University Institute for Oral
History, Waco, Texas.</extref>
</bibref>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://baylor.primo.exlibrisgroup.com/permalink/01BUL_INST/1idb1qn/alma991023724729705576" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Joe L. Ward, Jr.: Clippings [vertical file]. The Texas Collection, Baylor University.</extref>
</bibref>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="http://www.tributes.com/show/Joe-L.-Ward-87058637" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Joe L. Ward, Jr. obituary. Wilkirson-Hatch-Bailey Funeral Homes. Accessed 2017 August 9.</extref>
</bibref>
</relatedmaterial>
</descgrp>
</descgrp>
<controlaccess>
<head>Index Terms</head>
<controlaccess>
<head>Subjects (Persons)</head>
<persname encodinganalog="600" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Ward, Joe Lett, Jr., 1916-2009 -- Archives.</persname>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Subjects (Organizations)</head>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Association for Good Government (Waco, Tex.) -- Records and correspondence.</corpname>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Community Relations Committee (Waco, Tex.) -- Records and correspondence.</corpname>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Human Relations Commission (Waco, Tex.) -- Records and correspondence.</corpname>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Places</head>
<geogname encodinganalog="651" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Waco (Tex.) -- Race Relations.</geogname>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Subjects</head>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">School integration -- Citizen participation.</subject>
<subject encodinganalog="650" source="lcsh">School integration -- Texas -- Waco.</subject>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Genres</head>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Minutes (Records)</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Reports.</genreform>
</controlaccess>
</controlaccess>
<dsc type="combined">

<c01 id="recJLWARD.level1.000003672" level="series">
<did>
<unitid>1</unitid>
<unittitle>Civic Organizations</unittitle>
<unitdate normal="1953/1972" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1953-1972, undated</unitdate>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech>
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Good.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>Series I. Civic Organizations, the only series in the Joe Lett Ward, Jr. papers, contains materials from three different Waco civic organizations: the Waco Association for Good Government, the Community Relations Committee, and the Human Relations Commission.  The materials -- largely
correspondence, minutes, and reports -- are products of Ward's membership in these organizations.  Overall, the materials are in good condition.</p>
</bioghist>
<processinfo encodinganalog="583">
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Released on 2017-09-08.</p>
</processinfo>
</descgrp>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Waco Association for Good Government: Address, Constitution, and Clippings</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953/1954" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1953-1954, undated</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Waco Association for Good Government: Correspondence</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953/1954" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1953-1954, undated</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Waco Association for Good Government: Rosters and Telephone Reports</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953/1954" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1953-1954</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Community Relations Committee: Clippings and Notes</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1963, undated</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">5</container>
<unittitle>Community Relations Committee: Correspondence, Memoranda, and Attachments</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963/1970" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1963-1970</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">6</container>
<unittitle>Community Relations Committee: Minutes, Reports, and Printed Materials</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963/1964" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1963-1964, undated</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">7</container>
<unittitle>Human Relations Commission: Correspondence, Memoranda, and Attachments</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970/1972" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1970-1972</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">8</container>
<unittitle>Human Relations Commission: Minutes</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969/1970" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1969 September-1970 May</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">9</container>
<unittitle>Human Relations Commission: Minutes</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1970/1972" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1970 June-1972 May</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">10</container>
<unittitle>Human Relations Commission: Procedures, Reports, and Rosters</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1969/1972" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1969-1972</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>

