<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 ead.xsd" relatedencoding="MARC21">
<eadheader audience="internal" repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" langencoding="iso639-2b" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601">
   <eadid mainagencycode="US-txwabtc" countrycode="US" identifier="Baylor University /The Texas Collection/SKCA/40500/20210806081551" encodinganalog="856$u">urn:taro:baylor.tc.10646</eadid>
<filedesc>
<titlestmt>
   <titleproper>Horace Clark papers, <date normal="1862/1909" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">Inclusive: 1862-1909, undated</date>
</titleproper>
</titlestmt>
<publicationstmt>
<date normal="2021-08-06" encodinganalog="260$c" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">August 6, 2021</date>
<publisher>Baylor University, The Texas Collection</publisher>
</publicationstmt>
<notestmt>
<note>
<p>© 2021 The Texas Collection. All rights reserved.</p>
</note>
</notestmt>
</filedesc>
<profiledesc>
<creation>Finding Aid was generated by The Texas Collection staff, using the STAR Knowledge Center for Archives (SKCA) task that automatically creates EAD files from the Archive's SKCA catalog records.
</creation>
<langusage><language encodinganalog="546" langcode="eng">English</language></langusage>
</profiledesc>
</eadheader>


<archdesc level="otherlevel" otherlevel="papers">
<did>
<head>Papers Summary</head>
<repository encodinganalog="852$a" label="Repository">
<corpname>Baylor University, <subarea>The Texas Collection</subarea>
</corpname>
<extref xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:actuate="onRequest" xlink:show="new" xlink:href="http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/" xlink:type="simple">http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/</extref>
</repository>
<unitid encodinganalog="099" repositorycode="US-txwabtc" countrycode="US" label="Accession Number">530</unitid>
<origination label="Creator">
<persname encodinganalog="100" source="lcnaf">Clark, Horace</persname></origination>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245" label="Title">Horace Clark papers</unittitle>
<unitdate normal="1862/1909" encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">Inclusive: 1862-1909, undated</unitdate>
<physdesc encodinganalog="300$a">
<extent label="Quantity">4 folders</extent>
</physdesc>
<abstract encodinganalog="520$a" label="Abstract">The Horace Clark papers contain materials documenting the life of Horace Clark, principal of the Baylor Female Department and Baylor Female College in Independence, Texas.
</abstract>
<langmaterial encodinganalog="546$a" label="Language of the Material"><language langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech encodinganalog="340">
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Good.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>Horace Clark (1819-1909) was born in Massachusetts to John and Catherine Aldrich Clark. After his father passed away in 1821, he served aboard a merchant ship and was nearly forced into the Portuguese Navy in Rio de Janeiro. At seventeen years old, he enrolled in Shurtleff College in Illinois
then transferred to Georgetown College in Kentucky to complete his degree. He and Martha Davis were married on 1844 March 30.</p><p> </p><p>Clark served as principal of Henry Academy in New Castle, Kentucky for four years before becoming principal of La Grange Collegiate Institute in La Grange,
Texas, in 1851. On 1851 June 18, he became the principal of the Baylor Female Department in Independence, Texas. For the next fifteen years, he played a pivotal role in female education in Texas as head of Baylor University's Female Department, which had its own campus and buildings separate from
the Male Department. He raised the funds to build a large three-story stone building for the Female Department, one of the finest university buildings at the time. Despite his sometimes rocky relationship with Rufus Burleson, president of Baylor University and head of the Male Department, he ensured
female students received a quality education, and defended the need to educate women in a time when that was not recognized by everyone. Clark also served as the secretary of the Baptist State Convention 1856-1868, and was corresponding secretary in 1861, 1864, 1868-1870, and 1875. He was ordained a
Baptist pastor by Independence Baptist Church in 1858.</p><p> </p><p>In 1866, Horace Clark resigned as principal of the department. The Male Department had moved to Waco from Independence in 1861; so, in 1866 the Baptist State Convention of Texas organized Clark's Female Department into Baylor
Female College. Benjamin Simms Fitzgerald was named the first president. He served for one year before Horace Clark was elected to replace him. Clark served for four years, before resigning to open his own school in Houston, called Clark's Academy. The school operated until 1878 or 1879.</p><p>
</p><p>In 1877, Horace Clark joined the Episcopal Church, as he had been Baptist until that time. His wife, Martha Davis Clark, remained a Baptist until her death in 1896 January 9. In 1878, he became an Episcopal deacon at Christ Church, Houston. In 1879, he was ordained as an Episcopal priest, and
became the priest at the Church of the Good Shepherd in Corpus Christ in in 1880. He served there for the next eighteen years. Clark was also a Mason and served as grand chaplain of the Grand Lodge of Texas 1876-1879, 1884-1885, 1901-1902. </p><p> </p><p>Horace Clark passed away on 1909 February 10
and is buried in Glennwood Cemetery, Houston.</p>
</bioghist>
<scopecontent encodinganalog="520$b">
   <head>Scope and Content</head>
   <p>The Horace Clark papers include personal  correspondence, newspaper clippings written by and about Clark, a biographical manuscript at least partially written by Clark, and several copies of poems. Only the clippings describe his work with Baylor University, and most of them are about him, not
his work with education at Baylor. One of the clippings is a poem written by Clark in 1862, about a Confederate military unit. A large clipping, labeled Secession Article, is a lengthy newspaper article that Clark wrote about his views on slavery, secession, and the Confederacy.</p>
</scopecontent>
<arrangement encodinganalog="351">
<head>Arrangement</head>
<p>The Horace Clark papers were arranged in four folders by material type at the time of current processing. These four folders were retained, with slightly altered titles. Currently, the Horace Clark papers are arranged in one series: I. Personal.</p>
</arrangement>
<accessrestrict encodinganalog="506">
<head>Access Restrictions</head>
<p>All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing.  Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on
use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially
exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.</p>
</accessrestrict>
<userestrict encodinganalog="540">
<head>Use/Re-use Restrictions</head>
<p>The collection is open for research.</p>
</userestrict>
<prefercite encodinganalog="524">
<head>Preferred Citation</head>
<p>Horace Clark papers, Accession #530, Box #, Folder #, The Texas Collection, Baylor University.</p>
</prefercite>
<acqinfo encodinganalog="541">
<head>Acquisition Information</head>
<p>Accession No. 530.</p></acqinfo>
<processinfo encodinganalog="583">
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Described by Paul T. Fisher. Released on 2021-08-06.</p>
</processinfo>
<descgrp>
<head>Related Resources</head>
<relatedmaterial encodinganalog="544">
<head>Related references</head>
<bibref>
<extref xlink:type="simple" xlink:href="https://www.tshaonline.org/handbook/entries/clark-horace" xlink:show="new" xlink:actuate="onRequest"> Hesler, Samuel B. “Clark, Horace.” Handbook of Texas Online. Accessed 2021 June 21.</extref>
</bibref>
</relatedmaterial>
</descgrp>
</descgrp>
<controlaccess>
<head>Index Terms</head>
<controlaccess>
<head>Subjects (Organizations)</head>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Baylor Female College -- History.</corpname>
<corpname encodinganalog="610" source="lcnaf" role="subject">Baylor University (Independence, Tex.) -- History.</corpname>
</controlaccess>
<controlaccess>
<head>Genres</head>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Clippings (Books, newspapers, etc.)</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Manuscripts.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Personal correspondence.</genreform>
<genreform encodinganalog="655" source="local">Poems.</genreform>
</controlaccess>
</controlaccess>
<dsc type="combined">

<c01 id="recHCPAPERS.level1.000007129" level="series">
<did>
<unitid>1</unitid>
<unittitle>Personal</unittitle>
<unitdate normal="1862/1909" type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1862-1909, undated</unitdate>
</did>
<descgrp type="admininfo">
<head>Administrative Information</head>
<phystech>
<head>Physical Description</head>
<p>General condition: Average.</p>
</phystech>

<bioghist encodinganalog="545">
   <head>Biography/Profile</head>
   <p>This series contains materials documenting the life of Horace Clark, principal of Baylor Female Department and College and later an Episcopal minister. This series is in average condition.</p>
</bioghist>
<processinfo encodinganalog="583">
<head>Processing Information</head>
<p>Released on 2021-08-06.</p>
</processinfo>
</descgrp>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle encodinganalog="245$a">Correspondence</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1902" encodinganalog="245$f" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1902</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">2</container>
<unittitle>Newspaper Clippings</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1862/1909" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">1862-1909</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">2 OVZ</container>
<container type="folder">1</container>
<unittitle>Secession article</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">undated</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">3</container>
<unittitle>Poems</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">undated</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
<c02 level="file">
<did>
<container type="box">1</container>
<container type="folder">4</container>
<unittitle>Manuscript</unittitle>
<unitdate type="inclusive" era="ce" calendar="gregorian">undated</unitdate>
</did>
</c02>
</c01>
</dsc>
</archdesc>
</ead>

